<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0220.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Returns; filing requirement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A return with respect to the tax imposed by this code shall be made by every taxpayer for each taxable year in which such taxpayer either is liable for tax under this code or is required to make a federal income tax return, regardless of whether such taxpayer is liable for tax under this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every Florida partnership having any partner subject to tax under this code, shall make an information return setting forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All items of income, gain, loss, and deduction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of all partners subject to tax hereunder who would be entitled to share in the net income of the partnership if distributed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and proportion of the distributive share of each partner-taxpayer; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other pertinent information as the department may by form or regulation prescribe.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a receiver, trustee in bankruptcy, or assignee, by order of law or otherwise, has possession of or holds title to all or substantially all of the property or business of a taxpayer, whether or not such property or business is being operated, such receiver, trustee, or assignee shall make the returns and notices required of such taxpayer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall designate by rule certain not-for-profit entities and others that are not required to file a return under this code, including an initial information return, unless the entities have taxable income as defined in s. 220.13(2). These entities shall include subchapter S corporations, tax-exempt entities, and others that do not usually owe federal income tax.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-984; s. 3, ch. 98-100; s. 8, ch. 98-101; s. 43, ch. 2002-218.</History></Section>