<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0220.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature in enacting this code to impose a tax upon all corporations, organizations, associations, and other artificial entities which derive from this state or from any other jurisdiction permanent and inherent attributes not inherent in or available to natural persons, such as perpetual life, transferable ownership represented by shares or certificates, and limited liability for all owners. It is intended that any limited liability company that is classified as a partnership for federal income tax purposes and formed under chapter 608 or qualified to do business in this state as a foreign limited liability company not be subject to the tax imposed by this code. It is the intent of the Legislature to subject such corporations and other entities to taxation hereunder for the privilege of conducting business, deriving income, or existing within this state. This code is not intended to tax, and shall not be construed so as to tax, any natural person who engages in a trade, business, or profession in this state under his or her own or any fictitious name, whether individually as a proprietorship or in partnership with others, or as a member or a manager of a limited liability company classified as a partnership for federal income tax purposes; any estate of a decedent or incompetent; or any testamentary trust. However, a corporation or other taxable entity which is or which becomes partners with one or more natural persons shall not, merely by reason of being a partner, exclude from its net income subject to tax its respective share of partnership net income. This statement of intent shall be given preeminent consideration in any construction or interpretation of this code in order to avoid any conflict between this code and the mandate in s. 5, Art. VII of the State Constitution that no income tax be levied upon natural persons who are residents and citizens of this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the tax levied by this code be construed to be an excise or privilege tax measured by net income and that such tax not be deemed or construed to be a property tax or a tax on property or a tax measured by the value of property for any purpose.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the income tax imposed by this code utilize, to the greatest extent possible, concepts of law which have been developed in connection with the income tax laws of the United States, in order to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimize the expenses of the Department of Revenue and difficulties in administering this code;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimize the costs and difficulties of taxpayer compliance; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maximize, for both revenue and statistical purposes, the sharing of information between the state and the Federal Government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the tax imposed by this code be prospective in effect only. Consistent with this intention and the intent expressed in subsection (3), it is hereby declared to be the intent of the Legislature that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Income,” for purposes of this code, including gains from the sale, exchange, or other disposition of property, be deemed to be created for Florida income tax purposes at such time as such income is realized for federal income tax purposes;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No accretion of value, no accrual of gain, and no acquisition of a right to receive or accrue income which has occurred or been generated prior to November 2, 1971, be deemed to be “property,” or an interest in property, for any purpose under this code; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All income realized for federal income tax purposes after November 2, 1971, be subject to taxation in full by this state and be taxed in the manner and to the extent provided in this code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that, if there is included in any taxpayer’s net income subject to tax under this code any item or items of income which are determined to be improperly so included because of a conflict with any federal statute, the Constitution of the United States, or the State Constitution, all such items of income be excluded from the net incomes of all taxpayers subject to tax under this code, but all other provisions of this chapter, and their application, not be invalidated or in any way impaired by such required exclusion of an item or items of income.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the enterprise zone jobs credit provided by s. 220.181 be applicable only to those businesses located in an enterprise zone. It is further the intent of the Legislature to provide an incentive for the increased provision of employment opportunities leading to the improvement of the quality of life of those employed and the positive expansion of the economy of the state as well as the economy of present enterprise zones.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person charged with any criminal offense arising from a civil disorder associated with an emergency, as defined in s. 220.03(1)(i), and found guilty, whether or not adjudication of guilt or imposition of sentence is suspended, deferred, or withheld, is not eligible to make application for, receive, or in any other manner enjoy the benefits or any form of assistance available under chapter 80-247, Laws of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection expires on the date specified in s. 290.016 for the expiration of the Florida Enterprise Zone Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the enterprise zone property tax credit provided by s. 220.182 be applicable only to those new or expanded businesses located in enterprise zones which make a positive expansionary contribution to the economy of this state and to the economy of their local communities in terms of new jobs for residents of enterprise zones and improvements to real and personal property located in enterprise zones.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person charged with any criminal offense arising from a civil disorder associated with an emergency, as defined in s. 220.03(1)(i), and found guilty, whether or not adjudication of guilt or imposition of sentence is suspended, deferred, or withheld, is not eligible to make application for, receive, or in any other manner enjoy the benefits or any form of assistance available under chapter 80-248, Laws of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection expires on the date specified in s. 290.016 for the expiration of the Florida Enterprise Zone Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that credits against either the corporate income tax or the franchise tax be applied in the following order: those enumerated in s. 631.828, those enumerated in s. 220.191, those enumerated in s. 220.181, those enumerated in s. 220.183, those enumerated in s. 220.182, those enumerated in s. 220.1895, those enumerated in s. 220.195, those enumerated in s. 220.184, those enumerated in s. 220.186, those enumerated in s. 220.1845, those enumerated in s. 220.19, those enumerated in s. 220.185, those enumerated in s. 220.1875, those enumerated in s. 220.192, those enumerated in s. 220.193, those enumerated in s. 288.9916, those enumerated in s. 220.1899, those enumerated in s. 220.1896, those enumerated in s. 220.194, and those enumerated in s. 220.196.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, it is the intent of the Legislature that, except as otherwise provided under the Internal Revenue Code, for the purposes of this chapter, the term “qualified subchapter S subsidiary,” as that term is defined in s. 1361(b)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, shall not be treated as a separate corporation or entity from the S corporation parent to which the subsidiary’s assets, liabilities, income, deductions, and credits are attributed under s. 1361(b)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-984; s. 1, ch. 72-278; s. 5, ch. 80-77; ss. 1, 5, 6, ch. 80-247; ss. 1, 9, 10, ch. 80-248; s. 2, ch. 82-119; s. 3, ch. 82-177; s. 5, ch. 82-232; s. 59, ch. 83-3; s. 11, ch. 83-297; ss. 18, 19, ch. 83-310; s. 10, ch. 83-334; s. 36, ch. 84-356; s. 16, ch. 87-99; s. 15, ch. 88-201; s. 22, ch. 88-388; s. 8, ch. 89-167; s. 48, ch. 94-136; s. 1517, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 97-50; s. 1, ch. 98-61; s. 2, ch. 98-100; s. 7, ch. 98-101; s. 11, ch. 98-132; s. 2, ch. 98-189; s. 1, ch. 98-293; s. 22, ch. 98-342; s. 94, ch. 99-2; ss. 16, 17, ch. 99-378; ss. 29, 30, ch. 2000-210; s. 6, ch. 2001-225; s. 23, ch. 2005-287; s. 11, ch. 2006-230; s. 2, ch. 2009-50; s. 5, ch. 2010-24; s. 11, ch. 2010-147; ss. 5, 6, ch. 2011-76.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 20, ch. 2010-24, provides that “[t]he Department of Revenue is authorized and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54, Florida Statutes, to administer the provisions of this act. The emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the rules are adopted and the rules may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 35, ch. 2011-76, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the date adopted and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>