<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0220.801" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties; failure to timely file returns.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of failure to file any tax return required under this chapter on the date prescribed therefor, including any extensions thereof, there shall be added as a penalty to the amount of tax due with such return 10 percent of the amount of such tax, if the failure is not for more than 1 month, plus an additional 10 percent for each additional month or fraction thereof during which such failure continues, not exceeding 50 percent in the aggregate. The department may settle or compromise such penalties pursuant to s. 213.21. For purposes of this section, the amount of tax due with any return shall be reduced by any part of the tax which is paid on or before the date prescribed for payment of the tax and by the amount of any credit against the tax which was properly allowable on the date the return was required to be filed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of failure to file any tax return required by this chapter, notwithstanding that no tax is shown to be due thereon, a penalty in the amount of $50 for each month or portion thereof, not to exceed $300 in the aggregate, shall be assessed and paid for each such failure to file. This subsection shall only apply to corporations when they also are required to file a federal income tax return.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any penalty is assessed under subsection (1) for failure to file a return by the prescribed date, no penalty under subsection (2) for failure to file a return with no tax shown to be due shall be assessed with respect to the same return.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall specifically apply to the notice of federal change required under s. 220.23.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 71-359; s. 4, ch. 74-324; s. 15, ch. 81-178; s. 8, ch. 86-121; s. 94, ch. 87-6; s. 61, ch. 87-101; s. 62, ch. 91-112; s. 29, ch. 92-320; s. 18, ch. 2011-76.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 35, ch. 2011-76, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the date adopted and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 214.40.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>