<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0220.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemption.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In computing a taxpayer’s liability for tax under this code, there shall be exempt from the tax $50,000 of net income as defined in s. 220.12 or such lesser amount as will, without increasing the taxpayer’s federal income tax liability, provide the state with an amount under this code which is equal to the maximum federal income tax credit which may be available from time to time under federal law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a taxable year for a period of less than 12 months, the exemption allowed by this section shall be prorated on the basis of the number of days in such year to 365.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only one exemption shall be allowed to taxpayers filing a consolidated return under this code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this code, not more than one exemption under this section may be allowed to the Florida members of a controlled group of corporations, as defined in s. 1563 of the Internal Revenue Code with respect to taxable years ending on or after December 31, 1970, filing separate returns under this code. The exemption described in this section shall be divided equally among such Florida members of the group, unless all of such members consent, at such time and in such manner as the department shall by regulation prescribe, to an apportionment plan providing for an unequal allocation of such exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-984; s. 6, ch. 83-349; s. 3, ch. 84-549; s. 5, ch. 2011-229; s. 10, ch. 2012-32.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 10, ch. 2012-32, amended subsection (1) “[e]ffective January 1, 2013, and applying to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2013.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 3, ch. 2011-229, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 25, ch. 2012-32, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the date adopted and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>