<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0220.62" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this part:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “bank” means a bank holding company registered under the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 of the United States, 12 U.S.C. ss. 1841-1849, as amended, or a bank or trust company incorporated and doing business under the laws of the United States (including laws relating to the District of Columbia), of any state, or of any territory, a substantial part of the business of which consists of receiving deposits and making loans and discounts or of exercising fiduciary powers similar to those permitted to national banks under authority of the Comptroller of the Currency and which is subject by law to supervision and examination by state, territorial, or federal authority having supervision over banking institutions. The term “bank” also includes any banking association, corporation, or other similar organization organized and operated under the laws of any foreign country, which banking association, corporation, or other organization is also operating in this state pursuant to chapter 663.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “savings association” means a savings association holding company registered under the Homeowners’ Loan Act (HOLA) of 1933, 12 U.S.C. s. 1467a, as amended, or any savings association, building and loan association, savings and loan association, or mutual savings bank not having capital stock, whether subject to the laws of this or any other jurisdiction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “international banking facility” means a set of asset and liability accounts segregated on the books and records of a banking organization that includes only international banking facility deposits, borrowings, and extensions of credit, as those terms are defined by the Financial Services Commission, taking into account all transactions in which international banking facilities are permitted to engage by regulations of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, as from time to time amended. When providing such definitions, the Financial Services Commission shall also consider the public interest, including the need to maintain a sound and competitive banking system, as well as the purpose of this act, which is to create an environment conducive to the conduct of an international banking business in the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “banking organization” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank organized and existing under the laws of any state;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A national bank organized and existing as a national banking association pursuant to the provisions of the National Bank Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 21 et seq.;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An Edge Act corporation organized pursuant to the provisions of s. 25(a) of the Federal Reserve Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 611 et seq.;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An international bank agency licensed pursuant to the laws of any state;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federal agency licensed pursuant to ss. 4 and 5 of the International Banking Act of 1978;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A savings association organized and existing under the laws of any state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federal association organized and existing pursuant to the provisions of the Home Owners’ Loan Act of 1933, 12 U.S.C. ss. 1461 et seq.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “foreign person” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who is not a resident of the United States;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation, foreign partnership, or foreign trust, as defined in s. 7701 of the Internal Revenue Code, other than a domestic branch thereof;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign branch of a domestic corporation (including the taxpayer);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign government or an international organization, or an agency of either; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An international banking facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of this subsection, the terms “foreign” and “domestic” have the same meaning as set forth in s. 7701 of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 72-278; s. 1, ch. 73-152; s. 6, ch. 78-299; s. 149, ch. 80-260; s. 5, ch. 81-179; s. 18, ch. 88-119; s. 23, ch. 2000-355; s. 259, ch. 2003-261; s. 4, ch. 2011-97.</History>
</Section>