<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0220.186" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Credit for Florida alternative minimum tax.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A taxpayer required to determine taxable income pursuant to s. 220.13(2)(k) shall be allowed a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter in any subsequent taxable years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The credit pursuant to this section shall be the amount of the excess, if any, of the tax paid based upon taxable income determined pursuant to s. 220.13(2)(k) over the amount of tax which would have been due based upon taxable income without application of s. 220.13(2)(k), before application of this credit without application of any credit under s. 220.1875.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of credit allowable in any subsequent taxable years shall not exceed the excess, if any, of the amount of tax computed under this chapter without application of s. 220.13(2)(k) over the amount of tax computed with application of s. 220.13(2)(k), whether or not such paragraph is required to compute taxable income for the year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 87-99; s. 16, ch. 90-203; s. 1, ch. 2009-108; s. 8, ch. 2010-24.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 20, ch. 2010-24, provides that “[t]he Department of Revenue is authorized and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54, Florida Statutes, to administer the provisions of this act. The emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the rules are adopted and the rules may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>