<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0220.222" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Returns; time and place for filing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Returns required by this code shall be filed with the office of the department in Leon County or at such other place as the department may by regulation prescribe. All returns required for a DISC (Domestic International Sales Corporation) under paragraph 6011(c)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code shall be filed on or before the 1st day of the 10th month following the close of the taxable year; all partnership information returns shall be filed on or before the 1st day of the 5th month following the close of the taxable year; and all other returns shall be filed on or before the 1st day of the 4th month following the close of the taxable year or the 15th day following the due date, without extension, for the filing of the related federal return for the taxable year, unless under subsection (2) one or more extensions of time, not to exceed 6 months in the aggregate, for any such filing is granted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a taxpayer has been granted an extension or extensions of time within which to file its federal income tax return for any taxable year, and if the requirements of s. 220.32 are met, the filing of a request for such extension or extensions with the department shall automatically extend the due date of the return required under this code until 15 days after the expiration of the federal extension or until the expiration of 6 months from the original due date, whichever first occurs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may grant an extension or extensions of time for the filing of any return required under this code upon receiving a prior request therefor if good cause for an extension is shown. However, the aggregate extensions of time under paragraphs (a) and (b) shall not exceed 6 months. No extension granted under this paragraph shall be valid unless the taxpayer complies with the requirements of s. 220.32.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, a taxpayer is not in compliance with the requirements of s. 220.32 if the taxpayer underpays the required payment by more than the greater of $2,000 or 30 percent of the tax shown on the return when filed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-984; s. 6, ch. 72-278; s. 3, ch. 74-324; s. 2, ch. 79-326; s. 17, ch. 87-99; s. 27, ch. 98-342; s. 32, ch. 99-208.</History></Section>