<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0220.63" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Franchise tax imposed on banks and savings associations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A franchise tax measured by net income is hereby imposed on every bank and savings association for each taxable year commencing on or after January 1, 1973, and for each taxable year which begins before and ends after January 1, 1973. The franchise tax base of any bank for a taxable year which begins before and ends after January 1, 1972, shall be prorated in the manner prescribed for the proration of net income under <Reference Number="1" />s. 220.12(2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax imposed by this section shall be an amount equal to 5<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> percent of the franchise tax base of the bank or savings association for the taxable year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Reference Number="2"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this part, the franchise tax base shall be adjusted federal income, as defined in s. 220.13, apportioned to this state, plus nonbusiness income allocated to this state pursuant to s. 220.16, less the deduction allowed in subsection (5) and less $50,000.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this part shall be construed to prohibit a savings association, in computing its franchise tax base, from claiming the maximum deduction allowed under s. 593 of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be allowed as a deduction from adjusted federal income, to the extent not deductible in determining federal taxable income or subtracted pursuant to s. 220.13(1)(b)2., the eligible net income of an international banking facility determined as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The “eligible net income of an international banking facility” is the amount remaining after subtracting from the eligible gross income the applicable expenses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The “eligible gross income” is the gross income derived by an international banking facility from:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making, arranging for, placing, or servicing loans to foreign persons, provided, however, that in the case of a foreign person which is an individual, a foreign branch of a domestic corporation (other than a bank or savings association), or a foreign corporation or a foreign partnership which is 80 percent or more owned or controlled, either directly or indirectly, by one or more domestic corporations (other than banks or savings associations), domestic partnerships, or resident individuals, substantially all the proceeds of the loan are for use outside the United States;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or placing deposits with foreign persons which are banks or savings associations or foreign branches of banks or savings associations, including foreign subsidiaries or foreign branches of the taxpayer, or with other international banking facilities; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entering into foreign exchange trading or hedging transactions in connection with the activities described in this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, the term “eligible gross income” does not include any amount derived by an international banking facility from making, arranging for, placing, or servicing loans or making or placing deposits if the loans or deposits of funds are secured by mortgages, deeds of trust, or other liens upon real property located in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The “applicable expenses” are any expenses or other deductions attributable, directly or indirectly, to the eligible gross income described in paragraph (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 72-278; s. 2, ch. 73-152; s. 6, ch. 81-179; s. 9, ch. 83-349; ss. 8, 12, 22, ch. 84-549; s. 102, ch. 91-112; s. 6, ch. 2011-229; s. 11, ch. 2012-32.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 14, ch. 90-203.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 11, ch. 2012-32, amended subsection (3) “[e]ffective January 1, 2013, and applying to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2013.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 3, ch. 2011-229, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 25, ch. 2012-32, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the date adopted and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>