<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0220.735" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Production of witnesses and records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, or any officer or employee of the department designated by the executive director in writing or by regulation, shall at its, her, or his own instance, or on the written request of any other party to the proceeding, issue subpoenas requiring the attendance of, and the giving of testimony by, witnesses and issue subpoenas duces tecum requiring the production of books, papers, records, or memoranda. All subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum issued under this chapter may be served by any person of full age.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Witnesses other than employees of the state shall be entitled to receive for attendance and travel the same fees as witnesses before the circuit courts of this state, such fees to be paid when the witness is excused from further attendance. When the witness is subpoenaed for the department or any officer or employee thereof, such fees shall be paid in the same manner as other expenses of the department. When the witness is subpoenaed for any other party, the cost of subpoena service and the witness fee shall be borne by the party at whose instance the witness is summoned, and the department may, in its discretion, require a deposit or advance payment to cover the cost of such service and witness fee. Subpoenas issued hereunder shall be served in the same manner as subpoenas issued from the circuit courts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any circuit court of the state, or any judge thereof, upon application of the department or any officer or employee thereof or upon the application of any other party to the proceeding may, in its, her, or his discretion, compel the attendance of witnesses, the production of books, papers, records, or memoranda, and the giving of testimony before the department or any officer or employee thereof conducting an investigation authorized by this chapter in the same manner as the production of evidence may be compelled before said court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 71-359; s. 54, ch. 78-95; s. 58, ch. 91-112; s. 1190, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 214.20.</Text></Note></Section>