<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0220.185" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State housing tax credit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Credit period” means the period of 5 years beginning with the year the project is completed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible basis” means a project’s adjusted basis of the housing portion of the qualified project as of the close of the first taxable year of the credit period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adjusted basis” means the owner’s adjusted basis in the project, calculated in a manner consistent with the calculation of basis under the Internal Revenue Code, taking into account the adjusted basis of property of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation used in common areas or provided as comparable amenities to the entire project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Designated project” means a qualified project designated pursuant to s. 420.5093 to receive the tax credit under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified project” means a project located in an urban infill area, at least 50 percent of which, on a cost basis, consists of a qualified low-income project within the meaning of s. 42(g) of the Internal Revenue Code, including such projects designed specifically for the elderly but excluding any income restrictions imposed pursuant to s. 42(g) of the Internal Revenue Code upon residents of the project unless such restrictions are otherwise established by the Florida Housing Finance Corporation pursuant to s. 420.5093, and the remainder of which constitutes commercial or single-family residential development consistent with and serving to complement the qualified low-income project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Urban infill area” means an area designated for urban infill as defined by s. 163.3164 or as defined through a statewide urban infill study solicited and approved by the Board of Directors of the Florida Housing Finance Corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZATION TO GRANT STATE HOUSING TAX CREDITS; LIMITATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be allowed a credit of up to 9 percent, but no more than necessary to make the project feasible, of the eligible basis of any designated project for each year of the credit period against any tax due for a taxable year under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount of tax credits allocated for all projects shall not exceed the amount appropriated for the State Housing Tax Credit Program in the General Appropriations Act. The total tax credits allocated is defined as the total credits pledged over a 5-year period for all projects.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax credit shall be allocated among designated projects by the Florida Housing Finance Corporation as provided in s. 420.5093.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each designated project must comply with the applicable provisions of s. 42 of the Internal Revenue Code with respect to the multifamily residential rental housing element of the project, including specifically the provisions of s. 42(h)(6).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tax credit shall be allocated to a designated project and shall not be subject to transfer by the recipient unless the transferee is also an owner of the designated project.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 99-378; s. 27, ch. 2000-210.</History></Section>