<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0220.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Returns and records; regulations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every taxpayer liable for the tax imposed by this code shall keep such records, render such statements, make such returns and notices, and comply with such rules and regulations, as the department may from time to time prescribe. The director may require any taxpayer or class of taxpayers, by notice or by regulation, to make such returns and notices, render such statements, and keep such records as the director deems necessary to determine whether such taxpayer or taxpayers are liable for tax under this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A taxpayer who is required to file its federal income tax return by electronic means on a separate or consolidated basis shall file returns required by this chapter by electronic means. For the reasons described in s. 213.755(9), the department may waive the requirement to file a return by electronic means for taxpayers that are unable to comply despite good faith efforts or due to circumstances beyond the taxpayer’s reasonable control. The provisions of this subsection are in addition to the requirements of s. 213.755 to electronically file returns and remit payments required under this chapter. The department may prescribe by rule the format and instructions necessary for electronic filing to ensure a full collection of taxes due. In addition to the authority granted under s. 213.755, the acceptable method of transfer, the method, form, and content of the electronic data interchange, and the means, if any, by which the taxpayer will be provided with an acknowledgment may be prescribed by the department. In the case of any failure to comply with the electronic filing requirements of this subsection, a penalty shall be added to the amount of tax due with such return equal to 5 percent of the amount of such tax for the first 30 days the return is not filed electronically, with an additional 5 percent of such tax for each additional month or fraction thereof, not to exceed $250 in the aggregate. The department may settle or compromise the penalty pursuant to s. 213.21. This penalty is in addition to any other penalty that may be applicable and shall be assessed, collected, and paid in the same manner as taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to its authority under s. 213.755, the department may adopt rules requiring or allowing taxpayers to use an electronic filing system to file returns required by subsection (2), including any electronic systems developed by the Internal Revenue Service. Rulemaking authority requiring electronic filing is limited to the federal corporate income tax filing threshold for electronic filing as it exists on January 1, 2007.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-984; s. 30, ch. 99-208; s. 31, ch. 2007-106.</History></Section>