<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0218.407" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local government investment authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to any determination by the governing body that it is in the interest of the unit of local government to deposit surplus funds in the trust fund, the board or a professional money management firm must provide to the governing body enrollment materials, including a trust fund profile containing impartial educational information describing the administration and investment policy of the trust fund, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rights and conditions of participation, including potential restrictions on withdrawals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The historical performance, investment holdings, credit quality, and average maturity of the trust fund investments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicable administrative rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate determination processes for any deposit or withdrawal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any fees, charges, penalties, and deductions that apply to the account.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The most recently published financial statements or independent audits, if available, prepared under generally accepted accounting principles.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A disclosure statement for signature by the appropriate local government official.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon review of the enrollment materials and upon determination by the governing body that it is in the interest of the unit of local government to deposit surplus funds in the trust fund, a resolution by the governing body and the signed acceptance of the disclosure statement by the local government official, who may be the chief financial or administrative officer of the local government, shall be filed with the board and, if appropriate, a copy shall be provided to a professional money management firm authorizing investment of its surplus funds in the trust fund established by this part. The resolution shall name:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government official, who may be the chief financial or administrative officer of the local government, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An independent trustee holding funds on behalf of the unit of local government,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">responsible for deposit and withdrawal of such funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board or a professional money management firm shall, upon the filing of the resolution, invest the moneys in the trust fund in the same manner and subject to the same restrictions as are set forth in s. 215.47. All units of local government that qualify to be participants in the trust fund shall have surplus funds deposited into a pooled investment account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this part shall not impair the power of a unit of local government to hold funds in deposit accounts with banking or savings institutions or to invest funds as otherwise authorized by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-394; s. 6, ch. 82-45; s. 3, ch. 84-137; s. 5, ch. 87-239; s. 9, ch. 98-47; s. 4, ch. 98-124; s. 4, ch. 2008-59.</History></Section>