<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0218.418" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 218.421 and 218.422, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the State Board of Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surplus funds” means any funds in any general or special account or fund of a unit of local government, or funds held by an independent trustee on behalf of a unit of local government, which in reasonable contemplation will not be immediately needed for the purposes intended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trust fund” means the pooled investment fund known as the Fund B Surplus Funds Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trustees” means the Trustees of the State Board of Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unit of local government” means any governmental entity within the state not part of state government and includes, but is not limited to, the following and the officers thereof: any county, municipality, school district, special district, clerk of the circuit court, sheriff, property appraiser, tax collector, supervisor of elections, authority, board, public corporation, or other political subdivision of the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 11, ch. 2008-59.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 11, ch. 2008-59, provides that “[s]ections 218.418, 218.421, and 218.422, Florida Statutes, as created by this act, shall expire at the time the Fund B Surplus Funds Trust Fund is terminated by law or self-liquidates as determined and announced by the executive director of the State Board of Administration, whichever occurs first.”</Text></Note></Section>