<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0218.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appropriations to offset reductions in ad valorem tax revenue in fiscally constrained counties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in fiscal year 2008-2009, the Legislature shall appropriate moneys to offset the reductions in ad valorem tax revenue experienced by fiscally constrained counties, as defined in s. 218.67(1), which occur as a direct result of the implementation of revisions of Art. VII of the State Constitution approved in the special election held on January 29, 2008. The moneys appropriated for this purpose shall be distributed in January of each fiscal year among the fiscally constrained counties based on each county’s proportion of the total reduction in ad valorem tax revenue resulting from the implementation of the revision.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before November 15 of each year, each fiscally constrained county shall apply to the Department of Revenue to participate in the distribution of the appropriation and provide documentation supporting the county’s estimated reduction in ad valorem tax revenue in the form and manner prescribed by the Department of Revenue. The documentation must include an estimate of the reduction in taxable value directly attributable to revisions of Art. VII of the State Constitution for all county taxing jurisdictions within the county and shall be prepared by the property appraiser in each fiscally constrained county. The documentation must also include the county millage rates applicable in all such jurisdictions for both the current year and the prior year; rolled-back rates, determined as provided in s. 200.065, for each county taxing jurisdiction; and maximum millage rates that could have been levied by majority vote pursuant to s. 200.065(5). For purposes of this section, each fiscally constrained county’s reduction in ad valorem tax revenue shall be calculated as 95 percent of the estimated reduction in taxable value times the lesser of the 2007 applicable millage rate or the applicable millage rate for each county taxing jurisdiction in the current year. If a fiscally constrained county fails to apply for the distribution, its share shall revert to the fund from which the appropriation was made.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the reductions in ad valorem tax revenues occurring as a result of the implementation of the revisions to Art. VII of the State Constitution approved in the special election held on January 29, 2008, the value of assessments reduced pursuant to s. 4(d)(8)a., Art. VII of the State Constitution shall include only the reduction in taxable value for homesteads established January 1 of the year in which the determination is being made.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 2008-173; ss. 24, 25, ch. 2009-82; ss. 18, 19, 73, ch. 2010-153; s. 9, ch. 2010-166; s. 8, ch. 2011-125; s. 30, ch. 2012-193.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 13, ch. 2008-173, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 18 months after the date of adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 8, ch. 2011-125, amended s. 218.12, effective “[i]f House Joint Resolution 381 or Senate Joint Resolution 658, 2011 Regular Session, is approved by a vote of the electors  . . .  in the general election held in November 2012.” House Joint Resolution 381 passed; if it is approved by a vote of the electors  . . .  in the general election held in November 2012, s. 218.12, as amended by s. 30, ch. 2012-193, and s. 8, ch. 2011-125, will read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">218.12 Appropriations to offset reductions in ad valorem tax revenue in fiscally constrained counties.</Font><EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1)(a) Beginning in fiscal year 2008-2009, the Legislature shall appropriate moneys to offset the reductions in ad valorem tax revenue experienced by fiscally constrained counties, as defined in s. 218.67(1), which occur as a direct result of the implementation of revisions of Art. VII of the State Constitution approved in the special election held on January 29, 2008. The moneys appropriated for this purpose shall be distributed in January of each fiscal year among the fiscally constrained counties based on each county’s proportion of the total reduction in ad valorem tax revenue resulting from the implementation of the revision.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) On or before November 15 of each year, each fiscally constrained county shall apply to the Department of Revenue to participate in the distribution of the appropriation and provide documentation supporting the county’s estimated reduction in ad valorem tax revenue in the form and manner prescribed by the Department of Revenue. The documentation must include an estimate of the reduction in taxable value directly attributable to revisions of Art. VII of the State Constitution for all county taxing jurisdictions within the county and shall be prepared by the property appraiser in each fiscally constrained county. The documentation must also include the county millage rates applicable in all such jurisdictions for both the current year and the prior year; rolled-back rates, determined as provided in s. 200.065, for each county taxing jurisdiction; and maximum millage rates that could have been levied by majority vote pursuant to s. 200.165(5). For purposes of this section, each fiscally constrained county’s reduction in ad valorem tax revenue shall be calculated as 95 percent of the estimated reduction in taxable value times the lesser of the 2007 applicable millage rate or the applicable millage rate for each county taxing jurisdiction in the current year. If a fiscally constrained county fails to apply for the distribution, its share shall revert to the fund from which the appropriation was made.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) In determining the reductions in ad valorem tax revenues occurring as a result of the implementation of the revisions to Art. VII of the State Constitution approved in the special election held on January 29, 2008, the value of assessments reduced pursuant to s. 4(d)(8)a., Art. VII of the State Constitution shall include only the reduction in taxable value for homesteads established January 1 of the year in which the determination is being made.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2)(a) Beginning in the 2012-2013 fiscal year, the Legislature shall consider appropriating moneys to offset the reductions in ad valorem tax revenue experienced by fiscally constrained counties, as defined in s. 218.67(1), which occur as a direct result of the implementation of the revision of Art. VII of the State Constitution contained in House Joint Resolution 381 or Senate Joint Resolution 658, 2011 Regular Session. The moneys appropriated for this purpose shall be distributed among the fiscally constrained counties based on each county’s proportion of the total reduction in ad valorem tax revenue resulting from the implementation of the revision.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) On or before February 1 each year, each fiscally constrained county shall apply to the Department of Revenue to participate in the distribution of the appropriation and provide documentation supporting the county’s estimated reduction in ad valorem tax revenue to the Department of Revenue.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 9, ch. 2011-125, provides that “[t]his act shall take effect upon becoming a law, except that  . . . the sections of this act which take effect upon the approval of House Joint Resolution 381 or Senate Joint Resolution 658, 2011 Regular Session, by a vote of the electors in the general election held in November 2012 shall apply to the 2013 tax roll if the revision of the State Constitution contained in House Joint Resolution 381 or Senate Joint Resolution 658, 2011 Regular Session, is approved by a vote of the electors in the general election held in November 2012.” House Joint Resolution 381 passed the Legislature.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>