<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0218.735" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Timely payment for purchases of construction services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The due date for payment for the purchase of construction services by a local governmental entity is determined as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an agent must approve the payment request or invoice before the payment request or invoice is submitted to the local governmental entity, payment is due 25 business days after the date on which the payment request or invoice is stamped as received as provided in s. 218.74(1). The contractor may send the local government an overdue notice. If the payment request or invoice is not rejected within 4 business days after delivery of the overdue notice, the payment request or invoice shall be deemed accepted, except for any portion of the payment request or invoice that is fraudulent or misleading.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an agent need not approve the payment request or invoice submitted by the contractor, payment is due 20 business days after the date on which the payment request or invoice is stamped as received as provided in s. 218.74(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A local governmental entity shall identify the agent or employee of the local governmental entity, or the facility or office, to which the contractor may submit its payment request or invoice. This requirement shall be included in the contract between the local governmental entity and contractor, or shall be provided by the local governmental entity through a separate written notice, as required under the contract, no later than 10 days after the contract award or notice to proceed. A contractor’s submission of a payment request or invoice to the identified agent, employee, facility, or office of the local governmental entity shall be stamped as received as provided in s. 218.74(1) and shall commence the time periods for payment or rejection of a payment request or invoice as provided in this subsection and subsection (2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a payment request or invoice does not meet the contract requirements, the local governmental entity must reject the payment request or invoice within 20 business days after the date on which the payment request or invoice is stamped as received as provided in s. 218.74(1). The rejection must be written and must specify the deficiency and the action necessary to make the payment request or invoice proper.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a payment request or an invoice is rejected under subsection (2) and the contractor submits a payment request or invoice that corrects the deficiency, the corrected payment request or invoice must be paid or rejected on the later of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten business days after the date the corrected payment request or invoice is stamped as received as provided in s. 218.74(1); or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local governmental entity is required by ordinance, charter, or other law to approve or reject the corrected payment request or invoice, the first business day after the next regularly scheduled meeting of the local governmental entity held after the corrected payment request or invoice is stamped as received as provided in s. 218.74(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a dispute between the local governmental entity and the contractor cannot be resolved by the procedure in subsection (3), the dispute must be resolved in accordance with the dispute resolution procedure prescribed in the construction contract or in any applicable ordinance, which shall be referenced in the contract. In the absence of a prescribed procedure, the dispute must be resolved by the procedure specified in s. 218.76(2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local governmental entity disputes a portion of a payment request or an invoice, the undisputed portion shall be paid timely, in accordance with subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a contractor receives payment from a local governmental entity for labor, services, or materials furnished by subcontractors and suppliers hired by the contractor, the contractor must remit payment due to those subcontractors and suppliers within 10 days after the contractor’s receipt of payment. If a subcontractor receives payment from a contractor for labor, services, or materials furnished by subcontractors and suppliers hired by the subcontractor, the subcontractor must remit payment due to those subcontractors and suppliers within 7 days after the subcontractor’s receipt of payment. This subsection does not prohibit a contractor or subcontractor from disputing, pursuant to the terms of the relevant contract, all or any portion of a payment alleged to be due to another party if the contractor or subcontractor notifies the party whose payment is disputed, in writing, of the amount in dispute and the actions required to cure the dispute. The contractor or subcontractor must pay all undisputed amounts due within the time limits imposed by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract for construction services between a local governmental entity and a contractor must provide for the development of a single list of items required to render complete, satisfactory, and acceptable the construction services purchased by the local governmental entity.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract must specify the process for developing the list, including the responsibilities of the local governmental entity and the contractor in developing and reviewing the list and a reasonable time for developing the list:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For construction projects having an estimated cost of Less than $10 million, within 30 calendar days after reaching substantial completion of the construction services purchased as defined in the contract, or, if not defined in the contract, upon reaching beneficial occupancy or use; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For construction projects having an estimated cost of $10 million or more, within 30 calendar days, or, if extended by contract, up to 60 calendar days after reaching substantial completion of the construction services purchased as defined in the contract, or, if not defined in the contract, upon reaching beneficial occupancy or use.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The contract must also specify a date for the delivery of the list of items, not to exceed 5 days after the list of items has been developed and reviewed in accordance with the time periods set forth in subparagraphs 1. and 2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the contract between the local governmental entity and the contractor relates to the purchase of construction services on more than one building or structure, or involves a multiphased project, the contract must provide for the development of a list of items required to render complete, satisfactory, and acceptable all the construction services purchased pursuant to the contract for each building, structure, or phase of the project within the time limitations provided in paragraph (a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The final contract completion date must be at least 30 days after the delivery of the list of items. If the list is not provided to the contractor by the agreed upon date for delivery of the list, the contract time for completion must be extended by the number of days the local governmental entity exceeded the delivery date. Damages may not be assessed against a contractor for failing to complete a project within the time required by the contract, unless the contractor failed to complete the project within the contract period as extended under this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure to include any corrective work or pending items not yet completed on the list does not alter the responsibility of the contractor to complete all the construction services purchased pursuant to the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon completion of all items on the list, the contractor may submit a payment request for all remaining retainage withheld by the local governmental entity pursuant to this section. If a good faith dispute exists as to whether one or more items identified on the list have been completed pursuant to the contract, the local governmental entity may continue to withhold up to 150 percent of the total costs to complete such items.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All items that require correction under the contract and that are identified after the preparation and delivery of the list remain the obligation of the contractor as defined by the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Warranty items or items not included in the list of items required under paragraph (a) may not affect the final payment of retainage as provided in this section or as provided in the contract between the contractor and its subcontractors and suppliers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retainage may not be held by a local governmental entity or a contractor to secure payment of insurance premiums under a consolidated insurance program or series of insurance policies issued to a local governmental entity or a contractor for a project or group of projects, and the final payment of retainage as provided in this section may not be delayed pending a final audit by the local governmental entity’s or contractor’s insurance provider.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local governmental entity fails to comply with its responsibilities to develop the list required under paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) within the time limitations provided in paragraph (a), the contractor may submit a payment request for all remaining retainage withheld by the local governmental entity pursuant to this section; and payment of any remaining undisputed contract amount, less any amount withheld pursuant to the contract for incomplete or uncorrected work, must be paid within 20 business days after receipt of a proper invoice or payment request. If the local governmental entity has provided written notice to the contractor specifying the failure of the contractor to meet contract requirements in the development of the list of items to be completed, the local governmental entity need not pay or process any payment request for retainage if the contractor has, in whole or in part, failed to cooperate with the local governmental entity in the development of the list or to perform its contractual responsibilities, if any, with regard to the development of the list or if paragraph (8)(f) applies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With regard to any contract for construction services, a local governmental entity may withhold from each progress payment made to the contractor an amount not exceeding 10 percent of the payment as retainage until 50-percent completion of such services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After 50-percent completion of the construction services purchased pursuant to the contract, the local governmental entity must reduce to 5 percent the amount of retainage withheld from each subsequent progress payment made to the contractor. For purposes of this subsection, the term “50-percent completion” has the meaning set forth in the contract between the local governmental entity and the contractor or, if not defined in the contract, the point at which the local governmental entity has expended 50 percent of the total cost of the construction services purchased as identified in the contract together with all costs associated with existing change orders and other additions or modifications to the construction services provided for in the contract. However, notwithstanding this subsection, a municipality having a population of 25,000 or fewer, or a county having a population of 100,000 or fewer, may withhold retainage in an amount not exceeding 10 percent of each progress payment made to the contractor until final completion and acceptance of the project by the local governmental entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After 50-percent completion of the construction services purchased pursuant to the contract, the contractor may elect to withhold retainage from payments to its subcontractors at a rate higher than 5 percent. The specific amount to be withheld must be determined on a case-by-case basis and must be based on the contractor’s assessment of the subcontractor’s past performance, the likelihood that such performance will continue, and the contractor’s ability to rely on other safeguards. The contractor shall notify the subcontractor, in writing, of its determination to withhold more than 5 percent of the progress payment and the reasons for making that determination, and the contractor may not request the release of such retained funds from the local governmental entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After 50-percent completion of the construction services purchased pursuant to the contract, the contractor may present to the local governmental entity a payment request for up to one-half of the retainage held by the local governmental entity. The local governmental entity shall promptly make payment to the contractor, unless the local governmental entity has grounds, pursuant to paragraph (f), for withholding the payment of retainage. If the local governmental entity makes payment of retainage to the contractor under this paragraph which is attributable to the labor, services, or materials supplied by one or more subcontractors or suppliers, the contractor shall timely remit payment of such retainage to those subcontractors and suppliers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit a local governmental entity from withholding retainage at a rate less than 10 percent of each progress payment, from incrementally reducing the rate of retainage pursuant to a schedule provided for in the contract, or from releasing at any point all or a portion of any retainage withheld by the local governmental entity which is attributable to the labor, services, or materials supplied by the contractor or by one or more subcontractors or suppliers. If a local governmental entity makes any payment of retainage to the contractor which is attributable to the labor, services, or materials supplied by one or more subcontractors or suppliers, the contractor shall timely remit payment of such retainage to those subcontractors and suppliers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not require the local governmental entity to pay or release any amounts that are the subject of a good faith dispute, the subject of a claim brought pursuant to s. 255.05, or otherwise the subject of a claim or demand by the local governmental entity or contractor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time limitations set forth in this section for payment of payment requests apply to any payment request for retainage made pursuant to this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraphs (a)-(d) do not apply to construction services purchased by a local governmental entity which are paid for, in whole or in part, with federal funds and are subject to federal grantor laws and regulations or requirements that are contrary to any provision of the Local Government Prompt Payment Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to any construction services purchased by a local governmental entity if the total cost of the construction services purchased as identified in the contract is $200,000 or less.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All payments due under this section and not made within the time periods specified by this section shall bear interest at the rate of 1 percent per month, or the rate specified by contract, whichever is greater.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 95-331; s. 3, ch. 2001-169; s. 3, ch. 2005-230; s. 2, ch. 2010-111.</History>
</Section>