<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0218.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration; distribution schedule.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is empowered to promulgate rules and regulations and to issue special instructions to local governments as required to carry out the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, for all taxes collected and received into the revenue sharing trust funds, establish a schedule of equal monthly distribution for any computation period. The department is authorized to receive funds pursuant to s. 215.18 at any time in order to make such monthly payments by the 25th day of the month.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall compute the apportionment factors once each fiscal year for use during the fiscal year. The computation shall be made prior to July 25 of each fiscal year and shall be based upon information submitted and certified to the department prior to June 1 of each year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The apportionment factors shall, except in the case of error, remain in effect for the fiscal year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of each agency and unit of local government required to submit certified information to the department pursuant to the administration of this part to file timely information. Any unit of local government failing to provide timely information required pursuant to the administration of this part shall, by such action, authorize the department to utilize the best information available or, if no such information is available, to take any necessary action, including disqualification, either partial or entire, and shall further, by such action, waive any right to challenge the determination of the department as to its share, if any, pursuant to the privilege of receiving shared revenues under this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-360; s. 1, ch. 73-349; s. 1, ch. 74-194.</History></Section>