<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0218.421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fund B Surplus Funds Trust Fund; purpose; rulemaking; administration; reporting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the Fund B Surplus Funds Trust Fund is to maximize the payout of principal on invested surplus funds of units of local government formerly in Fund B of the Local Government Surplus Funds Trust Fund through a prudent work out of the trust fund with the ultimate goal of self-liquidating the trust fund through maturity and payout of the investments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Administration may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to administer this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board or a professional money management firm shall administer the trust fund on behalf of the participants based on a written investment policy, approved by the trustees, and shall have the power to work out, restructure, or invest such funds. The trustees shall annually certify to the Joint Legislative Auditing Committee that the trustees have conducted a review of the trust fund and that the trust fund is in compliance with the requirements of this section. Any new investments must be made in money market or equivalent funds. The board or a professional money management firm shall keep a separate account, designated by name and number of each participating local government. Individual transactions and totals of all investments, or the share belonging to each participant, shall be recorded in the accounts. Any moneys accrued in the trust fund shall be subject to payment from the trust fund on a monthly basis to the trust fund participants according to their proportional interest in the trust fund so long as at least $100,000 is in the trust fund at the end of that month. After all securities have matured, been sold, or worked out, a final distribution shall be made to the participants in the trust fund. Participants may not conduct transactions in the trust fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board or a professional money management firm and all employees of the board or firm have an affirmative duty to immediately disclose any material impact to the trust fund to the participants. To ensure such disclosure, a system of internal controls shall be established by the board, which shall be documented in writing as part of the investment policy. The controls shall be designed to prevent the loss of public funds arising from fraud, employee error, and misrepresentation by third parties, unanticipated changes in financial markets, or imprudent actions by employees and officers of the board or a professional money management firm. The controls shall also include formal escalation reporting guidelines for all employees. The guidelines shall establish procedures to address material impacts on the trust fund that require reporting and action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The investment policy shall be reviewed and approved by the trustees upon the transfer of the funds into the trust fund or when market changes dictate, and in each event, the investment policy shall be reviewed by the Investment Advisory Council and by the Participant Local Government Advisory Council.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Costs incurred in carrying out the provisions of this section, which shall be prorated among the participants in the percentage that each participant’s deposits bear to the total trust fund, may be deducted from any interest earned in the trust fund. The board or a professional money management firm may not transfer the interest or use the interest for any other purpose, including, but not limited to, making up investment losses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the trust fund self-liquidates, any remaining reserve may be transferred by the trustees at their sole discretion back to the trust fund from which the assets were originally separated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board or a professional money management firm shall provide a report at a minimum, monthly, or upon the occurrence of a material event, to every participant having a beneficial interest in the trust fund, the board’s executive director, the trustees, the Joint Legislative Auditing Committee, the Investment Advisory Council, and the Participant Local Government Advisory Council. The report shall include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports of any material impacts on the trust fund, and any actions or escalations taken by staff to address such impacts. The trustees shall provide quarterly a report to the Joint Legislative Auditing Committee that the trustees have reviewed and approved the monthly reports and actions taken, if any, to address any impacts.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A management summary that provides an analysis of the status of the current investment portfolio and the individual transactions executed over the last month. This management summary shall be prepared in a manner that will allow anyone to ascertain whether investment activities during the reporting period have conformed to investment policies. Such reporting shall be in conformance with best market practices.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board or a professional money management firm shall furnish upon request the details of an investment transaction to any participant, the trustees, the Investment Advisory Council, and the Participant Local Government Advisory Council.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additional reporting may be made to participants in the trust fund through regular and frequent ongoing multimedia educational materials and communications, including, but not limited to, historical performance, investment holdings, amortized cost and market value of the trust fund, credit quality, and average maturity of the trust fund investments.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trustees shall review the board’s progress in returning the principal in the trust fund to the participants at each meeting of the board until the trust fund self-liquidates or is terminated by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 11, ch. 2008-59.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 11, ch. 2008-59, provides that “[s]ections 218.418, 218.421, and 218.422, Florida Statutes, as created by this act, shall expire at the time the Fund B Surplus Funds Trust Fund is terminated by law or self-liquidates as determined and announced by the executive director of the State Board of Administration, whichever occurs first.”</Text></Note></Section>