<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0218.077" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimum wage requirements by political subdivisions; restrictions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee” means any natural person who is entitled under federal law to receive a federal minimum wage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employer” means any person who is required under federal law to pay a federal minimum wage to the person’s employees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employer contracting to provide goods or services for the political subdivision” means a person contracting with the political subdivision to provide goods or services to, for the benefit of, or on behalf of, the political subdivision in exchange for valuable consideration, and includes a person leasing or subleasing real property owned by the political subdivision.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Federal minimum wage” means a minimum wage required under federal law, including the federal Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, 29 U.S.C. ss. 201 et seq.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Political subdivision” means a county, municipality, department, commission, district, board, or other public body, whether corporate or otherwise, created by or under state law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wage” means that compensation for employment to which any federal minimum wage applies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3), a political subdivision may not establish, mandate, or otherwise require an employer to pay a minimum wage, other than a federal minimum wage, or to apply a federal minimum wage to wages exempt from a federal minimum wage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not limit the authority of a political subdivision to establish a minimum wage other than a federal minimum wage:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the employees of the political subdivision;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the employees of an employer contracting to provide goods or services for the political subdivision, or for the employees of a subcontractor of such an employer, under the terms of a contract with the political subdivision; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the employees of an employer receiving a direct tax abatement or subsidy from the political subdivision, as a condition of the direct tax abatement or subsidy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is determined by the officer or agency responsible for distributing federal funds to a political subdivision that compliance with this act would prevent receipt of those federal funds, or would otherwise be inconsistent with federal requirements pertaining to such funds, then this act shall not apply, but only to the extent necessary to allow receipt of the federal funds or to eliminate the inconsistency with such federal requirements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-87.</History></Section>