<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0218.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of Division of Bond Finance; advisory council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration, with respect to both general obligation bonds and revenue bonds, shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide information, upon request of a unit of local government, on the preliminary planning of a new bond issue.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect, maintain, and make available information on new bonds of units of local government and of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as a clearinghouse for information on bond issues of units of local government and of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undertake or commission studies on methods to reduce the costs of local and state bond issues.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend changes in law and in local practices to improve the sale and servicing of local bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a regular newsletter to issuers, underwriters, attorneys, investors, and other parties within the bond community and the general public containing information of interest relating to local and state bonds. The division may charge fees for subscriptions to the newsletter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 1 each year, provide the Special District Information Program of the Department of Economic Opportunity with a list of special districts that are not in compliance with the requirements in s. 218.38.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration shall also collect, maintain, and make available information from units of local government on lease-purchase agreements or certificates of participation, or other similar debt instruments, for which the total amount of principal payments under the agreement or series of agreements is $2 million or more.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration may adopt rules to implement this section and ss. 218.38 and 218.385.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration shall conduct a study of professional fees paid to fiscal advisers, bond counsel, and others and shall adopt a recommended fee schedule that is commensurate with fees typically paid in states similar to Florida in size and character. The schedule must be adopted by the division as the recommended fee schedule for all state and state agency financings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 79-183; s. 1, ch. 82-46; ss. 1, 9, ch. 82-195; s. 85, ch. 83-217; s. 2, ch. 88-318; s. 44, ch. 89-169; s. 15, ch. 92-173; s. 165, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 20, ch. 95-196; s. 23, ch. 96-324; s. 43, ch. 2004-305; s. 86, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>