<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0218.415" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local government investment policies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investment activity by a unit of local government must be consistent with a written investment plan adopted by the governing body, or in the absence of the existence of a governing body, the respective principal officer of the unit of local government and maintained by the unit of local government or, in the alternative, such activity must be conducted in accordance with subsection (17). Any such unit of local government shall have an investment policy for any public funds in excess of the amounts needed to meet current expenses as provided in subsections (1)-(16), or shall meet the alternative investment guidelines contained in subsection (17). Such policies shall be structured to place the highest priority on the safety of principal and liquidity of funds. The optimization of investment returns shall be secondary to the requirements for safety and liquidity. Each unit of local government shall adopt policies that are commensurate with the nature and size of the public funds within its custody.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCOPE.<EmDash />The investment policy shall apply to funds under the control of the unit of local government in excess of those required to meet current expenses. The investment policy shall not apply to pension funds, including those funds in chapters 175 and 185, or funds related to the issuance of debt where there are other existing policies or indentures in effect for such funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES.<EmDash />The investment policy shall describe the investment objectives of the unit of local government. Investment objectives shall include safety of capital, liquidity of funds, and investment income, in that order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERFORMANCE MEASUREMENT.<EmDash />The investment policy shall specify performance measures as are appropriate for the nature and size of the public funds within the custody of the unit of local government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRUDENCE AND ETHICAL STANDARDS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall describe the level of prudence and ethical standards to be followed by the unit of local government in carrying out its investment activities with respect to funds described in this section. The unit of local government shall adopt the Prudent Person Rule, which states that: “Investments should be made with judgment and care, under circumstances then prevailing, which persons of prudence, discretion, and intelligence exercise in the management of their own affairs, not for speculation, but for investment, considering the probable safety of their capital as well as the probable income to be derived from the investment.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LISTING OF AUTHORIZED INVESTMENTS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall list investments authorized by the governing body of the unit of local government, subject to the provisions of subsection (16). Investments not listed in the investment policy are prohibited. If the policy authorizes investments in derivative products, the policy must require that the unit of local government’s officials responsible for making investment decisions or chief financial officer have developed sufficient understanding of the derivative products and have the expertise to manage them. For purposes of this subsection, a “derivative” is defined as a financial instrument the value of which depends on, or is derived from, the value of one or more underlying assets or index or asset values. If the policy authorizes investments in reverse repurchase agreements or other forms of leverage, the policy must limit the investments to transactions in which the proceeds are intended to provide liquidity and for which the unit of local government has sufficient resources and expertise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MATURITY AND LIQUIDITY REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall require that the investment portfolio is structured in such manner as to provide sufficient liquidity to pay obligations as they come due. To that end, the investment policy should direct that, to the extent possible, an attempt will be made to match investment maturities with known cash needs and anticipated cash-flow requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PORTFOLIO COMPOSITION.<EmDash />The investment policy shall establish guidelines for investments and limits on security issues, issuers, and maturities. Such guidelines shall be commensurate with the nature and size of the public funds within the custody of the unit of local government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RISK AND DIVERSIFICATION.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for appropriate diversification of the investment portfolio. Investments held should be diversified to the extent practicable to control the risk of loss resulting from overconcentration of assets in a specific maturity, issuer, instrument, dealer, or bank through which financial instruments are bought and sold. Diversification strategies within the established guidelines shall be reviewed and revised periodically, as deemed necessary by the appropriate management staff.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZED INVESTMENT INSTITUTIONS AND DEALERS.<EmDash />The investment policy should specify the authorized securities dealers, issuers, and banks from whom the unit of local government may purchase securities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THIRD-PARTY CUSTODIAL AGREEMENTS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide appropriate arrangements for the holding of assets of the unit of local government. Securities should be held with a third party; and all securities purchased by, and all collateral obtained by, the unit of local government should be properly designated as an asset of the unit of local government. No withdrawal of securities, in whole or in part, shall be made from safekeeping, except by an authorized staff member of the unit of local government. Securities transactions between a broker-dealer and the custodian involving purchase or sale of securities by transfer of money or securities must be made on a “delivery vs. payment” basis, if applicable, to ensure that the custodian will have the security or money, as appropriate, in hand at the conclusion of the transaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MASTER REPURCHASE AGREEMENT.<EmDash />The investment policy shall require all approved institutions and dealers transacting repurchase agreements to execute and perform as stated in the Master Repurchase Agreement. All repurchase agreement transactions shall adhere to the requirements of the Master Repurchase Agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BID REQUIREMENT.<EmDash />The investment policy shall require that the unit of local government’s staff determine the approximate maturity date based on cash-flow needs and market conditions, analyze and select one or more optimal types of investment, and competitively bid the security in question when feasible and appropriate. Except as otherwise required by law, the bid deemed to best meet the investment objectives specified in subsection (2) must be selected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTERNAL CONTROLS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for a system of internal controls and operational procedures. The unit of local government’s officials responsible for making investment decisions or chief financial officer shall establish a system of internal controls which shall be in writing and made a part of the governmental entity’s operational procedures. The investment policy shall provide for review of such controls by independent auditors as part of any financial audit periodically required of the unit of local government. The internal controls should be designed to prevent losses of funds which might arise from fraud, employee error, misrepresentation by third parties, or imprudent actions by employees of the unit of local government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTINUING EDUCATION.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for the continuing education of the unit of local government’s officials responsible for making investment decisions or chief financial officer. Such officials must annually complete 8 hours of continuing education in subjects or courses of study related to investment practices and products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORTING.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for appropriate annual or more frequent reporting of investment activities. To that end, the governmental entity’s officials responsible for making investment decisions or chief financial officer shall prepare periodic reports for submission to the legislative and governing body of the unit of local government, which shall include securities in the portfolio by class or type, book value, income earned, and market value as of the report date. Such reports shall be available to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZED INVESTMENTS; WRITTEN INVESTMENT POLICIES.<EmDash />Those units of local government electing to adopt a written investment policy as provided in subsections (1)-(15) may by resolution invest and reinvest any surplus public funds in their control or possession in:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Local Government Surplus Funds Trust Fund or any intergovernmental investment pool authorized pursuant to the Florida Interlocal Cooperation Act of 1969, as provided in s. 163.01.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securities and Exchange Commission registered money market funds with the highest credit quality rating from a nationally recognized rating agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest-bearing time deposits or savings accounts in qualified public depositories as defined in s. 280.02.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct obligations of the United States Treasury.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal agencies and instrumentalities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rated or unrated bonds, notes, or instruments backed by the full faith and credit of the government of Israel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securities of, or other interests in, any open-end or closed-end management-type investment company or investment trust registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940, 15 U.S.C. ss. 80a-1 et seq., as amended from time to time, provided that the portfolio of such investment company or investment trust is limited to obligations of the United States Government or any agency or instrumentality thereof and to repurchase agreements fully collateralized by such United States Government obligations, and provided that such investment company or investment trust takes delivery of such collateral either directly or through an authorized custodian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other investments authorized by law or by ordinance for a county or a municipality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other investments authorized by law or by resolution for a school district or a special district.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZED INVESTMENTS; NO WRITTEN INVESTMENT POLICY.<EmDash />Those units of local government electing not to adopt a written investment policy in accordance with investment policies developed as provided in subsections (1)-(15) may invest or reinvest any surplus public funds in their control or possession in:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Local Government Surplus Funds Trust Fund, or any intergovernmental investment pool authorized pursuant to the Florida Interlocal Cooperation Act of 1969, as provided in s. 163.01.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securities and Exchange Commission registered money market funds with the highest credit quality rating from a nationally recognized rating agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest-bearing time deposits or savings accounts in qualified public depositories, as defined in s. 280.02.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct obligations of the U.S. Treasury.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The securities listed in paragraphs (c) and (d) shall be invested to provide sufficient liquidity to pay obligations as they come due.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SECURITIES; DISPOSITION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every security purchased under this section on behalf of the governing body of a unit of local government must be properly earmarked and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If registered with the issuer or its agents, must be immediately placed for safekeeping in a location that protects the governing body’s interest in the security;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If in book entry form, must be held for the credit of the governing body by a depository chartered by the Federal Government, the state, or any other state or territory of the United States which has a branch or principal place of business in this state as defined in s. 658.12, or by a national association organized and existing under the laws of the United States which is authorized to accept and execute trusts and which is doing business in this state, and must be kept by the depository in an account separate and apart from the assets of the financial institution; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If physically issued to the holder but not registered with the issuer or its agents, must be immediately placed for safekeeping in a secured vault.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unit of local government’s governing body may also receive bank trust receipts in return for investment of surplus funds in securities. Any trust receipts received must enumerate the various securities held, together with the specific number of each security held. The actual securities on which the trust receipts are issued may be held by any bank depository chartered by the Federal Government, this state, or any other state or territory of the United States which has a branch or principal place of business in this state as defined in s. 658.12, or by a national association organized and existing under the laws of the United States which is authorized to accept and execute trusts and which is doing business in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SALE OF SECURITIES.<EmDash />When the invested funds are needed in whole or in part for the purposes originally intended or for more optimal investments, the unit of local government’s governing body may sell such investments at the then-prevailing market price and place the proceeds into the proper account or fund of the unit of local government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PREEXISTING CONTRACT.<EmDash />Any public funds subject to a contract or agreement existing on October 1, 2000, may not be invested contrary to such contract or agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PREEMPTION.<EmDash />Any provision of any special act, municipal charter, or other law which prohibits or restricts a local governmental entity from complying with this section or any rules adopted under this section is void to the extent of the conflict.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUDITS.<EmDash />Certified public accountants conducting audits of units of local government pursuant to s. 218.39 shall report, as part of the audit, whether or not the unit of local government has complied with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZED DEPOSITS.<EmDash />In addition to the investments authorized for local governments in subsections (16) and (17) and notwithstanding any other provisions of law, a unit of local government may deposit any portion of surplus public funds in its control or possession in accordance with the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds are initially deposited in a qualified public depository, as defined in s. 280.02, selected by the unit of local government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selected depository arranges for depositing the funds in financial deposit instruments insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation in one or more federally insured banks or savings and loan associations, wherever located, for the account of the unit of local government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full amount of the principal and accrued interest of each financial deposit instrument is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selected depository acts as custodian for the unit of local government with respect to each financial deposit instrument issued for its account.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 95-194; s. 2, ch. 97-9; s. 3, ch. 2000-264; ss. 66, 141, ch. 2001-266; s. 2, ch. 2005-126; s. 1, ch. 2007-89; s. 42, ch. 2008-4; s. 2, ch. 2009-140.</History></Section>