<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0218.245" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revenue sharing; apportionment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The apportionment factor for all eligible counties shall be composed of three equally weighted portions as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each eligible county’s percentage of the total population of all eligible counties in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each eligible county’s percentage of the total population of the state residing in unincorporated areas of all eligible counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each eligible county’s percentage of total sales tax collections in all eligible counties during the preceding year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The apportionment factor for all eligible municipalities shall be composed of three equally weighted portions as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proportion of the population of a given municipality to the total population of all the eligible municipalities in the state, as adjusted by the following factors:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a municipality with a population in excess of 50,000, the population shall be adjusted by multiplying its population by a factor of 1.791.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a municipality with a population in excess of 20,000, but less than 50,001, the population shall be adjusted by multiplying its population by a factor of 1.709.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a municipality with a population in excess of 5,000, but less than 20,001, the population shall be adjusted by multiplying its population by a factor of 1.425.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a municipality with a population in excess of 2,000, but less than 5,001, the population shall be adjusted by multiplying its population by a factor of 1.135.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proportion of the sales tax collected within a given municipality to the total sales tax collected within all the eligible municipalities in the state. The sales tax collected within a given municipality shall be derived by allocating the amount of sales tax collections for the county in which the municipality is located to each municipality in the county on the basis of the proportion of each municipality’s population to the total population of the county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ratio of the relative local ability to raise revenue, to be determined:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By dividing the per capita nonexempt assessed real and personal property valuation of all eligible municipalities by the per capita nonexempt real and personal property valuation of each eligible municipality.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By multiplying the population of an eligible municipality by the percentage applicable to that municipality as established under subparagraph 1.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By dividing the population, as recalculated to reflect the relative local ability, by the total recalculated population of all eligible municipalities in the state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a metropolitan or consolidated government, as provided by s. 3, s. 6(e), or s. 6(f), Art. VIII of the State Constitution, the population or sales tax collections of the unincorporated area or areas outside of urban service districts, if such have been established, as determined in paragraphs (a)-(c) above and after adjustments made as provided therein, shall be further adjusted by multiplying the adjusted or recalculated population or sales tax collections, as the case may be, by a percentage which is derived by dividing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount of ad valorem taxes levied by the county government on real and personal property in the area of the county outside of municipal limits, as created pursuant to general or special law, or outside of urban service district limits, where such are established; by</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount of ad valorem taxes levied on real and personal property by the county and municipal governments.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues attributed to the increase in distribution to the Revenue Sharing Trust Fund for Municipalities pursuant to s. 212.20(6)(d)5. from 1.0715 percent to 1.3409 percent provided in chapter 2003-402, Laws of Florida, shall be distributed to each eligible municipality and any unit of local government that is consolidated as provided by s. 9, Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1885, as preserved by s. 6(e), Art. VIII, 1968 revised constitution, as follows: each eligible local government’s allocation shall be based on the amount it received from the half-cent sales tax under s. 218.61 in the prior state fiscal year divided by the total receipts under s. 218.61 in the prior state fiscal year for all eligible local governments. However, for the purpose of calculating this distribution, the amount received from the half-cent sales tax under s. 218.61 in the prior state fiscal year by a unit of local government which is consolidated as provided by s. 9, Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1885, as amended, and as preserved by s. 6(e), Art. VIII, of the Constitution as revised in 1968, shall be reduced by 50 percent for such local government and for the total receipts. For eligible municipalities that began participating in the allocation of half-cent sales tax under s. 218.61 in the previous state fiscal year, their annual receipts shall be calculated by dividing their actual receipts by the number of months they participated, and the result multiplied by 12.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-360; s. 1, ch. 73-349; s. 1, ch. 74-194; s. 57, ch. 2004-265; s. 44, ch. 2005-236; s. 7, ch. 2009-68.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 218.22 and 218.23.</Text></Note></Section>