<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0218.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual financial audit reports.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, by the first day in any fiscal year, a local governmental entity, district school board, charter school, or charter technical career center has not been notified that a financial audit for that fiscal year will be performed by the Auditor General, each of the following entities shall have an annual financial audit of its accounts and records completed within 9 months after the end of its fiscal year by an independent certified public accountant retained by it and paid from its public funds:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any municipality with revenues or the total of expenditures and expenses in excess of $250,000, as reported on the fund financial statements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any special district with revenues or the total of expenditures and expenses in excess of $100,000, as reported on the fund financial statements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each charter school established under s. 1002.33.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each charter technical center established under s. 1002.34.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each municipality with revenues or the total of expenditures and expenses between $100,000 and $250,000, as reported on the fund financial statements, which has not been subject to a financial audit pursuant to this subsection for the 2 preceding fiscal years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each special district with revenues or the total of expenditures and expenses between $50,000 and $100,000, as reported on the fund financial statement, which has not been subject to a financial audit pursuant to this subsection for the 2 preceding fiscal years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county audit report must be a single document that includes a financial audit of the county as a whole and, for each county agency other than a board of county commissioners, an audit of its financial accounts and records, including reports on compliance and internal control, management letters, and financial statements as required by rules adopted by the Auditor General. In addition, if a board of county commissioners elects to have a separate audit of its financial accounts and records in the manner required by rules adopted by the Auditor General for other county agencies, the separate audit must be included in the county audit report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dependent special district may provide for an annual financial audit by being included in the audit of the local governmental entity upon which it is dependent. An independent special district may not make provision for an annual financial audit by being included in the audit of another local governmental entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A special district that is a component unit, as defined by generally accepted accounting principles, of a local governmental entity shall provide the local governmental entity, within a reasonable time period as established by the local governmental entity, with financial information necessary to comply with this section. The failure of a component unit to provide this financial information must be noted in the annual financial audit report of the local governmental entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A management letter shall be prepared and included as a part of each financial audit report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the conclusion of the audit, the auditor shall discuss with the chair of the governing body of the local governmental entity or the chair’s designee, the elected official of each county agency or the elected official’s designee, the chair of the district school board or the chair’s designee, the chair of the board of the charter school or the chair’s designee, or the chair of the board of the charter technical career center or the chair’s designee, as appropriate, all of the auditor’s comments that will be included in the audit report. If the officer is not available to discuss the auditor’s comments, their discussion is presumed when the comments are delivered in writing to his or her office. The auditor shall notify each member of the governing body of a local governmental entity, district school board, charter school, or charter technical career center for which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deteriorating financial conditions exist that may cause a condition described in s. 218.503(1) to occur if actions are not taken to address such conditions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fund balance deficit in total or for that portion of a fund balance not classified as restricted, committed, or nonspendable, or a total or unrestricted net assets deficit, as reported on the fund financial statements of entities required to report under governmental financial reporting standards or on the basic financial statements of entities required to report under not-for-profit financial reporting standards, for which sufficient resources of the local governmental entity, charter school, charter technical career center, or district school board, as reported on the fund financial statements, are not available to cover the deficit. Resources available to cover reported deficits include fund balance or net assets that are not otherwise restricted by federal, state, or local laws, bond covenants, contractual agreements, or other legal constraints. Property, plant, and equipment, the disposal of which would impair the ability of a local governmental entity, charter school, charter technical career center, or district school board to carry out its functions, are not considered resources available to cover reported deficits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officer’s written statement of explanation or rebuttal concerning the auditor’s findings, including corrective action to be taken, must be filed with the governing body of the local governmental entity, district school board, charter school, or charter technical career center within 30 days after the delivery of the auditor’s findings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All audits conducted pursuant to this section must be conducted in accordance with the rules of the Auditor General adopted pursuant to s. 11.45. Upon completion of the audit, the auditor shall prepare an audit report in accordance with the rules of the Auditor General. The audit report shall be filed with the Auditor General within 45 days after delivery of the audit report to the governing body of the audited entity, but no later than 9 months after the end of the audited entity’s fiscal year. The audit report must include a written statement describing corrective actions to be taken in response to each of the auditor’s recommendations included in the audit report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General shall notify the Legislative Auditing Committee of any audit report prepared pursuant to this section which indicates that an audited entity has failed to take full corrective action in response to a recommendation that was included in the two preceding financial audit reports.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The committee may direct the governing body of the audited entity to provide a written statement to the committee explaining why full corrective action has not been taken or, if the governing body intends to take full corrective action, describing the corrective action to be taken and when it will occur.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the committee determines that the written statement is not sufficient, it may require the chair of the governing body of the local governmental entity or the chair’s designee, the elected official of each county agency or the elected official’s designee, the chair of the district school board or the chair’s designee, the chair of the board of the charter school or the chair’s designee, or the chair of the board of the charter technical career center or the chair’s designee, as appropriate, to appear before the committee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the committee determines that an audited entity has failed to take full corrective action for which there is no justifiable reason for not taking such action, or has failed to comply with committee requests made pursuant to this section, the committee may proceed in accordance with s. 11.40(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The predecessor auditor of a district school board shall provide the Auditor General access to the prior year’s working papers in accordance with the Statements on Auditing Standards, including documentation of planning, internal control, audit results, and other matters of continuing accounting and auditing significance, such as the working paper analysis of balance sheet accounts and those relating to contingencies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each charter school and charter technical career center must file a copy of its audit report with the sponsoring entity; the local district school board, if not the sponsoring entity; the Auditor General; and with the Department of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to housing authorities created under chapter 421.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of any local law, the provisions of this section shall govern.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 65, ch. 2001-266; s. 924, ch. 2002-387; s. 28, ch. 2004-305; s. 2, ch. 2006-190; s. 2, ch. 2009-214; s. 20, ch. 2011-144; s. 25, ch. 2012-5; s. 1, ch. 2012-38.</History>
</Section>