<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0678.4041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Wrongful registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 678.4061, an issuer is liable for wrongful registration of transfer if the issuer has registered a transfer of a security to a person not entitled to it, and the transfer was registered:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to an ineffective indorsement or instruction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a demand that the issuer not register transfer became effective under s. 678.4031(1) and the issuer did not comply with s. 678.4031(2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the issuer had been served with an injunction, restraining order, or other legal process enjoining it from registering the transfer, issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and the issuer had a reasonable opportunity to act on the injunction, restraining order, or other legal process; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By an issuer acting in collusion with the wrongdoer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An issuer that is liable for wrongful registration of transfer under subsection (1) on demand shall provide the person entitled to the security with a like certificated or uncertificated security, and any payments or distributions that the person did not receive as a result of the wrongful registration. If an overissue would result, the issuer’s liability to provide the person with a like security is governed by s. 678.2101.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (1) or in a law relating to the collection of taxes, an issuer is not liable to an owner or other person suffering loss as a result of the registration of a transfer of a security if registration was made pursuant to an effective indorsement or instruction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 98-11.</History></Section>