<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0250.36" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mandates and process.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Military courts may issue all process and mandates, including writs, warrants, and subpoenas, necessary to carry out the powers vested in the courts. Such mandates and process may be directed to the sheriff of any county and must be in the form prescribed by the Adjutant General in the rules issued by him or her under this chapter. All officers to whom such mandates and process are directed must execute the same and make returns of their acts thereunder according to the requirements of the form of process. Any sheriff or other officer who neglects or refuses to perform the duty enjoined upon him or her by this chapter is subject to the same liabilities, penalties, and punishments as are prescribed by the law for neglect or refusal to perform any other duty of his or her office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When not in the active service of the United States, the Adjutant General, or his or her designee, or a military judge of the Florida National Guard may issue a pretrial confinement warrant for the purpose of securing the presence of an accused at trial. The warrant must be directed to the sheriff of the county, directing the sheriff to arrest the accused and bring the accused before the court for trial if the accused has disobeyed an order in writing to appear before the court which was delivered to the accused in person or mailed to the accused’s last known address, along with a copy of the charges. Pretrial confinement may not exceed 48 hours. However, the Adjutant General or military judge may extend pretrial confinement for not more than 15 days in order to facilitate the presence of the accused at trial. For purposes of this subsection, the term “military judge” does not include a summary court-martial officer who is not qualified to act as a military judge in general or special courts-martial.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When not in the active service of the United States, the Adjutant General, or his or her designee, or a military judge of the Florida National Guard may issue subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum and enforce by attachment the attendance of witnesses and the production of documents and other items of evidentiary value.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a sentence of confinement is imposed by any court-martial of the Florida National Guard, the Adjutant General or his or her designee whose approval makes effective the sentence imposed by the court-martial shall issue a warrant directing the sheriff of the appropriate county to take the convicted person into custody and confine him or her in the jail of such county for the period specified in the sentence of the court. Any sheriff receiving such warrant must promptly execute the warrant by taking the convicted person into custody and confining him or her in jail. The sheriff or jailer in charge of any county jail shall receive any person committed for confinement in such jail under proper process from a court-martial, and provide for the care, subsistence, and safekeeping of such prisoner just as the sheriff or jailer would a prisoner properly committed for custody under the sentence of any civil court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All sums of money collected through fines adjudged by a general, special, or summary court-martial or through the imposition of nonjudicial punishment of the Florida National Guard shall be paid over at once by the officer collecting the fine to the commanding officer of the organization to which the member belongs and be deposited in accordance with s. 250.40(5)(c)1.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 50, 52, ch. 8502, 1921; ss. 9, 11, ch. 9337, 1923; s. 8, ch. 10185, 1925; CGL 2063, 2065; s. 1, ch. 25112, 1949; s. 22, ch. 73-334; s. 3, ch. 85-168; s. 1, ch. 88-297; s. 5, ch. 92-86; s. 111, ch. 95-148; s. 33, ch. 2003-68.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 250.57, 250.59.</Text></Note></Section>