<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0250.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment and duties of the Adjutant General.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of a vacancy, the Governor shall, subject to confirmation by the Senate, appoint a federally recognized officer of the Florida National Guard, who has served in the Florida National Guard for the preceding 5 years and attained the rank of colonel or higher, to be the Adjutant General of the state with the rank of not less than brigadier general or such higher rank as authorized by applicable tables of organization of the Department of the Army or the Department of the Air Force. The Adjutant General and all other military personnel of the Florida National Guard on full-time military duty with the Department of Military Affairs, except military police and firefighters, who are paid from state funds shall receive the pay and allowances of their respective grade as prescribed by applicable pay tables of the national military establishment for similar grade and period of service of personnel, unless a different rate of pay and allowances is specified in an appropriation act of the Legislature. An officer, with his or her consent, may be ordered to state active duty for administrative duty with the Department of Military Affairs at a grade lower than the officer currently holds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervise the receipt, preservation, repair, distribution, issue, and collection of all arms and military equipment of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervise all troops and branches of the Florida National Guard, including their organization, armament, discipline, training, recruiting, inspection, instruction, pay, subsistence, and supplies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain records of all military personnel of the Florida National Guard, and maintain copies of all orders, reports, and communications received and issued by him or her.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause the law and orders relating to the Florida National Guard to be indexed, printed, and bound, and prepare and publish blank books, forms, and stationery when necessary, and furnish them at the expense of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare and publish by order of the Governor orders, rules, and regulations, consistent with law, to bring the organization, armament, equipment, training, and discipline of the Florida National Guard to a state of efficiency as near as possible to that of the regular United States Army and Air Force, and the Adjutant General shall attest all orders of the commander in chief relating to the Florida National Guard.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish by directive an organized and supervised physical fitness program for military personnel of the Department of Military Affairs, provided that the program does not exceed 1 hour per day, for a maximum of 3 hours per week, and originates and terminates at the normal worksite. All fees, membership dues, equipment, and clothing relating to such physical fitness program shall be at no cost to the state. Administrative leave, not to exceed 3 hours per week, shall be provided by the department to all personnel authorized to participate in the physical fitness program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish by directive a post exchange store for members of the Florida National Guard, their families, guests, and other authorized users. The post exchange store shall be located at the Camp Blanding Training Site. The primary purpose of the store is to provide for the morale, recreation, and welfare of all servicemembers training at the Camp Blanding Training Site. The operation of the post exchange store must be in accordance with state and federal laws, rules, and regulations. Profits of the post exchange store, if any, shall be deposited in the Camp Blanding Management Trust Fund and shall be used to enhance the facilities and services provided by the Camp Blanding Training Site. The Adjutant General may establish an account with a federally insured financial institution in the state to facilitate the operations of the post exchange store.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare reports required by the Secretary of Defense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform other duties required of the Adjutant General by the commander in chief.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ personnel as necessary for the proper conduct of the Department of Military Affairs. The Adjutant General may accept personnel provided by the Federal Government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and maintain as part of the Adjutant General’s office a repository of records of the services of Florida troops during all wars, and be the custodian of all records, relics, trophies, colors, and histories relating to such wars which are possessed or acquired by the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a seal of office, approved by the commander in chief, and all copies of papers in his or her office, duly certified and authenticated under the seal, are admissible in evidence in all cases in like manner as if the original were produced.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, upon request, a summary to the Governor on the number and condition of the Florida National Guard and the number and condition of the arms and property in the custody of the state, and transmit to the Governor at that time a detailed report of all funds and moneys received and disbursed by the Department of Military Affairs. The Adjutant General may also recommend needed legislation as he or she deems proper.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to annual appropriations, administer youth About Face programs and adult Forward March programs at sites to be selected by the Adjutant General. Both programs must provide schoolwork assistance, focusing on the skills needed to master basic high school competencies and functional life skills, including teaching students to work effectively in groups; providing basic instruction in computer skills; teaching basic problem-solving, decisionmaking, and reasoning skills; teaching how the business world and free enterprise work through computer simulations; and teaching home finance and budgeting and other daily living skills.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">About Face is a summer and year-round after-school life-preparation program for economically disadvantaged and at-risk youths from 13 through 17 years of age. The program must provide training in academic study skills, and the basic skills that businesses require for employment consideration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forward March is a job-readiness program for economically disadvantaged participants who are directed to Forward March by the local regional workforce development boards. The Forward March program shall provide training on topics that directly relate to the skills required for real-world success. The program shall emphasize functional life skills, computer literacy, interpersonal relationships, critical-thinking skills, business skills, preemployment and work maturity skills, job-search skills, exploring careers activities, how to be a successful and effective employee, and some job-specific skills. The program also shall provide extensive opportunities for participants to practice generic job skills in a supervised work setting. Upon completion of the program, Forward March shall return participants to the local regional workforce development boards for placement in a job placement pool.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order troops to state active duty for training, subject to approved appropriations or grants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue decorations and awards pursuant to military regulations and instructions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General shall furnish suitable buildings for conducting the business of the Department of Military Affairs and for the proper storage, repair, and issuance of military property.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General shall, subject to confirmation by the Senate, employ a federally recognized officer of the Florida National Guard, who has served in the Florida Army Guard for the preceding 5 years and attained the rank of colonel or higher at the time of appointment, to be the Assistant Adjutant General for Army.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General may, subject to confirmation by the Senate, employ an additional, federally recognized officer of the Florida National Guard, who has served in the Florida Army Guard for the preceding 5 years and attained the rank of colonel or higher at the time of appointment, to be a second Assistant Adjutant General for Army.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Each officer shall perform the duties required by the Adjutant General.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General shall, subject to confirmation by the Senate, employ a federally recognized officer of the Florida National Guard, who has served in the Florida Air Guard for the preceding 5 years and attained the rank of colonel or higher at the time of appointment, to be the Assistant Adjutant General for Air. The officer shall perform the duties required by the Adjutant General.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General shall employ a federally recognized officer of the Florida National Guard as the state quartermaster who, under the direction of the Adjutant General, shall account for all funds accruing to the Department of Military Affairs; shall receive, preserve, repair, issue, distribute, and account for all Department of Military Affairs property, including real estate pertaining to the State Armory Board; and may construct, maintain, improve, and repair facilities pertaining to the Department of Military Affairs and the armory board. The state quartermaster shall be the recorder of the armory board and perform any other duties required of him or her by the Adjutant General.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General shall develop an education assistance program for members in good standing of the Florida National Guard who enroll in an authorized course of study at a public or nonpublic institution of higher learning in the state which has been accredited by an accrediting body recognized by the United States Department of Education or licensed by the Commission for Independent Education. This program shall be known as the Educational Dollars for Duty program (EDD).</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall set forth application requirements, including, but not limited to, requirements that the applicant:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be 17 years of age or older.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be presently domiciled in the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be an active drilling member and in good standing in the Florida National Guard at the beginning of and throughout the entire academic term for which benefits are received.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain continuous satisfactory participation in the Florida National Guard for any school term for which exemption benefits are received.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon enrollment in the program, complete a memorandum of agreement to comply with the rules of the program and serve in the Florida National Guard for the period specified in the member’s enlistment or reenlistment contract.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall define those members of the Florida National Guard who are ineligible to participate in the program and those courses of study which are not authorized for the program.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ineligible members include, but are not limited to, any member, commissioned officer, warrant officer, or enlisted person who has obtained a master’s degree using the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courses not authorized include noncredit courses, courses that do not meet degree requirements, courses that do not meet requirements for completion of career training, or other courses as determined by program definitions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">College-preparatory courses are authorized for the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Adjutant General shall adopt rules for the overall policy, guidance, administration, implementation, and proper use of the program. Such rules must include, but not be limited to, guidelines for certification by the Adjutant General of a guard member’s eligibility, procedures for notification to an institution of a guard member’s termination of eligibility, and procedures for restitution when a guard member fails to comply with the penalties described in this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to appropriations, the Department of Military Affairs may pay the full cost of tuition and fees for required courses for current members of the Florida National Guard. Members are eligible to use the program upon enlistment in the Florida National Guard. If a member is enrolled in a nonpublic postsecondary education institution or a nonpublic vocational-technical program, the Department of Military Affairs shall pay an amount equal to the amount that would be required to pay for the average tuition and fees at a public postsecondary education institution or public vocational-technical program.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member may participate in the program if he or she maintains satisfactory participation in, and is an active drilling member of, the Florida National Guard. Inactive members of the Florida National Guard and members of the Individual Ready Reserve (IRR) are not eligible to participate in the program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Penalties for noncompliance with program requirements include, but are not limited to, the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a member of the Florida National Guard receives payment of tuition and fees for any academic term and fails to maintain satisfactory participation in the Florida National Guard during that academic term, the member shall reimburse the Department of Military Affairs all tuition charges and student fees for the academic term for which the member received payment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a member of the Florida National Guard leaves the Florida National Guard during the period specified in the member’s enlistment or reenlistment contract, the member shall reimburse the Department of Military Affairs all tuition charges and student fees for which the member received payments, regardless of whether the obligation to reimburse the department was incurred before, on, or after July 1, 2009, unless the Adjutant General finds that there are justifiable extenuating circumstances.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the service of a member of the Florida National Guard is terminated or the member is placed on scholastic probation while receiving payments, the member shall reimburse the Department of Military Affairs all tuition charges and student fees for the academic term for which the member received payment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a member defaults on any reimbursement made under this paragraph, the department may charge the member the maximum interest rate authorized by law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 10<Fraction>1/2</Fraction>, 12, 13, ch. 8502, 1921; s. 2, ch. 10185, 1925; CGL 2021, 2022, 2024, 2025; s. 4, ch. 20849, 1941; s. 1, ch. 25112, 1949; s. 83, ch. 73-333; s. 5, ch. 77-85; s. 114, ch. 79-400; s. 1, ch. 86-239; s. 2, ch. 90-165; s. 1, ch. 91-302; s. 2, ch. 92-86; s. 1, ch. 94-229; s. 838, ch. 95-148; s. 24, ch. 95-196; s. 1, ch. 95-422; s. 8, ch. 97-100; ss. 1, 2, ch. 97-158; s. 28, ch. 98-34; s. 1, ch. 98-179; s. 1, ch. 99-177; s. 33, ch. 99-241; s. 10, ch. 2003-68; s. 2, ch. 2004-228; s. 20, ch. 2004-357; s. 28, ch. 2007-217; s. 1, ch. 2009-123; s. 2, ch. 2010-79; s. 5, ch. 2010-182.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 250.11, 250.12, 250.14, 250.15.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>