<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0250.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Military equipment regulations; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who sells, offers for sale, barters, exchanges, pledges, loans, gives away, secretes, or retains after demand is made by civil or military officers of the state, any clothing, arms, military outfits or property furnished by or through the state to any member of the militia, or who receives by purchase, barter, exchange, pledge, loan, or gift any such clothing, arms, military outfits or property commits theft as provided in chapter 812.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All members of the Florida National Guard who, due to their military responsibilities, have been entrusted any military property, must account for such property according to applicable rules and regulations or special orders made by superior authority. Such military property may not be removed without proper authority. Any person who fails to account for or return to proper military authority any property in that person’s possession to which the state military authorities are entitled, or who conceals or converts the property to the person’s own use, commits theft as provided in chapter 812. Any prosecution under this section may be abated upon making full satisfaction for such property to the military authorities of the state and paying all court costs resulting from the prosecution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clothing, arms, military outfits, and property furnished by or through the state to any member of the militia, may not be sold, bartered, loaned, exchanged, pledged, or given away. A person who is not a member of the military forces of this state or the United States, or an authorized agent of this state or the United States, who possesses clothing, arms, military outfits, or property that is unlawfully disposed of has no right, title, or interest therein, and the clothing, arms, military outfits, or property shall be seized and taken wherever found by any civil or military officer of the state and delivered to any commanding officer or other authorized officer who must make an immediate report to the Adjutant General. The possession of any such clothing, arms, military outfits, or property by any person not a member of the military forces of this state, or any other state, or of the United States, is presumptive evidence of such sale, barter, loan, exchange, pledge, or gift and is punishable as provided in chapter 812.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 61, 62, ch. 8502, 1921; s. 9, ch. 12089, 1927; CGL 2072, 8128; s. 1, ch. 25112, 1949; s. 147, ch. 71-136; s. 8, ch. 91-139; s. 40, ch. 2003-68.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 250.68, 250.69.</Text></Note></Section>