<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0250.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Expenses of courts-martial.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All expenses incurred in a court-martial proceeding, including the payment of court reporters, sheriff’s fees for service of warrants, summons, subpoenas, and all other necessary and lawful fees to civil officers for service, and witness fees at the same rate allowed by law in criminal cases, together with the pay, subsistence, and necessary expenses of the members of the court, shall, except as provided in subsection (4), be paid by the state in the usual manner upon the approval of the Governor. Members of the court are entitled to reimbursement for travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061. Courts-martial may subpoena any witness residing within the state to appear and testify before it, and the sheriff of any county upon receiving any subpoena issued by direction of a court-martial, and signed by the military judge or president thereof, shall make service and return of service as provided by law in criminal cases.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment of a court reporter shall be authorized by the convening authority for all general courts-martial, and may be authorized by the convening authority for special courts-martial. When a court reporter is employed, he or she shall be paid upon the certificate of the military judge or president of the court and the approval of the Adjutant General from the military appropriation, such fees as are provided for official reporters.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees for the service of all process issuing out of military courts and for the attendance of witnesses to attend such courts shall be the same as provided by law for the service of similar process issued by the civil courts of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In trials by summary court, the sheriff’s costs and fees, including costs of subsistence of the soldier, if sentenced to confinement, shall be paid by the county in which the summary court convenes and exercises its jurisdiction and powers. Such costs, fees, and subsistence charges to be made from the fine and forfeiture fund of any such county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 48, 51, 54, 55, ch. 8502, 1921; ss. 8, 10, ch. 9337, 1923; ss. 7, 9, ch. 10185, 1925; CGL 2061, 2064, 2067, 2068; s. 1, ch. 25112, 1949; s. 10, ch. 26484, 1951; s. 19, ch. 63-400; s. 4, ch. 85-168; s. 112, ch. 95-148; s. 34, ch. 2003-68.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 250.55, 250.58, 250.61, 250.62.</Text></Note></Section>