<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0250.43" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Wearing of uniform and insignia of rank; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The uniform or insignia of rank worn by officers of the Florida National Guard shall be worn only by persons entitled thereto by commission under the laws of the state or the United States. Any person violating this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, and may also be punished as a court-martial directs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person other than an officer or enlisted person of the Florida National Guard, naval militia, or marine corps of this state, any other state, Puerto Rico, or the District of Columbia, or of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, or Air Force, who wears the uniform of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, National Guard, Naval Militia, or Marine Corps or any part of such uniform, or a uniform or part of uniform similar thereto, or in imitation thereof, within the bounds of the state, except in cases where the wearing of such uniform is permitted by the laws of the United States and the regulations of the Secretary of Defense, commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. This section does not prohibit persons in the theatrical profession from wearing such uniforms while actually engaged in such profession, in any playhouse or theater, in a production in no way reflecting upon such uniform; does not prohibit the uniform rank of civic societies parading or traveling in a body or assembling in a lodge room; and does not apply to cadets of any military school or to Boy Scouts or Girl Scouts.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 58, 59, ch. 8502, 1921; CGL 2071, 8125, 8126; s. 1, ch. 25112, 1949; s. 146, ch. 71-136; s. 7, ch. 91-139; s. 39, ch. 2003-68.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 250.65, 250.66.</Text></Note></Section>