<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0250.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liability of members of the organized militia; defense of actions or proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the Florida National Guard ordered into state active duty or full-time National Guard duty or ordered into federal training or duty are not liable, civilly or criminally, for any lawful act done by them in the performance of their duty, while acting in good faith and while acting in the scope of either state or federal duty. For purposes of this section, Florida National Guard personnel serving in any drug interdiction program under the authority of the Governor are in state active duty.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action or proceeding of any nature, civil or criminal, commenced in any court by any person or by the state against any member of the Florida National Guard because of any act done or caused, ordered, or directed to be done, the defendant in such action or proceeding, upon his or her request, shall be defended at the expense of the state by a qualified attorney designated by the Department of Legal Affairs. However, this section does not prohibit such defendant from employing his or her own private counsel at the defendant’s own expense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant may be ordered to state active duty with full pay and allowances for the time his or her presence is required in defense of such actions or proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any such action or proceeding, if the plaintiff dismisses his or her suit, or a verdict or judgment in favor of the defendant is entered, the court shall award costs and reasonable attorney’s fees incurred by the state and the defendant in the defense of such action or proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 8502, 1921; CGL 2047; s. 1, ch. 25112, 1949; s. 1, ch. 73-92; s. 1, ch. 87-379; s. 13, ch. 91-139; s. 1, ch. 91-259; s. 107, ch. 95-148; s. 26, ch. 2003-68.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 250.41.</Text></Note></Section>