<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0250.175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trust funds; authorization; name; purpose.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Federal Law Enforcement Trust Fund is created within the Department of Military Affairs. The department shall deposit into the trust fund moneys received from the forfeiture of assets obtained through illegal drug activities, which shall be used to support law enforcement and counter-drug activities and drug interdiction programs of the Florida National Guard.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance in the trust fund at the end of any fiscal year will remain in the trust fund and be available for carrying out the purposes of the trust fund. This trust fund is exempt from the service charges imposed by s. 215.20.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Emergency Response Trust Fund is created within the Department of Military Affairs. Reimbursements from the Federal Emergency Management Agency for the costs of activating the Florida National Guard and transfers of state funds approved by budget amendments processed under chapter 216 shall be deposited into the trust fund. The trust fund shall be used to pay all operational costs incurred by the Florida National Guard when called to active duty.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance in the trust fund at the end of any fiscal year shall remain in the trust fund and is available for carrying out the purposes of the trust fund. The trust fund is exempt from the service charges imposed by s. 215.20.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Camp Blanding Management Trust Fund is created within the Department of Military Affairs. The department shall deposit funds generated by revenue-producing activities on the Camp Blanding Military Reservation into the trust fund, which shall be used to support required training of the Florida National Guard.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance in the trust fund at the end of any fiscal year shall remain in the trust fund and is available for carrying out the purposes of the trust fund. The trust fund is exempt from the service charges imposed by s. 215.20.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Federal Grants Trust Fund is created within the Department of Military Affairs. The department shall deposit into the trust fund federal funds received by the department under cooperative agreements between the federal and state governments, which shall be used to perform the functions and tasks specified in the agreements. The department shall also deposit into the trust fund other funds received by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance in the trust fund at the end of any fiscal year shall remain in the trust fund and is available for carrying out the purposes of the trust fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Welfare Transition Trust Fund is created within the Department of Military Affairs.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds to be credited to the trust fund shall consist of funds collected from the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Block Grant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trust fund moneys shall be used exclusively for the purpose of providing services to individuals eligible for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families pursuant to the requirements and limitations of Title IV, part A of the Social Security Act, as amended, or any other applicable federal requirement or limitation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance in the trust fund at the end of any fiscal year shall remain in the trust fund at the end of the year and shall be available for carrying out the purposes of the trust fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-394; s. 2, ch. 2002-142; s. 14, ch. 2003-68; s. 1, ch. 2005-25; s. 2, ch. 2007-8; s. 2, ch. 2007-9; s. 2, ch. 2009-24; s. 2, ch. 2010-19.</History>
</Section>