<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0250.84" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Uniformed Servicemembers Protection Act; rights of servicemembers; incorporation by reference.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to ensure that those individuals affected by the provisions of the Florida Uniformed Servicemembers Protection Act be made aware of the rights and responsibilities of servicemembers. The Department of Military Affairs shall make available a document containing the rights and responsibilities of servicemembers set forth in Florida Statutes, either through printed or electronic means, to appropriate state or local organizations composed of parties affected by said rights, including, but not limited to, those representing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motor vehicle dealers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial institutions and mortgage brokers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Telecommunications service companies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential tenancies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real estate salespersons and brokers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of The Florida Bar Association who serve on a military affairs-related committee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Military Affairs shall also make available a document containing the rights and responsibilities of servicemembers set forth in Florida Statutes, either through printed or electronic means, to servicemembers and their families.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such documents containing the rights and responsibilities of servicemembers set forth in this act shall include an enumeration of all rights and responsibilities under state and federal law, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and responsibilities provided by the Florida Uniformed Servicemembers Protection Act, including a listing of all sections of Florida Statutes relating to servicemembers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and responsibilities provided by the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and responsibilities provided by the Uniformed Servicemembers Employment and Reemployment Rights Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-72; s. 28, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>