<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0102.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Maintenance of good order at polls; authorities; persons allowed in polling rooms and early voting areas; unlawful solicitation of voters.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each election board shall possess full authority to maintain order at the polls and enforce obedience to its lawful commands during an election and the canvass of the votes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff shall deputize a deputy sheriff for each polling place and each early voting site who shall be present during the time the polls or early voting sites are open and until the election is completed, who shall be subject to all lawful commands of the clerk or inspectors, and who shall maintain good order. The deputy may summon assistance from among bystanders to aid him or her when necessary to maintain peace and order at the polls or early voting sites.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may enter any polling room or polling place where the polling place is also a polling room, or any early voting area during voting hours except the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Official poll watchers;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspectors;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Election clerks;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisor of elections or his or her deputy;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons there to vote, persons in the care of a voter, or persons caring for such voter;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Law enforcement officers or emergency service personnel there with permission of the clerk or a majority of the inspectors; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person, whether or not a registered voter, who is assisting with or participating in a simulated election for minors, as approved by the supervisor of elections.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The restriction in this subsection does not apply where the polling room is in an area commonly traversed by the public in order to gain access to businesses or homes or in an area traditionally utilized as a public area for discussion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person, political committee, committee of continuous existence, or other group or organization may solicit voters inside the polling place or within 100 feet of the entrance to any polling place, or polling room where the polling place is also a polling room, or early voting site. Before the opening of the polling place or early voting site, the clerk or supervisor shall designate the no-solicitation zone and mark the boundaries.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this subsection, the terms “solicit” or “solicitation” shall include, but not be limited to, seeking or attempting to seek any vote, fact, opinion, or contribution; distributing or attempting to distribute any political or campaign material, leaflet, or handout; conducting a poll except as specified in this paragraph; seeking or attempting to seek a signature on any petition; and selling or attempting to sell any item. The terms “solicit” or “solicitation” shall not be construed to prohibit exit polling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each supervisor of elections shall inform the clerk of the area within which soliciting is unlawful, based on the particular characteristics of that polling place. The supervisor or the clerk may take any reasonable action necessary to ensure order at the polling places, including, but not limited to, having disruptive and unruly persons removed by law enforcement officers from the polling room or place or from the 100-foot zone surrounding the polling place.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No photography is permitted in the polling room or early voting area.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 58, ch. 4328, 1895; GS 237; RGS 282; CGL 338; s. 6, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 1, ch. 59-212; s. 25, ch. 77-175; s. 2, ch. 85-205; s. 4, ch. 87-184; s. 15, ch. 87-363; s. 29, ch. 89-338; s. 2, ch. 92-134; s. 598, ch. 95-147; s. 5, ch. 2000-249; s. 54, ch. 2005-277; s. 25, ch. 2008-95.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 99.38.</Text></Note></Section>