<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0185.162" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Beneficiaries.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, chapter plan, local law municipality, or local law plan under this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each police officer may, on a form, provided for that purpose, signed and filed with the board of trustees, designate a choice of one or more persons, named sequentially or jointly, as his or her beneficiary (or beneficiaries) to receive the benefit, if any, which may be payable in the event of the police officer’s death, and each designation may be revoked by such police officer by signing and filing with the board of trustees a new designation or beneficiary form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no beneficiary is named in the manner provided by subsection (1), or if no beneficiary designated by the member survives him or her, the death benefit, if any, which may be payable under the plan with respect to such deceased police officer shall be paid by the board of trustees to the estate of such deceased police officer, provided that in any of such cases the board of trustees, in its discretion, may direct that the commuted value of the remaining monthly income payments be paid in a lump sum. Any payment made to any person pursuant to this subsection shall operate as a complete discharge of all obligations under the plan with regard to such deceased police officer and shall not be subject to review by anyone, but shall be final, binding and conclusive on all persons ever interested hereunder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the surviving spouse of any pension participant member killed in the line of duty shall not lose survivor retirement benefits if the spouse remarries. The surviving spouse of such deceased member whose benefit terminated because of remarriage shall have the benefit reinstated as of July 1, 1994, at an amount that would have been payable had such benefit not been terminated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 59-320; s. 5, ch. 94-171; s. 1459, ch. 95-147; s. 58, ch. 99-1.</History></Section>