<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0185.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation and maintenance of fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, chapter plan, local law municipality, or local law plan under this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The municipal police officers’ retirement trust fund in each municipality described in s. 185.03 shall be created and maintained in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the net proceeds of the .85-percent excise tax which may be imposed by the respective cities and towns upon certain casualty insurance companies on their gross receipts of premiums from holders of policies, which policies cover property within the corporate limits of such municipalities, as is hereinafter expressly authorized.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as reduced or increased contributions are authorized by subsection (2), by the payment to the fund of 5 percent of the salary of each full-time police officer duly appointed and enrolled as a member of such police department, which 5 percent shall be deducted by the municipality from the compensation due to the police officer and paid over to the board of trustees of the retirement trust fund wherein such police officer is employed. No police officer shall have any right to the money so paid into the fund except as provided in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By all fines and forfeitures imposed and collected from any police officer because of the violation of any rule adopted by the board of trustees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By payment by the municipality or other sources of a sum equal to the normal cost and the amount required to fund any actuarial deficiency shown by an actuarial valuation as provided in part VII of chapter 112.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By all gifts, bequests and devises when donated to the fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By all accretions to the fund by way of interest or dividends on bank deposits or otherwise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By all other sources of income now or hereafter authorized by law for the augmentation of such municipal police officers’ retirement trust fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Member contribution rates may be adjusted as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employing municipality, by local ordinance, may elect to make an employee’s contributions. However, under no circumstances may a municipality reduce the member contribution to less than one-half of 1 percent of salary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Police officer member contributions may be increased by consent of the members’ collective bargaining representative or, if none, by majority consent of police officer members of the fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require adjustment of member contribution rates in effect on the date this act becomes a law, including rates that exceed 5 percent of salary, provided that such rates are at least one-half of 1 percent of salary.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 28230, 1953; s. 3, ch. 29825, 1955; s. 5, ch. 59-320; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 6, ch. 86-42; s. 943, ch. 95-147; s. 5, ch. 95-250; s. 47, ch. 99-1; s. 10, ch. 2011-216.</History></Section>