<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0185.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Revenue and Division of Retirement to keep accounts of deposits; disbursements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality having a chapter plan or local law plan under this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall keep a separate account of all moneys collected for each municipality under the provisions of this chapter. All moneys so collected must be transferred to the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund and shall be separately accounted for by the division. The moneys budgeted as necessary to pay the expenses of the division for the daily oversight and monitoring of the police officers’ retirement plans under this chapter and for the oversight and actuarial reviews conducted under part VII of chapter 112 are annually appropriated from the interest and investment income earned on the moneys collected for each municipality or special fire control district and deposited in the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund. Interest and investment income remaining thereafter in the trust fund which is unexpended and otherwise unallocated by law shall revert to the General Revenue Fund on June 30 of each year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall, on or before July 1 of each year, and at such other times as authorized by the division, draw his or her warrants on the full net amount of money then on deposit pursuant to this chapter in the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund, specifying the municipalities to which the moneys must be paid and the net amount collected for and to be paid to each municipality, respectively. The sum payable to each municipality is appropriated annually out of the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund. The warrants of the Chief Financial Officer shall be payable to the respective municipalities entitled to receive them and shall be remitted annually by the division to the respective municipalities. In lieu thereof, the municipality may provide authorization to the division for the direct payment of the premium tax to the board of trustees. In order for a municipality and its retirement fund to participate in the distribution of premium tax moneys under this chapter, all the provisions shall be complied with annually, including state acceptance pursuant to part VII of chapter 112.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 28230, 1953; s. 2, ch. 29734, 1955; s. 2, ch. 61-119; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 74-297; s. 4, ch. 85-61; s. 8, ch. 86-42; s. 43, ch. 93-193; s. 13, ch. 94-259; s. 1458, ch. 95-147; s. 6, ch. 95-250; s. 50, ch. 99-1; s. 165, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>