<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0185.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Report of premiums paid; date tax payable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, chapter plan, local law municipality, or local law plan under this chapter, whenever any municipality passes an ordinance establishing a chapter plan or local law plan and assessing and imposing the tax authorized in s. 185.08, a certified copy of such ordinance shall be deposited with the division; and thereafter every insurance company, corporation, or other insurer carrying on the business of casualty insuring, on or before the succeeding March 1 after date of the passage of the ordinance, shall report fully in writing to the division and the Department of Revenue a just and true account of all premiums received by such insurer for casualty insurance policies covering or insuring any property located within the corporate limits of such municipality during the period of time elapsing between the date of the passage of the ordinance and the end of the calendar year. The aforesaid insurer shall annually thereafter, on March 1, file with the Department of Revenue a similar report covering the preceding year’s premium receipts. Every such insurer shall, at the time of making such report, pay to the Department of Revenue the amount of the tax heretofore mentioned. Every insurer engaged in carrying on a general casualty insurance business in the state shall keep accurate books of account of all such business done by it within the limits of such incorporated municipality in such a manner as to be able to comply with the provisions of this chapter. Based on the insurers’ reports of premium receipts, the division shall prepare a consolidated premium report and shall furnish to any municipality requesting the same a copy of the relevant section of that report.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 28230, 1953; s. 2, ch. 61-85; ss. 12, 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 42, ch. 93-193; s. 49, ch. 99-1; s. 7, ch. 2000-355.</History></Section>