<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0185.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State excise tax on casualty insurance premiums authorized; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, chapter plan, local law municipality, or local law plan under this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each incorporated municipality in this state described and classified in s. 185.03, as well as each other city or town of this state which on July 31, 1953, had a lawfully established municipal police officers’ retirement trust fund or city fund, by whatever name known, providing pension or relief benefits to police officers as provided under this chapter, may assess and impose on every insurance company, corporation, or other insurer now engaged in or carrying on, or who shall hereafter engage in or carry on, the business of casualty insurance as shown by records of the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission, an excise tax in addition to any lawful license or excise tax now levied by each of the said municipalities, respectively, amounting to .85 percent of the gross amount of receipts of premiums from policyholders on all premiums collected on casualty insurance policies covering property within the corporate limits of such municipalities, respectively.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of multiple peril policies with a single premium for both property and casualty coverages in such policies, 30 percent of such premium shall be used as the basis for the .85-percent tax above.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The excise tax shall be payable annually March 1 of each year after the passing of an ordinance assessing and imposing the tax herein authorized. Installments of taxes shall be paid according to the provisions of s. 624.5092(2)(a), (b), and (c).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 28230, 1953; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 63-196; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 86-42; s. 24, ch. 87-99; s. 15, ch. 88-206; s. 11, ch. 89-167; s. 944, ch. 95-147; s. 48, ch. 99-1; s. 164, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>