<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0185.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Municipal police officers’ retirement trust funds; creation; applicability of provisions; participation by public safety officers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, chapter plan, local law municipality, or local law plan under this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be established a special fund exclusively for the purpose of this chapter, which in the case of chapter plans shall be known as the “Municipal Police Officers’ Retirement Trust Fund,” in each municipality of this state, heretofore or hereafter created, which now has or which may hereafter have a regularly organized police department, and which now owns and uses or which may hereafter own and use equipment and apparatus of a value exceeding $500 in serviceable condition for the prevention of crime and for the preservation of life and property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter shall apply only to municipalities organized and established pursuant to the laws of the state, and said provisions shall not apply to the unincorporated areas of any county or counties nor shall the provisions hereof apply to any governmental entity whose police officers are eligible to participate in the Florida Retirement System.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No municipality shall establish more than one retirement plan for public safety officers which is supported in whole or in part by the distribution of premium tax funds as provided by this chapter or chapter 175, nor shall any municipality establish a retirement plan for public safety officers which receives premium tax funds from both this chapter and chapter 175.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 28230, 1953; s. 2, ch. 29825, 1955; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 65-152; s. 7, ch. 79-380; s. 2, ch. 79-388; s. 3, ch. 86-42; s. 43, ch. 99-1.</History></Section>