<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0185.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual report to Division of Retirement; actuarial valuations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, chapter plan, local law municipality, or local law plan under this chapter, the board of trustees for every chapter plan and local law plan shall submit the following reports to the division:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to chapter plans:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each year by February 1, the chair or secretary of each municipal police officers’ retirement trust fund operating a chapter plan shall file a report with the division which contains:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of whether in fact the municipality is within the provisions of s. 185.03.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An independent audit by a certified public accountant if the fund has $250,000 or more in assets, or a certified statement of accounting if the fund has less than $250,000 in assets, for the most recent plan year, showing a detailed listing of assets and methods used to value them and a statement of all income and disbursements during the year. Such income and disbursements shall be reconciled with the assets at the beginning and end of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statistical exhibit showing the total number of police officers on the force of the municipality, the number included in the retirement plan and the number ineligible classified according to the reasons for their being ineligible, and the number of disabled and retired police officers and their beneficiaries receiving pension payments and the amounts of annual retirement income or pension payments being received by them.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the amount the municipality, or other income source, has contributed to the retirement plan for the most recent plan year and the amount the municipality will contribute to the retirement plan for the current plan year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any benefits are insured with a commercial insurance company, the report shall include a statement of the relationship of the insured benefits to the benefits provided by this chapter. This report shall also contain information about the insurer, basis of premium rates and mortality table, interest rate and method used in valuing retirement benefits.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to annual reports provided under paragraph (a), by February 1 of each triennial year, an actuarial valuation of the chapter plan must be made by the division at least once every 3 years, as provided in s. 112.63, commencing 3 years from the last actuarial valuation of the plan or system for existing plans, or commencing 3 years from the issuance of the initial actuarial impact statement submitted under s. 112.63 for newly created plans. To that end, the chair of the board of trustees for each municipal police officers’ retirement trust fund operating under a chapter plan shall report to the division such data as the division needs to complete an actuarial valuation of each fund. The forms for each municipality shall be supplied by the division. The expense of the actuarial valuation shall be borne by the municipal police officers’ retirement trust fund established by s. 185.10. The requirements of this section are supplemental to the actuarial valuations necessary to comply with s. 218.39.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to local law plans:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each year, on or before March 15, the trustees of the retirement plan shall submit the following information to the division in order for the retirement plan of such municipality to receive a share of the state funds for the then-current calendar year:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified copy of each and every instrument constituting or evidencing the plan. This includes the formal plan, including all amendments, the trust agreement, copies of all insurance contracts, and formal announcement materials.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An independent audit by a certified public accountant if the fund has $250,000 or more in assets, or a certified statement of accounting if the fund has less than $250,000 in assets, for the most recent plan year, showing a detailed listing of assets and a statement of all income and disbursements during the year. Such income and disbursements must be reconciled with the assets at the beginning and end of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified statement listing the investments of the plan and a description of the methods used in valuing the investments.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statistical exhibit showing the total number of police officers, the number included in the plan, and the number ineligible classified according to the reasons for their being ineligible, and the number of disabled and retired police officers and their beneficiaries receiving pension payments and the amounts of annual retirement income or pension payments being received by them.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified statement describing the methods, factors, and actuarial assumptions used in determining the cost.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified statement by an enrolled actuary showing the results of the latest actuarial valuation of the plan and a copy of the detailed worksheets showing the computations used in arriving at the results.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the amount the municipality, or other income source, has contributed toward the plan for the most recent plan year and will contribute toward the plan for the current plan year.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">When any of the items required hereunder is identical to the corresponding item submitted for a previous year, it is not necessary for the trustees to submit duplicate information if they make reference to the item in the previous year’s report.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to annual reports provided under paragraph (a), an actuarial valuation of the retirement plan must be made at least once every 3 years, as provided in s. 112.63, commencing 3 years from the last actuarial valuation of the plan or system for existing plans, or commencing 3 years from issuance of the initial actuarial impact statement submitted under s. 112.63 for newly created plans. Such valuation shall be prepared by an enrolled actuary, subject to the following conditions:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assets shall be valued as provided in s. 112.625(7).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost of the actuarial valuation must be paid by the individual police officer’s retirement trust fund or by the sponsoring municipality.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report of the valuation, including actuarial assumptions and type and basis of funding, shall be made to the division within 3 months after the date of the valuation. If any benefits are insured with a commercial insurance company, the report must include a statement of the relationship of the retirement plan benefits to the insured benefits, the name of the insurer, the basis of premium rates, and the mortality table, interest rate, and method used in valuing the retirement benefits.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 59-320; s. 2, ch. 61-119; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 16, ch. 86-42; s. 44, ch. 93-193; s. 951, ch. 95-147; s. 8, ch. 96-324; s. 64, ch. 99-1; s. 43, ch. 2001-266; s. 16, ch. 2004-305.</History></Section>