<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.68" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Codification of ordinances; exceptions; public record.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraphs (b) and (c), counties shall maintain a current codification of all ordinances. Such codification shall be published annually by the board of county commissioners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any comprehensive plan, or amendment to such plan, adopted by ordinance pursuant to s. 163.3184, is exempt from codification and annual publication requirements if the board of county commissioners determines that the text of the comprehensive plan, or an amendment to such plan, or any associated maps, diagrams, or charts cannot be published in a reasonable manner according to the county’s established method of publication. Factors which may be considered in determining reasonableness of publication include the cost of publication, changes that are required in the method of publication, the number of documents in the comprehensive plan or amendment, and how frequently a plan is amended. This paragraph does not prohibit the adoption or incorporation by reference of a comprehensive plan, or amendment to such plan, in order to enact the plan or amendment by ordinance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following ordinances are exempt from codification and annual publication requirements:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any development agreement, or amendment to such agreement, adopted by ordinance pursuant to ss. 163.3220-163.3243.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any development order, or amendment to such order, adopted by ordinance pursuant to s. 380.06(15).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any ordinance that is exempt from codification and annual publication requirements must be recorded in a book kept for that purpose and maintained by the clerk of the board of county commissioners. The existence and location of such records shall be noted in any ordinance that adopts a comprehensive plan, development order, development agreement, or an amendment to any such plan, order, or agreement. The existence and location of such records shall also be noted in any ordinance that establishes procedures or requirements for development orders or development agreements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All ordinances shall be public records, and copies of such ordinances shall be available to the public. A reasonable charge may be made for the provision of copies, but such charges shall not exceed the actual costs incidental to providing such copies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 69-32; s. 2, ch. 90-152.</History></Section>