<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement and amendment of the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code; inspection fees; inspectors; etc.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of county commissioners of each of the several counties of the state is authorized to enforce the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code, as provided in ss. 553.80, 633.022, and 633.025, and, at its discretion, to adopt local technical amendments to the Florida Building Code, pursuant to s. 553.73(4)(b) and (c) and local technical amendments to the Florida Fire Prevention Code, pursuant to s. 633.0215, to provide for the safe construction, erection, alteration, repair, securing, and demolition of any building within its territory outside the corporate limits of any municipality. Upon a determination to consider amending the Florida Building Code or the Florida Fire Prevention Code by a majority of the members of the board of county commissioners of such county, the board shall call a public hearing and comply with the public notice requirements of s. 125.66(2). The board shall hear all interested parties at the public hearing and may then amend the building code or the fire code consistent with the terms and purposes of this act. Upon adoption, an amendment to the code shall be in full force and effect throughout the unincorporated area of such county until otherwise notified by the Florida Building Commission pursuant to s. 553.73 or the State Fire Marshal pursuant to s. 633.0215. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to prevent the board of county commissioners from repealing such amendment to the building code or the fire code at any regular meeting of such board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of county commissioners of each of the several counties may provide a schedule of reasonable inspection fees in order to defer the costs of inspection and enforcement of the provisions of this act, and of the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of county commissioners of each of the several counties may employ a building code inspector and such other personnel as it deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this act and may pay reasonable salaries for such services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After adoption of the Florida Building Code by the Florida Building Commission or the Florida Fire Prevention Code by the State Fire Marshal, or amendment of the building code or the fire code as herein provided, it shall be unlawful for any person, firm, or corporation to construct, erect, alter, repair, secure, or demolish any building within the territory embraced by the terms of this act without first obtaining a permit therefor from the appropriate board of county commissioners, or from such persons as may by resolution be directed to issue such permits, upon the payment of such reasonable fees as shall be set forth in the schedule of fees adopted by the board; the board is hereby empowered to revoke any such permit upon a determination by the board that the construction, erection, alteration, repair, securing, or demolition of the building for which the permit was issued is in violation of or not in conformity with the building code or the fire code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, or corporation that violates any of the provisions of this section or of the Florida Building Code or the Florida Fire Prevention Code is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-5, 7, 8, ch. 63-290; s. 3, ch. 71-14; s. 76, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 83-160; s. 5, ch. 90-279; s. 1, ch. 95-310; s. 3, ch. 2000-141; s. 24, ch. 2000-372; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372.</History></Section>