<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.85" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County charters; executive responsibilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive responsibilities and power of the county shall be assigned to, and vested in, the appropriate executive officer, pursuant to the optional form adopted under s. 125.83, and shall consist of the following powers and duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report annually, or more often if necessary, to the board of commissioners and to the citizens on the state of the county, the work of the previous year, recommendations for action or programs for improvement of the county, and the welfare of its residents;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare and submit to the board for its consideration and adoption an annual operating budget, a capital budget, and a capital program; establish the schedules and procedures to be followed by all county departments, offices, and agencies in connection therewith; and supervise and administer all phases of the budgetary process;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer and carry out the directives and policies of the board of county commissioners and enforce all orders, resolutions, ordinances, and regulations of the board, the county charter, and all applicable general law, to assure that they are faithfully executed;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervise the care and custody of all county property, institutions, and agencies;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervise the collection of revenues, audit and control all disbursements and expenditures, and prepare a complete account of all expenditures;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review, analyze, and forecast trends of county services and finances and programs of all boards, commissions, agencies, and other county bodies and report and recommend thereon to the board;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, install, and maintain centralized budgeting, personnel, legal, and purchasing procedures as may be authorized by the administrative code;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Negotiate contracts, bonds, or other instruments for the county, subject to board approval; make recommendations concerning the nature and location of county improvements; and execute services determined by the board;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assure that all terms and conditions imposed in favor of the county or its inhabitants in any statute, franchise, or other contract are faithfully kept and performed;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervise, direct, and control all county administrative departments;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint, with the advice and consent of the board, all appointed departmental heads, who shall serve at his or her pleasure, and employ, pursuant to appropriation and the administrative code, such personnel as necessary to administer county functions and services;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order, at his or her discretion, any agency under his or her jurisdiction as specified in the administrative code to undertake any task for any other agency on a temporary basis if he or she deems it necessary for the proper and efficient administration of the county government to do so; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other power or duty which may be assigned by county charter or by ordinance or resolution of the board.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-193; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 824, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>