<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0125.0104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tourist development tax; procedure for levying; authorized uses; referendum; enforcement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section shall be known and may be cited as the “Local Option Tourist Development Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION; DEFINITIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Application.</Font><EmDash />The provisions contained in chapter 212 apply to the administration of any tax levied pursuant to this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Definitions.</Font><EmDash />For purposes of this section:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Promotion” means marketing or advertising designed to increase tourist-related business activities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tourist” means a person who participates in trade or recreation activities outside the county of his or her permanent residence or who rents or leases transient accommodations as described in paragraph (3)(a).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retained spring training franchise” means a spring training franchise that had a location in this state on or before December 31, 1998, and that has continuously remained at that location for at least the 10 years preceding that date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TAXABLE PRIVILEGES; EXEMPTIONS; LEVY; RATE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is declared to be the intent of the Legislature that every person who rents, leases, or lets for consideration any living quarters or accommodations in any hotel, apartment hotel, motel, resort motel, apartment, apartment motel, roominghouse, mobile home park, recreational vehicle park, condominium, or timeshare resort for a term of 6 months or less is exercising a privilege which is subject to taxation under this section, unless such person rents, leases, or lets for consideration any living quarters or accommodations which are exempt according to the provisions of chapter 212.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tax shall be due on the consideration paid for occupancy in the county pursuant to a regulated short-term product, as defined in s. 721.05, or occupancy in the county pursuant to a product that would be deemed a regulated short-term product if the agreement to purchase the short-term right were executed in this state. Such tax shall be collected on the last day of occupancy within the county unless such consideration is applied to the purchase of a timeshare estate. The occupancy of an accommodation of a timeshare resort pursuant to a timeshare plan, a multisite timeshare plan, or an exchange transaction in an exchange program, as defined in s. 721.05, by the owner of a timeshare interest or such owner’s guest, which guest is not paying monetary consideration to the owner or to a third party for the benefit of the owner, is not a privilege subject to taxation under this section. A membership or transaction fee paid by a timeshare owner that does not provide the timeshare owner with the right to occupy any specific timeshare unit but merely provides the timeshare owner with the opportunity to exchange a timeshare interest through an exchange program is a service charge and not subject to taxation under this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consideration paid for the purchase of a timeshare license in a timeshare plan, as defined in s. 721.05, is rent subject to taxation under this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of this section, any county in this state may levy and impose a tourist development tax on the exercise within its boundaries of the taxable privilege described in paragraph (a), except that there shall be no additional levy under this section in any cities or towns presently imposing a municipal resort tax as authorized under chapter 67-930, Laws of Florida, and this section shall not in any way affect the powers and existence of any tourist development authority created pursuant to chapter 67-930, Laws of Florida. No county authorized to levy a convention development tax pursuant to s. 212.0305, or to s. 8 of chapter 84-324, Laws of Florida, shall be allowed to levy more than the 2-percent tax authorized by this section. A county may elect to levy and impose the tourist development tax in a subcounty special district of the county. However, if a county so elects to levy and impose the tax on a subcounty special district basis, the district shall embrace all or a significant contiguous portion of the county, and the county shall assist the Department of Revenue in identifying the rental units subject to tax in the district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tourist development tax shall be levied, imposed, and set by the governing board of the county at a rate of 1 percent or 2 percent of each dollar and major fraction of each dollar of the total consideration charged for such lease or rental. When receipt of consideration is by way of property other than money, the tax shall be levied and imposed on the fair market value of such nonmonetary consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any 1-percent or 2-percent tax imposed under paragraph (c), the governing board of the county may levy, impose, and set an additional 1 percent of each dollar above the tax rate set under paragraph (c) by the extraordinary vote of the governing board for the purposes set forth in subsection (5) or by referendum approval by the registered electors within the county or subcounty special district. No county shall levy, impose, and set the tax authorized under this paragraph unless the county has imposed the 1-percent or 2-percent tax authorized under paragraph (c) for a minimum of 3 years prior to the effective date of the levy and imposition of the tax authorized by this paragraph. Revenues raised by the additional tax authorized under this paragraph shall not be used for debt service on or refinancing of existing facilities as specified in subparagraph (5)(a)1. unless approved by a resolution adopted by an extraordinary majority of the total membership of the governing board of the county. If the 1-percent or 2-percent tax authorized in paragraph (c) is levied within a subcounty special taxing district, the additional tax authorized in this paragraph shall only be levied therein. The provisions of paragraphs (4)(a)-(d) shall not apply to the adoption of the additional tax authorized in this paragraph. The effective date of the levy and imposition of the tax authorized under this paragraph shall be the first day of the second month following approval of the ordinance by the governing board or the first day of any subsequent month as may be specified in the ordinance. A certified copy of such ordinance shall be furnished by the county to the Department of Revenue within 10 days after approval of such ordinance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tourist development tax shall be in addition to any other tax imposed pursuant to chapter 212 and in addition to all other taxes and fees and the consideration for the rental or lease.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tourist development tax shall be charged by the person receiving the consideration for the lease or rental, and it shall be collected from the lessee, tenant, or customer at the time of payment of the consideration for such lease or rental.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person receiving the consideration for such rental or lease shall receive, account for, and remit the tax to the Department of Revenue at the time and in the manner provided for persons who collect and remit taxes under s. 212.03. The same duties and privileges imposed by chapter 212 upon dealers in tangible property, respecting the collection and remission of tax; the making of returns; the keeping of books, records, and accounts; and compliance with the rules of the Department of Revenue in the administration of that chapter shall apply to and be binding upon all persons who are subject to the provisions of this section. However, the Department of Revenue may authorize a quarterly return and payment when the tax remitted by the dealer for the preceding quarter did not exceed $25.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall keep records showing the amount of taxes collected, which records shall also include records disclosing the amount of taxes collected for and from each county in which the tax authorized by this section is applicable. These records shall be open for inspection during the regular office hours of the Department of Revenue, subject to the provisions of s. 213.053.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collections received by the Department of Revenue from the tax, less costs of administration of this section, shall be paid and returned monthly to the county which imposed the tax, for use by the county in accordance with the provisions of this section. They shall be placed in the county tourist development trust fund of the respective county, which shall be established by each county as a condition precedent to receipt of such funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue is authorized to employ persons and incur other expenses for which funds are appropriated by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall promulgate such rules and shall prescribe and publish such forms as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other tax which is imposed pursuant to this section, a county may impose up to an additional 1-percent tax on the exercise of the privilege described in paragraph (a) by majority vote of the governing board of the county in order to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the debt service on bonds issued to finance the construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a professional sports franchise facility, or the acquisition, construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a retained spring training franchise facility, either publicly owned and operated, or publicly owned and operated by the owner of a professional sports franchise or other lessee with sufficient expertise or financial capability to operate such facility, and to pay the planning and design costs incurred prior to the issuance of such bonds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the debt service on bonds issued to finance the construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a convention center, and to pay the planning and design costs incurred prior to the issuance of such bonds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the operation and maintenance costs of a convention center for a period of up to 10 years. Only counties that have elected to levy the tax for the purposes authorized in subparagraph 2. may use the tax for the purposes enumerated in this subparagraph. Any county that elects to levy the tax for the purposes authorized in subparagraph 2. after July 1, 2000, may use the proceeds of the tax to pay the operation and maintenance costs of a convention center for the life of the bonds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote and advertise tourism in the State of Florida and nationally and internationally; however, if tax revenues are expended for an activity, service, venue, or event, the activity, service, venue, or event shall have as one of its main purposes the attraction of tourists as evidenced by the promotion of the activity, service, venue, or event to tourists.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The provision of paragraph (b) which prohibits any county authorized to levy a convention development tax pursuant to s. 212.0305 from levying more than the 2-percent tax authorized by this section, and the provisions of paragraphs (4)(a)-(d), shall not apply to the additional tax authorized in this paragraph. The effective date of the levy and imposition of the tax authorized under this paragraph shall be the first day of the second month following approval of the ordinance by the governing board or the first day of any subsequent month as may be specified in the ordinance. A certified copy of such ordinance shall be furnished by the county to the Department of Revenue within 10 days after approval of such ordinance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other tax which is imposed pursuant to this section, a high tourism impact county may impose an additional 1-percent tax on the exercise of the privilege described in paragraph (a) by extraordinary vote of the governing board of the county. The tax revenues received pursuant to this paragraph shall be used for one or more of the authorized uses pursuant to subsection (5).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county is considered to be a high tourism impact county after the Department of Revenue has certified to such county that the sales subject to the tax levied pursuant to this section exceeded $600 million during the previous calendar year, or were at least 18 percent of the county’s total taxable sales under chapter 212 where the sales subject to the tax levied pursuant to this section were a minimum of $200 million, except that no county authorized to levy a convention development tax pursuant to s. 212.0305 shall be considered a high tourism impact county. Once a county qualifies as a high tourism impact county, it shall retain this designation for the period the tax is levied pursuant to this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraphs (4)(a)-(d) shall not apply to the adoption of the additional tax authorized in this paragraph. The effective date of the levy and imposition of the tax authorized under this paragraph shall be the first day of the second month following approval of the ordinance by the governing board or the first day of any subsequent month as may be specified in the ordinance. A certified copy of such ordinance shall be furnished by the county to the Department of Revenue within 10 days after approval of such ordinance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other tax that is imposed under this section, a county that has imposed the tax under paragraph (l) may impose an additional tax that is no greater than 1 percent on the exercise of the privilege described in paragraph (a) by a majority plus one vote of the membership of the board of county commissioners in order to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the debt service on bonds issued to finance:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a facility either publicly owned and operated, or publicly owned and operated by the owner of a professional sports franchise or other lessee with sufficient expertise or financial capability to operate such facility, and to pay the planning and design costs incurred prior to the issuance of such bonds for a new professional sports franchise as defined in s. 288.1162.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition, construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a facility either publicly owned and operated, or publicly owned and operated by the owner of a professional sports franchise or other lessee with sufficient expertise or financial capability to operate such facility, and to pay the planning and design costs incurred prior to the issuance of such bonds for a retained spring training franchise.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote and advertise tourism in the State of Florida and nationally and internationally; however, if tax revenues are expended for an activity, service, venue, or event, the activity, service, venue, or event shall have as one of its main purposes the attraction of tourists as evidenced by the promotion of the activity, service, venue, or event to tourists.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A county that imposes the tax authorized in this paragraph may not expend any ad valorem tax revenues for the acquisition, construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a facility for which tax revenues are used pursuant to subparagraph 1. The provision of paragraph (b) which prohibits any county authorized to levy a convention development tax pursuant to s. 212.0305 from levying more than the 2-percent tax authorized by this section shall not apply to the additional tax authorized by this paragraph in counties which levy convention development taxes pursuant to s. 212.0305(4)(a). Subsection (4) does not apply to the adoption of the additional tax authorized in this paragraph. The effective date of the levy and imposition of the tax authorized under this paragraph is the first day of the second month following approval of the ordinance by the board of county commissioners or the first day of any subsequent month specified in the ordinance. A certified copy of such ordinance shall be furnished by the county to the Department of Revenue within 10 days after approval of the ordinance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ORDINANCE LEVY TAX; PROCEDURE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tourist development tax shall be levied and imposed pursuant to an ordinance containing the county tourist development plan prescribed under paragraph (c), enacted by the governing board of the county. The ordinance levying and imposing the tourist development tax shall not be effective unless the electors of the county or the electors in the subcounty special district in which the tax is to be levied approve the ordinance authorizing the levy and imposition of the tax, in accordance with subsection (6). The effective date of the levy and imposition of the tax shall be the first day of the second month following approval of the ordinance by referendum, as prescribed in subsection (6), or the first day of any subsequent month as may be specified in the ordinance. A certified copy of the ordinance shall be furnished by the county to the Department of Revenue within 10 days after approval of such ordinance. The governing authority of any county levying such tax shall notify the department, within 10 days after approval of the ordinance by referendum, of the time period during which the tax will be levied.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 60 days prior to the enactment of the ordinance levying the tax, the governing board of the county shall adopt a resolution establishing and appointing the members of the county tourist development council, as prescribed in paragraph (e), and indicating the intention of the county to consider the enactment of an ordinance levying and imposing the tourist development tax.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to enactment of the ordinance levying and imposing the tax, the county tourist development council shall prepare and submit to the governing board of the county for its approval a plan for tourist development. The plan shall set forth the anticipated net tourist development tax revenue to be derived by the county for the 24 months following the levy of the tax; the tax district in which the tourist development tax is proposed; and a list, in the order of priority, of the proposed uses of the tax revenue by specific project or special use as the same are authorized under subsection (5). The plan shall include the approximate cost or expense allocation for each specific project or special use.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board of the county shall adopt the county plan for tourist development as part of the ordinance levying the tax. After enactment of the ordinance levying and imposing the tax, the plan of tourist development may not be substantially amended except by ordinance enacted by an affirmative vote of a majority plus one additional member of the governing board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board of each county which levies and imposes a tourist development tax under this section shall appoint an advisory council to be known as the “<Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of county)</Directions> Tourist Development Council.” The council shall be established by ordinance and composed of nine members who shall be appointed by the governing board. The chair of the governing board of the county or any other member of the governing board as designated by the chair shall serve on the council. Two members of the council shall be elected municipal officials, at least one of whom shall be from the most populous municipality in the county or subcounty special taxing district in which the tax is levied. Six members of the council shall be persons who are involved in the tourist industry and who have demonstrated an interest in tourist development, of which members, not less than three nor more than four shall be owners or operators of motels, hotels, recreational vehicle parks, or other tourist accommodations in the county and subject to the tax. All members of the council shall be electors of the county. The governing board of the county shall have the option of designating the chair of the council or allowing the council to elect a chair. The chair shall be appointed or elected annually and may be reelected or reappointed. The members of the council shall serve for staggered terms of 4 years. The terms of office of the original members shall be prescribed in the resolution required under paragraph (b). The council shall meet at least once each quarter and, from time to time, shall make recommendations to the county governing board for the effective operation of the special projects or for uses of the tourist development tax revenue and perform such other duties as may be prescribed by county ordinance or resolution. The council shall continuously review expenditures of revenues from the tourist development trust fund and shall receive, at least quarterly, expenditure reports from the county governing board or its designee. Expenditures which the council believes to be unauthorized shall be reported to the county governing board and the Department of Revenue. The governing board and the department shall review the findings of the council and take appropriate administrative or judicial action to ensure compliance with this section. The changes in the composition of the membership of the tourist development council mandated by chapter 86-4, Laws of Florida, and this act shall not cause the interruption of the current term of any person who is a member of a council on October 1, 1996.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZED USES OF REVENUE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All tax revenues received pursuant to this section by a county imposing the tourist development tax shall be used by that county for the following purposes only:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire, construct, extend, enlarge, remodel, repair, improve, maintain, operate, or promote one or more publicly owned and operated convention centers, sports stadiums, sports arenas, coliseums, auditoriums, aquariums, or museums that are publicly owned and operated or owned and operated by not-for-profit organizations and open to the public, within the boundaries of the county or subcounty special taxing district in which the tax is levied. Tax revenues received pursuant to this section may also be used for promotion of zoological parks that are publicly owned and operated or owned and operated by not-for-profit organizations and open to the public. However, these purposes may be implemented through service contracts and leases with lessees with sufficient expertise or financial capability to operate such facilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote and advertise tourism in the State of Florida and nationally and internationally; however, if tax revenues are expended for an activity, service, venue, or event, the activity, service, venue, or event shall have as one of its main purposes the attraction of tourists as evidenced by the promotion of the activity, service, venue, or event to tourists;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund convention bureaus, tourist bureaus, tourist information centers, and news bureaus as county agencies or by contract with the chambers of commerce or similar associations in the county, which may include any indirect administrative costs for services performed by the county on behalf of the promotion agency; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To finance beach park facilities or beach improvement, maintenance, renourishment, restoration, and erosion control, including shoreline protection, enhancement, cleanup, or restoration of inland lakes and rivers to which there is public access as those uses relate to the physical preservation of the beach, shoreline, or inland lake or river. However, any funds identified by a county as the local matching source for beach renourishment, restoration, or erosion control projects included in the long-range budget plan of the state’s Beach Management Plan, pursuant to s. 161.091, or funds contractually obligated by a county in the financial plan for a federally authorized shore protection project may not be used or loaned for any other purpose. In counties of less than 100,000 population, no more than 10 percent of the revenues from the tourist development tax may be used for beach park facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tax revenues received pursuant to this section by a county of less than 750,000 population imposing a tourist development tax may only be used by that county for the following purposes in addition to those purposes allowed pursuant to paragraph (a): to acquire, construct, extend, enlarge, remodel, repair, improve, maintain, operate, or promote one or more zoological parks, fishing piers or nature centers which are publicly owned and operated or owned and operated by not-for-profit organizations and open to the public. All population figures relating to this subsection shall be based on the most recent population estimates prepared pursuant to the provisions of s. 186.901. These population estimates shall be those in effect on July 1 of each year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The revenues to be derived from the tourist development tax may be pledged to secure and liquidate revenue bonds issued by the county for the purposes set forth in subparagraphs (a)1. and 4. or for the purpose of refunding bonds previously issued for such purposes, or both; however, no more than 50 percent of the revenues from the tourist development tax may be pledged to secure and liquidate revenue bonds or revenue refunding bonds issued for the purposes set forth in subparagraph (a)4. Such revenue bonds and revenue refunding bonds may be authorized and issued in such principal amounts, with such interest rates and maturity dates, and subject to such other terms, conditions, and covenants as the governing board of the county shall provide. The Legislature intends that this paragraph shall be full and complete authority for accomplishing such purposes, but such authority shall be supplemental and additional to, and not in derogation of, any powers now existing or later conferred under law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any use of the local option tourist development tax revenues collected pursuant to this section for a purpose not expressly authorized by paragraph (3)(l) or paragraph (3)(n) or paragraph (a), paragraph (b), or paragraph (c) of this subsection is expressly prohibited.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REFERENDUM.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No ordinance enacted by any county levying the tax authorized by paragraphs (3)(b) and (c) shall take effect until the ordinance levying and imposing the tax has been approved in a referendum election by a majority of the electors voting in such election in the county or by a majority of the electors voting in the subcounty special tax district affected by the tax.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board of the county levying the tax shall arrange to place a question on the ballot at the next regular or special election to be held within the county, substantially as follows:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />FOR the Tourist Development Tax</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />AGAINST the Tourist Development Tax.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of the electors voting on the question approve the levy, the ordinance shall be deemed to be in effect.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case where a referendum levying and imposing the tax has been approved pursuant to this section and 15 percent of the electors in the county or 15 percent of the electors in the subcounty special district in which the tax is levied file a petition with the board of county commissioners for a referendum to repeal the tax, the board of county commissioners shall cause an election to be held for the repeal of the tax which election shall be subject only to the outstanding bonds for which the tax has been pledged. However, the repeal of the tax shall not be effective with respect to any portion of taxes initially levied in November 1989, which has been pledged or is being used to support bonds under paragraph (3)(d) or paragraph (3)(l) until the retirement of those bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTOMATIC EXPIRATION ON RETIREMENT OF BONDS.<EmDash />Anything in this section to the contrary notwithstanding, if the plan for tourist development approved by the governing board of the county, as amended from time to time pursuant to paragraph (4)(d), includes the acquisition, construction, extension, enlargement, remodeling, repair, or improvement of a publicly owned and operated convention center, sports stadium, sports arena, coliseum, auditorium, aquarium, or museum that is publicly owned and operated or owned and operated by a not-for-profit organization, the county ordinance levying and imposing the tax shall automatically expire upon the later of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retirement of all bonds issued by the county for financing the same; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expiration of any agreement by the county for the operation or maintenance, or both, of a publicly owned and operated convention center, sports stadium, sports arena, coliseum, auditorium, aquarium, or museum. However, nothing herein shall preclude that county from amending the ordinance extending the tax to the extent that the board of the county determines to be necessary to provide funds with which to operate, maintain, repair, or renew and replace a publicly owned and operated convention center, sports stadium, sports arena, coliseum, auditorium, aquarium, or museum or from enacting an ordinance which shall take effect without referendum approval, unless the original referendum required ordinance expiration, pursuant to the provisions of this section reimposing a tourist development tax, upon or following the expiration of the previous ordinance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROHIBITED ACTS; ENFORCEMENT; PENALTIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is taxable hereunder who fails or refuses to charge and collect from the person paying any rental or lease the taxes herein provided, either by himself or herself or through agents or employees, is, in addition to being personally liable for the payment of the tax, guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall advertise or hold out to the public in any manner, directly or indirectly, that he or she will absorb all or any part of the tax, that he or she will relieve the person paying the rental of the payment of all or any part of the tax, or that the tax will not be added to the rental or lease consideration or, when added, that it or any part thereof will be refunded or refused, either directly or indirectly, by any method whatsoever. Any person who willfully violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax authorized to be levied by this section shall constitute a lien on the property of the lessee, customer, or tenant in the same manner as, and shall be collectible as are, liens authorized and imposed in ss. 713.67, 713.68, and 713.69.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COUNTY TOURISM PROMOTION AGENCIES.<EmDash />In addition to any other powers and duties provided for agencies created for the purpose of tourism promotion by a county levying the tourist development tax, such agencies are authorized and empowered to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, arrange, and make expenditures for transportation, lodging, meals, and other reasonable and necessary items and services for such persons, as determined by the head of the agency, in connection with the performance of promotional and other duties of the agency. However, entertainment expenses shall be authorized only when meeting with travel writers, tour brokers, or other persons connected with the tourist industry. All travel and entertainment-related expenditures in excess of $10 made pursuant to this subsection shall be substantiated by paid bills therefor. Complete and detailed justification for all travel and entertainment-related expenditures made pursuant to this subsection shall be shown on the travel expense voucher or attached thereto. Transportation and other incidental expenses, other than those provided in s. 112.061, shall only be authorized for officers and employees of the agency, other authorized persons, travel writers, tour brokers, or other persons connected with the tourist industry when traveling pursuant to paragraph (c). All other transportation and incidental expenses pursuant to this subsection shall be as provided in s. 112.061. Operational or promotional advancements, as defined in s. 288.35(4), obtained pursuant to this subsection, shall not be commingled with any other funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay by advancement or reimbursement, or a combination thereof, the costs of per diem and incidental expenses of officers and employees of the agency and other authorized persons, for foreign travel at the current rates as specified in the federal publication “Standardized Regulations (Government Civilians, Foreign Areas).” The provisions of this paragraph shall apply for any officer or employee of the agency traveling in foreign countries for the purposes of promoting tourism and travel to the county, if such travel expenses are approved and certified by the agency head from whose funds the traveler is paid. As used in this paragraph, the term “authorized person” shall have the same meaning as provided in s. 112.061(2)(e). With the exception of provisions concerning rates of payment for per diem, the provisions of s. 112.061 are applicable to the travel described in this paragraph. As used in this paragraph, “foreign travel” means all travel outside the United States. Persons traveling in foreign countries pursuant to this subsection shall not be entitled to reimbursements or advancements pursuant to s. 112.061(6)(a)2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay by advancement or reimbursement, or by a combination thereof, the actual reasonable and necessary costs of travel, meals, lodging, and incidental expenses of officers and employees of the agency and other authorized persons when meeting with travel writers, tour brokers, or other persons connected with the tourist industry, and while attending or traveling in connection with travel or trade shows. With the exception of provisions concerning rates of payment, the provisions of s. 112.061 are applicable to the travel described in this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undertake marketing research and advertising research studies and provide reservations services and convention and meetings booking services consistent with the authorized uses of revenue as set forth in subsection (5).</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information given to a county tourism promotion agency which, if released, would reveal the identity of persons or entities who provide data or other information as a response to a sales promotion effort, an advertisement, or a research project or whose names, addresses, meeting or convention plan information or accommodations or other visitation needs become booking or reservation list data, is exempt from s. 119.07(1) and from s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following information, when held by a county tourism promotion agency, is exempt from s. 119.07(1) and from s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trade secret, as defined in s. 812.081.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Booking business records, as defined in s. 255.047.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trade secrets and commercial or financial information gathered from a person and privileged or confidential, as defined and interpreted under 5 U.S.C. s. 552(b)(4), or any amendments thereto.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Represent themselves to the public as convention and visitors bureaus, visitors bureaus, tourist development councils, vacation bureaus, or county tourism promotion agencies operating under any other name or names specifically designated by ordinance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOCAL ADMINISTRATION OF TAX.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county levying a tax under this section or s. 125.0108 may be exempted from the requirements of the respective section that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax collected be remitted to the Department of Revenue before being returned to the county; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax be administered according to chapter 212,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">if the county adopts an ordinance providing for the local collection and administration of the tax.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ordinance shall include provision for, but need not be limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initial collection of the tax to be made in the same manner as the tax imposed under chapter 212.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designation of the local official to whom the tax shall be remitted, and that official’s powers and duties with respect thereto. Tax revenues may be used only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements respecting the keeping of appropriate books, records, and accounts by those responsible for collecting and administering the tax.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision for payment of a dealer’s credit as required under chapter 212.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A portion of the tax collected may be retained by the county for costs of administration, but such portion shall not exceed 3 percent of collections.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county adopting an ordinance providing for the collection and administration of the tax on a local basis shall also adopt an ordinance electing either to assume all responsibility for auditing the records and accounts of dealers, and assessing, collecting, and enforcing payments of delinquent taxes, or to delegate such authority to the Department of Revenue. If the county elects to assume such responsibility, it shall be bound by all rules promulgated by the Department of Revenue pursuant to paragraph (3)(k), as well as those rules pertaining to the sales and use tax on transient rentals imposed by s. 212.03. The county may use any power granted in this section to the department to determine the amount of tax, penalties, and interest to be paid by each dealer and to enforce payment of such tax, penalties, and interest. The county may use a certified public accountant licensed in this state in the administration of its statutory duties and responsibilities. Such certified public accountants are bound by the same confidentiality requirements and subject to the same penalties as the county under s. 213.053. If the county delegates such authority to the department, the department shall distribute any collections so received, less costs of administration, to the county. The amount deducted for costs of administration by the department shall be used only for those costs which are solely and directly attributable to auditing, assessing, collecting, processing, and enforcing payments of delinquent taxes authorized in this section. If a county elects to delegate such authority to the department, the department shall audit only those businesses in the county that it audits pursuant to chapter 212.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTEREST PAID ON DISTRIBUTIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest shall be paid on undistributed taxes collected and remitted to the Department of Revenue under this section. Such interest shall be included along with the tax proceeds distributed to the counties and shall be paid from moneys transferred from the General Revenue Fund. The department shall calculate the interest for net tax distributions using the average daily rate that was earned by the State Treasury for the preceding calendar quarter and paid to the General Revenue Fund. This rate shall be certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the department by the 20th day following the close of each quarter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interest applicable to taxes collected under this section shall be calculated by multiplying the tax amounts to be distributed times the daily rate times the number of days after the third working day following the date the tax is due and payable pursuant to s. 212.11 until the date the department issues a voucher to request the Chief Financial Officer to issue the payment warrant. The warrant shall be issued within 7 days after the request.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an overdistribution of taxes is made by the department, interest shall be paid on the overpaid amount beginning on the date the warrant including the overpayment was issued until the third working day following the due date of the payment period from which the overpayment is being deducted. The interest on an overpayment shall be calculated using the average daily rate from the applicable calendar quarter and shall be deducted from moneys distributed to the county under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, ch. 77-209; s. 3, ch. 79-359; s. 72, ch. 79-400; s. 4, ch. 80-209; s. 2, ch. 80-222; s. 5, ch. 83-297; s. 1, ch. 83-321; s. 40, ch. 85-55; s. 1, ch. 86-4; s. 76, ch. 86-163; s. 61, ch. 87-6; s. 1, ch. 87-99; s. 35, ch. 87-101; s. 1, ch. 87-175; s. 5, ch. 87-280; s. 4, ch. 88-226; s. 6, ch. 88-243; s. 2, ch. 89-217; ss. 31, 66, ch. 89-356; s. 2, ch. 89-362; s. 1, ch. 90-107; s. 1, ch. 90-349; s. 81, ch. 91-45; s. 230, ch. 91-224; s. 3, ch. 92-175; s. 1, ch. 92-204; s. 32, ch. 92-320; s. 4, ch. 93-233; s. 1, ch. 94-275; s. 3, ch. 94-314; s. 37, ch. 94-338; s. 3, ch. 94-353; s. 1, ch. 95-133; s. 1434, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 95-304; s. 1, ch. 95-360; s. 1, ch. 95-416; ss. 44, 46, ch. 96-397; s. 43, ch. 96-406; s. 15, ch. 97-99; s. 1, ch. 98-106; s. 58, ch. 99-2; s. 1, ch. 99-287; ss. 6, 11, 14, ch. 2000-312; s. 11, ch. 2000-351; s. 14, ch. 2001-252; s. 10, ch. 2002-265; s. 1, ch. 2003-34; s. 1, ch. 2003-37; s. 2, ch. 2003-78; s. 145, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2005-96; s. 1, ch. 2009-133; s. 1, ch. 2012-180.</History>
</Section>