<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.74" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County administrator; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator may be responsible for the administration of all departments responsible to the board of county commissioners and for the proper administration of all affairs under the jurisdiction of the board. To that end, the administrator may, by way of enumeration and not by way of limitation, have the following specific powers and duties to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer and carry out the directives and policies of the board of county commissioners and enforce all orders, resolutions, ordinances, and regulations of the board to assure that they are faithfully executed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report to the board on action taken pursuant to any directive or policy within the time set by the board and provide an annual report to the board on the state of the county, the work of the previous year, and any recommendations as to actions or programs the administrator deems necessary for the improvement of the county and the welfare of its residents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the board, or individual members thereof, upon request, with data or information concerning county government and to provide advice and recommendations on county government operations to the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare and submit to the board of county commissioners for its consideration and adoption an annual operating budget, a capital budget, and a capital program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the schedules and procedures to be followed by all county departments, offices, and agencies in connection with the budget and supervise and administer all phases of the budgetary process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare and submit to the board after the end of each fiscal year a complete report on the finances and administrative activities of the county for the preceding year and submit his or her recommendations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervise the care and custody of all county property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the board a current position classification and pay plan for all positions in county service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, install, and maintain centralized budgeting, personnel, legal, and purchasing procedures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organize the work of county departments, subject to an administrative code developed by the administrator and adopted by the board, and review the departments, administration, and operation of the county and make recommendations pertaining thereto for reorganization by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Select, employ, and supervise all personnel and fill all vacancies, positions, or employment under the jurisdiction of the board. However, the employment of all department heads shall require confirmation by the board of county commissioners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suspend, discharge, or remove any employee under the jurisdiction of the board pursuant to procedures adopted by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Negotiate leases, contracts, and other agreements, including consultant services, for the county, subject to approval of the board, and make recommendations concerning the nature and location of county improvements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">See that all terms and conditions in all leases, contracts, and agreements are performed and notify the board of any noted violation thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order, upon advising the board, any agency under the administrator’s jurisdiction as specified in the administrative code to undertake any task for any other agency on a temporary basis if he or she deems it necessary for the proper and efficient administration of the county government to do so.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attend all meetings of the board with authority to participate in the discussion of any matter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform such other duties as may be required by the board of county commissioners.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to grant to the county administrator only those powers and duties which are administrative or ministerial in nature and not to delegate any governmental power imbued in the board of county commissioners as the governing body of the county pursuant to s. 1(e), Art. VIII of the State Constitution. To that end, the above specifically enumerated powers are to be construed as administrative in nature, and in any exercise of governmental power the administrator shall only be performing the duty of advising the board of county commissioners in its role as the policy-setting governing body of the county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-193; s. 822, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>