<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.84" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County charters; optional forms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county desiring to adopt a county charter shall provide for one of the following optional forms of government:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COUNTY EXECUTIVE FORM.<EmDash />The county executive form shall provide for governance by an elected board of commissioners and an elected county executive and such other officers as may be duly elected or appointed pursuant to the charter. The elected county executive shall exercise the executive responsibilities assigned by the charter and shall, in addition, approve each ordinance by signing it or allowing it to become approved without signature by failing to veto it or may veto any ordinance by returning it to the clerk of the board within 10 days of passage with a written statement of his or her objections. If two-thirds of the members of the board present and voting and constituting a quorum shall, upon reconsideration, vote for the ordinance, the executive’s veto shall be overridden and the ordinance shall become law in 10 days or at such other time as may be provided in the ordinance or by resolution of the board, without the executive’s signature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COUNTY MANAGER FORM.<EmDash />The county manager form shall provide for governance by an elected board of commissioners and an appointed county manager and such other officers as may be duly elected or appointed pursuant to the charter. The county manager shall be appointed by, and serve at the pleasure of, the board and shall exercise the executive responsibilities assigned by the charter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COUNTY CHAIR-ADMINISTRATOR PLAN.<EmDash />The county chair-administrator plan shall provide for governance by an elected board of commissioners, presided over by an elected chair who shall vote only in case of tie, and an appointed county administrator and such other officers as may be duly elected or appointed pursuant to the charter. The county administrator shall be appointed by, and serve at the pleasure of, the chair. The chair shall exercise, in conjunction with the administrator, the executive responsibilities assigned by the charter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-193; s. 823, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>