<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.411" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conveyance of land by county.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deeds of conveyance of lands, the title to which is held by any county or in the name of its board of county commissioners, may be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">THIS DEED, made this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida, party of the first part, and <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, party of the second part,</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">WITNESSETH that the said party of the first part, for and in consideration of the sum of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> to it in hand paid by the party of the second part, receipt whereof is hereby acknowledged, has granted, bargained and sold to the party of the second part, his or her heirs and assigns forever, the following described land lying and being in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida: 
<HorizontalRule Type="Full" /> 
<HorizontalRule Type="Full" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">IN WITNESS WHEREOF the said party of the first part has caused these presents to be executed in its name by its Board of County Commissioners acting by the Chair or Vice Chair of said board, the day and year aforesaid.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(OFFICIAL SEAL)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">ATTEST: <Directions xml:space="preserve">Clerk (or Deputy Clerk of Circuit Court)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">By its Board of County Commissioners</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">By <Directions xml:space="preserve">Chair (or Vice Chair)</Directions></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No such deed of conveyance shall be required to be witnessed or acknowledged, but shall be entitled to record when properly executed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All deeds of conveyance by any county or by its board of county commissioners shall convey only the interest of the county and such board in the property covered thereby, and shall not be deemed to warrant the title or to represent any state of facts concerning the same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any conveyance of real property executed by the board of county commissioners of any county after May 5, 1971, and before October 1, 1975, if it would have been valid had this act been in effect at the time such conveyance was executed, and the recording thereof by the clerk of the circuit court are hereby validated, ratified, and confirmed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 75-26; s. 818, ch. 95-147; s. 15, ch. 99-6.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 125.41.</Text></Note></Section>