<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.86" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County charters; legislative responsibilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The legislative responsibilities and power of the county shall be assigned to, and vested in, the board of county commissioners and shall consist of the following powers and duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and consent to all appointments by the executive for which board confirmation is specified;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt or enact, in accordance with the procedures provided by general law, ordinances and resolutions it deems necessary and proper for the good governance of the county;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a clerk to the board who shall serve at its pleasure and keep the records and minutes of the board;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve the annual operating and capital budgets and any long-term capital or financial program;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct continuing studies in the operation of county programs and services and take action on programs for improvement of the county and the welfare of its residents;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt, and amend as necessary, a county administrative code to govern the operation of the county;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt, pursuant to the provisions of the charter, such ordinances of countywide force and effect as are necessary for the health, safety, and welfare of the residents. It is the specific legislative intent to recognize that a county charter may properly determine that certain governmental areas are more conducive to uniform countywide enforcement and may provide the county government powers in relation to those areas as recognized and as may be amended from time to time by the people of that county; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other powers of local self-government not inconsistent with general law as recognized by the Constitution and laws of the state and which have not been limited by the county charter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-193.</History></Section>