<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.0101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County may contract to provide services to municipalities and special districts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the legislative intent of this act to permit counties to contract for services with municipalities and special districts as provided by s. 4, Art. VIII of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the powers enumerated in this chapter, the legislative and governing body of a county shall have the power to contract with a municipality or special district within the county for fire protection, law enforcement, library services and facilities, beach erosion control, recreation services and facilities, water, streets, sidewalks, street lighting, garbage and trash collection and disposal, waste and sewage collection and disposal, drainage, transportation, and other essential facilities and municipal services. Such services shall be funded as agreed upon between the county and the municipality or special district. This section shall not be construed to authorize the county to impose any service charge or special assessment or to levy any tax within the municipality or special district, nor shall this section be construed to authorize the creation of a municipal service taxing unit within such area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Municipalities and special districts are hereby authorized and empowered to enter into service contracts pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the powers granted by this section shall not be deemed to be a limitation of powers already existing but shall be deemed to be cumulative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to any county operating under a home rule charter adopted pursuant to ss. 10, 11, and 24, Art. VIII of the Constitution of 1885, as preserved by s. 6(e), Art. VIII, of the Constitution of 1968.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-47.</History></Section>