<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.73" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County administrator; appointment, qualifications, compensation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county to which this part applies shall appoint a county administrator, who shall be the administrative head of the county and shall be responsible for the administration of all departments of the county government which the board of county commissioners has authority to control pursuant to this act, the general laws of Florida, or other applicable legislation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county administrator shall be qualified by administrative and executive experience and ability to serve as the chief administrator of the county. He or she shall be appointed by an affirmative vote of not less than three members of the board of county commissioners and may be removed at any time by an affirmative vote, upon notice, of not less than three members of the board, after a hearing if such be requested by the county administrator. The administrator need not be a resident of the county at the time of appointment, but during his or her tenure in office shall reside within the county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The compensation of the administrator shall be fixed by the board of county commissioners unless otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office of county administrator shall be deemed vacant if the incumbent moves his or her residence from the county or is, by death, illness, or other casualty, unable to continue in office. A vacancy in the office shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. The board of county commissioners may appoint an acting administrator in the case of vacancy or temporary absence or disability until a successor has been appointed and qualified or the administrator returns.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-193; s. 821, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>