<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0125.581" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain local employment registration prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as authorized by law, no county or municipality shall enact or enforce any ordinance, resolution, rule, regulation, policy, or other action which requires the registration or background screening of any individual engaged in or applying for a specific type or category of employment in the county or municipality or requires the carrying of an identification card issued as a result of such registration or screening, whether or not such requirement is based upon the residency of the person. However, an ordinance that regulates any business, institution, association, profession, or occupation by requiring background screening, which may include proof of certain skills, knowledge, or moral character, is not prohibited by this section, provided that such regulation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not preempted to the state or is not otherwise prohibited by law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a valid exercise of the police power;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is narrowly designed to offer the protection sought by the county or municipality; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not unfairly discriminate against any class of individuals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act shall not be construed to prohibit any employer, including a local government, from investigating the background of employees or prospective employees or from requiring employees to carry an identification card or registration card.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 86-259.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also published at s. 166.0443.</Text></Note></Section>