<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1007.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Articulated acceleration mechanisms.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that a variety of articulated acceleration mechanisms be available for secondary and postsecondary students attending public educational institutions. It is intended that articulated acceleration serve to shorten the time necessary for a student to complete the requirements associated with the conference of a high school diploma and a postsecondary degree, broaden the scope of curricular options available to students, or increase the depth of study available for a particular subject. Articulated acceleration mechanisms shall include, but are not limited to, dual enrollment and early admission as provided for in s. 1007.271, advanced placement, credit by examination, the International Baccalaureate Program, and the Advanced International Certificate of Education Program. Credit earned through the Florida Virtual School shall provide additional opportunities for early graduation and acceleration. Students of Florida public secondary schools enrolled pursuant to this subsection shall be deemed authorized users of the state-funded electronic library resources that are licensed for Florida College System institutions and state universities by the Florida Virtual Campus. Verification of eligibility shall be in accordance with rules established by the State Board of Education and regulations established by the Board of Governors and processes implemented by Florida College System institutions and state universities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall annually identify and publish the minimum scores, maximum credit, and course or courses for which credit is to be awarded for each College Level Examination Program (CLEP) subject examination, College Board Advanced Placement Program examination, Advanced International Certificate of Education examination, and International Baccalaureate examination. The department shall use student performance data in subsequent postsecondary courses to determine the appropriate examination scores and courses for which credit is to be granted. Minimum scores may vary by subject area based on available performance data. In addition, the department shall identify such courses in the general education core curriculum of each state university and Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Florida College System institution and state university must award credit for specific courses for which competency has been demonstrated by successful passage of one of the examinations in subsection (2) unless the award of credit duplicates credit already awarded. Florida College System institutions and state universities may not exempt students from courses without the award of credit if competencies have been so demonstrated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to provide articulated acceleration mechanisms for students who are in home education programs, as defined in s. 1002.01, consistent with the educational opportunities available to public and private secondary school students. Home education students may participate in dual enrollment, career dual enrollment, early admission, and credit by examination. Credit earned by home education students through dual enrollment shall apply toward the completion of a home education program that meets the requirements of s. 1002.41.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advanced placement shall be the enrollment of an eligible secondary student in a course offered through the Advanced Placement Program administered by the College Board. Postsecondary credit for an advanced placement course shall be limited to students who score a minimum of 3, on a 5-point scale, on the corresponding Advanced Placement Examination. The specific courses for which students receive such credit shall be identified in the statewide articulation agreement required by s. 1007.23(1). Students of Florida public secondary schools enrolled pursuant to this subsection shall be exempt from the payment of any fees for administration of the examination regardless of whether or not the student achieves a passing score on the examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit by examination shall be the program through which secondary and postsecondary students generate postsecondary credit based on the receipt of a specified minimum score on nationally standardized general or subject-area examinations. For the purpose of statewide application, such examinations and the corresponding minimum scores required for an award of credit shall be delineated by the State Board of Education and the Board of Governors in the statewide articulation agreement required by s. 1007.23(1). The maximum credit generated by a student pursuant to this subsection shall be mitigated by any related postsecondary credit earned by the student prior to the administration of the examination. This subsection shall not preclude Florida College System institutions and universities from awarding credit by examination based on student performance on examinations developed within and recognized by the individual postsecondary institutions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The International Baccalaureate Program shall be the curriculum in which eligible secondary students are enrolled in a program of studies offered through the International Baccalaureate Program administered by the International Baccalaureate Office. The State Board of Education and the Board of Governors shall specify in the statewide articulation agreement required by s. 1007.23(1) the cutoff scores and International Baccalaureate Examinations which will be used to grant postsecondary credit at Florida College System institutions and universities. Any changes to the articulation agreement, which have the effect of raising the required cutoff score or of changing the International Baccalaureate Examinations which will be used to grant postsecondary credit, shall only apply to students taking International Baccalaureate Examinations after such changes are adopted by the State Board of Education and the Board of Governors. Students shall be awarded a maximum of 30 semester credit hours pursuant to this subsection. The specific course for which a student may receive such credit shall be specified in the statewide articulation agreement required by s. 1007.23(1). Students enrolled pursuant to this subsection shall be exempt from the payment of any fees for administration of the examinations regardless of whether or not the student achieves a passing score on the examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Advanced International Certificate of Education Program and the International General Certificate of Secondary Education (pre-AICE) Program shall be the curricula in which eligible secondary students are enrolled in programs of study offered through the Advanced International Certificate of Education Program or the International General Certificate of Secondary Education (pre-AICE) Program administered by the University of Cambridge Local Examinations Syndicate. The State Board of Education and the Board of Governors shall specify in the statewide articulation agreement required by s. 1007.23(1) the cutoff scores and Advanced International Certificate of Education examinations which will be used to grant postsecondary credit at Florida College System institutions and universities. Any changes to the cutoff scores, which changes have the effect of raising the required cutoff score or of changing the Advanced International Certification of Education examinations which will be used to grant postsecondary credit, shall apply to students taking Advanced International Certificate of Education examinations after such changes are adopted by the State Board of Education and the Board of Governors. Students shall be awarded a maximum of 30 semester credit hours pursuant to this subsection. The specific course for which a student may receive such credit shall be determined by the Florida College System institution or university that accepts the student for admission. Students enrolled in either program of study pursuant to this subsection shall be exempt from the payment of any fees for administration of the examinations regardless of whether the student achieves a passing score on the examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 356, ch. 2002-387; s. 6, ch. 2003-8; s. 167, ch. 2004-5; s. 108, ch. 2004-357; s. 5, ch. 2005-196; s. 120, ch. 2007-217; s. 22, ch. 2010-154; s. 99, ch. 2011-5; s. 11, ch. 2011-177; s. 17, ch. 2012-134; s. 19, ch. 2012-191.</History>
</Section>