<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1007.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Articulation; postsecondary institution coordination and collaboration.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university boards of trustees, Florida College System institution boards of trustees, and district school boards are encouraged to establish intrainstitutional and interinstitutional programs to maximize articulation. Programs may include upper-division-level courses offered at the Florida College System institution, distance learning, transfer agreements that facilitate the transfer of credits between public and nonpublic postsecondary institutions, and the concurrent enrollment of students at a Florida College System institution and a state university to enable students to take any level of baccalaureate degree coursework.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The levels of postsecondary education shall collaborate in further developing and providing articulated programs in which students can proceed toward their educational objectives as rapidly as their circumstances permit. Time-shortened educational programs, as well as the use of acceleration mechanisms, shall include, but not be limited to, the International Baccalaureate, Advanced International Certificate of Education, credit by examination or demonstration of competency, advanced placement, early admissions, and dual enrollment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public postsecondary educational institutions serving the same students in a geographic and service area are encouraged to establish appropriate interinstitutional mechanisms to achieve cooperative planning and delivery of academic programs and related services, share a high-cost instructional facility and equipment, coordinate credit and noncredit outreach activities, have access to each other’s library and media holdings and services, and provide cooperative campus activities and consultative relationships for the discussion and resolution of interinstitutional issues and problems which discourage student access or transfer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public postsecondary education institutions are encouraged to include independent colleges and universities and industries within their service areas in mutual planning of a comprehensive, complementary, cost-effective array of undergraduate and beginning graduate programs of study to serve that geographic area.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 347, ch. 2002-387; s. 3, ch. 2005-196; s. 112, ch. 2007-217; s. 89, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>