<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for license; carriers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to engage in business as a private or common carrier of motor fuel within this state or to engage in the business of transporting fuel by pipeline or marine vessel unless he or she is the holder of an unrevoked license issued by the department to engage in such business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To procure such license, a person shall file with the department an application under oath and in such form as the department may prescribe, setting forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name under which the person will transact business within the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location, with street number address, of his or her principal office or place of business within this state and the location where records will be made available for inspection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, federal employer identification number or, if such number is not available, the social security number, and complete residence address of the owner or the names and addresses of the partners, if such person is a partnership, or of the principal officers, if such person is a corporation or association; and, if such person is a corporation organized under the laws of another state, territory, or country, he or she shall also file with the application a certified copy of the certificate or license issued by the Department of State showing that such corporation is authorized to transact business in the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall require a $30 license tax. Each license shall be renewed annually through application, including an annual $30 license tax.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person transporting fuel without first obtaining such license commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Such person shall also be subject to the provisions of s. 206.205.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary contained in this chapter, the department may grant a temporary fuel license for immediate use if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor has declared a state of emergency under s. 252.36; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The President of the United States has declared a major disaster in this state or in any other state or territory of the United States.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter requiring a license tax and a bond or criminal background check, the department may issue a temporary license as a carrier to a person who holds a valid Florida wholesaler, importer, exporter, or blender license or to a person who is an unlicensed dealer. A license may be issued under this subsection only to a business that has a physical location in this state and holds a valid Florida sales and use tax certificate of registration or that holds a valid fuel license issued by another state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary license expires on the last day of the month following the month in which the temporary license was issued. The department may extend any temporary license on a month-to-month basis during the period of a declared state of emergency or major disaster as provided in this subsection. If the department extends a temporary license, the extended license expires on the last day of the month in which the temporary license was extended.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to procure a temporary license, a nonresident business must provide to the department the information required in subsection (2); the federal identification number of the business or, if such number is unavailable, the social security number of the owner; and any other information that is required by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary license authorized by this subsection may not be renewed if the licensee has not filed the required returns or made payment of the taxes required under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 75, ch. 85-342; s. 1060, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 95-417; s. 16, ch. 2007-106.</History></Section>