<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.8745" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Credits and refund claims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsections (2) and (7), any person who purchases undyed, tax-paid diesel fuel who has paid the tax imposed by this part to the seller may file a claim for refund of such taxes paid as provided in s. 215.26 if the fuel is used for an exempt purpose identified in s. 206.874(3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsection (1) do not apply to any person purchasing undyed, tax-paid diesel fuel for use on a farm for farming purposes, or to sales of undyed, tax-paid diesel fuel to the United States or its departments or agencies in bulk lots of not less than 500 gallons in each delivery. Such sales shall be made tax-free and the seller, if a registered ultimate vendor, shall be entitled to file a refund of such taxes or apply for a credit on its monthly return as authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed terminal supplier, importer, or wholesaler which holds title to undyed diesel fuel which has been mixed with dyed diesel fuel in storage may claim a refund or credit for any state and local option tax paid on the undyed diesel fuel. In lieu of applying for a refund, a credit may be taken on the return required pursuant to s. 206.43. Any refund or credit claimed under this subsection shall be supported by documentation showing the date and location of the mixing, number of gallons involved, and disposition of the mixed fuel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any mixture of dyed and undyed diesel fuel shall not be subject to a taxable use, and shall remain subject to the dye specifications provided by s. 206.8741.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed wholesaler which has paid the tax imposed by this part and any applicable local option tax on undyed diesel fuel subsequently sold tax-free for use on a farm for farming purposes, or to the United States or its departments or agencies in bulk lots of not less than 500 gallons in each delivery may, in lieu of applying for a refund, take a credit on its monthly consolidated fuel tax return against any motor or diesel fuel local option taxes due to the department pursuant to s. 206.41(1)(d), (e), and (f).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A terminal supplier or position holder which removes undyed diesel fuel from a terminal and subsequently places the fuel back into the same or another terminal may claim a refund or credit for all state and local option tax which it paid or accrued on the first removal of the fuel. Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing a terminal supplier or position holder to remove undyed diesel fuel from a terminal without paying or accruing the tax imposed by this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undyed, tax-paid diesel fuel consumed by a power takeoff or engine exhaust for the purpose of unloading bulk cargo by pumping or turning a concrete mixer drum used in the manufacturing process, or for the purpose of compacting solid waste, which is mounted on a motor vehicle and which has no separate fuel tank or power unit, is subject to a refund as provided by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who purchases undyed diesel fuel for use by a noncommercial vessel who has paid the tax imposed by this part to the seller may claim a refund of such taxes paid subject to the following restrictions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser may make one claim for refund per calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual refund claim shall be submitted prior to April 1 of the year subsequent to the year in which the tax was paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No refund shall be allowed on purchases of less than 2,500 gallons per calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser shall submit, with the refund request, original purchase invoices showing the taxes paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser shall remit as an offset to the refund the sales tax due under chapter 212 based on the purchase price of the fuel net of the state tax refunded.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undyed, tax-paid diesel fuel purchased in this state and consumed by the engine of a qualified motor coach during idle time for the purpose of running climate control systems and maintaining electrical systems for the motor coach is subject to a refund. As used in this subsection, the term “qualified motor coach” means a privately owned vehicle that is designed to carry nine or more passengers, that has a gross vehicle weight of at least 33,000 pounds, that is used exclusively in the commercial application of transporting passengers for compensation, and that has the capacity to measure diesel fuel consumed in Florida during idling, separate from diesel fuel consumed to propel the vehicle in this state, by way of an on-board computer.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser may make one claim for refund per calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual refund claim must be submitted before April 1 of the year following the year in which the tax was paid and after December 31, 2000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser must submit original or copies of original purchase invoices showing the taxes paid, or, in lieu of original invoices, a purchaser may submit a schedule of purchases containing the information required by s. 206.41(5)(b)1.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser must remit, as an offset to the refund, sales tax due under chapter 212 based on the purchase price of the fuel, net of the state tax refunded.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Department of Revenue may adopt rules to administer this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 77, ch. 95-417; s. 17, ch. 96-323; s. 10, ch. 97-54; s. 2, ch. 2000-266.</History></Section>