<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.9941" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following items shall be exempt from the tax imposed under s. 206.9935(3): American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) grades No. 5 and No. 6 residual oils; intermediate fuel oils (IFO) used by the taxpayer for marine bunkering with a viscosity of 30 and higher; asphalt oil; petrochemical feedstocks; and pesticides, ammonia, chlorine, and derivatives thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petroleum products exported from the first storage facility at which they are held in this state by a licensed terminal supplier, importer, exporter, wholesaler, or producer are exempt from the taxes imposed under s. 206.9935(2) and (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pollutants exported from the manufacturing plant, first storage tank system, or first warehouse at which they are held in this state by a licensed importer or producer are exempt from the tax imposed under s. 206.9935(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solvents consumed in the manufacture or production of a material that is not itself a pollutant, as defined in s. 206.9925, are exempt from the tax imposed by s. 206.9935(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solvents, motor oil, and lubricants are exempt from the taxes imposed by s. 206.9935(1) and (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crude oil produced at a well site subject to regulation under s. 377.22 and exported from that site by the producer exclusively by pipeline, truck, or rail to beyond the jurisdiction of this state without intermediate storage or stoppage shall be exempt from the tax imposed under s. 206.9935(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petroleum products bunkered into marine vessels engaged in interstate or foreign commerce from the first storage facility at which they are held in this state by a licensed terminal supplier, importer, exporter, wholesaler, or producer are exempt from the taxes imposed under s. 206.9935(2) and (3).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-159; s. 67, ch. 87-99; s. 3, ch. 88-393; s. 3, ch. 89-171; s. 15, ch. 92-30; s. 95, ch. 95-417; s. 3, ch. 96-352.</History></Section>