<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.91" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax reports; computation and payment of tax.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of determining the amount of taxes imposed by s. 206.87, each diesel fuel registrant shall, not later than the 20th day of each calendar month, mail to the department, on forms prescribed by the department, monthly reports which shall show such information on inventories, purchases, nontaxable disposals, and taxable sales in gallons of diesel fuel and alternative fuel, for the preceding calendar month as may be required by the department. However, if the 20th day falls on a Saturday, a Sunday, or a federal or state legal holiday, returns shall be accepted if postmarked on the next succeeding workday. The reports shall contain or be verified by a written declaration that such report is made under the penalties of perjury. The diesel fuel registrant shall deduct from the amount of taxes shown by the report to be payable an amount equivalent to .67 percent of the taxes on diesel fuel imposed by s. 206.87(1)(a) and (e), which deduction is hereby allowed to the diesel fuel registrant on account of services and expenses in complying with the provisions of this part. The allowance on taxable gallons of diesel fuel sold to persons licensed under this chapter shall not be deductible unless the diesel fuel registrant has allowed 50 percent of the allowance provided by this section to a purchaser with a valid wholesaler or terminal supplier license. This allowance shall not be deductible unless payment of the taxes is made on or before the 20th day of the month as herein required. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize a deduction from the constitutional fuel tax or fuel sales tax.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of filing the monthly report, each diesel fuel registrant shall pay to the department the full amount of diesel fuel taxes for the preceding calendar month at the rate provided for in s. 206.87, less the amount allowable to the diesel fuel registrant on account of services and expenses as provided in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may authorize a quarterly return and payment of taxes when the taxes remitted by the diesel fuel registrant for the preceding quarter did not exceed $100, and may authorize a semiannual return and payment of taxes when the taxes remitted by the diesel fuel registrant for the preceding 6 months did not exceed $200.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the allowance authorized by subsection (1), every diesel fuel registrant shall be entitled to a deduction of 1.1 percent of the taxes imposed under s. 206.87(1)(b) and (c), which deduction is hereby allowed on account of services and expenses in complying with the provisions of this part. This allowance shall not be deductible unless payment of the tax is made on or before the 20th day of the month as herein required.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 19446, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 1167(109); s. 8, ch. 26718, 1951; s. 7, ch. 63-253; s. 5, ch. 65-371; s. 2, ch. 65-420; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 4, ch. 78-250; s. 1, ch. 81-165; s. 27, ch. 83-3; s. 9, ch. 83-137; s. 11, ch. 83-138; s. 80, ch. 87-99; s. 15, ch. 89-356; s. 84, ch. 95-417; s. 11, ch. 97-54.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 209.07.</Text></Note></Section>