<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Importer and exporter; credit authorization and bonding requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to being licensed, an importer must establish credit worthiness with the department. This shall be accomplished by posting a bond equivalent to 60 days’ tax liability or by making a cash deposit or providing an irrevocable letter of credit in that amount. An importer shall then be authorized to import fuels and remit taxes directly to the state as provided in this part up to the amount of credit so established. Before an importer’s liability may exceed its established credit limit, the importer shall make a tax deposit, by electronic funds transfer to the department, in an amount equal to its current tax liability, or provide the department with additional security as provided by this section. Any importer who fails to timely remit taxes and supply sufficient credit as required by this section shall be prohibited from importing untaxed fuel into this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to each importation of taxable motor or diesel fuels upon which tax has not been charged by the supplier, an importer must notify the department and obtain an import authorization number which shall be recorded by the importer on the shipping papers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to being licensed, an exporter must post a bond with the department equal to 3 times the total state and local option taxes that would be due if sold for highway use in Florida, based on the average monthly number of gallons of motor and diesel fuel to be exported, subject to the maximum bonding restrictions for motor fuels in s. 206.05 and diesel fuels in s. 206.90. To the extent that a taxpayer already has established a bond under those sections, only an amount necessary to comply with this section will be required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed exporter shall be authorized to take a credit on its monthly fuel tax return or apply for a refund of all state fuel tax and local option fuel tax paid on fuel exported from the state in compliance with this section. To establish the right to refund, an exporter shall provide a copy of the return filed in the destination state showing the import of all fuels claimed for refund. The department shall, absent any violation, authorize a refund based on the information submitted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any exporter filing a false refund claim or claiming a false credit shall be prohibited from making future refund or credit claims for taxes paid on motor fuels exported from this state for a period of not less than 12 months. A false claim for credit or refund shall be a basis for license revocation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 95-417.</History></Section>