<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection of records; audits; hearings; forms; rules and regulations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the authority to prescribe all forms upon which reports shall be made to it and any other forms required for the proper administration of this law and shall prescribe and publish all rules and regulations for the enforcement of this part, which rules and regulations shall have the force and effect of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or any authorized deputy, employee, or agent is authorized to audit and examine the records, books, papers, and equipment of terminal suppliers, importers, exporters, or wholesalers, retail dealers, terminal operators, or all private and common carriers to verify the truth and accuracy of any statement or report and ascertain whether or not the tax imposed by this law has been paid. No prior written notification is necessary. In addition to making all records available to the department to determine the accuracy of tax payments to the state and suppliers, all persons, including retail dealers, wholesalers, importers, exporters, terminal suppliers, and end users with storage other than the fuel tank of a highway vehicle, shall make available to the department, during normal business hours, records disclosing all receipts, sales, inventory records, fuel payments, and tax payment information. These records shall cover all transactions within the last 3 complete calendar months and shall be made available within 3 business days of the department’s request. The department may correct by credit or refund any overpayment of tax, penalty, or interest revealed by an audit or examination and shall make assessment of any deficiency in tax, penalty, or interest determined to be due.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to provide the records required by this section shall, in addition to all other penalties, be subject to a fine of $5,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or any of its duly authorized agents shall have the power in the enforcement of the provisions of this part to hold hearings, administer oaths to witnesses, and take sworn testimony of any person and cause it to be transcribed into writing; and for such purposes the department is authorized to issue subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum, compel the attendance of witnesses and records, and conduct such investigations as it may deem necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person unreasonably refuses access to such records, books, papers or other documents, or equipment, or if any person fails or refuses to obey such subpoenas duces tecum or to testify, except for lawful reasons, before the department or any of its authorized agents, the department shall certify the names and facts to the clerk of the circuit court of any county; and the circuit court shall enter such order against such person in the premises as the enforcement of this law and justice requires.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action or proceeding for the collection of the tax and penalties or interest imposed in connection therewith, an assessment by the department of the amount of the tax, penalties, or interest due shall be prima facie evidence of the claim of the state, and the burden of proof shall be upon the person charged to show the assessment was incorrect and contrary to law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys derived from the penalties imposed by this section shall be deposited into the Fuel Tax Collection Trust Fund and allocated in the same manner as provided by s. 206.875.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 16082, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 1167(70); s. 7, ch. 63-253; s. 5, ch. 65-371; s. 2, ch. 65-420; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 31, ch. 74-382; s. 3, ch. 83-137; s. 94, ch. 85-342; s. 23, ch. 95-417; s. 12, ch. 2003-254; s. 9, ch. 2005-280.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 207.17.</Text></Note></Section>