<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Departmental powers; cancellation of licenses; surrender of bond; interstate enforcement agreements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a terminal supplier, importer, exporter, or wholesaler at any time:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly files a false monthly report of the data or information required by the provisions of this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails, refuses, or neglects to file the monthly report required by such laws;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails to pay the fuel taxes as required by part I or part II of this chapter or the local option tax required under this chapter and the laws of the state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly files a false claim for refund or credit of fuel tax;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the department may cancel the license of the terminal supplier, importer, exporter, or wholesaler.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may cancel any license hitherto or hereafter issued to any such person if it ascertains and finds that the person to whom such license has been issued is no longer engaged in such business and has not been so engaged for the period of 6 months immediately preceding such cancellation; but no license shall be canceled upon the request of any person until and unless the person has, prior to the date of such cancellation, paid to the state all fuel taxes payable under the laws of the state, together with any and all penalties, interest, and fines accruing by reason of any failure on the part of said person to make accurate reports as required by the fuel tax laws of Florida or to pay said taxes, interest, and penalties. In the event that any license is canceled by the department as provided in this section, and in the further event that the licensee shall have paid to the state all fuel taxes due and payable by it under the laws of this state, together with any and all penalties and interest accruing by reason of any failure on the part of the licensee to make accurate reports or to pay said tax, interest, and penalties, the department shall cancel and surrender the bond held on file by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized, with the consent of another jurisdiction of the United States whose cooperation is needed, to enforce this chapter in that jurisdiction, either directly or, at the option of that jurisdiction, by entering into an agreement with its agencies, officers, and employees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 16082, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 1167(65); s. 7, ch. 63-253; s. 5, ch. 65-371; s. 2, ch. 65-420; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 54, ch. 78-95; s. 87, ch. 81-259; s. 84, ch. 85-342; s. 11, ch. 95-417.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 207.07.</Text></Note></Section>