<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.9925" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Barrel” means 42 U.S. gallons at 60 °F.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Oil” means crude petroleum oil and other hydrocarbons, regardless of gravity, which are produced at the well in liquid form by ordinary production methods and which are not the result of condensation of gas after it leaves the reservoir.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gas” means all natural gas, including casinghead gas, and all other hydrocarbons not defined as oil in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Petroleum product” means any refined liquid commodity made wholly or partially from oil or gas, or blends or mixtures of oil with one or more liquid products or byproducts derived from oil or gas, or blends or mixtures of two or more liquid products or byproducts derived from oil or gas, and includes, but is not limited to, motor gasoline, gasohol, aviation gasoline, naphtha-type jet fuel, kerosene-type jet fuel, kerosene, distillate fuel oil, residual fuel oil, motor oil and other lubricants, naphtha of less than 400 °F for petroleum feed, special naphthas, road oil, still gas, unfinished oils, motor gas blending components, including petroleum-derived ethanol when used for such purpose, and aviation gas blending components.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pollutants” includes any petroleum product as defined in subsection (4) as well as pesticides, ammonia, and chlorine; lead-acid batteries, including, but not limited to, batteries that are a component part of other tangible personal property; and solvents as defined in subsection (6), but the term excludes liquefied petroleum gas, medicinal oils, and waxes. Products intended for application to the human body or for use in human personal hygiene or for human ingestion are not pollutants, regardless of their contents. For the purpose of the tax imposed under s. 206.9935(1), “pollutants” also includes crude oil.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Solvents” means the following organic compounds, if the listed organic compound is in liquid form: acetamide, acetone, acetonitrile, acetophenone, amyl acetates (all), aniline, benzene, butyl acetates (all), butyl alcohols (all), butyl benzyl phthalate, carbon disulfide, carbon tetrachloride, chlorobenzene, chloroform, cumene, cyclohexane, cyclohexanone, dibutyl phthalate, dichlorobenzenes (all), dichlorodifluoromethane, diethyl phthalate, dimethyl phthalate, dioctyl phthalate (di2-ethyl hexyl phthalate), n-dioctyl phthalate, 1,4-dioxane, petroleum-derived ethanol, ethyl acetate, ethyl benzene, ethylene dichloride, 2-ethoxy ethanol (ethylene glycol ethyl ether), ethylene glycol, furfural, formaldehyde, n-hexane, isophorone, isopropyl alcohol, methanol, 2-methoxy ethanol (ethylene glycol methyl ether), methyl tert-butyl ether, methylene chloride (dichloromethane), methyl ethyl ketone, methyl isobutyl ketone, mineral spirits, 140-F naphtha, naphthalene, nitrobenzene, 2-nitropropane, pentachlorobenzene, phenol, perchloroethylene (tetrachloroethylene), stoddard solvent, tetrahydrofuran, toluene, 1,1,1-trichloroethane, trichloroethylene, 1,1,2-trichloro-1,2,2-trifluoroethane, and xylenes (all).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consume” means to destroy or to alter the chemical or physical structure of a solvent so that it is no longer identifiable as the solvent it was.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Storage facility” means a location owned, operated, or leased by a licensed terminal operator, which location contains any stationary tank or tanks for holding petroleum products.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-159; s. 1, ch. 88-393; s. 1, ch. 89-171; s. 3, ch. 91-194; s. 2, ch. 91-305; s. 92, ch. 95-417; s. 5, ch. 96-323; s. 1, ch. 96-352.</History></Section>