<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License requirements for retail dealers and resellers; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to engage in the business of selling motor or diesel fuel at retail without first obtaining the license required by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to engage in the business of reselling tax-paid fuel to retailers or end users without first obtaining the license required by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person engaging in the business of selling motor or diesel fuel at retail or engaging in business as a reseller shall, prior to engaging in business, register with the department pursuant to chapter 212.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No license shall be transferred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each business location shall have a separate license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application shall include the federal employer identification number or, if such number is not available, the social security number of the applicant and the Department of Environmental Protection storage tank facility number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant shall declare his or her primary business activity as either the sale of motor fuel at retail, the sale of diesel fuel at retail, or acting as a reseller.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person required to be licensed by this section shall maintain all records required under s. 206.12 and shall make those records available to the department for inspection or audit upon request.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person required to register under this section who fails to make records available to the department within the time specified in s. 206.12 commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, and the department shall estimate such person’s tax liability and make a jeopardy assessment for the estimated tax due. In addition to any estimated tax, delinquency penalty, and interest found to be due, the licensee shall be subject to a civil penalty of $500 and the department shall revoke such person’s registration under chapter 212.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any retail dealer or reseller in violation of the provisions of this chapter or the provisions of the Florida Motor Fuel Tax Relief Act of 2004 shall be subject to revocation of his or her license under chapter 212.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 15659, 1931; CGL 1936 Supp. 1167(16); s. 1, ch. 20303, 1941; s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 2, ch. 75-286; s. 99, ch. 85-342; s. 31, ch. 86-152; s. 39, ch. 95-417; s. 7, ch. 96-323; s. 10, ch. 2004-73.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 208.01.</Text></Note></Section>