<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.609" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer of funds to the Agricultural Emergency Eradication Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys transferred to the Agricultural Emergency Eradication Trust Fund pursuant to ss. 206.606 and 206.608 are subject to the following provisions:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the unobligated balance of the Agricultural Emergency Eradication Trust Fund exceeds $20 million, the transfers provided for in ss. 206.606(1)(c) and 206.608(1) shall be discontinued until the unobligated balance of the trust fund falls below $10 million, at which time such transfers shall be reinstated to return the balance to $20 million.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A change in transfers pursuant to this section shall take effect on the first day of the month after 30 days’ notification to the Department of Revenue by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services when the unobligated balance of the trust fund exceeds or falls below a limit set pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any refunds of the tax imposed under s. 206.41(1)(f) claimed under s. 206.41(4)(c)1. in excess of such refunds claimed during the fiscal year preceding the effective date of this act shall be deducted from the amount transferred pursuant to s. 206.608(1), during the year the claims are made, to the Agricultural Emergency Eradication Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any refunds of the tax imposed under s. 206.41(1)(g) claimed under s. 206.41(4)(c)1. in excess of such refunds claimed during the fiscal year preceding the effective date of this act shall be deducted from the amount transferred pursuant to s. 206.606(1)(c), during the year the claims are made, to the Agricultural Emergency Eradication Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 98-114; s. 36, ch. 2000-151.</History></Section>