<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any false or fraudulent statement or report submitted under the fuel tax laws of this state and sworn to by a person knowing same to be false or fraudulent shall constitute perjury, and, upon conviction thereof, the person so convicted shall be punished as provided by law for conviction of perjury under <Reference Number="1" />s. 837.01.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who willfully refuses or neglects to make any statement, report, or return required by the provisions of this law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who knowingly makes, or assists any other person in making, a false statement in a return or report or in connection with an application for refund of any tax;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who knowingly collects, or attempts to collect or causes to be paid to that person or to any other person, either directly or indirectly, any refund of such tax without being entitled to the same; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who violates any of the provisions of part I or part II of this chapter, a penalty for which is not otherwise provided,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084; and, in addition thereto, the department may revoke or suspend the license of any violator. Each day or part thereof during which any person engages in business without being the holder of an uncanceled license as provided by part I or part II of this chapter shall constitute a separate offense within the meaning of this section. In addition to the penalty imposed by part I or part II of this chapter, the defendant shall be required to pay all fuel taxes, interest, and penalties due to the state. The penalties provided in this section shall be in addition to those provided for in s. 206.44.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 115, ch. 71-136; s. 92, ch. 81-259; s. 91, ch. 85-342; s. 72, ch. 87-6; s. 1065, ch. 95-147; s. 20, ch. 95-417.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transferred to s. 837.012 by s. 54, ch. 74-383.</Text></Note></Section>