<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retention of records; all persons that purchase, import, export, use, sell, or store motor fuel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person shall maintain and keep such record of motor fuel received, used, transferred, sold, and delivered within this state by such person, together with invoices, bills of lading, and other pertinent records and papers, as may be required by the department for the reasonable administration of the motor fuel tax laws of this state. Records shall include all import and export documentation, all records necessary to provide evidence of exemptions claimed as a result of use, sale, or export, or through the sale, use, or storage of diesel fuels exempted for meeting dyeing requirements in part II. Each licensee or any other person who purchases, imports, exports, stores, sells, or uses motor fuel shall preserve such records as long as required by s. 213.35. This section shall not apply to noncommercial retail purchases of tax-paid fuel in quantities of 100 gallons or less. All purchases made by commercial and agricultural users shall be covered by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person required to maintain records by this chapter does not have adequate records of sales, use, imports, exports, transfers, exchanges, loans, or purchases, the department shall advise the person as to the adequacy of the records, and test or make a reasonable examination of the person’s available records or other available information relating to the sales or purchases made by such person for a representative period. This subsection does not affect the duty of the terminal supplier, terminal operator, importer, exporter, wholesaler, or dealer to collect, or the liability of any person to pay, any tax imposed by this part. The department shall provide the person with information concerning the method and extent of the test or reasonable examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the records of a person are adequate but voluminous in nature and substance, the department may use a representative sample of such records and estimate the audit findings derived therefrom for the entire audit period. The department must first make a good faith effort to reach an agreement with the person which provides for the means and methods to be used in the examination process. In the event that no agreement is reached, the person is entitled to a review by the executive director or the appropriate designee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 16082, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 1167(69), 7794(7); s. 7, ch. 63-253; s. 5, ch. 65-371; s. 2, ch. 65-420; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 1, ch. 80-104; s. 92, ch. 85-342; s. 7, ch. 88-119; s. 92, ch. 90-136; s. 3, ch. 90-351; s. 21, ch. 95-417.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 207.16.</Text></Note></Section>