<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discontinuance or transfer of business; liability of tax, procedure; penalty for violation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a person ceases to engage in business as a terminal supplier, importer, exporter, or wholesaler within the state by reason of the discontinuance, sale, or transfer of the business, such person shall notify the department in writing at least 10 days prior to the time the discontinuance, sale, or transfer takes effect. Such notice shall give the date of discontinuance and, in the event of a sale or transfer of the business, the date thereof and the name and address of the purchaser or transferee. All fuel taxes, penalties, and interest not due and payable under the provisions of the laws of this state shall, notwithstanding such provisions, become due and payable concurrently with such discontinuance, sale, or transfer; and any such person shall, concurrently with such discontinuance, sale, or transfer, make a report, pay all such taxes, interest, and penalties, and surrender to the department the license certificate theretofore issued to said person by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the above notice shall have been given to the department as above provided, such purchaser or transferee shall be liable to the state for the amount of all taxes, penalties, and interest under the laws of Florida accrued against any such person selling or transferring his or her business on the date of such sale or transfer, but only to the extent of the value of the property and business thereby acquired from such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed as releasing the person so transferring or discontinuing his or her business from liability for any fuel taxes or for any interest or penalty due under the fuel tax laws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event any dealer is delinquent in the payment of the tax herein provided for, the department may give notice of the amount of such delinquency by registered mail to all persons having in their possession or under their control any credits or other personal property belonging to such dealer or owing any debts to such dealer at the time of receipt by them of such notice. All persons so notified shall within 5 days after receipt of the notice advise the department of all such credits, other personal property, or debts in their possession, under their control, or owing by them. After receiving the notice, the persons so notified shall neither transfer nor make any other disposition of the credits, other personal property, or debts in their possession or under their control at the time they receive the notice until the department consents to a transfer or disposition or until 60 days elapse after the receipt of the notice, whichever period expires earlier, except that the credits, other personal property, or debts which exceed the delinquent amount stipulated in the notice shall not be subject to the provisions of this section, wherever held, in any case in which such dealer does not have a prior history of tax delinquencies. All persons notified shall likewise within 5 days advise the department of any subsequent credits or other personal property belonging to such dealer or any debts incurred and owing to such dealer which may come within their possession or under their control during the time prescribed by the notice or until the department consents to a transfer or disposition, whichever expires earlier. If such notice seeks to prevent transfer or other disposition of a deposit in a bank or other credits or personal property in the possession or under the control of a bank, the notice to be effective shall be delivered or mailed to the office of such bank, at which such deposit is carried or at which such credits or personal property is held. If, during the effective period of the notice to withhold, any person so notified makes any transfer or disposition of the property or debts required to be withheld hereunder, he or she shall be liable to the state for any indebtedness due under this chapter from the person with respect to whose obligation the notice was given to the extent of the value of the property or the amount of the debts thus transferred or paid if, solely by reason of such transfer or disposition, the state is unable to recover the indebtedness of the person with respect to whose obligation the notice was given. All such credits or other personal property or debts are subject to garnishment by the department for satisfaction of the delinquent tax due.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of the provisions of this section is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 16082, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 1167(72), 7794(8); s. 7, ch. 63-253; s. 5, ch. 65-371; s. 2, ch. 65-420; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 95, ch. 85-342; s. 73, ch. 87-6; s. 44, ch. 87-101; s. 50, ch. 87-224; s. 1066, ch. 95-147; s. 28, ch. 95-417.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 207.22.</Text></Note></Section>