<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transportation of motor fuel over public highways.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person hauling, transporting, or conveying motor fuel over any of the public highways of this state must, during the entire time he or she is so engaged, have in his or her possession an invoice or delivery ticket, bill of sale, or other record evidence showing the true name and address of the person from whom he or she has received the motor fuel, the number of gallons so originally received by him or her from said person, the true name and address, including state of destination, of every person to whom he or she has made deliveries of said motor fuel, and the number of gallons so delivered to each of said persons, and the destination address of the undelivered gallons. The person hauling, transporting, or conveying such motor fuel shall, at the request of any person required by law to inquire into or investigate said matters, produce and offer for inspection said invoice or delivery ticket, bill of sale, or record evidence. If the person fails to produce the invoice or delivery ticket, bill of sale, or record evidence, or if, when produced, it fails clearly to disclose said information, the same shall be prima facie evidence of a violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person engaged in the business activity of transporting fuel over public highways as a private or common carrier or for his or her own account shall maintain records disclosing all receipts and deliveries of fuel products enumerated in subsection (1). Records shall include terminal location or receiving point of origin, federal employer identification numbers of the fuel owner, the shipper and the consignee, the volume and type of fuel transported, the complete address of delivery destination, the date and time of pickup and delivery and, for all imports of untaxed fuel, the import authorization number required by this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not apply to vehicles transporting motor fuel not in excess of 200 gallons contained in the fuel tank of such vehicle provided for the carrying of motor fuel for propelling same, which motor fuel is to be used solely for the motive power of such vehicle, to vehicles transporting motor fuel in quantities of not more than 5 gallons for emergency purposes, or to motor fuel being transported by common carrier in railroad cars.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as authorized by this chapter, it is unlawful for any person to transport or cause to be transported any taxable motor or diesel fuels, other than through bulk transfer, within this state, upon which the tax imposed by this part has not been paid, including all fuels removed from bulk storage through a loading rack.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may authorize a licensed importer to transport untaxed fuel if all credit requirements set forth in s. 206.051 have been met.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation of fuel by common carrier from a point outside the state to a destination outside the state in interstate or foreign commerce shall not constitute a violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates this section commits a first degree misdemeanor, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083; and, in addition, the department may revoke or cancel the license of such person.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 16082, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 1167(74), 7794(9); s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 1067, ch. 95-147; s. 30, ch. 95-417.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 207.24.</Text></Note></Section>