<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0206.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Aviation gasoline exempt from excise tax; rocket fuel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each and every dealer in aviation gasoline in the state by whatever name designated who purchases from any terminal supplier, importer, or wholesaler, and sells, aviation gasoline (A.S.T.M. specification D-910 or current specification), of such quality not adapted for use in ordinary motor vehicles, being designed for and sold and exclusively used for aircraft, is exempted from the payment of taxes levied under this part, but is subject to the tax levied under part III.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A terminal supplier or wholesaler may be entitled to a refund of taxes paid under this chapter on all gallons of aviation motor fuel sold to aviation dealers monthly. A terminal supplier or wholesaler may instead of refund take credit for taxes paid on his or her monthly returns.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All sales of aviation motor fuel must be in compliance with the requirements of parts I, II, and III of this chapter and chapter 212 to qualify for the exemption.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fuels of such quality not adapted for use in ordinary motor vehicles, being produced for and sold and exclusively used for space flight as defined in s. 212.02 are not subject to the tax pursuant to this part, parts II and III, and chapter 212.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 16789, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 1167(102); s. 1, ch. 70-995; s. 13, ch. 83-3; s. 4, ch. 83-137; s. 103, ch. 85-342; s. 1, ch. 85-348; ss. 25, 61, ch. 89-300; s. 8, ch. 90-192; s. 1076, ch. 95-147; s. 43, ch. 95-417.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 208.05.</Text></Note></Section>