<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.307" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Water Quality Assurance Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Water Quality Assurance Trust Fund is intended to serve as a broad-based fund for use in responding to incidents of contamination that pose a serious danger to the quality of groundwater and surface water resources or otherwise pose a serious danger to the public health, safety, or welfare. Moneys in this fund may be used:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To carry out the provisions of ss. 376.30-376.317, relating to assessment, cleanup, restoration, monitoring, and maintenance of any site involving spills, discharges, or escapes of pollutants or hazardous substances which occur as a result of procedures taken by private and governmental entities involving the storage, transportation, and disposal of such products.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To carry out the provisions of s. 376.3078, relating to assessment, cleanup, restoration, monitoring, and maintenance of sites involving drycleaning products.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For activities to expeditiously restore or replace potable water supplies as provided in s. 376.30(3)(c)1.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For response actions under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To restore or replace contaminated private potable water wells or water systems. However, funds used as provided in this paragraph must be expended for water supply systems or filters for contaminated potable water wells only as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who have contaminated potable water wells that were permitted and constructed after January 1, 1989, in accordance with standards adopted under s. 373.309 are eligible for:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsidies to connect to existing water supply systems or extensions thereof. However, the subsidy may not exceed the present worth of the 10-year cost of providing and maintaining filters for residents served by the connections; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filters and filter maintenance to provide treatment for water from contaminated wells sufficient to ensure its potability. However, a filter may not be provided for a potable water well designed to provide water to a household that is part of a subdivision or development of a size that would, according to the department, be more effectively served by a water supply system, if the subdivision or development received its development order after January 1, 1989.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsidies to develop new water supply systems to be permitted and constructed after January 1, 1989, in accordance with standards adopted pursuant to s. 373.309 because of actual or potential contamination of potable water wells. However, a subsidy may not exceed one-half of the present worth of the 10-year cost of providing and maintaining filters for the residents to be served by the system.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The most cost-effective remedy, as determined by the department, for wells drilled before January 1, 1989.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons permitting and constructing potable water wells on or after July 1, 1997, in accordance with standards adopted pursuant to s. 373.309 because of actual or potential contamination, may be eligible for:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsidies or filters as identified in sub-subparagraphs 1.a. and b.; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsidies for any increased costs associated with potable water well construction pursuant to s. 373.309(1)(e)4., provided that no such subsidy shall exceed one-half the cost of the well including testing, or one-half the present worth of the 10-year cost of providing and maintaining filters for the residents to be served by said well, whichever is less, provided that the household is not part of a subdivision or development of a size that would, according to the department, be more effectively served by a water supply system, if such subdivision or development received its development order on or after July 1, 1997.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For activities by the department to administer brownfield sites.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the fund may not be expended for sites eligible for funding under ss. 376.3071 and 376.3073, relating to the Inland Protection Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the fund may not be expended to clean up hazardous waste that a federal agency is removing from navigable waters in accordance with the National Oil and Hazardous Substances Pollution Contingency Plan, established pursuant to the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, Pub. L. No. 92-500, as amended, or that the department is removing from any coastal waters, estuaries, tidal flats, beaches, or lands adjoining the coastline of the state pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trust fund shall be funded as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual transfer of interest funds from the Florida Coastal Protection Trust Fund pursuant to s. 376.11(4)(f).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All excise taxes levied, collected, and credited to the Water Quality Assurance Trust Fund in accordance with the provisions of ss. 206.9935(2) and 206.9945(1)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All penalties, judgments, recoveries, reimbursements, and other fees and charges related to the enforcement of ss. 376.30-376.317, other than penalties, judgments, and other fees and charges related to the enforcement of ss. 376.3071 and 376.3073.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee on the retail sale of lead-acid batteries credited to the Water Quality Assurance Trust Fund under s. 403.7185.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All penalties, judgments, recoveries, reimbursements, loans, and other fees and charges collected under s. 376.3078; tax revenues levied, collected, and credited under ss. 376.70 and 376.75; and registration fees collected under s. 376.303(1)(d).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law, the department shall recover to the use of the fund from a person or persons at any time causing or having caused the discharge or from the Federal Government, jointly and severally, all sums owed or expended from the fund, pursuant to s. 376.308, except that the department may decline to pursue such recovery if it finds the amount involved too small or the likelihood of recovery too uncertain. Sums recovered as a result of damage due to discharge of a pollutant or other similar disaster shall be apportioned between the fund and the General Revenue Fund so as to repay the full costs to the General Revenue Fund of any sums disbursed therefrom as a result of such disaster. Any request for reimbursement to the fund for such costs, if not paid within 30 days of demand, shall be turned over to the department for collection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the fund which are not needed currently to meet the obligations of the department in the exercise of its responsibilities under this section shall be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the fund and may be invested in such manner as is provided for by statute. The interest received on such investment shall be credited to the fund. Any provisions of law to the contrary notwithstanding, such interest may be freely transferred between this trust fund and the Inland Protection Trust Fund, in the discretion of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law, the department, in administering the fund, shall diligently pursue the reimbursement to the fund of any sum expended from the fund in accordance with this section for cleanup and abatement, unless the department finds the amount involved too small or the likelihood of recovery too uncertain. For the purposes of s. 95.11, the limitation period within which to institute an action to recover such sums commences on the last date on which any such sums were expended, and not the date that the discharge occurred.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 84, ch. 83-310; s. 3, ch. 83-353; s. 10, ch. 84-338; ss. 3, 14, 34, ch. 86-159; s. 82, ch. 86-163; s. 4, ch. 88-393; s. 9, ch. 89-171; s. 72, ch. 90-331; s. 14, ch. 91-305; s. 5, ch. 92-75; s. 300, ch. 94-356; s. 48, ch. 96-321; s. 31, ch. 97-160; s. 391, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2005-57; s. 61, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>