<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.30716" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cleanup of certain sites.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exclusion zone” means the subsurface area within 10 feet of an underground storage tank, integral piping, and dispenser, and the area between the underground storage tank and dispenser.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Subsequently discovered discharge” means a discharge or suspected discharge that is discovered on or after July 1, 2005, at a site eligible for state funding under s. 376.305, s. 376.3071, or s. 376.3072.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As noted in s. 376.30714, it may be difficult to distinguish between a discharge of petroleum products from a petroleum storage system which is eligible for state funding and a discharge reported after December 31, 1998, which is not eligible for state funding. Until the secondary containment upgrade of underground storage tanks, as required under rule 62-761, Florida Administrative Code, is complete at a site, a subsequently discovered discharge at the site is presumed to be part of the original discharge that qualifies for state funding. However, this presumption does not apply:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department presents competent and substantial evidence demonstrating that the subsequently discovered discharge occurred from a source that is independent and separate from the discharge that qualifies for state funding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a site where petroleum storage systems have been upgraded, prior to July 1, 2005, to secondary containment in accordance with rule 62-761, Florida Administrative Code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a site having newly discovered free product outside the exclusion zone.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a site having an increase in the concentration of existing petroleum contamination outside the exclusion zone of 1,000 percent or greater.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a site for which the department has, by a current valid order, determined that the discharge that is eligible for state funding has been cleaned up or no further action is necessary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 376.30714 does not apply to a subsequently discovered discharge. The department shall not, as part of a closure report or assessment for a site that is eligible for state funding under s. 376.305, s. 376.3071, or s. 376.3072, require soil or groundwater sampling.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regardless of whether the presumption specified in subsection (2) applies, a facility owner or operator shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report all incidents or discharges in accordance with rules of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to the department a copy of all test results of storage tank and piping tightness regardless of the results.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2006-104.</History></Section>