<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.75" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax on production or importation of perchloroethylene.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning October 1, 1994, a tax of $5 per gallon is levied on the sale of perchloroethylene (tetrachloroethylene) in this state to a drycleaning facility located in this state or the import of perchloroethylene into this state by a drycleaning facility. This tax is not subject to sales and use tax pursuant to chapter 212.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person producing in, importing into, or causing to be imported into, or selling in, this state perchloroethylene must register with the Department of Revenue and become licensed for the purposes of remitting the tax pursuant to, or providing information required by, this section. Such person must register as a seller of perchloroethylene, a user of perchloroethylene in drycleaning facilities, or a user of perchloroethylene for purposes other than drycleaning. Persons operating at more than one location are only required to have a single registration. The fee for registration is $30. Failure to timely register is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax imposed by this section is due on the 1st day of the month succeeding the month of the sale and must be paid on or before the 20th day of each month. Tax shall be reported on forms and in the manner prescribed by the Department of Revenue by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person subject to taxation under this section or any person who sells tax-paid perchloroethylene, other than a retail dealer, must separately state the amount of such tax paid on any charge ticket, sales slip, invoice, or other tangible evidence of the sale or must certify on the sales document that the tax required pursuant to this section has been paid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All perchloroethylene imported, produced, or sold in this state is presumed to be subject to the tax imposed by this section. Any person who has purchased perchloroethylene for use in such person’s drycleaning facility in this state must document that the tax imposed by this section has been paid or must pay such tax directly to the Department of Revenue in accordance with subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, to demonstrate that perchloroethylene is not sold or transferred to a drycleaning facility for eventual use in a drycleaning facility in this state, a person may rely on a certificate signed under penalty of perjury by a transferee of the perchloroethylene stating that the transferee does not own or operate a drycleaning facility or the transferee will not use the perchloroethylene in a drycleaning facility in this state. Any producer, importer, seller, or other transferor of perchloroethylene who is required to register in accordance with subsection (2) but who does not make any taxable sales or taxable transfers during a year shall file with the Department of Revenue a form containing the quantity of perchloroethylene sold or transferred, a statement indicating that all sales were exempt from tax, and such other information as the Department of Revenue may prescribe.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue may authorize a quarterly return and payment when the tax remitted by the licensee for the preceding quarter did not exceed $100; may authorize a semiannual return and payment when the tax remitted by the licensee for the preceding 6 months did not exceed $200; and may authorize an annual return and payment when the tax remitted by the licensee for the preceding 12 months did not exceed $400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax imposed by this section shall be reported to the Department of Revenue. The payment shall be accompanied by such forms as the Department of Revenue prescribes. The proceeds of the tax, after deducting the administrative costs incurred by the Department of Revenue in administering, auditing, collecting, distributing, and enforcing the tax, shall be transferred by the Department of Revenue into the Water Quality Assurance Trust Fund and shall be used as provided in s. 376.3078. For the purposes of this section, the proceeds of the tax include all funds collected and received by the Department of Revenue, including interest and penalties on delinquent taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall administer, collect, and enforce the tax authorized under this section pursuant to the same procedures used in the administration, collection, and enforcement of the general state sales tax imposed under chapter 212, except as provided in this section. The provisions of chapter 212 regarding the authority to audit and make assessments, the keeping of books and records, and interest and penalties on delinquent taxes shall apply. The tax shall not be included in the computation of estimated taxes pursuant to s. 212.11, nor shall the dealer’s credit for collecting taxes or fees in s. 212.12 apply to the tax. The provisions of s. 212.07(4) shall not apply to the tax imposed by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue, under the applicable rules of the Public Employees Relations Commission, is authorized to employ persons and incur other expenses for which funds are appropriated by the Legislature. The Department of Revenue is empowered to adopt such rules and shall prescribe and publish such forms as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue is authorized to establish audit procedures and to assess delinquent taxes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature declares that the failure to promptly implement the provisions of this section would present an immediate threat to the welfare of the state. Therefore, the executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized to adopt emergency rules pursuant to s. 120.54(4) to implement this section. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain effective for 180 days from the date of adoption. Other rules of the Department of Revenue related to and in furtherance of the orderly implementation of this section shall not be subject to a s. 120.56(2) rule challenge or a s. 120.54(3)(c)2. drawout proceeding, but, once adopted, shall be subject to a s. 120.56(3) invalidity challenge. Such rules shall be adopted by the Governor and Cabinet and shall become effective upon filing with the Department of State, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 120.54(3)(e)6.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If perchloroethylene on which tax has been paid is exported from this state or acquired for purposes other than use in a drycleaning facility in this state or for sale, resale, or other transfer for such use, the person who paid the tax to the Department of Revenue may apply for a refund or take a credit of such tax paid. The person applying for the refund or credit must refund such tax to the person who incurred the burden of the tax before the claim to the state for refund or credit will be approved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any drycleaning facility which includes in the total retail charge to a consumer of drycleaning services any portion of the tax imposed pursuant to this section shall disclose on the receipt for the amount charged for such services the amount of such tax and a statement that the imposition of the tax was requested by the Florida Dry Cleaners Coalition.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 94-355; s. 9, ch. 95-239; s. 53, ch. 96-321; s. 109, ch. 96-410; s. 34, ch. 97-99; s. 14, ch. 98-189.</History></Section>