<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.3071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inland Protection Trust Fund; creation; purposes; funding.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FINDINGS.<EmDash />In addition to the legislative findings set forth in s. 376.30, the Legislature finds and declares:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That significant quantities of petroleum and petroleum products are being stored in storage systems in this state, which is a hazardous undertaking.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That spills, leaks, and other discharges from such storage systems have occurred, are occurring, and will continue to occur and that such discharges pose a significant threat to the quality of the groundwaters and inland surface waters of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, where contamination of the ground or surface water has occurred, remedial measures have often been delayed for long periods while determinations as to liability and the extent of liability are made and that such delays result in the continuation and intensification of the threat to the public health, safety, and welfare; in greater damage to the environment; and in significantly higher costs to contain and remove the contamination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That adequate financial resources must be readily available to provide for the expeditious supply of safe and reliable alternative sources of potable water to affected persons and to provide a means for investigation and cleanup of contamination sites without delay.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it is necessary to fulfill the intent and purposes of ss. 376.30-376.317, and further it is hereby determined to be in the best interest of, and necessary for the protection of the public health, safety, and general welfare of the residents of this state, and therefore a paramount public purpose, to provide for the creation of a nonprofit public benefit corporation as an instrumentality of the state to assist in financing the functions provided in ss. 376.30-376.317 and to authorize the department to enter into one or more service contracts with such corporation for the provision of financing services related to such functions and to make payments thereunder from the amount on deposit in the Inland Protection Trust Fund, subject to annual appropriation by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That to achieve the purposes established in paragraph (e) and in order to facilitate the expeditious handling and rehabilitation of contamination sites and remedial measures with respect to contamination sites provided hereby without delay, it is in the best interests of the residents of this state to authorize such corporation to issue evidences of indebtedness payable from amounts paid by the department under any such service contract entered into between the department and such corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTENT AND PURPOSE.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to establish the Inland Protection Trust Fund to serve as a repository for funds which will enable the department to respond without delay to incidents of inland contamination related to the storage of petroleum and petroleum products in order to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and to minimize environmental damage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the department implement rules and procedures to improve the efficiency of the Petroleum Restoration Program. The department is directed to implement rules and policies to eliminate and reduce duplication of site rehabilitation efforts, paperwork, and documentation, and micromanagement of site rehabilitation tasks.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is directed to adopt and implement uniform and standardized forms for the requests for preapproval site rehabilitation work and for the submittal of reports to ensure that information is submitted to the department in a concise, standardized uniform format seeking only information that is necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is directed to implement computerized and electronic filing capabilities of preapproval requests and submittal of reports in order to expedite submittal of the information and elimination of delay in paperwork. The computerized, electronic filing system shall be implemented no later than January 1, 1997.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is directed to adopt uniform scopes of work with templated labor and equipment costs to provide definitive guidance as to the type of work and authorized expenditures that will be allowed for preapproved site rehabilitation tasks.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is directed to establish guidelines for consideration and acceptance of new and innovative technologies for site rehabilitation work.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREATION.<EmDash />There is hereby created the Inland Protection Trust Fund, hereinafter referred to as the “fund,” to be administered by the department. This fund shall be used by the department as a nonlapsing revolving fund for carrying out the purposes of this section and s. 376.3073. To this fund shall be credited all penalties, judgments, recoveries, reimbursements, loans, and other fees and charges related to the implementation of this section and s. 376.3073 and the excise tax revenues levied, collected, and credited pursuant to ss. 206.9935(3) and 206.9945(1)(c). Charges against the fund shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USES.<EmDash />Whenever, in its determination, incidents of inland contamination related to the storage of petroleum or petroleum products may pose a threat to the environment or the public health, safety, or welfare, the department shall obligate moneys available in the fund to provide for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prompt investigation and assessment of contamination sites.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expeditious restoration or replacement of potable water supplies as provided in s. 376.30(3)(c)1.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rehabilitation of contamination sites, which shall consist of cleanup of affected soil, groundwater, and inland surface waters, using the most cost-effective alternative that is technologically feasible and reliable and that provides adequate protection of the public health, safety, and welfare and minimizes environmental damage, in accordance with the site selection and cleanup criteria established by the department under subsection (5), except that nothing herein shall be construed to authorize the department to obligate funds for payment of costs which may be associated with, but are not integral to, site rehabilitation, such as the cost for retrofitting or replacing petroleum storage systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance and monitoring of contamination sites.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspection and supervision of activities described in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of expenses incurred by the department in its efforts to obtain from responsible parties the payment or recovery of reasonable costs resulting from the activities described in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of any other reasonable costs of administration, including those administrative costs incurred by the Department of Health in providing field and laboratory services, toxicological risk assessment, and other assistance to the department in the investigation of drinking water contamination complaints and costs associated with public information and education activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment and implementation of the compliance verification program as authorized in s. 376.303(1)(a), including contracting with local governments or state agencies to provide for the administration of such program through locally administered programs, to minimize the potential for further contamination sites.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding of the provisions of ss. 376.305(6) and 376.3072.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Activities related to removal and replacement of petroleum storage systems, exclusive of costs of any tank, piping, dispensing unit, or related hardware, if soil removal is preapproved as a component of site rehabilitation and requires removal of the tank where remediation is conducted under s. 376.30711 or if such activities were justified in an approved remedial action plan performed pursuant to subsection (12).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Activities related to reimbursement application preparation and activities related to reimbursement application examination by a certified public accountant pursuant to subsection (12).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable costs of restoring property as nearly as practicable to the conditions which existed prior to activities associated with contamination assessment or remedial action taken under s. 376.303(4).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repayment of loans to the fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenditure of sums from the fund to cover ineligible sites or costs as set forth in subsection (13), if the department in its discretion deems it necessary to do so. In such cases, the department may seek recovery and reimbursement of costs in the same manner and in accordance with the same procedures as are established for recovery and reimbursement of sums otherwise owed to or expended from the fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of amounts payable under any service contract entered into by the department pursuant to s. 376.3075, subject to annual appropriation by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petroleum remediation pursuant to s. 376.30711 throughout a state fiscal year. The department shall establish a process to uniformly encumber appropriated funds throughout a state fiscal year and shall allow for emergencies and imminent threats to human health and the environment as provided in paragraph (5)(a). This paragraph does not apply to appropriations associated with the free product recovery initiative of paragraph (5)(c) or the preapproved advanced cleanup program of s. 376.30713.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcement of this section and ss. 376.30-376.317 by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission. The department shall disburse moneys to the commission for such purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Inland Protection Trust Fund may only be used to fund the activities in ss. 376.30-376.317 except ss. 376.3078 and 376.3079. Amounts on deposit in the Inland Protection Trust Fund in each fiscal year shall first be applied or allocated for the payment of amounts payable by the department pursuant to paragraph (o) under a service contract entered into by the department pursuant to s. 376.3075 and appropriated in each year by the Legislature prior to making or providing for other disbursements from the fund. Nothing in this subsection shall authorize the use of the Inland Protection Trust Fund for cleanup of contamination caused primarily by a discharge of solvents as defined in s. 206.9925(6), or polychlorinated biphenyls when their presence causes them to be hazardous wastes, except solvent contamination which is the result of chemical or physical breakdown of petroleum products and is otherwise eligible. Facilities used primarily for the storage of motor or diesel fuels as defined in ss. 206.01 and 206.86 shall be presumed not to be excluded from eligibility pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SITE SELECTION AND CLEANUP CRITERIA.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules to establish priorities based upon a scoring system for state-conducted cleanup at petroleum contamination sites based upon factors that include, but need not be limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The degree to which human health, safety, or welfare may be affected by exposure to the contamination;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The size of the population or area affected by the contamination;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The present and future uses of the affected aquifer or surface waters, with particular consideration as to the probability that the contamination is substantially affecting, or will migrate to and substantially affect, a known public or private source of potable water; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect of the contamination on the environment.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Moneys in the fund shall then be obligated for activities described in paragraphs (4)(a)-(e) at individual sites in accordance with such established criteria. However, nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to restrict the department from modifying the priority status of a rehabilitation site where conditions warrant, taking into consideration the actual distance between the contamination site and groundwater or surface water receptors or other factors that affect the risk of exposure to petroleum products’ chemicals of concern. The department may use the effective date of a department final order granting eligibility pursuant to subsections (9) and (13) and ss. 376.305(6) and 376.3072 to establish a prioritization system within a particular priority scoring range.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to protect the health of all people under actual circumstances of exposure. The secretary shall establish criteria by rule for the purpose of determining, on a site-specific basis, the rehabilitation program tasks that comprise a site rehabilitation program and the level at which a rehabilitation program task and a site rehabilitation program may be deemed completed. In establishing the rule, the department shall incorporate, to the maximum extent feasible, risk-based corrective action principles to achieve protection of human health and safety and the environment in a cost-effective manner as provided in this subsection. Criteria for determining what constitutes a rehabilitation program task or completion of site rehabilitation program tasks and site rehabilitation programs shall be based upon the factors set forth in paragraph (a) and the following additional factors:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The current exposure and potential risk of exposure to humans and the environment including multiple pathways of exposure.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate point of compliance with cleanup target levels for petroleum products’ chemicals of concern. The point of compliance shall be at the source of the petroleum contamination. However, the department is authorized to temporarily move the point of compliance to the boundary of the property, or to the edge of the plume when the plume is within the property boundary, while cleanup, including cleanup through natural attenuation processes in conjunction with appropriate monitoring, is proceeding. The department also is authorized, pursuant to criteria provided for in this paragraph, to temporarily extend the point of compliance beyond the property boundary with appropriate monitoring, if such extension is needed to facilitate natural attenuation or to address the current conditions of the plume, provided human health, public safety, and the environment are adequately protected. Temporary extension of the point of compliance beyond the property boundary, as provided in this subparagraph, shall include notice to local governments and owners of any property into which the point of compliance is allowed to extend.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate site-specific cleanup goal. The site-specific cleanup goal shall be that all petroleum contamination sites ultimately achieve the applicable cleanup target levels provided in this paragraph. However, the department is authorized to allow concentrations of the petroleum products’ chemicals of concern to temporarily exceed the applicable cleanup target levels while cleanup, including cleanup through natural attenuation processes in conjunction with appropriate monitoring, is proceeding, provided human health, public safety, and the environment are adequately protected.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriateness of using institutional or engineering controls. Site rehabilitation programs may include the use of institutional or engineering controls to eliminate the potential exposure to petroleum products’ chemicals of concern to humans or the environment. Use of such controls must be preapproved by the department, and institutional controls shall not be acquired with funds from the Inland Protection Trust Fund. When institutional or engineering controls are implemented to control exposure, the removal of such controls must have prior department approval and must be accompanied immediately by the resumption of active cleanup, or other approved controls, unless cleanup target levels pursuant to this paragraph have been achieved.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The additive effects of the petroleum products’ chemicals of concern. The synergistic effects of petroleum products’ chemicals of concern shall also be considered when the scientific data becomes available.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual site characteristics which shall include, but not be limited to, the current and projected use of the affected groundwater in the vicinity of the site, current and projected land uses of the area affected by the contamination, the exposed population, the degree and extent of contamination, the rate of contaminant migration, the apparent or potential rate of contaminant degradation through natural attenuation processes, the location of the plume, and the potential for further migration in relation to site property boundaries.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicable state water quality standards.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cleanup target levels for petroleum products’ chemicals of concern found in groundwater shall be the applicable state water quality standards. Where such standards do not exist, the cleanup target levels for groundwater shall be based on the minimum criteria specified in department rule. The department shall consider the following, as appropriate, in establishing the applicable minimum criteria: calculations using a lifetime cancer risk level of 1.0E-6; a hazard index of 1 or less; the best achievable detection limit; the naturally occurring background concentration; or nuisance, organoleptic, and aesthetic considerations.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where surface waters are exposed to petroleum contaminated groundwater, the cleanup target levels for the petroleum products’ chemicals of concern shall be based on the surface water standards as established by department rule. The point of measuring compliance with the surface water standards shall be in the groundwater immediately adjacent to the surface water body.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether deviation from state water quality standards or from established criteria is appropriate. The department may issue a “No Further Action Order” based upon the degree to which the desired cleanup target level is achievable and can be reasonably and cost-effectively implemented within available technologies or engineering and institutional control strategies. Where a state water quality standard is applicable, a deviation may not result in the application of cleanup target levels more stringent than said standard. In determining whether it is appropriate to establish alternate cleanup target levels at a site, the department may consider the effectiveness of source removal that has been completed at the site and the practical likelihood of: the use of low yield or poor quality groundwater; the use of groundwater near marine surface water bodies; the current and projected use of the affected groundwater in the vicinity of the site; or the use of groundwater in the immediate vicinity of the storage tank area, where it has been demonstrated that the groundwater contamination is not migrating away from such localized source; provided human health, public safety, and the environment are adequately protected.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate cleanup target levels for soils.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In establishing soil cleanup target levels for human exposure to petroleum products’ chemicals of concern found in soils from the land surface to 2 feet below land surface, the department shall consider the following, as appropriate: calculations using a lifetime cancer risk level of 1.0E-6; a hazard index of 1 or less; the best achievable detection limit; or the naturally occurring background concentration.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leachability-based soil target levels shall be based on protection of the groundwater cleanup target levels or the alternate cleanup target levels for groundwater established pursuant to this paragraph, as appropriate. Source removal and other cost-effective alternatives that are technologically feasible shall be considered in achieving the leachability soil target levels established by the department. The leachability goals shall not be applicable if the department determines, based upon individual site characteristics, that petroleum products’ chemicals of concern will not leach into the groundwater at levels which pose a threat to human health and safety or the environment.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to restrict the department from temporarily postponing completion of any site rehabilitation program for which funds are being expended whenever such postponement is deemed necessary in order to make funds available for rehabilitation of a contamination site with a higher priority status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require source removal, if warranted and cost-effective, at each site eligible for restoration funding from the Inland Protection Trust Fund.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for free product recovery may be provided in advance of the order established by the priority ranking system under paragraph (a) for site cleanup activities. However, a separate prioritization for free product recovery shall be established consistent with paragraph (a). No more than $5 million shall be encumbered from the Inland Protection Trust Fund in any fiscal year for free product recovery conducted in advance of the priority order under paragraph (a) established for site cleanup activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once free product removal and other source removal identified in this paragraph are completed at a site, and notwithstanding the order established by the priority ranking system under paragraph (a) for site cleanup activities, the department may reevaluate the site to determine the degree of active cleanup needed to continue site rehabilitation. Further, the department shall determine if the reevaluated site qualifies for natural attenuation monitoring, long-term natural attenuation monitoring, or no further action. If additional site rehabilitation is necessary to reach no further action status, the site rehabilitation shall be conducted in the order established by the priority ranking system under paragraph (a). The department shall utilize natural attenuation monitoring strategies and, when cost-effective, transition sites eligible for restoration funding assistance to long-term natural attenuation monitoring where the plume is shrinking or stable and confined to the source property boundaries and the petroleum products’ chemicals of concern meet the natural attenuation default concentrations, as defined by department rule. If the plume migrates beyond the source property boundaries, natural attenuation monitoring may be conducted in accordance with department rule, or if the site no longer qualifies for natural attenuation monitoring, active remediation may be resumed. For long-term natural attenuation monitoring, if the petroleum products’ chemicals of concern increase or are not significantly reduced after 42 months of monitoring, or if the plume migrates beyond the property boundaries, active remediation shall be resumed as necessary. For sites undergoing active remediation, the department shall template the cost of natural attenuation monitoring pursuant to s. 376.30711 to ensure that site mobilizations are performed in a cost-effective manner. Sites that are not eligible for state restoration funding may transition to long-term natural attenuation monitoring using the criteria in this subparagraph. Nothing in this subparagraph precludes a site from pursuing a “No Further Action” order with conditions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall evaluate whether higher natural attenuation default concentrations for natural attenuation monitoring or long-term natural attenuation monitoring are cost-effective and would adequately protect public health and the environment. The department shall also evaluate site-specific characteristics that would allow for higher natural attenuation or long-term natural attenuation concentration levels.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government may not deny a building permit based solely on the presence of petroleum contamination for any construction, repairs, or renovations performed in conjunction with tank upgrade activities to an existing retail fuel facility if the facility was fully operational before the building permit was requested and if the construction, repair, or renovation is performed by a licensed contractor. All building permits and any construction, repairs, or renovations performed in conjunction with such permits must comply with the applicable provisions of chapters 489 and 553.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNDING.<EmDash />The Inland Protection Trust Fund shall be funded as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All excise taxes levied, collected, and credited to the fund in accordance with the provisions of ss. 206.9935(3) and 206.9945(1)(c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All penalties, judgments, recoveries, reimbursements, and other fees and charges credited to the fund in accordance with the provisions of subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENTAL DUTY TO SEEK RECOVERY AND REIMBURSEMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (9) and as otherwise provided by law, the department shall recover to the use of the fund from a person or persons at any time causing or having caused the discharge or from the Federal Government, jointly and severally, all sums owed or expended from the fund, pursuant to s. 376.308, except that the department may decline to pursue such recovery if it finds the amount involved too small or the likelihood of recovery too uncertain. Sums recovered as a result of damage due to a discharge related to the storage of petroleum or petroleum products or other similar disaster shall be apportioned between the fund and the General Revenue Fund so as to repay the full costs to the General Revenue Fund of any sums disbursed therefrom as a result of such disaster. Any request for reimbursement to the fund for such costs, if not paid within 30 days of demand, shall be turned over to the department for collection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (9) and as otherwise provided by law, it is the duty of the department in administering the fund diligently to pursue the reimbursement to the fund of any sum expended from the fund for cleanup and abatement in accordance with the provisions of this section or s. 376.3073, unless the department finds the amount involved too small or the likelihood of recovery too uncertain. For the purposes of s. 95.11, the limitation period within which to institute an action to recover such sums shall commence on the last date on which any such sums were expended, and not the date that the discharge occurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department initiates an enforcement action to clean up a contaminated site and determines that the responsible party is financially unable to undertake complete restoration of the contaminated site, that the current property owner was not responsible for the discharge when the contamination first occurred, or that the state’s interest can best be served by conducting cleanup, the department may enter into an agreement with the responsible party or property owner whereby the department agrees to conduct site rehabilitation and the responsible party or property owner agrees to pay for the portion of the cleanup costs that are within such party’s or owner’s financial capabilities as determined by the department, taking into consideration the party’s net worth and the economic impact on the party.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENTS; INTEREST.<EmDash />Moneys in the fund which are not needed currently to meet the obligations of the department in the exercise of its responsibilities under this section and s. 376.3073 shall be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the fund and may be invested in such manner as is provided for by statute. The interest received on such investment shall be credited to the fund. Any provisions of law to the contrary notwithstanding, such interest may be freely transferred between this trust fund and the Water Quality Assurance Trust Fund, in the discretion of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EARLY DETECTION INCENTIVE PROGRAM.<EmDash />To encourage early detection, reporting, and cleanup of contamination from leaking petroleum storage systems, the department shall, within the guidelines established in this subsection, conduct an incentive program which shall provide for a 30-month grace period ending on December 31, 1988. Pursuant thereto:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish reasonable requirements for the written reporting of petroleum contamination incidents and shall distribute forms to registrants under s. 376.303(1)(b) and to other interested parties upon request to be used for such purpose. Until such forms are available for distribution, the department shall take reports of such incidents, however made, but shall notify any person making such a report that a complete written report of the incident will be required by the department at a later time, the form for which will be provided by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When reporting forms become available for distribution, all sites involving incidents of contamination from petroleum storage systems initially reported to the department at any time from midnight on June 30, 1986, to midnight on December 31, 1988, shall be qualified sites, provided that such a complete written report is filed with respect thereto within a reasonable time. Subject to the delays which may occur as a result of the prioritization of sites under paragraph (5)(a) for any qualified site, costs for activities described in paragraphs (4)(a)-(e) shall be absorbed at the expense of the fund, without recourse to reimbursement or recovery, with the following exceptions:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any site where the department has been denied site access to implement the provisions of this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this subsection shall not be construed to authorize or require reimbursement from the fund for costs expended prior to the beginning of the grace period, except as provided in subsection (12).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon discovery by the department that the owner or operator of a petroleum storage system has been grossly negligent in the maintenance of such petroleum storage system; has, with willful intent to conceal the existence of a serious discharge, falsified inventory or reconciliation records maintained with respect to the site at which such system is located; or has intentionally damaged such petroleum storage system, the site at which such system is located shall be ineligible for participation in the incentive program and the owner shall be liable for all costs due to discharges from petroleum storage systems at that site, any other provisions of chapter 86-159, Laws of Florida, to the contrary notwithstanding. For the purposes of this paragraph, willful failure to maintain inventory and reconciliation records, willful failure to make monthly monitoring system checks where such systems are in place, and failure to meet monitoring and retrofitting requirements within the schedules established under chapter 62-761, Florida Administrative Code, or violation of similar rules adopted by the department under this chapter, shall be construed to be gross negligence in the maintenance of a petroleum storage system.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall redetermine the eligibility of petroleum storage systems for which a timely EDI application was filed, but which were deemed ineligible by the department, under the following conditions:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or operator, on or before March 31, 1991, shall submit, in writing, notification that the storage system is now in compliance with department rules adopted pursuant to s. 376.303, and which requests the department to reevaluate the storage system eligibility; and</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department verifies the storage system compliance based on a compliance inspection.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Provided, however, that a site may be determined eligible by the department for good cause shown, including, but not limited to, demonstration by the owner or operator that to achieve compliance would cause an increase in the potential for the spread of the contamination.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Redetermination of eligibility pursuant to sub-subparagraph b. shall not be available to:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petroleum storage systems owned or operated by the Federal Government.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities that denied site access to the department.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="III"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities where a discharge was intentionally concealed.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities that were denied eligibility due to:</Text><SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="A"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Absence of contamination, unless any such facility subsequently establishes that contamination did exist at that facility on or before December 31, 1988.</Text></SubSubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="B"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contamination from substances that were not petroleum or a petroleum product.</Text></SubSubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="C"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contamination that was not from a petroleum storage system.</Text></SubSubSubSubParagraph></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EDI applicants who demonstrate compliance for a site pursuant to sub-subparagraph b. are eligible for the Early Detection Incentive Program and site rehabilitation funding pursuant to subsection (5) and s. 376.30711.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If, in order to avoid prolonged delay, the department in its discretion deems it necessary to expend sums from the fund to cover ineligible sites or costs as set forth in this paragraph, the department may do so and seek recovery and reimbursement therefor in the same manner and in accordance with the same procedures as are established for recovery and reimbursement of sums otherwise owed to or expended from the fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No report of a discharge made to the department by any person in accordance with this subsection, or any rules promulgated pursuant hereto, shall be used directly as evidence of liability for such discharge in any civil or criminal trial arising out of the discharge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to petroleum storage systems owned or operated by the Federal Government.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VIOLATIONS; PENALTY.<EmDash />It is unlawful for any person to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Falsify inventory or reconciliation records maintained in compliance with chapters 62-761 and 62-762, Florida Administrative Code, with willful intent to conceal the existence of a serious leak; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally damage a petroleum storage system.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person convicted of such a violation shall be guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SITE CLEANUP.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Voluntary cleanup.</Font><EmDash />This section <Reference Number="1" />does not prohibit a person from conducting site rehabilitation either through his or her own personnel or through responsible response action contractors or subcontractors when such person is not seeking site rehabilitation funding from the fund. Such voluntary cleanups must meet all applicable environmental standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Low-scored site initiative.</Font><EmDash />Notwithstanding s. 376.30711, any site with a priority ranking score of 29 points or less may voluntarily participate in the low-scored site initiative, whether or not the site is eligible for state restoration funding.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To participate in the low-scored site initiative, the responsible party or property owner must affirmatively demonstrate that the following conditions are met:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon reassessment pursuant to department rule, the site retains a priority ranking score of 29 points or less.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No excessively contaminated soil, as defined by department rule, exists onsite as a result of a release of petroleum products.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minimum of 6 months of groundwater monitoring indicates that the plume is shrinking or stable.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The release of petroleum products at the site does not adversely affect adjacent surface waters, including their effects on human health and the environment.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The area of groundwater containing the petroleum products’ chemicals of concern is less than one-quarter acre and is confined to the source property boundaries of the real property on which the discharge originated.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soils onsite that are subject to human exposure found between land surface and 2 feet below land surface meet the soil cleanup target levels established by department rule or human exposure is limited by appropriate institutional or engineering controls.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon affirmative demonstration of the conditions under subparagraph 1., the department shall issue a determination of “No Further Action.” Such determination acknowledges that minimal contamination exists onsite and that such contamination is not a threat to human health or the environment. If no contamination is detected, the department may issue a site rehabilitation completion order.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sites that are eligible for state restoration funding may receive payment of preapproved costs for the low-scored site initiative as follows:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A responsible party or property owner may submit an assessment plan designed to affirmatively demonstrate that the site meets the conditions under subparagraph 1. Notwithstanding the priority ranking score of the site, the department may preapprove the cost of the assessment pursuant to s. 376.30711, including 6 months of groundwater monitoring, not to exceed $30,000 for each site. The department may not pay the costs associated with the establishment of institutional or engineering controls.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assessment work shall be completed no later than 6 months after the department issues its approval.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than $10 million for the low-scored site initiative may be encumbered from the Inland Protection Trust Fund in any fiscal year. Funds shall be made available on a first-come, first-served basis and shall be limited to 10 sites in each fiscal year for each responsible party or property owner.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program deductibles, copayments, and the limited contamination assessment report requirements under paragraph (13)(c) do not apply to expenditures under this paragraph.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REIMBURSEMENT FOR CLEANUP EXPENSES.<EmDash />Except as provided in s. 2(3), chapter 95-2, Laws of Florida, this subsection shall not apply to any site rehabilitation program task initiated after March 29, 1995. Effective August 1, 1996, no further site rehabilitation work on sites eligible for state-funded cleanup from the Inland Protection Trust Fund shall be eligible for reimbursement pursuant to this subsection. The person responsible for conducting site rehabilitation may seek reimbursement for site rehabilitation program task work conducted after March 28, 1995, in accordance with s. 2(2) and (3), chapter 95-2, Laws of Florida, regardless of whether the site rehabilitation program task is completed. A site rehabilitation program task shall be considered to be initiated when actual onsite work or engineering design, pursuant to chapter 62-770, Florida Administrative Code, which is integral to performing a site rehabilitation program task has begun and shall not include contract negotiation and execution, site research, or project planning. All reimbursement applications pursuant to this subsection must be submitted to the department by January 3, 1997. The department shall not accept any applications for reimbursement or pay any claims on applications for reimbursement received after that date; provided, however if an application filed on or prior to January 3, 1997, was returned by the department on the grounds of untimely filing, it shall be refiled within 30 days after the effective date of this act in order to be processed.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Legislative findings.</Font><EmDash />The Legislature finds and declares that rehabilitation of contamination sites should be conducted in a manner and to a level of completion which will protect the public health, safety, and welfare and will minimize damage to the environment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Conditions.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner, operator, or his or her designee of a site which is eligible for restoration funding assistance in the EDI, PLRIP, or ATRP programs shall be reimbursed from the Inland Protection Trust Fund of allowable costs at reasonable rates incurred on or after January 1, 1985, for completed program tasks as identified in the department rule promulgated pursuant to paragraph (5)(b), or uncompleted program tasks pursuant to chapter 95-2, Laws of Florida, subject to the conditions in this section. It is unlawful for a site owner or operator, or his or her designee, to receive any remuneration, in cash or in kind, directly or indirectly from the rehabilitation contractor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize reimbursement to any person for costs of contaminated soil treatment or disposal that does not meet the applicable rules of this state for such treatment or disposal, including all general permitting, state air emission standards, monitoring, sampling, and reporting rules more specifically described in department rules.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Legislative intent.</Font><EmDash />Due to the value of the potable water of this state, it is the intent of the Legislature that the department initiate and facilitate as many cleanups as possible utilizing the resources of the state, local governments, and the private sector, recognizing that source removal, wherever it is technologically feasible and cost-effective, shall be considered the primary initial response to protect public health, safety, and the environment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Amount of reimbursement.</Font><EmDash />The department shall reimburse actual and reasonable costs for site rehabilitation. The department shall not reimburse interest on the amount of reimbursable costs for any reimbursement application. However, nothing herein shall affect the department’s authority to pay interest authorized under prior law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Records.</Font><EmDash />The person responsible for conducting site rehabilitation, or his or her agent, shall keep and preserve suitable records as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hydrological and other site investigations and assessments; site rehabilitation plans; contracts and contract negotiations; and accounts, invoices, sales tickets, or other payment records from purchases, sales, leases, or other transactions involving costs actually incurred related to site rehabilitation. Such records shall be made available upon request to agents and employees of the department during regular business hours and at other times upon written request of the department.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, the department may from time to time request submission of such site-specific information as it may require, unless a waiver or variance from such department request is granted pursuant to paragraph (k).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All records of costs actually incurred for cleanup shall be certified by affidavit to the department as being true and correct.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Application for reimbursement.</Font><EmDash />Any eligible person who performs a site rehabilitation program or performs site rehabilitation program tasks such as preparation of site rehabilitation plans or assessments; product recovery; cleanup of groundwater or inland surface water; soil treatment or removal; or any other tasks identified by department rule developed pursuant to subsection (5), may apply for reimbursement. Such applications for reimbursement must be submitted to the department on forms provided by the department, together with evidence documenting that site rehabilitation program tasks were conducted or completed in accordance with department rule developed pursuant to subsection (5), and other such records or information as the department requires. The reimbursement application and supporting documentation shall be examined by a certified public accountant in accordance with standards established by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants. A copy of the accountant’s report shall be submitted with the reimbursement application. Applications for reimbursement shall not be approved for site rehabilitation program tasks which have not been completed, except for the task of remedial action and except for uncompleted program tasks pursuant to chapter 95-2, Laws of Florida, and this subsection. Applications for remedial action may be submitted semiannually at the discretion of the person responsible for cleanup. After an applicant has filed an application with the department and before payment is made, the applicant may assign the right to payment to any other person, without recourse of the assignee or assignor to the state, without affecting the order in which payment is made. Information necessary to process the application shall be requested from and provided by the assigning applicant. Proper notice of the assignment and assignment information shall be made to the department which notice shall be signed and notarized by the assigning applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Review.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provided there are sufficient unencumbered funds available in the Inland Protection Trust Fund, or to the extent proceeds of debt obligations are available for the payment of existing reimbursement obligations pursuant to s. 376.3075, the department shall have 60 days to determine if the applicant has provided sufficient information for processing the application and shall request submission of any additional information that the department may require within such 60-day period. If the applicant believes any request for additional information is not authorized, the applicant may request a hearing pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57. Once the department requests additional information, the department may request only that information needed to clarify such additional information or to answer new questions raised by or directly related to such additional information.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deny or approve the application for reimbursement within 90 days after receipt of the last item of timely requested additional material, or, if no additional material is requested, within 90 days of the close of the 60-day period described in subparagraph 1., unless the total review period is otherwise extended by written mutual agreement of the applicant and the department.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Final disposition of an application shall be provided to the applicant in writing, accompanied by a written explanation setting forth in detail the reason or reasons for the approval or denial. If the department fails to make a determination on an application within the time provided in subparagraph 2., or denies an application, or if a dispute otherwise arises with regard to reimbursement, the applicant may request a hearing pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Reimbursement.</Font><EmDash />Upon approval of an application for reimbursement, reimbursement for reasonable expenditures of a site rehabilitation program or site rehabilitation program tasks documented therein shall be made in the order in which the department receives completed applications. Effective January 1, 1997, all unpaid reimbursement applications are subject to payment on the following terms: The department shall develop a schedule of the anticipated dates of reimbursement of applications submitted to the department pursuant to this subsection. The schedule shall specify the projected date of payment based on equal monthly payments and projected annual revenue of $100 million. Based on the schedule, the department shall notify all reimbursement applicants of the projected date of payment of their applications. The department shall direct the Inland Protection Financing Corporation to pay applicants the present value of their applications as soon as practicable after approval by the department, subject to the availability of funds within the Inland Protection Financing Corporation. The present value of an application shall be based on the date on which the department anticipates the Inland Protection Financing Corporation will settle the reimbursement application and the schedule’s projected date of payment and shall use 3.5 percent as the annual discount rate. The determination of the amount of the claim and the projected date of payment shall be subject to s. 120.57.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Liberal construction.</Font><EmDash />With respect to site rehabilitation initiated prior to July 1, 1986, the provisions of this subsection shall be given such liberal construction by the department as will accomplish the purposes set forth in this subsection. With regard to the keeping of particular records or the giving of certain notice, the department may accept as compliance action by a person which meets the intent of the requirements set forth in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Reimbursement-review contracts.</Font><EmDash />The department may contract with entities capable of processing or assisting in the review of reimbursement applications. Any purchase of such services shall not be subject to chapter 287.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Audits.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to perform financial and technical audits in order to certify site restoration costs and ensure compliance with this chapter. The department shall seek recovery of any overpayments based on the findings of these audits. The department must commence any audit within 5 years after the date of reimbursement, except in cases where the department alleges specific facts indicating fraud.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determination by the department that any portion of costs which have been reimbursed are disallowed, the department shall give written notice to the applicant setting forth with specificity the allegations of fact which justify the department’s proposed action and ordering repayment of disallowed costs within 60 days of notification of the applicant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the applicant does not make payment to the department within 60 days of receipt of such notice, the department shall seek recovery in a court of competent jurisdiction to recover reimbursement overpayments made to the person responsible for conducting site rehabilitation, unless the department finds the amount involved too small or the likelihood of recovery too uncertain.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the amount of any overpayment, the applicant shall be liable to the department for interest of 1 percent per month or the prime rate, whichever is less, on the amount of overpayment, from the date of overpayment by the department until the applicant satisfies the department’s request for repayment pursuant to this paragraph. The calculation of interest shall be tolled during the pendency of any litigation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial and technical audits frequently are conducted under this section many years after the site rehabilitation activities were performed and the costs examined in the course of the audit were incurred by the person responsible for site rehabilitation. During the intervening span of years, the department’s rule requirements and its related guidance and other nonrule policy directives may have changed significantly. The Legislature finds that it may be appropriate for the department to provide relief to persons subject to such requirements in financial and technical audits conducted pursuant to this section.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to grant variances and waivers from the documentation requirements of subparagraph (e)2. and from the requirements of rules applicable in technical and financial audits conducted under this section. Variances and waivers shall be granted when the person responsible for site rehabilitation demonstrates to the department that application of a financial or technical auditing requirement would create a substantial hardship or would violate principles of fairness. For purposes of this subsection, “substantial hardship” means a demonstrated economic, technological, legal, or other type of hardship to the person requesting the variance or waiver. For purposes of this subsection, “principles of fairness” are violated when the application of a requirement affects a particular person in a manner significantly different from the way it affects other similarly situated persons who are affected by the requirement or when the requirement is being applied retroactively without due notice to the affected parties.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose reimbursed costs are subject to a financial and technical audit under this section may file a written request to the department for grant of a variance or waiver. The request shall specify:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirement from which a variance or waiver is requested.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of action requested.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="III"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific facts which would justify a waiver or variance.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reason or reasons why the requested variance or waiver would serve the purposes of this section.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days after receipt of a written request for variance or waiver under this subsection, the department shall grant or deny the request. If the request is not granted or denied within 90 days of receipt, the request shall be deemed approved. An order granting or denying the request shall be in writing and shall contain a statement of the relevant facts and reasons supporting the department’s action. The department’s decision to grant or deny the petition shall be supported by competent substantial evidence and is subject to ss. 120.569 and 120.57. Once adopted, model rules promulgated by the Administration Commission under s. 120.542 shall govern the processing of requests under this provision.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer may audit the records of persons who receive or who have received payments pursuant to this chapter in order to verify site restoration costs, ensure compliance with this chapter, and verify the accuracy and completeness of audits performed by the department pursuant to this paragraph. The Chief Financial Officer may contract with entities or persons to perform audits pursuant to this subparagraph. The Chief Financial Officer shall commence any audit within 1 year after the department’s completion of an audit conducted pursuant to this paragraph, except in cases where the department or the Chief Financial Officer alleges specific facts indicating fraud.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PETROLEUM CLEANUP PARTICIPATION PROGRAM.<EmDash />To encourage detection, reporting, and cleanup of contamination caused by discharges of petroleum or petroleum products, the department shall, within the guidelines established in this subsection, implement a cost-sharing cleanup program to provide rehabilitation funding assistance for all property contaminated by discharges of petroleum or petroleum products occurring before January 1, 1995, subject to a copayment provided for in a preapproved site rehabilitation agreement. Eligibility shall be subject to an annual appropriation from the Inland Protection Trust Fund. Additionally, funding for eligible sites shall be contingent upon annual appropriation in subsequent years. Such continued state funding shall not be deemed an entitlement or a vested right under this subsection. Eligibility in the program shall be notwithstanding any other provision of law, consent order, order, judgment, or ordinance to the contrary.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall accept any discharge reporting form received prior to January 1, 1995, as an application for this program, and the facility owner or operator need not reapply.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owners or operators of property contaminated by petroleum or petroleum products from a petroleum storage system may apply for such program by filing a written report of the contamination incident, including evidence that such incident occurred prior to January 1, 1995, with the department. Incidents of petroleum contamination discovered after December 31, 1994, at sites which have not stored petroleum or petroleum products for consumption, use, or sale after such date shall be presumed to have occurred prior to January 1, 1995. An operator’s filed report shall be deemed an application of the owner for all purposes. Sites reported to the department after December 31, 1998, shall not be eligible for this program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to annual appropriation from the Inland Protection Trust Fund, sites meeting the criteria of this subsection are eligible for up to $400,000 of site rehabilitation funding assistance in priority order pursuant to subsection (5) and s. 376.30711. Sites meeting the criteria of this subsection for which a site rehabilitation completion order was issued prior to June 1, 2008, do not qualify for the 2008 increase in site rehabilitation funding assistance and are bound by the pre-June 1, 2008, limits. Sites meeting the criteria of this subsection for which a site rehabilitation completion order was not issued prior to June 1, 2008, regardless of whether or not they have previously transitioned to nonstate-funded cleanup status, may continue state-funded cleanup pursuant to s. 376.30711 until a site rehabilitation completion order is issued or the increased site rehabilitation funding assistance limit is reached, whichever occurs first. At no time shall expenses incurred outside the preapproved site rehabilitation program under s. 376.30711 be reimbursable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon notification by the department that rehabilitation funding assistance is available for the site pursuant to subsection (5) and s. 376.30711, the owner, operator, or person otherwise responsible for site rehabilitation shall provide the department with a limited contamination assessment report and shall enter into a preapproved site rehabilitation agreement with the department and a contractor qualified under s. 376.30711(2)(b). The agreement shall provide for a 25-percent copayment by the owner, operator, or person otherwise responsible for conducting site rehabilitation. The owner, operator, or person otherwise responsible for conducting site rehabilitation shall adequately demonstrate the ability to meet the copayment obligation. The limited contamination assessment report and the copayment costs may be reduced or eliminated if the owner and all operators responsible for restoration under s. 376.308 demonstrate that they are financially unable to comply with the copayment and limited contamination assessment report requirements. The department shall take into consideration the owner’s and operator’s net worth in making the determination of financial ability. In the event the department and the owner, operator, or person otherwise responsible for site rehabilitation are unable to complete negotiation of the cost-sharing agreement within 120 days after commencing negotiations, the department shall terminate negotiations and the site shall be deemed ineligible for state funding under this subsection and all liability protections provided for in this subsection shall be revoked.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No report of a discharge made to the department by any person in accordance with this subsection, or any rules adopted pursuant hereto, shall be used directly as evidence of liability for such discharge in any civil or criminal trial arising out of the discharge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude the department from pursuing penalties in accordance with s. 403.141 for violations of any law or any rule, order, permit, registration, or certification adopted or issued by the department pursuant to its lawful authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a discharge reporting form under paragraph (a), neither the department nor any local government shall pursue any judicial or enforcement action to compel rehabilitation of the discharge. This paragraph shall not prevent any such action with respect to discharges determined ineligible under this subsection or to sites for which rehabilitation funding assistance is available in accordance with subsection (5) and s. 376.30711.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following shall be excluded from participation in the program:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sites at which the department has been denied reasonable site access to implement the provisions of this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sites that were active facilities when owned or operated by the Federal Government.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sites that are identified by the United States Environmental Protection Agency to be on, or which qualify for listing on, the National Priorities List under Superfund. This exception does not apply to those sites for which eligibility has been requested or granted as of the effective date of this act under the Early Detection Incentive Program established pursuant to s. 15, chapter 86-159, Laws of Florida.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contamination is covered under the Early Detection Incentive Program, the Abandoned Tank Restoration Program or the Petroleum Liability and Restoration Insurance Program, in which case site rehabilitation funding assistance shall continue under the respective program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE APPROVAL AND AUTHORIZATION.<EmDash />Prior to the department entering into a service contract with the Inland Protection Financing Corporation which includes payments by the department to support any existing or planned note, bond, certificate of indebtedness, or other obligation or evidence of indebtedness of the corporation pursuant to s. 376.3075, the Legislature, by law, must specifically authorize the department to enter into such a contract. The corporation may issue bonds in an amount not to exceed $104 million, with a term up to 15 years, and annual payments not in excess of $10.4 million. The department may enter into a service contract in conjunction with the issuance of such bonds which provides for annual payments for debt service payments or other amounts payable with respect to bonds, plus any administrative expenses of the corporation to finance the rehabilitation of petroleum contamination sites pursuant to ss. 376.30-376.317.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 16, ch. 86-159; s. 3, ch. 87-374; s. 2, ch. 88-331; s. 4, ch. 89-188; s. 10, ch. 90-98; s. 81, ch. 90-132; s. 15, ch. 91-305; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 7, ch. 92-30; s. 67, ch. 93-207; s. 301, ch. 94-356; s. 1017, ch. 95-148; s. 15, ch. 95-396; s. 134, ch. 95-417; s. 5, ch. 96-277; s. 105, ch. 96-410; s. 14, ch. 97-277; s. 69, ch. 99-8; s. 177, ch. 99-13; s. 1, ch. 99-376; s. 8, ch. 2000-211; s. 392, ch. 2003-261; ss. 29, 54, ch. 2005-71; s. 1, ch. 2005-180; s. 62, ch. 2007-5; s. 1, ch. 2008-127; s. 44, ch. 2008-153; s. 3, ch. 2009-68; s. 31, ch. 2009-82; ss. 1, 3, ch. 2010-278; HJR 7-A, 2010 Special Session A; s. 19, ch. 2012-88; s. 9, ch. 2012-205.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “shall” preceding the word “does” was deleted by the editors.</Text></Note></Section>