<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.79" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to Brownfields Redevelopment Act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 376.77-376.85, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Additive effects” means a scientific principle that the toxicity that occurs as a result of exposure is the sum of the toxicities of the individual chemicals to which the individual is exposed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Antagonistic effects” means a scientific principle that the toxicity that occurs as a result of exposure is less than the sum of the toxicities of the individual chemicals to which the individual is exposed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Brownfield sites” means real property, the expansion, redevelopment, or reuse of which may be complicated by actual or perceived environmental contamination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Brownfield area” means a contiguous area of one or more brownfield sites, some of which may not be contaminated, and which has been designated by a local government by resolution. Such areas may include all or portions of community redevelopment areas, enterprise zones, empowerment zones, other such designated economically deprived communities and areas, and Environmental Protection Agency-designated brownfield pilot projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contaminant” means any physical, chemical, biological, or radiological substance present in any medium which may result in adverse effects to human health or the environment or which creates an adverse nuisance, organoleptic, or aesthetic condition in groundwater.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contaminated site” means any contiguous land, sediment, surface water, or groundwater areas that contain contaminants that may be harmful to human health or the environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Engineering controls” means modifications to a site to reduce or eliminate the potential for exposure to chemicals of concern from petroleum products, drycleaning solvents, or other contaminants. Such modifications may include, but are not limited to, physical or hydraulic control measures, capping, point of use treatments, or slurry walls.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Environmental justice” means the fair treatment of all people of all races, cultures, and incomes with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Institutional controls” means the restriction on use of or access to a site to eliminate or minimize exposure to chemicals of concern from petroleum products, drycleaning solvents, or other contaminants. Such restrictions may include, but are not limited to, deed restrictions, restrictive covenants, or conservation easements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local pollution control program” means a local pollution control program that has received delegated authority from the Department of Environmental Protection under ss. 376.80(9) and 403.182.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Natural attenuation” means a verifiable approach to site rehabilitation that allows natural processes to contain the spread of contamination and reduce the concentrations of contaminants in contaminated groundwater and soil. Natural attenuation processes may include sorption, biodegradation, chemical reactions with subsurface materials, diffusion, dispersion, and volatilization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person responsible for brownfield site rehabilitation” means the individual or entity that is designated by the local government to enter into the brownfield site rehabilitation agreement with the department or an approved local pollution control program and enters into an agreement with the local government for redevelopment of the site.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, partner, joint venture, or corporation; any group of the foregoing, organized or united for a business purpose; or any governmental entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Risk reduction” means the lowering or elimination of the level of risk posed to human health or the environment through interim remedial actions, remedial action, or institutional, and if appropriate, engineering controls.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secretary” means the secretary of the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Site rehabilitation” means the assessment of site contamination and the remediation activities that reduce the levels of contaminants at a site through accepted treatment methods to meet the cleanup target levels established for that site. For purposes of sites subject to the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, as amended, the term includes removal, decontamination, and corrective action of releases of hazardous substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Source removal” means the removal of free product, or the removal of contaminants from soil or sediment that has been contaminated to the extent that leaching to groundwater or surface water has occurred or is occurring.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Synergistic effects” means a scientific principle that the toxicity that occurs as a result of exposure is more than the sum of the toxicities of the individual chemicals to which the individual is exposed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 97-277; s. 2, ch. 98-75; s. 10, ch. 2000-317; s. 1, ch. 2004-40; s. 4, ch. 2008-239.</History></Section>