<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of the Department of Environmental Protection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers and duties conferred by ss. 376.011-376.21 shall be exercised by the department and shall be deemed to be an essential governmental function in the exercise of the police power of the state. The department may call upon any other state agency for consultative services and technical advice and the agencies are directed to cooperate in said request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers and duties of the department under ss. 376.011-376.21 shall extend to the boundaries of the state described in s. 1, Art. II of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration certificates and discharge prevention and response certificates required under ss. 376.011-376.21 shall be issued from the department subject to such terms and conditions as are set forth in ss. 376.011-376.21 and as set forth in rules adopted by the department as authorized herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever it becomes necessary for the state to protect the public interest under ss. 376.011-376.21, it shall be the duty of the department to keep an accurate record of costs and expenses incurred and thereafter diligently to pursue the recovery of any sums so incurred from the person responsible or from the Government of the United States under any applicable federal act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may bring an action on behalf of the state to enforce the liabilities imposed by s. 376.12. The Department of Legal Affairs shall represent the department in any such proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is specifically authorized to utilize risk-based cleanup criteria as described in ss. 376.3071, 376.3078, and 376.81 in conducting cleanups on lands owned by the state university system.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 70-244; s. 2, ch. 71-137; s. 5, ch. 74-336; s. 62, ch. 79-65; s. 81, ch. 83-310; s. 11, ch. 90-54; s. 5, ch. 92-113; s. 290, ch. 94-356; s. 6, ch. 2000-317.</History></Section>