<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.70" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax on gross receipts of drycleaning facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is levied a gross receipts tax on each drycleaning facility and dry drop-off facility, as defined in s. 376.301, for the privilege of engaging in the business of laundering and drycleaning clothing and other fabrics in this state. The tax shall be at a rate of 2 percent of all charges imposed by the drycleaning facility or the dry drop-off facility for the drycleaning or laundering of clothing or other fabrics. Gross receipts from coin-operated laundry machines and from laundry done on a wash, dry, and fold basis shall not be subject to tax.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each drycleaning facility or dry drop-off facility imposing a charge for the drycleaning or laundering of clothing or other fabrics is required to register with the Department of Revenue and become licensed for the purposes of this section. The owner or operator of the facility shall register the facility with the Department of Revenue. Drycleaning facilities or dry drop-off facilities operating at more than one location are only required to have a single registration. The fee for registration is $30. The owner or operator of the facility shall pay the registration fee to the Department of Revenue. The department may waive the registration fee for applications submitted through the department’s Internet registration process.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax imposed by this section is due on the 1st day of the month succeeding the month in which the charge is imposed and shall be paid on or before the 20th day of each month. The tax shall be reported on forms and in the manner prescribed by the Department of Revenue by rule. The proceeds of the taxes, after deducting the administrative costs incurred by the Department of Revenue in administering, auditing, collecting, distributing, and enforcing the tax, shall be transferred by the Department of Revenue into the Water Quality Assurance Trust Fund and shall be used as provided in s. 376.3078. For the purposes of this section, the proceeds of the tax include all funds collected and received by the Department of Revenue, including interest and penalties on delinquent taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any drycleaning facility which includes in the total retail charge to a consumer of drycleaning services any portion of the tax imposed pursuant to this section shall disclose on the receipt for the amount charged for such services the amount of such tax and a statement that the imposition of the tax was requested by the Florida Dry Cleaners Coalition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross receipts arising from charges for services taxable pursuant to this section to persons who also impose charges to others for those same services are exempt from the tax imposed pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall administer, collect, and enforce the tax imposed under this section pursuant to the procedures for administration, collection, and enforcement of the general state sales tax imposed under chapter 212, except as provided in this subsection. Such procedures include, but are not limited to, those regarding the filing of consolidated returns, the granting of sale for resale exemptions, and the interest and penalties on delinquent taxes. The tax shall not be included in the computation of estimated taxes pursuant to s. 212.11, nor shall the dealer’s credit for collecting taxes or fees in s. 212.12 apply. The provisions of s. 212.07(4) shall not apply to the tax imposed by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue is authorized to employ persons and incur other expenses for which funds are appropriated by the Legislature. The Department of Revenue is empowered to adopt such rules and shall prescribe and publish such forms as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue is authorized to establish audit procedures and to assess delinquent taxes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not deny eligibility in the drycleaning solvent cleanup program because of the facility owner’s, the facility operator’s, and the real property owner’s failure to remit all taxes due pursuant to this section and s. 376.75, unless the Department of Revenue:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ascertains the amount of the delinquent tax, if any, and communicates this amount in writing to the drycleaning solvent cleanup program applicant and the real property owner; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides a method to the facility owner, the facility operator, and the real property owner for the payment of the taxes.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Pursuant to this subsection, the owner or operator of a drycleaning facility must demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Department of Revenue that failure to remit all taxes due in a timely manner was not due to willful and overt actions to avoid payment of taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature declares that the failure to promptly implement the provisions of this section would present an immediate threat to the welfare of the state. Therefore, the executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized to adopt emergency rules pursuant to s. 120.54(4) to implement this section. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain effective for 180 days from the date of adoption. Other rules of the Department of Revenue related to and in furtherance of the orderly implementation of this section shall not be subject to a s. 120.56(2) rule challenge or a s. 120.54(3)(c)2. drawout proceeding, but, once adopted, shall be subject to a s. 120.56(3) invalidity challenge. Such rules shall be adopted by the Governor and Cabinet and shall become effective upon filing with the Department of State, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 120.54(3)(e)6.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 94-355; s. 7, ch. 95-239; s. 52, ch. 96-321; s. 108, ch. 96-410; s. 13, ch. 98-189; s. 49, ch. 2002-218.</History></Section>