<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency proclamation; Governor’s powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any emergency exists or appears imminent, arising from the discharge of oil, petroleum products or their byproducts, or any other pollutants, the Governor shall by proclamation declare the fact and that a state of emergency exists in any or all sections of the state. If the Governor is unavailable, the Lieutenant Governor shall, by proclamation, declare the fact and that a state of emergency exists in any or all sections of the state. A copy of such proclamation shall be filed with the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In performing his or her duties under this section, the Governor is authorized and directed to cooperate with all departments and agencies of the Federal Government, the offices and agencies of other states and foreign countries and the political subdivisions thereof, and private agencies in all matters pertaining to an emergency as described herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In performing his or her duties under this section, the Governor is further authorized and empowered:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make, amend, and rescind the necessary orders, rules, and regulations to carry out this section within the limits of the authority conferred upon the Governor and not inconsistent with the rules, regulations, and directives of the President of the United States or of any federal department or agency having specifically authorized emergency functions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To delegate any authority vested in the Governor under this section and to provide for the subdelegation of any such authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the Governor is satisfied that an emergency no longer exists, he or she may terminate the proclamation by another proclamation affecting the sections of the state covered by the original proclamation, or any part thereof. The proclamation shall be published in such newspapers of the state and posted in such places as the Governor, or any person acting in that capacity, deems appropriate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 70-244; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 39, ch. 83-334; s. 614, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>