<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.304" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Review and analysis of disposal materials or byproducts; disposal at designated local government solid waste disposal facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that it is in the public interest to facilitate the activities necessary and essential to clean up the release of pollutants which threaten Florida’s unique and fragile environment. The Legislature finds that it is in the public interest to authorize appropriate actions to manage and control the costs associated with activities integrally involved with cleanup of sites contaminated with pollutants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to review and analyze the disposal materials or byproducts used or resulting from the cleanup of the release of pollutants in the waters of the state. Such materials that are determined by the department not to require extraordinary handling or disposal requirements may be designated for disposal in nearby existing local government solid waste disposal facilities where such facilities are determined to be designed and operated in a manner where disposal of such materials would not constitute an unreasonable risk to public health and the environment. Such designation by the department shall not be disallowed by actions of the local government responsible for operating the solid waste disposal facility. The designation by the department of a local government’s solid waste facility as the location for disposing of materials and byproducts resulting from the activities essential to the cleanup of pollutants in the waters of the state shall constitute final agency action subject to review pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 90-54; s. 299, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>