<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.84" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Brownfield redevelopment economic incentives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that brownfield redevelopment activities be viewed as opportunities to significantly improve the utilization, general condition, and appearance of these sites. Different standards than those in place for new development, as allowed under current state and local laws, should be used to the fullest extent to encourage the redevelopment of a brownfield. State and local governments are encouraged to offer redevelopment incentives for this purpose, as an ongoing public investment in infrastructure and services, to help eliminate the public health and environmental hazards, and to promote the creation of jobs in these areas. Such incentives may include financial, regulatory, and technical assistance to persons and businesses involved in the redevelopment of the brownfield pursuant to this act.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial incentives and local incentives for redevelopment may include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tax increment financing through community redevelopment agencies pursuant to part III of chapter 163.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enterprise zone tax exemptions for businesses pursuant to chapters 196 and 290.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Safe neighborhood improvement districts as provided in ss. 163.501-163.523.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waiver, reduction, or limitation by line of business with respect to business taxes pursuant to chapter 205.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tax exemption for historic properties as provided in s. 196.1997.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential electricity exemption of up to the first 500 kilowatts of use may be exempted from the municipal public service tax pursuant to s. 166.231.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minority business enterprise programs as provided in s. 287.0943.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electric and gas tax exemption as provided in s. 166.231(6).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Economic development tax abatement as provided in s. 196.1995.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grants, including community development block grants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pledging of revenues to secure bonds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Low-interest revolving loans and zero-interest loan pools.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local grant programs for facade, storefront, signage, and other business improvements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Governmental coordination of loan programs with lenders, such as microloans, business reserve fund loans, letter of credit enhancements, gap financing, land lease and sublease loans, and private equity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment schedules over time for payment of fees, within criteria, and marginal cost pricing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulatory incentives may include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cities’ absorption of developers’ concurrency needs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developers’ performance of certain analyses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exemptions and lessening of state and local review requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water and sewer regulatory incentives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waiver of transportation impact fees and permit fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Zoning incentives to reduce review requirements for redevelopment changes in use and occupancy; establishment of code criteria for specific uses; and institution of credits for previous use within the area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Flexibility in parking standards and buffer zone standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Environmental management through specific code criteria and conditions allowed by current law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance standards and activities by ordinance and otherwise, and increased security and crime prevention measures available through special assessments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Traffic-calming measures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Historic preservation ordinances, loan programs, and review and permitting procedures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One-stop permitting and streamlined development and permitting process.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Technical assistance incentives may include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expedited development applications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Formal and informal information on business incentives and financial programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Site design assistance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marketing and promotion of projects or areas.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 97-277; s. 72, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>