<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.321" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; ss. 376.320-376.326.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 376.320-376.326, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Aboveground” means that more than 90 percent of a tank volume is not buried below the ground surface. An aboveground tank may either be in contact with the ground or elevated above it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Containment and integrity plan” or “CIP” means a document designed, created, and maintained at a facility, which shall be considered a public record and made available pursuant to the provisions of chapter 119, and which sets forth the procedures for the inspection and maintenance program for aboveground tanks at that facility which store specified mineral acids. That program shall be designed for the chemical and physical characteristics of the specific mineral acid stored and for the specific materials of construction of the aboveground tank. The CIP shall be designed to ensure control of the specific mineral acid stored in an aboveground tank for the expected lifetime, as determined by standard engineering practices, of the materials of construction of the specific aboveground tank in which that mineral acid is stored.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Facility” means any nonresidential location or part thereof containing an aboveground tank or aboveground tanks which contain specified mineral acids, which have an individual storage capacity greater than 110 gallons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Flow-through process tank” means a flow-through process tank as defined in s. 376.301.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Liner” means an artificially constructed material of sufficient thickness, density, and composition that will contain the discharge of any specified mineral acid from an aboveground tank until such time as the mineral acid can be neutralized and/or removed. The liner shall prevent any escape of specified mineral acids or accumulated liquid to the soil or to the surface water or groundwater except through secondary containment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mineral acids” means hydrobromic acid (HBr), hydrochloric acid (HCl), hydrofluoric acid (HF), phosphoric acid (H<Font xml:space="preserve" Baseline="Subscript">3</Font>PO<Font xml:space="preserve" Baseline="Subscript">4</Font>), and sulfuric acid (H<Font xml:space="preserve" Baseline="Subscript">2</Font>SO<Font xml:space="preserve" Baseline="Subscript">4</Font>), including those five acids in solution, if at least 20 percent by weight of the solution is one of the five listed acids.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonresidential” means that the tank is not used at a private dwelling.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Operator” means any person operating a facility whether by lease, contract, or other form of agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means any person owning an aboveground tank subject to ss. 376.320-376.326.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permitted wastewater treatment system” means a facility to which the department has issued a permit to treat wastewater and release the treated product into the environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secondary containment” means a system that is used for release prevention, and may include one or more of the following devices:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A double-walled tank;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An external liner; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A system or structure constructed such that accidental releases from an aboveground tank would be collected by a drainage system within the system or structure and routed to a permitted wastewater treatment system, plant recirculating process system, or approved alternate containment system.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stationary” means a tank or tanks not meant for multiple site use or a tank or tanks which remain in one location at the facility site for a period of 180 days or longer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tank” means a stationary device which is constructed primarily of nonearthen materials (e.g., concrete, metal, plastic, glass) that provides structural support and is designed primarily to contain mineral acids. Connected piping from the tank to and including the nearest cutoff valve shall be considered part of the tank for purposes of this definition. “Tank” does not include flow-through process tanks.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 90-98; s. 17, ch. 92-30; s. 304, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>