<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0376.302" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be a violation of this chapter and it shall be prohibited for any reason:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To discharge pollutants or hazardous substances into or upon the surface or ground waters of the state or lands, which discharge violates any departmental “standard” as defined in s. 403.803(13).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fail to obtain any permit or registration required by this chapter or by rule, or to violate or fail to comply with any statute, rule, order, permit, registration, or certification adopted or issued by the department pursuant to its lawful authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To knowingly make any false statement, representation, or certification in any application, record, report, plan, or other document filed or required to be maintained under this chapter, or to falsify, tamper with, or knowingly render inaccurate any monitoring device or method required to be maintained under this chapter or by any permit, registration, rule, or order issued under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 376.311, any person who commits a violation specified in subsection (1) is liable to the state for any damage caused and for civil penalties as provided in s. 403.141.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully commits a violation specified in paragraph (1)(a) or paragraph (1)(b) shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree punishable as provided in ss. 775.082(4)(a) and 775.083(1)(g), by a fine of not less than $2,500 or more than $25,000, or punishable by 1 year in jail, or by both for each offense. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who commits a violation specified in paragraph (1)(c) shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree punishable as provided in ss. 775.082(4)(a) and 775.083(1)(g), by a fine of not more than $10,000, or by 6 months in jail, or by both for each offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who commits fraud in representing their qualifications for reimbursement or in submitting a reimbursement request pursuant to s. 376.3071(12) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the legislative intent that the civil penalties and criminal fines imposed by the court be of such amount as to ensure immediate and continued compliance with this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 84, ch. 83-310; s. 8, ch. 84-338; s. 4, ch. 92-30; s. 1, ch. 94-311; s. 4, ch. 94-355.</History></Section>