<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0017.0401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidentiality of information relating to financial investigations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by this section, information relative to an investigation conducted by the Division of Accounting and Auditing pursuant to s. 17.04, including any consumer complaint, is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution until the investigation is completed or ceases to be active. Any information relating to an investigation conducted by the division pursuant to s. 17.04 shall remain confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution after the division’s investigation is completed or ceases to be active if the division submits the information to any law enforcement or prosecutorial agency for further investigation. Such information shall remain confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution until that agency’s investigation is completed or ceases to be active. For purposes of this section, an investigation shall be considered “active” so long as the division or any law enforcement or prosecutorial agency is proceeding with reasonable dispatch and has a reasonable good faith belief that the investigation may lead to the filing of an administrative, civil, or criminal proceeding. This section shall not be construed to prohibit disclosure of information that is required by law to be filed with the Department of Financial Services or the Office of Financial Regulation and that, but for the investigation, would otherwise be subject to public disclosure. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the division from providing information to any law enforcement or prosecutorial agency. Any law enforcement or prosecutorial agency receiving confidential information from the division in connection with its official duties shall maintain the confidentiality of the information as provided for in this section.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 95-425; s. 3, ch. 96-406; s. 19, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>