<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0017.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County and district accounts and claims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the Chief Financial Officer to adjust and settle, or cause to be adjusted and settled, all accounts and claims heretofore or hereafter reported to it by the Auditor General, the appropriate county or district official, or any person against all county and district officers and employees, and against all other persons entrusted with, or who may have received, any property, funds, or moneys of a county or district or who may be in anywise indebted to or accountable to a county or district for any property, funds, moneys, or other thing of value, and to require such officer, employee, or person to render full accounts thereof and to yield up such property, funds, moneys, or other thing of value according to law to the officer or authority entitled by law to receive the same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the failure of such officer, employee, or person to adjust and settle such account, or to yield up such property, funds, moneys, or other thing of value, the Chief Financial Officer shall direct the attorney for the board of county commissioners, the district school board, or the district, as the case may be, entitled to such account, property, funds, moneys, or other thing of value to represent such county or district in enforcing settlement, payment, or delivery of such account, property, funds, moneys, or other thing of value. The Chief Financial Officer may enforce such settlement, payment, or delivery pursuant to s. 17.20.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Should the attorney for the county or district aforesaid be disqualified or unable to act, and no other attorney be furnished by the county or district, or should the Chief Financial Officer otherwise deem it advisable, such account or claim may be certified to the Department of Legal Affairs by the Chief Financial Officer, to be prosecuted by the Department of Legal Affairs at county or district expense, as the case may be, including necessary per diem and travel expense in accordance with s. 112.061, as now or hereafter amended. Such expenses, when approved by the Chief Financial Officer, shall be paid forthwith by such county or district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it appears to the Chief Financial Officer that any criminal statute of this state has or may have been violated by such defaulting officer, employee, or person, such information, evidence, documents, and other things tending to show such a violation, whether in the hands of the Chief Financial Officer, the Auditor General, the county, or the district, shall be forthwith turned over to the proper state attorney for inspection, study, and such action as may be deemed proper, or the same may be brought to the attention of the proper grand jury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No such account or claim, after it has been certified to the Chief Financial Officer, may be settled for less than the amount due according to law without the written consent of the Chief Financial Officer, and any attempt to make settlement in violation of this subsection shall be deemed null and void. A county or district board desiring to make such a settlement shall incorporate the proposed settlement into a resolution, stating that the proposed settlement is contingent upon the Chief Financial Officer’s approval, and shall submit two copies of the resolution to the department. The Chief Financial Officer shall return one copy with his or her action endorsed thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No settlement of account of any such officer, employee, or person, with the county or district, or any of their officers or agents, made in an amount or manner other than as authorized by law or for other than a lawful county or district purpose, shall be binding upon such county or district unless and until approved by the Chief Financial Officer, or unless more than 4 years shall have elapsed from the date of such settlement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall supersede the continuing duty of the proper county and district officers to require any officer, employee, or person to render full accounts of and to yield up according to law to the officer or authority entitled by law to receive the same, any property, funds, moneys, or other thing of value as to which such officer, employee, or person is in anywise indebted to or accountable to such county or district. The provisions of this section provide for collections and recoveries which the proper county or district officers have failed to make, and for correction of settlements made in an amount or manner other than as authorized by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-145; s. 8, ch. 69-82; s. 1, ch. 69-300; ss. 11, 12, 35, 69-106; s. 1, ch. 73-334; s. 7, ch. 77-104; s. 2, ch. 83-132; s. 55, ch. 95-147; s. 20, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>