<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0017.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of Treasury to make reproductions of certain warrants, records, and documents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Photographs, microphotographs, or reproductions on film of warrants, vouchers, or checks shall be deemed to be original records for all purposes; and any copy or reproduction thereof made from such original film, duly certified by the Division of Treasury as a true and correct copy or reproduction made from such film, shall be deemed to be a transcript, exemplification or certified copy of the original warrant, voucher, or check such copy represents, and shall in all cases and in all courts and places be admitted and received in evidence with the like force and effect as the original thereof might be.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Treasury may photograph, microphotograph, or reproduce on film, all records and documents of the division, as the Chief Financial Officer, in his or her discretion, selects; and the division may destroy any such documents or records after they have been photographed and filed and after audit of the division has been completed for the period embracing the dates of such documents and records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Photographs or microphotographs in the form of film or prints of any records made in compliance with the provisions of this section shall have the same force and effect as the originals thereof would have, and shall be treated as originals for the purpose of their admissibility in evidence. Duly certified or authenticated reproductions of such photographs or microphotographs shall be admitted in evidence equally with the original photographs or microphotographs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 22704, 1945; s. 9, ch. 29615, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-36; s. 76, ch. 95-147; s. 64, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 18.20.</Text></Note></Section>