<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0017.58" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Deposits of public money outside the State Treasury; revolving funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected by state agencies, boards, bureaus, commissions, institutions, and departments shall, except as otherwise provided by law, be deposited in the State Treasury. However, when the volume and complexity of collections so justify, the Chief Financial Officer may give written approval for such moneys to be deposited in clearing accounts outside the State Treasury in qualified public depositories pursuant to chapter 280. Such deposits shall only be made in depositories designated by the Chief Financial Officer. No money may be maintained in such clearing accounts for a period longer than approved by the Chief Financial Officer or 40 days, whichever is shorter, prior to its being transmitted to the Chief Financial Officer or to an account designated by him or her, distributed to a statutorily authorized account outside the State Treasury, refunded, or transmitted to the Department of Revenue. All depositories so designated shall pledge sufficient collateral to be security for such funds as provided in chapter 280.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revolving funds authorized by the Chief Financial Officer for all state agencies, boards, bureaus, commissions, institutions, and departments may be deposited by such agencies, boards, bureaus, commissions, institutions, and departments in qualified public depositories designated by the Chief Financial Officer for such revolving fund deposits; and the depositories in which such deposits are made shall pledge collateral security as provided in chapter 280.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions, clearing and revolving accounts may be established outside the state when necessary to facilitate the authorized operations of any agency, board, bureau, commission, institution, or department. Any of such accounts established in the United States shall be subject to the collateral security requirements of chapter 280. Accounts established outside the United States may be exempted from the requirements of chapter 280 as provided in chapter 280; but before any unsecured account is established, the agency requesting or maintaining the account shall recommend a financial institution to the Chief Financial Officer for designation to hold the account and shall submit evidence of the financial condition, size, reputation, and relative prominence of the institution from which the Chief Financial Officer can reasonably conclude that the institution is financially sound before designating it to hold the account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each department shall furnish a statement to the Chief Financial Officer, on or before the 20th of the month following the end of each calendar quarter, listing each clearing account and revolving fund within that department’s jurisdiction. Such statement shall report, as of the last day of the calendar quarter, the cash balance in each revolving fund and that portion of the cash balance in each clearing account that will eventually be deposited to the State Treasury as provided by law. The Chief Financial Officer shall show the sum total of state funds in clearing accounts and revolving funds, as most recently reported to the Chief Financial Officer by various departments, in his or her monthly statement to the Governor, pursuant to s. 17.55.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 28133, 1953; s. 3, ch. 67-129; ss. 2, 3, ch. 67-371; ss. 28, 31, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-162; s. 1, ch. 74-28; s. 1, ch. 78-54; s. 50, ch. 79-190; s. 2, ch. 81-285; s. 3, ch. 83-122; s. 11, ch. 83-132; s. 1, ch. 83-215; s. 2, ch. 85-138; s. 3, ch. 91-45; s. 73, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 96-177; s. 57, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 18.101.</Text></Note></Section>