<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0590.33">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State compact administrator; compact advisory committee.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In pursuance of art. III of the compact, the director of the Florida Forest Service shall act as compact administrator for Florida of the Southeastern Interstate Forest Fire Protection Compact during his or her term of office as director, and his or her successor as compact administrator shall be his or her successor as director of the Florida Forest Service. As compact administrator, he or she shall be an ex officio member of the advisory committee of the Southeastern Interstate Forest Fire Protection Compact, and chair ex officio of the Florida members of the advisory committee. There shall be four members of the Southeastern Interstate Forest Fire Protection Compact Advisory Committee from Florida. Two of the members from Florida shall be members of the Legislature of Florida, one from the Senate designated by the President of the Senate and one from the House of Representatives designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the terms of any such members shall terminate at the time they cease to hold legislative office, and their successors as members shall be named in like manner. The Governor shall appoint the other two members from Florida, one of whom shall be associated with forestry or forest products industries. The terms of such members shall be 3 years and such members shall hold office until their respective successors shall be appointed and qualified. Vacancies occurring in the office of such members from any reason or cause shall be filled by appointment by the Governor for the unexpired term. The director of the Florida Forest Service as compact administrator for Florida may delegate, from time to time, to any deputy or other subordinate in his or her department or office, the power to be present and participate, including voting as his or her representative or substitute at any meeting of or hearing by or other proceeding of the compact administrators or of the advisory committee. The terms of each of the initial four memberships, whether appointed at said time or not, shall begin upon the date upon which the compact shall become effective in accordance with art. II of said compact. Any member of the advisory committee may be removed from office by the Governor upon charges and after a hearing.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 29635, 1955; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 959, ch. 97-103; s. 17, ch. 99-292; s. 156, ch. 2010-102; s. 36, ch. 2011-34; s. 74, ch. 2012-5; s. 65, ch. 2012-7.</History>
</Section>