<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0590.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Forest Service; powers, authority, and duties; liability; building structures; Florida Center for Wildfire and Forest Resources Management Training.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service has the following powers, authority, and duties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enforce the provisions of this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prevent, detect, suppress, and extinguish wildfires wherever they may occur on public or private land in this state and to do all things necessary in the exercise of such powers, authority, and duties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide firefighting crews, who shall be under the control and direction of the Florida Forest Service and its designated agents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To appoint center managers, forest area supervisors, forestry program administrators, a forest protection bureau chief, a forest protection assistant bureau chief, a field operations bureau chief, deputy chiefs of field operations, district managers, forest operations administrators, senior forest rangers, investigators, forest rangers, firefighter rotorcraft pilots, and other employees who may, at the Florida Forest Service’s discretion, be certified as forestry firefighters pursuant to s. 633.35(4). Other provisions of law notwithstanding, center managers, district managers, forest protection assistant bureau chief, and deputy chiefs of field operations shall have Selected Exempt Service status in the state personnel designation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop a training curriculum for forestry firefighters which must contain the basic volunteer structural fire training course approved by the Florida State Fire College of the Division of State Fire Marshal and a minimum of 250 hours of wildfire training;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make rules to accomplish the purposes of this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide fire management services and emergency response assistance and to set and charge reasonable fees for performance of those services. Moneys collected from such fees shall be deposited into the Incidental Trust Fund of the Florida Forest Service; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require all state, regional, and local government agencies operating aircraft in the vicinity of an ongoing wildfire to operate in compliance with the applicable state Wildfire Aviation Plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service’s employees, and the firefighting crews under their control and direction, may enter upon any lands for the purpose of preventing and suppressing wildfires and investigating smoke complaints or open burning not in compliance with authorization and to enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employees of the Florida Forest Service and of federal, state, and local agencies, and all other persons and entities that are under contract or agreement with the Florida Forest Service to assist in firefighting operations as well as those entities, called upon by the Florida Forest Service to assist in firefighting may, in the performance of their duties, set counterfires, remove fences and other obstacles, dig trenches, cut firelines, use water from public and private sources, and carry on all other customary activities in the fighting of wildfires without incurring liability to any person or entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may build structures, notwithstanding chapters 216 and 255, not to exceed a cost of $50,000 per structure from existing resources on forest lands, federal excess property, and unneeded existing structures. These structures must meet all applicable building codes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 553.80(1), the department shall exclusively enforce the Florida Building Code as it pertains to wildfire and law enforcement facilities under the jurisdiction of the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service shall organize its operational units to most effectively prevent, detect, and suppress wildfires, and to that end, may employ the necessary personnel to manage its activities in each unit. The Florida Forest Service may construct lookout towers, roads, bridges, firelines, and other facilities and may purchase or fabricate tools, supplies, and equipment for firefighting. The Florida Forest Service may reimburse the public and private entities that it engages to assist in the suppression of wildfires for their personnel and equipment, including aircraft.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service shall undertake privatization alternatives for fire prevention activities including constructing fire lines and conducting prescribed burns and, where appropriate, entering into agreements or contracts with the private sector to perform such activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service may organize, staff, equip, and operate the Florida Center for Wildfire and Forest Resources Management Training. The center shall serve as a site where fire and forest resource managers can obtain current knowledge, techniques, skills, and theory as they relate to their respective disciplines.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The center may establish cooperative efforts involving federal, state, and local entities; hire appropriate personnel; and engage others by contract or agreement with or without compensation to assist in carrying out the training and operations of the center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The center shall provide wildfire suppression training opportunities for rural fire departments, volunteer fire departments, and other local fire response units.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The center will focus on curriculum related to, but not limited to, fuel reduction, an incident management system, prescribed burning certification, multiple-use land management, water quality, forest health, environmental education, and wildfire suppression training for structural firefighters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The center may assess appropriate fees for food, lodging, travel, course materials, and supplies in order to meet its operational costs and may grant free meals, room, and scholarships to persons and other entities in exchange for instructional assistance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advisory committee consisting of the following individuals or their designees must review program curriculum, course content, and scheduling: the director of the Florida Forest Service; the assistant director of the Florida Forest Service; the director of the School of Forest Resources and Conservation of the University of Florida; the director of the Division of Recreation and Parks of the Department of Environmental Protection; the director of the Division of the State Fire Marshal; the director of the Florida Chapter of The Nature Conservancy; the executive vice president of the Florida Forestry Association; the president of the Florida Farm Bureau Federation; the executive director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission; the executive director of a water management district as appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture; the supervisor of the National Forests in Florida; the president of the Florida Fire Chief’s Association; and the executive director of the Tall Timbers Research Station.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Cross City Work Center shall be named the L. Earl Peterson Forestry Station. This is to honor Mr. L. Earl Peterson, Florida’s sixth state forester, whose distinguished career in state government has spanned 44 years, and who is a native of Dixie County.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 273.055 and 287.16, the department may retain, transfer, warehouse, bid, destroy, scrap, or otherwise dispose of surplus equipment and vehicles that are used for wildland firefighting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All money received from the disposition of state-owned equipment and vehicles that are used for wildland firefighting shall be retained by the department. Money received pursuant to this section is appropriated for and may be disbursed for the acquisition of exchange and surplus equipment used for wildland firefighting, and for all necessary operating expenditures related to such equipment, in the same fiscal year and the fiscal year following the disposition. The department shall maintain records of the accounts into which the money is deposited.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service has exclusive authority to require and issue authorizations for broadcast burning and agricultural and silvicultural pile burning. An agency, commission, department, county, municipality, or other political subdivision of the state may not adopt or enforce laws, regulations, rules, or policies pertaining to broadcast burning or agricultural and silvicultural pile burning unless an emergency order is declared in accordance with s. 252.38(3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Forest Service may delegate to a county or municipality its authority, as delegated by the Department of Environmental Protection pursuant to ss. 403.061(28) and 403.081, to require and issue authorizations for the burning of yard trash and debris from land clearing operations in accordance with s. 590.125(6).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 17029, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(10-ss); s. 1, ch. 26915, 1951; s. 1, ch. 57-55; ss. 2, 3, ch. 67-371; ss. 14, 31, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 77-70; s. 1, ch. 79-91; s. 142, ch. 79-190; s. 231, ch. 79-400; s. 1, ch. 80-40; s. 1, ch. 81-111; s. 2, ch. 83-178; s. 2, ch. 86-59; s. 3, ch. 88-321; s. 1, ch. 92-187; s. 8, ch. 92-290; s. 103, ch. 92-291; s. 23, ch. 96-231; s. 9, ch. 97-220; s. 3, ch. 99-292; s. 76, ch. 2000-154; s. 27, ch. 2000-197; s. 39, ch. 2002-295; s. 55, ch. 2011-206; s. 58, ch. 2012-7; s. 45, ch. 2012-190.</History></Section>