<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0590.082" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Extraordinary fire hazard; certain acts made unlawful; proclamations by the Governor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the Commissioner of Agriculture has declared a severe drought emergency to exist and described the general boundaries of the area affected as prescribed in s. 590.081 and the drought emergency continues until the wild lands become so dry or parched as to create an extraordinary fire hazard, the commissioner will advise the Governor that because of prolonged severe drought conditions an extraordinary fire hazard that could endanger life or property exists on wild lands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor may by proclamation declare an extraordinary fire hazard to exist and describe the general boundaries of the area affected. Any proclamation promulgated by the Governor under authority of this section shall be effective immediately upon filing same with the Department of State and shall remain in effect until, when conditions warrant, an order of revocation of proclamation is made by the Governor and filed with the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, except the owner or his or her agents, or persons with express permission of the landowner, or other persons regularly engaged in harvesting, processing, or moving forest or farm products, to enter or travel in any public or private wild land within the area described by proclamation, except on public roads or highways or on well-defined private roads.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person violating any of the provisions of this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-293; s. 1, ch. 75-264; s. 955, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 99-292.</History></Section>