<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0132.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax by municipalities; bonds to constitute general obligations; debt limit inapplicable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of refunding bonds issued by municipalities it shall be the duty of the governing board of the municipality charged by law with determining and fixing the amount of general property taxes for any fiscal year of the municipality, to ascertain the amount of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Principal and interest of refunding bonds due in such year for which moneys are not in hand.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Principal and interest of refunding bonds due prior to such year and which are then or will be in default in such year, together with interest thereon.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sinking fund payments due in such year or due prior to such year and which are then or will be in default in such year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such additional sum as may be necessary to make up for the estimated failure to collect taxes in such year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The said governing body of the municipality shall determine and fix the total of said sums as the amount to be raised by tax in addition to all other taxes for said fiscal year. The said amount shall thereupon be apportioned against, and levied and assessed on, all property subject to taxation in the manner provided by law, for taxes for other purposes in the municipalities and shall be collected and applied to such purpose by the official of the municipality charged by law with duty of apportioning, levying, assessing, collecting and applying taxes for other purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The refunding bonds issued in pursuance of this chapter by municipalities shall be general and unlimited obligations of the municipalities and the full faith and credit of the municipality is hereby irrevocably pledged for their payment. The municipality and each and every official and governing board thereof shall levy, assess, apportion and collect on and from all taxable real and personal property in the municipality such taxes as shall be sufficient to pay the interest and principal of the refunding bonds as they become due and payable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No other section of this chapter or of any other law, or of any agreement or resolution made by the municipality shall be construed to limit or restrict the powers or obligations of the municipality under this chapter and the provisions of any resolution of the municipality made pursuant to this chapter shall be construed as supplemental hereto for the greater protection of the refunding bonds, and shall not be construed as limiting or restricting the application of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All refunding bonds issued pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall not be subject to any limitation or indebtedness prescribed by any statutes, charter or other special act relating to the municipality.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 15772, 1931; CGL 1936 Supp. 2383(23).</History></Section>