<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0132.41" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties and obligations of escrow agent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief financial officer of the unit, or such other official as the governing body shall designate, prior to the issuance of general obligation refunding bonds, shall notify the escrow agent of its appointment and of the intention of the unit to issue general obligation refunding bonds and, on behalf of the unit, shall enter into an escrow agreement with the escrow agent in respect of the escrowing of the proceeds, inclusive of any premium, from the sale of such general obligation refunding bonds, together with all income derived from the investment of such proceeds, and any other moneys to be provided by the unit to effectuate the refunding financial plan. Each escrow agreement shall contain such terms and conditions as shall be necessary in order to accomplish the refunding financial plan, including, without limiting the generality of the foregoing, provisions for the escrow agent, without further authorization or direction from the unit, except as otherwise provided therein:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make all required payments of principal, interest, and redemption premium to the appropriate paying agent with respect to either the general obligation bonds to be refunded or the general obligation refunding bonds;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay the refunding expenses;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the appropriate time or times to cause to be given on behalf of the unit such notice or notices of redemption, if any, authorized to be given in respect of the general obligation bonds to be refunded; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To invest the moneys held by it in accordance with the refunding financial plan and the direction of the chief financial officer of the unit. Each escrow agreement shall be irrevocable and shall constitute a covenant with the holders of the general obligation refunding bonds and the general obligation bonds to be refunded to which it relates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-181.</History></Section>