<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0132.34" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the context clearly indicates a different meaning, as used in ss. 132.33-132.47, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Average remaining term” means, with respect to any general obligation bonds to be refunded, the product obtained by multiplying the principal amount of such bonds maturing or subject to sinking fund installments in each bond year during the remaining term of such bonds by the number of bond years from the refunding date to each such maturity or sinking fund installment, and dividing the sum of the amounts thus obtained by the aggregate principal amount of such general obligation bonds to be refunded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Average term” means, with respect to any issue of general obligation refunding bonds, the product obtained by multiplying the principal amount of such general obligation refunding bonds maturing or subject to sinking fund installments in each bond year by the term of such general obligation refunding bonds, and dividing the sum of the amounts thus obtained by the aggregate principal amount of such issue of general obligation refunding bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bonds” includes bonds, debentures, notes, certificates of indebtedness, mortgage certificates, or other obligations or evidence of indebtedness of any type or character.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bond year” means the 1-year period commencing on the date of issuance of any bonds and each 1-year period subsequent thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Effective interest rate,” with respect to any issue of general obligation bonds or general obligation refunding bonds, means that rate which is equal to the internal rate of return, compounded at the same frequency as moneys are actually paid to bond owners, which equates all future debt service payments to the net proceeds realized by the unit from the issuance of general obligation bonds or general obligation refunding bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Escrow agent” means the department of any bank or trust company, within or without the state, appointed by the governing body of the unit to hold and invest the proceeds of refunding bonds issued pursuant to s. 132.35.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Escrow agreement” means an agreement entered into pursuant to s. 132.41 by and between a unit, as defined in s. 132.02, and the escrow agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General obligation bonds” means any bonds which are secured by, or provide for their payment by, the pledge, in addition to those special taxes levied for their discharge and such other sources as may be provided for their payment or pledged as security under the ordinance or resolution authorizing their issuance, of the full faith and credit and taxing power of the county or municipality issuing such bonds and for the payment of which recourse may be had against the general fund of such county or municipality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General obligation refunding bonds” means general obligation bonds issued pursuant to s. 132.35 for the purpose of refunding or refinancing all or part of a prior issue or multiple issues of general obligation bonds or general obligation refunding bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Governing body” means the board or body of a unit vested with the power of determining the amount of the tax levies required for taxing the taxable property of such unit for the purpose of such unit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Internal rate of return” means the rate which, when applied to a series of interest and principal payments due at different dates, will result in the determination of a present value which precisely equals the amount received at the time at which bonds are issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Issue” means any bonds which are issued at substantially the same time, are sold pursuant to a common plan of financing, and will be paid out of substantially the same source of funds or will have substantially the same claim to be paid out of substantially the same source of funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Maturity” means the date upon which any general obligation bond or general obligation refunding bond becomes due and payable to the owner thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Net average interest cost rate” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any general obligation bonds to be refunded, a fraction the numerator of which is the gross amount of interest to be paid from the refunding date through the remaining term of such bonds plus the original issue adjustment, and the denominator of which is the average remaining term of such general obligation bonds multiplied by the aggregate principal amount of such general obligation bonds outstanding on the refunding date; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any general obligation refunding bonds, a fraction the numerator of which is the gross amount of interest to be paid during the term of such refunding bonds plus the amount of any discount or minus the amount of any premium paid at the time of sale thereof, and the denominator of which is the average term of the issue of such general obligation refunding bonds multiplied by the aggregate principal amount thereof issued on the refunding date.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Net proceeds” means the total proceeds of any general obligation refunding bonds issued pursuant to s. 132.35, plus any premium received upon the sale of such general obligation refunding bonds, less the underwriter’s discount and all other management fees, costs, expenses, charges, and sales commissions associated with the issuance of such refunding bonds, including, but not limited to, any refunding expenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Original issue adjustment” means the product obtained by multiplying the amount of discount paid or the negative of the amount of premium received on the general obligation bonds to be refunded at the time of their issuance by a fraction, the numerator of which is the aggregate principal amount of general obligation bonds to be refunded on the refunding date and the denominator of which is the aggregate principal amount of the general obligation bonds originally issued, of which the general obligation bonds to be refunded are a part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Present value” means the amount computed by discounting the principal and interest payments on both the general obligation refunding bonds and the general obligation bonds to be refunded from the respective maturities, or sinking fund installment dates, thereof to the date of issue of such bonds at a rate equal to the effective interest rate of the refunding bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Refunding date” means the first date on which interest accrues on any refunding bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Refunding expenses” means the costs and expenses incidental to the issuance of general obligation refunding bonds, including, but not limited to, the costs and expenses of developing the refunding financial plan; credit enhancement costs and expenses; fees and expenses of consultants, advisers, and counsel; costs and expenses of printing disclosure documents and bonds; initial fees of the escrow agent, payment agent, and bond registrar; and the costs and fees of performing the terms and conditions of the escrow agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Refunding financial plan” means the financial plan for a refunding as set forth in the refunding bond resolution relating thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Refunding bond resolution” means a resolution or ordinance authorizing the issuance of refunding bonds adopted pursuant to s. 132.36.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Remaining term” means, with respect to any general obligation bonds to be refunded, the number of bond years from the refunding date to and including the earlier of the maturity or the sinking fund installment date of such bonds to be refunded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sinking fund installment” means the amount of term bonds subject to mandatory redemption in any bond year prior to the maturity of such term bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Term” means the number of bond years from the date of issuance of any bond to the date of its maturity, or date of earlier mandatory redemption for a sinking fund installment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Term bonds” means bonds maturing in a single bond year which are subject to sinking fund installments prior to their stated maturity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unit” means a county, city, town, special road and bridge district, special tax school district, and any other taxing district in the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-181; s. 26, ch. 91-45; s. 74, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326.</History></Section>