<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0132.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Levy of ad valorem tax for payment of bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In each year while any of the bonds shall be outstanding there shall be levied by or under the authority of the governing board upon all taxable property in the unit, an ad valorem tax sufficient to pay the interest and principal of such refunding bonds and any sinking funds which may be provided for by the bonds, or by the proceedings authorizing the sale, provided, however, that when there shall be in any fund or funds provided for such bonds, interest and sinking fund, an amount exceeding the amount at that time required for such fund or funds, the ad valorem tax required by this section for the current year may be reduced in the amount of such excess.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is expressly provided that in the case of taxing districts where bonds have been issued and are outstanding, which bonds are payable exclusively out of special assessments levied for the payment of such bonds, that no authority to levy an ad valorem tax upon the property of such taxing district shall be conferred or exist under this chapter, unless the same shall be duly authorized or approved by the affirmative vote of a majority of the taxpayers who are the owners of freeholds in said unit not wholly exempt from taxation voting at an election called and held under the provisions of law relating to the issuance of bonds under s. 12, Art. VII of the State Constitution and such election shall be called within 60 days after the governing body of such taxing district shall receive a petition requesting the same signed by a number of owners of freeholds not wholly exempt from taxation equal to 25 percent of the qualified electors who are owners of such freeholds residing in such district and by the holder or holders of a majority in amount of the bonds or outstanding indebtedness to be refunded, but nothing in this chapter shall preclude the issuance of refunding bonds under this chapter when such refunding bonds are issued and are provided to be supported by the proceeds of special assessments of the same kind and character as were provided for the issue which is refunded.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 15772, 1931; CGL 1936 Supp. 2383(22); s. 15, ch. 69-216.</History></Section>