<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0132.36" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Refunding bond resolution; form and contents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuance of general obligation refunding bonds shall be authorized by a refunding bond resolution. Each such resolution shall contain, in substance, at least the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum principal amount of general obligation refunding bonds authorized to be issued pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination that such maximum principal amount of general obligation refunding bonds does not exceed the limitation imposed by s. 132.35.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of the outstanding general obligation bonds to be refunded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial plan for the refunding proposed, showing the sources and amounts of all moneys required to accomplish such refunding; containing an estimate of the present value of the total debt service savings anticipated, computed in accordance with s. 132.35(2); and containing a statement that the general obligation refunding bonds will bear a lower net average interest cost rate than the general obligation bonds to be refunded.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without the assent of the electors, the refunding bond resolution may pledge to the payment of principal and interest of general obligation refunding bonds or to a sinking fund for such bonds only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such revenue or other security as is pledged to the payment of the general obligation bonds to be refunded;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent required by the refunding financial plan, all or a portion of the principal of and the interest on the moneys held in escrow by the escrow agent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other revenue or security as may otherwise be pledged by the unit without assent of the electors for and toward the payment of its general obligation bonds.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-181.</History></Section>