<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0044.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court-ordered mediation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Court-ordered mediation shall be conducted according to rules of practice and procedure adopted by the Supreme Court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court, under rules adopted by the Supreme Court:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must, upon request of one party, refer to mediation any filed civil action for monetary damages, provided the requesting party is willing and able to pay the costs of the mediation or the costs can be equitably divided between the parties, unless:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The action is a landlord and tenant dispute that does not include a claim for personal injury.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The action is filed for the purpose of collecting a debt.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The action is a claim of medical malpractice.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The action is governed by the Florida Small Claims Rules.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court determines that the action is proper for referral to nonbinding arbitration under this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parties have agreed to binding arbitration.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parties have agreed to an expedited trial pursuant to s. 45.075.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parties have agreed to voluntary trial resolution pursuant to s. 44.104.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May refer to mediation all or any part of a filed civil action for which mediation is not required under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In circuits in which a family mediation program has been established and upon a court finding of a dispute, shall refer to mediation all or part of custody, visitation, or other parental responsibility issues as defined in s. 61.13. Upon motion or request of a party, a court shall not refer any case to mediation if it finds there has been a history of domestic violence that would compromise the mediation process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In circuits in which a dependency or in need of services mediation program has been established, may refer to mediation all or any portion of a matter relating to dependency or to a child in need of services or a family in need of services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All written communications in a mediation proceeding, other than an executed settlement agreement, shall be exempt from the requirements of chapter 119.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief judge of each judicial circuit shall maintain a list of mediators who have been certified by the Supreme Court and who have registered for appointment in that circuit.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever possible, qualified individuals who have volunteered their time to serve as mediators shall be appointed. If a mediation program is funded pursuant to s. 44.108, volunteer mediators shall be entitled to reimbursement pursuant to s. 112.061 for all actual expenses necessitated by service as a mediator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonvolunteer mediators shall be compensated according to rules adopted by the Supreme Court. If a mediation program is funded pursuant to s. 44.108, a mediator may be compensated by the county or by the parties.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an action is referred to mediation by court order, the time periods for responding to an offer of settlement pursuant to s. 45.061, or to an offer or demand for judgment pursuant to s. 768.79, respectively, shall be tolled until:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An impasse has been declared by the mediator; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mediator has reported to the court that no agreement was reached.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 45.061 and 768.79 notwithstanding, an offer of settlement or an offer or demand for judgment may be made at any time after an impasse has been declared by the mediator, or the mediator has reported that no agreement was reached. An offer is deemed rejected as of commencement of trial.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 87-173; s. 2, ch. 89-31; s. 2, ch. 90-188; s. 2, ch. 93-161; s. 10, ch. 94-134; s. 10, ch. 94-135; s. 44, ch. 94-164; s. 18, ch. 96-406; s. 2, ch. 97-155; s. 2, ch. 99-225; s. 2, ch. 2002-65; s. 1, ch. 2004-291; s. 31, ch. 2005-236.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 44.302.</Text></Note></Section>