<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0044.403" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mediation Confidentiality and Privilege Act; definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 44.401-44.406, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mediation communication” means an oral or written statement, or nonverbal conduct intended to make an assertion, by or to a mediation participant made during the course of a mediation, or prior to mediation if made in furtherance of a mediation. The commission of a crime during a mediation is not a mediation communication.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mediation participant” means a mediation party or a person who attends a mediation in person or by telephone, videoconference, or other electronic means.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mediation party” or “party” means a person participating directly, or through a designated representative, in a mediation and a person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a named party;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a real party in interest; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Would be a named party or real party in interest if an action relating to the subject matter of the mediation were brought in a court of law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mediator” means a neutral, impartial third person who facilitates the mediation process. The mediator’s role is to reduce obstacles to communication, assist in identifying issues, explore alternatives, and otherwise facilitate voluntary agreements to resolve disputes, without prescribing what the resolution must be.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Subsequent proceeding” means an adjudicative process that follows a mediation, including related discovery.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2004-291.</History></Section>