<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0044.107" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Immunity for arbitrators, mediators, and mediator trainees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arbitrators serving under s. 44.103 or s. 44.104, mediators serving under s. 44.102, and trainees fulfilling the mentorship requirements for certification by the Supreme Court as a mediator shall have judicial immunity in the same manner and to the same extent as a judge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person serving as a mediator in any noncourt-ordered mediation shall have immunity from liability arising from the performance of that person’s duties while acting within the scope of the mediation function if such mediation is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Required by statute or agency rule or order;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducted under ss. 44.401-44.406 by express agreement of the mediation parties; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitated by a mediator certified by the Supreme Court, unless the mediation parties expressly agree not to be bound by ss. 44.401-44.406.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The mediator does not have immunity if he or she acts in bad faith, with malicious purpose, or in a manner exhibiting wanton and willful disregard of human rights, safety, or property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person serving under s. 44.106 to assist the Supreme Court in performing its disciplinary function shall have absolute immunity from liability arising from the performance of that person’s duties while acting within the scope of that person’s appointed function.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 89-31; s. 7, ch. 90-188; s. 1, ch. 95-421; s. 2, ch. 2004-291.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 44.307.</Text></Note></Section>