<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Resource planning and management committees; objectives; procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to recommending an area as an area of critical state concern pursuant to s. 380.05, the Governor, acting as the chief planning officer of the state, shall appoint a resource planning and management committee for the area under study by the state land planning agency. The objective of the committee shall be to organize a voluntary, cooperative resource planning and management program to resolve existing, and prevent future, problems which may endanger those resources, facilities, and areas described in s. 380.05(2) within the area under study by the state land planning agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The committee shall include, but shall not be limited to, representation from each of the following: elected officials from the local governments within the area under study; the planning office of each of the local governments within the area under study; the state land planning agency; any other state agency under chapter 20 a representative of which the Governor feels is relevant to the compilation of the committee; and a water management district, if appropriate, and regional planning council all or part of whose jurisdiction lies within the area under study. After the appointment of the members, the Governor shall select a chair and vice chair. A staff member of the state land planning agency shall be appointed by the director of such agency to serve as the secretary of the committee. The state land planning agency shall, to the greatest extent possible, provide technical assistance and administrative support to the committee. Meetings will be called as needed by the chair or on the demand of three or more members of the committee. The committee will act on a simple majority of a quorum present and shall make a report within 6 months to the head of the state land planning agency. The committee shall, from the time of appointment, remain in existence for no less than 6 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not later than 12 months after its appointment by the Governor, the committee shall either adopt a proposed voluntary resource planning and management program for the area under study or recommend that a voluntary resource planning and management program not be adopted. The proposed voluntary resource planning and management program shall contain the committee findings with respect to problems that endanger those resources, facilities, and areas described in s. 380.05(2) and shall contain detailed recommendations for state, regional, and local governmental actions necessary to resolve current and prevent future problems identified by the committee. A major objective of the proposed voluntary resource planning and management program shall be the effective coordination of state, regional, and local planning; program implementation; and regulatory activities for comprehensive resource management. The committee shall submit the proposed voluntary resource planning and management program to the head of the state land planning agency, who shall transmit the program along with the recommendations of the agency for monitoring and enforcing the program, as well as any other recommendations deemed appropriate, to the Administration Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Administration Commission shall by resolution approve, approve as modified, or reject the proposed voluntary resource planning and management program and state land planning agency recommendations; and the Administration Commission shall request each state or regional agency that is responsible for implementing a portion of an approved program to conduct its programs and regulatory activities in a manner consistent with the approved program. Each state and regional agency involved in implementing the program shall cooperate to the maximum extent possible in ensuring that the program is given full effect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall report to the Administration Commission within 12 months of the approval of the program by the commission concerning the implementation and the effects of the approved voluntary resource planning and management program. The report shall include, but shall not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of state agency compliance with the program, including the degree to which the program recommendations have been integrated into agency planning, program implementation, regulatory activities, and rules;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the compliance by each affected local government with the program;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An evaluation of state, regional, and local monitoring and enforcement activities and recommendations for improving such activities; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recommendation as to whether or not all or any portion of the study area should be designated an area of critical state concern pursuant to s. 380.05.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The state land planning agency may make such other reports to the commission as it deems necessary, including recommending that all or any portion of the study area be designated an area of critical state concern because of special circumstances in the study area or in the implementation of the approved voluntary resource planning and management program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 79-73; s. 1, ch. 84-281; s. 640, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>