<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.0666" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of land authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The land authority shall have all the powers necessary or convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes and provisions of this act, including the following powers, which are in addition to all other powers granted by other provisions of this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and be sued; to have a seal, to alter the same at pleasure, and to authorize the use of a facsimile thereof; and to make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to the exercise of the powers of the land authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To undertake and carry out studies and analyses of county land planning needs within areas of critical state concern and ways of meeting those needs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire and dispose of real and personal property or any interest therein when such acquisition is necessary or appropriate to protect the natural environment, provide public access or public recreational facilities, preserve wildlife habitat areas, provide affordable housing to families whose income does not exceed 160 percent of the median family income for the area, or provide access to management of acquired lands; to acquire interests in land by means of land exchanges; and to enter into all alternatives to the acquisition of fee interests in land, including, but not limited to, the acquisition of easements, development rights, life estates, leases, and leaseback arrangements. However, the land authority shall make such acquisition only if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such acquisition is consistent with land development regulations and local comprehensive plans adopted and approved pursuant to this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property acquired is within an area designated as an area of critical state concern at the time of acquisition or is within an area that was designated as an area of critical state concern for at least 20 consecutive years prior to removal of the designation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property to be acquired has not been selected for purchase through another local, regional, state, or federal public land acquisition program. Such restriction shall not apply if the land authority cooperates with the other public land acquisition programs which listed the lands for acquisition, to coordinate the acquisition and disposition of such lands. In such cases, the land authority may enter into contractual or other agreements to acquire lands jointly or for eventual resale to other public land acquisition programs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To borrow money through the issuance of bonds for the purposes provided in this act, to provide for and secure the payment thereof, and to provide for the rights of the holders thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To purchase bonds of the land authority out of any funds or moneys of the land authority available therefor and to hold, cancel, or resell such bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To invest any funds held in reserves or sinking funds, or any funds not required for immediate disbursement, in such investments as may be authorized for trust funds under s. 215.47, and in any authorized investments, if such investments are made on behalf of the land authority by the State Board of Administration or by another trustee appointed for that purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract for and to accept gifts, grants, loans, or other aid from the United States Government or any person or corporation, including gifts of real property or any interest therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To insure and procure insurance against any loss in connection with any bonds of the land authority and the land authority’s operations, including without limitation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The repayment of any loans to mortgage lenders or mortgage loans;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any project;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bonds of the land authority;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">in such amounts and from such insurers, including the Federal Government, as it may deem necessary or desirable and to pay any premiums therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make rules pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120 necessary to carry out the purposes of this act and to exercise any power granted in this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To engage the services of private consultants on a contract basis for rendering professional and technical assistance and advice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make and execute agreements, contracts, and other instruments necessary or convenient in the exercise of the powers and functions of the land authority under this act, including contracts with any person, firm, corporation, local government, or other entity; and all local governments established under the laws of the state are hereby authorized to enter into and do all things necessary to perform such contracts and otherwise cooperate with the land authority to facilitate the accomplishment of the purposes of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To undertake any actions necessary to conduct a feasibility and design study for a solid waste management facility in an area of critical state concern and, if such project is feasible, to carry out such project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To identify parcels of land within the area or areas of critical state concern that would be appropriate acquisitions by the state from the Conservation and Recreational Lands Trust Fund and recommend such acquisitions to the advisory council established pursuant to s. 259.035 or its successor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To do any and all things necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of, and exercise the powers given and granted in, this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-170; s. 5, ch. 88-164; s. 3, ch. 88-376; s. 15, ch. 89-116; s. 10, ch. 92-288; s. 40, ch. 99-247; s. 4, ch. 2006-223.</History></Section>