<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0380.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Communities Trust; creation; membership; expenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Environmental Protection a nonregulatory state agency and instrumentality, which shall be a public body corporate and politic, known as the “Florida Communities Trust.” The governing body of the trust shall consist of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Environmental Protection; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four public members whom the Governor shall appoint subject to Senate confirmation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Governor shall appoint a former elected official of a county government, a former elected official of a metropolitan municipal government, a representative of a nonprofit organization as defined in this part, and a representative of the development industry. The Secretary of Environmental Protection may appoint his or her deputy secretary, the director of the Division of State Lands, or the director of the Division of Recreation and Parks to serve in his or her absence. The Secretary of Environmental Protection shall be the chair of the governing body of the trust. The Governor shall make his or her appointments upon the expiration of any current terms or within 60 days after the effective date of the resignation of any member.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the initial governing body members, two of the Governor’s appointees shall serve for a term of 2 years and the remaining one shall serve for a term of 4 years from the date of appointment. Thereafter, governing body members whom the Governor appoints shall serve for terms of 4 years. The Governor may fill any vacancy for an unexpired term.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Governing body members shall receive no compensation for their services, but shall be entitled to the necessary expenses, including per diem and travel expenses, incurred in the discharge of their duties pursuant to this part, as provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 89-175; s. 2, ch. 90-192; s. 17, ch. 90-217; s. 7, ch. 91-192; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 67, ch. 93-206; s. 350, ch. 94-356; s. 1031, ch. 95-148; s. 44, ch. 99-247; s. 263, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>