<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coordinated agency review; Florida Keys area.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to facilitate the planning and preparation of permit applications for projects in the Florida Keys area of critical state concern, and in order to coordinate the information required to issue such permits, a developer may elect to request coordinated agency review under this section at the time of application for a development permit subject to s. 380.05.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Coordinated agency review” means review of the proposed location, densities, intensity of use, character, major design features, and environmental impacts of a proposed development in the Florida Keys area of critical state concern required to undergo review under s. 380.05 for the purposes of considering whether these aspects of the proposed development comply with the certifying agency’s statutes and rules.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a developer chooses to seek review under this section, the developer shall complete a coordinated review application and the state land planning agency shall distribute copies of the application to participating agencies. Each state and regional agency with jurisdiction over the project shall certify, within 60 days of receipt of such application, whether the project is consistent with agency statutes and rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection, the Department of Health, and other state and regional agencies that require permits in the Florida Keys area of critical state concern shall, within 180 days after the effective date of this act, enter into interagency agreements with the state land planning agency to establish a set of procedures necessary for coordinated agency review created pursuant to this section. Such procedures shall be consistent with paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and regional agencies shall enter into intergovernmental agreements with local governments in the Florida Keys area of critical state concern to coordinate their permit review, including delegation of review authority to local governments, where applicable, to ensure that state and regional agency decisions are reached in coordination with the local government decision on the local government order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and regional agencies shall coordinate with local governments and, when possible, federal permitting agencies to standardize, to the extent possible, review procedures, data requirements, and data collection methodologies among all participating agencies operating in the Florida Keys area of critical state concern consistent with the requirements of the statutes for permitting programs for each agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and regional agencies may adopt rules to implement the procedures for coordinated agency review under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 86-170; s. 341, ch. 94-356; s. 6, ch. 97-253; s. 1, ch. 2000-283.</History></Section>