<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0380.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administration commission” or “commission” means the Governor and the Cabinet; and for purposes of this chapter the commission shall act on a simple majority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Developer” means any person, including a governmental agency, undertaking any development as defined in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Development order” means any order granting, denying, or granting with conditions an application for a development permit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Development permit” includes any building permit, zoning permit, plat approval, or rezoning, certification, variance, or other action having the effect of permitting development as defined in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Downtown development authority” means a local governmental agency established under part III of chapter 163 or created with similar powers and responsibilities by special act for the purpose of planning, coordinating, and assisting in the implementation, revitalization, and redevelopment of a specific downtown area of a city.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Governmental agency” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States or any department, commission, agency, or other instrumentality thereof;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This state or any department, commission, agency, or other instrumentality thereof;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any local government, as defined in this chapter, or any department, commission, agency, or other instrumentality thereof;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any school board or other special district, authority, or other governmental entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land” means the earth, water, and air above, below, or on the surface, and includes any improvements or structures customarily regarded as land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land development regulations” include local zoning, subdivision, building, and other regulations controlling the development of land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land use” means the development that has occurred on land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local comprehensive plan” means any or all local comprehensive plans or elements or portions thereof prepared, adopted, or amended pursuant to the Community Planning Act, as amended.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local government” means any county or municipality and, where relevant, any joint airport zoning board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Major public facility” means any publicly owned facility of more than local significance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Parcel of land” means any quantity of land capable of being described with such definiteness that its location and boundaries may be established, which is designated by its owner or developer as land to be used or developed as a unit or which has been used or developed as a unit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual, corporation, governmental agency, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any other legal entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Regional planning agency” means the agency designated by the state land planning agency to exercise responsibilities under this chapter in a particular region of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rule” means a rule adopted under chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State land development plan” means a comprehensive statewide plan or any portion thereof setting forth state land development policies. Such plan shall not have any legal effect until enacted by general law or the Legislature confers express rulemaking authority on the state land planning agency to adopt such plan by rule for specific application.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State land planning agency” means the Department of Economic Opportunity and may be referred to in this part as the “department.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Structure” means anything constructed, installed, or portable, the use of which requires a location on a parcel of land. It includes a movable structure while it is located on land which can be used for housing, business, commercial, agricultural, or office purposes either temporarily or permanently. “Structure” also includes fences, billboards, swimming pools, poles, pipelines, transmission lines, tracks, and advertising signs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resource planning and management committee” or “committee” means a committee appointed pursuant to s. 380.045.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 72-317; s. 1, ch. 79-73; s. 1, ch. 80-313; s. 1, ch. 83-308; s. 41, ch. 85-55; s. 32, ch. 98-176; s. 53, ch. 2011-139; s. 257, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>