<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Areas of critical state concern.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency may from time to time recommend to the Administration Commission specific areas of critical state concern. In its recommendation, the agency shall include recommendations with respect to the purchase of lands situated within the boundaries of the proposed area as environmentally endangered lands and outdoor recreation lands under the Land Conservation Act of 1972. The agency also shall include any report or recommendation of a resource planning and management committee appointed pursuant to s. 380.045; the dangers that would result from uncontrolled or inadequate development of the area and the advantages that would be achieved from the development of the area in a coordinated manner; a detailed boundary description of the proposed area; specific principles for guiding development within the area; an inventory of lands owned by the state, federal, county, and municipal governments within the proposed area; and a list of the state agencies with programs that affect the purpose of the designation. The agency shall recommend actions which the local government and state and regional agencies must accomplish in order to implement the principles for guiding development. These actions may include, but shall not be limited to, revisions of the local comprehensive plan and adoption of land development regulations, density requirements, and special permitting requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 45 days following receipt of a recommendation from the agency, the commission shall either reject the recommendation as tendered or adopt the recommendation with or without modification and by rule designate the area of critical state concern. Any rule that designates an area of critical state concern must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A detailed boundary description of the area.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Principles for guiding development.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear statement of the purpose for the designation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A precise checklist of actions which, when implemented, will result in repeal of the designation by the Administration Commission, and the agencies or entities responsible for taking those actions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of those issues or programs for which mechanisms must be in place to assure ongoing implementation of the actions taken to result in repeal of the designation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of the state agencies which, in addition to those specified in subsection (22), administer programs that affect the purpose of the designation.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The rule shall become effective 20 days after being filed with the Secretary of State, except that an emergency rule adopted by the commission and designating an area of critical state concern shall become effective immediately on being filed. Any rule adopted pursuant to this paragraph shall be presented to the Legislature for review pursuant to paragraph (c). A statement of estimated regulatory costs prepared pursuant to s. 120.541 shall not be a ground for a challenge of the rule; however, a landowner shall not be precluded from using adverse economic results as grounds for challenge. Such principles for guiding development shall apply to any development undertaken subsequent to the legislative review pursuant to paragraph (c) of the designation of the area of critical state concern with or without modification but prior to the adoption of land development rules and regulations or a local comprehensive plan for the critical area pursuant to subsections (6) and (8). No boundaries or principles for guiding development shall be adopted without a specific finding by the commission that the boundaries or principles are consistent with the purpose of the designation. The commission is not authorized to adopt any rule that would provide for a moratorium on development in any area of critical state concern.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rule adopted by the commission pursuant to paragraph (b) designating an area of critical state concern and principles for guiding development shall be submitted to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives for review no later than 30 days prior to the next regular session of the Legislature. The Legislature may reject, modify, or take no action relative to the adopted rule. In its deliberations, the Legislature may consider, among other factors, whether a resource planning and management committee has established a program pursuant to s. 380.045. In addition to any other data and information required pursuant to this chapter, each rule presented to the Legislature shall include a detailed legal description of the boundary of the area of critical state concern, proposed principles for guiding development, and a detailed statement of how the area meets the criteria for designation as provided in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, after the repeal of the boundary designation of an area of critical state concern pursuant to subsection (15), the state land planning agency determines that the administration of the local land development regulations or a local comprehensive plan within a formerly designated area is inadequate to protect the former area of critical state concern, then the state land planning agency may recommend to the commission that the area be redesignated as an area of critical state concern. Within 45 days following the receipt of the recommendation from the agency, the commission shall either reject the recommendation as tendered or adopt the same with or without modification. The commission may, by rule, make such redesignation effective immediately, at which time the boundaries, regulations, and plans in effect at the time the previous designation was repealed shall be reinstated. Within 90 days of such redesignation, the commission shall begin rulemaking procedures to designate the area an area of critical state concern under paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area of critical state concern may be designated only for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area containing, or having a significant impact upon, environmental or natural resources of regional or statewide importance, including, but not limited to, state or federal parks, forests, wildlife refuges, wilderness areas, aquatic preserves, major rivers and estuaries, state environmentally endangered lands, Outstanding Florida Waters, and aquifer recharge areas, the uncontrolled private or public development of which would cause substantial deterioration of such resources. Specific criteria which shall be considered in designating an area under this paragraph include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the economic value of the area, as determined by the type, variety, distribution, relative scarcity, and condition of the environmental or natural resources within the area, is of substantial regional or statewide importance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the ecological value of the area, as determined by the physical and biological components of the environmental system, is of substantial regional or statewide importance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area is a designated critical habitat of any state or federally designated threatened or endangered plant or animal species.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area is inherently susceptible to substantial development due to its geographic location or natural aesthetics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether any existing or planned substantial development within the area will directly, significantly, and deleteriously affect any or all of the environmental or natural resources of the area which are of regional or statewide importance.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area containing, or having a significant impact upon, historical or archaeological resources, sites, or statutorily defined historical or archaeological districts, the private or public development of which would cause substantial deterioration or complete loss of such resources, sites, or districts. Specific criteria which shall be considered in designating an area under this paragraph include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area is associated with events that have made a significant contribution to the history of the state or region.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area is associated with the lives of persons who are significant to the history of the state or region.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area contains any structure that embodies the distinctive characteristics of a type, period, or method of construction, that represents the work of a master, that possesses high artistic values, or that represents a significant and distinguishable entity the components of which may lack individual distinction and which are of regional or statewide importance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area has yielded, or will likely yield, information important to the prehistory or history of the state or region.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area having a significant impact upon, or being significantly impacted by, an existing or proposed major public facility or other area of major public investment including, but not limited to, highways, ports, airports, energy facilities, and water management projects.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each regional planning agency may recommend to the state land planning agency from time to time areas wholly or partially within its jurisdiction that meet the criteria for areas of critical state concern as defined in this section. Each regional planning agency shall solicit from the local governments within its jurisdiction suggestions as to areas to be recommended. A local government in an area where there is no regional planning agency may recommend to the state land planning agency from time to time areas wholly or partially within its jurisdiction that meet the criteria for areas of critical state concern as defined in this section. If the state land planning agency does not recommend to the commission as an area of critical state concern an area substantially similar to one that has been recommended, it shall respond in writing as to its reasons therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to submitting any recommendation to the commission under subsection (1), the state land planning agency shall give notice to any committee appointed pursuant to s. 380.045 and to all local governments and regional planning agencies that include within their boundaries any part of any area of critical state concern proposed to be designated by the rule, in addition to any notice otherwise required under chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the commission adopts a rule designating the boundaries of, and principles for guiding development in, an area of critical state concern and within 180 days of such adoption, the local government having jurisdiction may submit to the state land planning agency its existing land development regulations and local comprehensive plan for the area, if any, or shall prepare, adopt, and submit the new or modified regulations and plan, the local government taking into consideration the principles set forth in the rule designating the area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once the state land planning agency determines whether the land development regulations or local comprehensive plan or amendment submitted by a local government is consistent with the principles for guiding the development of the area specified under the rule designating the area, the state land planning agency shall approve or reject the land development regulations or portions thereof by final order, and shall determine compliance of the plan or amendment, or portions thereof, pursuant to s. 163.3184. The state land planning agency shall publish its final order to approve or reject land development regulations, which shall constitute final agency action, in the Florida Administrative Weekly. If the final order is challenged pursuant to s. 120.57, the state planning agency has the burden of proving the validity of the final order. Such approval or rejection of the land development regulations shall be no later than 60 days after submission of the land development regulations by the local government. No proposed land development regulation within an area of critical state concern becomes effective under this subsection until the state land planning agency issues its final order or, if the final order is challenged, until the challenge to the order is resolved pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency and any applicable regional planning agency shall, to the greatest extent possible, provide technical assistance to local governments in the preparation of the land development regulations and local comprehensive plan for areas of critical state concern.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any local government fails to submit land development regulations or a local comprehensive plan, or if the regulations or plan or plan amendment submitted do not comply with the principles for guiding development set out in the rule designating the area of critical state concern, within 120 days after the adoption of the rule designating an area of critical state concern, or within 120 days after the issuance of a recommended order on the compliance of the plan or plan amendment pursuant to s. 163.3184, or within 120 days after the effective date of an order rejecting a proposed land development regulation, the state land planning agency shall submit to the commission recommended land development regulations and a local comprehensive plan or portions thereof applicable to that local government’s portion of the area of critical state concern. Within 45 days following receipt of the recommendation from the agency, the commission shall either reject the recommendation as tendered or adopt the recommendation with or without modification, and by rule establish land development regulations and a local comprehensive plan applicable to that local government’s portion of the area of critical state concern. However, such rule shall not become effective prior to legislative review of an area of critical state concern pursuant to paragraph (1)(c). In the rule, the commission shall specify the extent to which its land development regulations, plans, or plan amendments will supersede, or will be supplementary to, local land development regulations and plans. Notice of any proposed rule issued under this section shall be given to all local governments and regional planning agencies in the area of critical state concern, in addition to any other notice required under chapter 120. The land development regulations and local comprehensive plan adopted by the commission under this section may include any type of regulation and plan that could have been adopted by the local government. Any land development regulations or local comprehensive plan or plan amendments adopted by the commission under this section shall be administered by the local government as part of, or in the absence of, the local land development regulations and local comprehensive plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, within 12 months after the commission adopts a rule designating an area of critical state concern, land development regulations or local comprehensive plans for the area have not become effective under either subsection (6) or subsection (8), the designation of the area as an area of critical state concern terminates. No part of such area may be recommended for redesignation until at least 12 months after the date the designation terminates pursuant to this subsection. The running of the 12-month period subsequent to the initial designation shall be tolled upon challenge pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120 to either the designation of the area of critical state concern or the adoption of land development regulations and local comprehensive plans under subsection (6) or subsection (8).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time after the adoption of land development regulations and plans by the commission under this section, a local government may propose land development regulations or a local comprehensive plan which, if approved by the state land planning agency as provided in subsection (6), will supersede any regulations or plans adopted under subsection (8).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land development regulations or a local comprehensive plan submitted by a local government in an area of critical state concern and approved pursuant to subsection (6) may be amended or rescinded by the local government, but the amendment or rescission becomes effective only upon approval thereof by the state land planning agency. The state land planning agency shall either approve or reject the requested changes within 60 days of receipt thereof. Land development regulations or local comprehensive plans for an area of critical state concern adopted by the commission under subsection (8) may be amended or rescinded by rule by the commission in the same manner as for original adoption.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the request of a substantially interested person pursuant to s. 120.54(7), a local government or regional planning agency within the designated area, or the state land planning agency, the commission may by rule remove, contract, or expand any designated boundary. Boundary expansions are subject to legislative review pursuant to paragraph (1)(c). No boundary may be modified without a specific finding by the commission that such changes are consistent with necessary resource protection. The total boundaries of an entire area of critical state concern shall not be removed by the commission unless a minimum time of 1 year has elapsed from the adoption of regulations and a local comprehensive plan pursuant to subsection (1), subsection (6), subsection (8), or subsection (10). Before totally removing such boundaries, the commission shall make findings that the regulations and plans adopted pursuant to subsection (1), subsection (6), subsection (8), or subsection (10) are being effectively implemented by local governments within the area of critical state concern to protect the area and that adopted local government comprehensive plans within the area have been conformed to principles for guiding development for the area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the state land planning agency determines that the administration of the local land development regulations or local comprehensive plans within the area is inadequate to protect the state or regional interest prior to the repeal of the critical state concern designation pursuant to subsection (15), the state land planning agency may institute appropriate judicial proceedings, as provided in s. 380.11, to compel proper enforcement of the land development regulations or plans.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any local government which lies either wholly or partially within an area of critical state concern and which has previously adopted a local government comprehensive plan pursuant to chapter 163 shall conform such plan to the principles for guiding development for the area of critical state concern. No later than January 1, 1984, or any other time as agreed upon in writing by the state land planning agency and the governing body of the local government, these plans shall be submitted to the state land planning agency for review and action as provided in subsection (6) or subsection (8).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any rule adopted pursuant to this section designating the boundaries of an area of critical state concern and the principles for guiding development therein shall be repealed by the commission no earlier than 12 months and no later than 3 years after approval by the state land planning agency or adoption by the commission of all land development regulations and local comprehensive plans pursuant to subsection (6), subsection (8), or subsection (10), and the implementation of all the actions listed in the designation rule for repeal of the designation. Any repeal pursuant to this subsection may be limited to any portion of the area of critical state concern. The repeal must be contingent upon approval by the state land planning agency of local land development regulations and plans pursuant to subsection (6) or subsection (10) and upon such regulations and plans being effective for a period of 12 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall undertake any development within any area of critical state concern except in accordance with this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an area of critical state concern has been designated under subsection (1) and if land development regulations for the area of critical state concern have not yet become effective under subsection (6) or subsection (8), a local government may grant development permits in accordance with such land development regulations as were in effect immediately prior to the designation of the area as an area of critical state concern.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the designation of an area of critical state concern nor the adoption of any regulations for such an area shall in any way limit or modify the rights of any person to complete any development that was authorized by registration of a subdivision pursuant to former chapter 498 or former chapter 478, by recordation pursuant to local subdivision plat law, or by a building permit or other authorization to commence development on which there has been reliance and a change of position, and which registration or recordation was accomplished, or which permit or authorization was issued, prior to the approval under subsection (6), or the adoption under subsection (8), of land development regulations for the area of critical state concern. If a developer has by his or her actions in reliance on prior regulations obtained vested or other legal rights that in law would have prevented a local government from changing those regulations in a way adverse to the developer’s interests, nothing in this chapter authorizes any governmental agency to abridge those rights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other notice required to be given under the local land development regulations, the local government shall give notice to the state land planning agency of any application for a development permit in any area of critical state concern, except to the extent that the state land planning agency has in writing waived its right to such notice in regard to all or certain classes of such applications. The state land planning agency may by rule specify additional classes of persons who shall have the right to receive notices of, and participate in, hearings under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At no time shall a land area be designated an area of critical state concern if the effect of such designation would be to subject more than 5 percent of the land of the state to supervision under this section; except that, if any supervision by the state is retained, the area shall be considered to be included within the limitations of this subsection. If 5 percent of the lands of the state are designated as areas of critical state concern pursuant to this section, a redesignation pursuant to paragraph (1)(d) will not be prohibited by this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after the effective date of the designation of an area of critical state concern pursuant to paragraph (1)(c) or paragraph (1)(d), the state land planning agency shall record a legal description of the boundaries of the area of critical state concern in the public records of the county or counties in which the area of critical state concern is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state agencies with rulemaking authority for programs that affect a designated area of critical state concern shall review those programs for consistency with the purpose of the designation and principles for guiding development, and shall adopt specific permitting standards and criteria applicable in the designated area, or otherwise amend the program, as necessary to further the purpose of the designation.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 6 months after the effective date of the rule or statute that designates an area of critical state concern, and at any time thereafter as directed by the Administration Commission, the Department of Environmental Protection, the Department of Health, the water management districts with jurisdiction over any portion of the area of critical state concern, and any other state agency specified in the designation rule, shall each submit a report to the Administration Commission, and a copy of the report to the state land planning agency. The report shall evaluate the effect of the reporting agency’s programs upon the purpose of the designation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If different permitting standards or criteria, or other changes to the program, are necessary in order to further the purpose of the designation, the report shall recommend rules which further that purpose and which are consistent with the principles for guiding development. The report shall explain and justify the reasons for any different permitting standards or criteria that may be recommended. The commission shall reject the agency’s recommendation, or accept it with or without modification and direct the agency to adopt rules, including any changes. Any rule adopted pursuant to this paragraph shall be consistent with the principles for guiding development, and shall apply only within the boundary of the designated area. The agency shall file a copy of the adopted rule with the Administration Commission and the state land planning agency.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If statutory changes are required in order to implement the permitting standards or criteria that are necessary to further the purpose of the designation, the report shall recommend statutory amendments. The Administration Commission shall submit any report that recommends statutory amendments to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, together with the Administration Commission’s recommendation on the proposed amendments.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Administration Commission has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 72-317; s. 1, ch. 74-326; s. 1, ch. 76-190; s. 4, ch. 79-73; s. 235, ch. 81-259; s. 3, ch. 83-308; s. 2, ch. 84-281; s. 50, ch. 93-206; s. 340, ch. 94-356; s. 1027, ch. 95-148; s. 113, ch. 96-410; s. 5, ch. 97-253; s. 92, ch. 98-200; s. 27, ch. 99-5; s. 71, ch. 99-8; s. 16, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>