<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0380.0552" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Keys Area; protection and designation as area of critical state concern.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “Florida Keys Area Protection Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is the intent of the Legislature to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Establish a land use management system that protects the natural environment of the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Establish a land use management system that conserves and promotes the community character of the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Establish a land use management system that promotes orderly and balanced growth in accordance with the capacity of available and planned public facilities and services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Provide affordable housing in close proximity to places of employment in the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Establish a land use management system that promotes and supports a diverse and sound economic base.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Protect the constitutional rights of property owners to own, use, and dispose of their real property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Promote coordination and efficiency among governmental agencies that have permitting jurisdiction over land use activities in the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote an appropriate land acquisition and protection strategy for environmentally sensitive lands within the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protect and improve the nearshore water quality of the Florida Keys through the construction and operation of wastewater management facilities that meet the requirements of ss. 381.0065(4)(l) and 403.086(10), as applicable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the population of the Florida Keys can be safely evacuated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RATIFICATION OF DESIGNATION.<EmDash />The designation of the Florida Keys Area as an area of critical state concern, the boundaries of which are described in chapter 27F-8, Florida Administrative Code, as amended effective August 23, 1984, is hereby ratified.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REMOVAL OF DESIGNATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> The designation of the Florida Keys Area as an area of critical state concern under this section may be recommended for removal upon fulfilling the legislative intent under subsection (2) and completion of all the work program tasks specified in rules of the Administration Commission. </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning November 30, 2010, the state land planning agency shall annually submit a written report to the Administration Commission describing the progress of the Florida Keys Area toward completing the work program tasks specified in commission rules. The land planning agency shall recommend removing the Florida Keys Area from being designated as an area of critical state concern to the commission if it determines that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All of the work program tasks have been completed, including construction of, operation of, and connection to central wastewater management facilities pursuant to s. 403.086(10) and upgrade of onsite sewage treatment and disposal systems pursuant to s. 381.0065(4)(l);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All local comprehensive plans and land development regulations and the administration of such plans and regulations are adequate to protect the Florida Keys Area, fulfill the legislative intent specified in subsection (2), and are consistent with and further the principles guiding development; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government has adopted a resolution at a public hearing recommending the removal of the designation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After receipt of the state land planning agency report and recommendation, the Administration Commission shall determine whether the requirements have been fulfilled and may remove the designation of the Florida Keys as an area of critical state concern. If the commission removes the designation, it shall initiate rulemaking to repeal any rules relating to such designation within 60 days. If, after receipt of the state land planning agency’s report and recommendation, the commission finds that the requirements for recommending removal of designation have not been met, the commission shall provide a written report to the local governments within 30 days after making such a finding detailing the tasks that must be completed by the local government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Administration Commission’s determination concerning the removal of the designation of the Florida Keys as an area of critical state concern may be reviewed pursuant to chapter 120. All proceedings shall be conducted by the Division of Administrative Hearings and must be initiated within 30 days after the commission issues its determination. </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After removal of the designation of the Florida Keys as an area of critical state concern, the state land planning agency shall review proposed local comprehensive plans, and any amendments to existing comprehensive plans, which are applicable to the Florida Keys Area, the boundaries of which were described in chapter 28-29, Florida Administrative Code, as of January 1, 2006, for compliance as defined in s. 163.3184. All procedures and penalties described in s. 163.3184 apply to the review conducted pursuant to this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Administration Commission may adopt rules or revise existing rules as necessary to administer this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION OF THIS CHAPTER.<EmDash />Section 380.05(1)-(5), (9)-(11), (15), (17), and (21) shall not apply to the area designated by this section for so long as the designation remains in effect. Except as otherwise provided in this section, s. 380.045 shall not apply to the area designated by this section. All other provisions of this chapter shall apply, including s. 380.07.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESOURCE PLANNING AND MANAGEMENT COMMITTEE.<EmDash />The Governor, acting as the chief planning officer of the state, shall appoint a resource planning and management committee for the Florida Keys Area with the membership as specified in s. 380.045(2). Meetings shall be called as needed by the chair or on the demand of three or more members of the committee. The committee shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as a liaison between the state and local governments within Monroe County.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, with local government officials in the Florida Keys Area, recommendations to the state land planning agency as to the sufficiency of the Florida Keys Area’s comprehensive plan and land development regulations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the state land planning agency changes to state and regional plans and regulatory programs affecting the Florida Keys Area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist units of local government within the Florida Keys Area in carrying out the planning functions and other responsibilities required by this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review, at a minimum, all reports and other materials provided to it by the state land planning agency or other governmental agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRINCIPLES FOR GUIDING DEVELOPMENT.<EmDash />State, regional, and local agencies and units of government in the Florida Keys Area shall coordinate their plans and conduct their programs and regulatory activities consistent with the principles for guiding development as specified in chapter 27F-8, Florida Administrative Code, as amended effective August 23, 1984, which is adopted and incorporated herein by reference. For the purposes of reviewing the consistency of the adopted plan, or any amendments to that plan, with the principles for guiding development, and any amendments to the principles, the principles shall be construed as a whole and specific provisions may not be construed or applied in isolation from the other provisions. However, the principles for guiding development are repealed 18 months from July 1, 1986. After repeal, any plan amendments must be consistent with the following principles:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Strengthening local government capabilities for managing land use and development so that local government is able to achieve these objectives without continuing the area of critical state concern designation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protecting shoreline and marine resources, including mangroves, coral reef formations, seagrass beds, wetlands, fish and wildlife, and their habitat.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protecting upland resources, tropical biological communities, freshwater wetlands, native tropical vegetation (for example, hardwood hammocks and pinelands), dune ridges and beaches, wildlife, and their habitat.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring the maximum well-being of the Florida Keys and its citizens through sound economic development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limiting the adverse impacts of development on the quality of water throughout the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enhancing natural scenic resources, promoting the aesthetic benefits of the natural environment, and ensuring that development is compatible with the unique historic character of the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protecting the historical heritage of the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protecting the value, efficiency, cost-effectiveness, and amortized life of existing and proposed major public investments, including:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Keys Aqueduct and water supply facilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sewage collection, treatment, and disposal facilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solid waste treatment, collection, and disposal facilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Key West Naval Air Station and other military facilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation facilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal parks, wildlife refuges, and marine sanctuaries;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State parks, recreation facilities, aquatic preserves, and other publicly owned properties;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">City electric service and the Florida Keys Electric Co-op; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other utilities, as appropriate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protecting and improving water quality by providing for the construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of stormwater management facilities; central sewage collection; treatment and disposal facilities; and the installation and proper operation and maintenance of onsite sewage treatment and disposal systems.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring the improvement of nearshore water quality by requiring the construction and operation of wastewater management facilities that meet the requirements of ss. 381.0065(4)(l) and 403.086(10), as applicable, and by directing growth to areas served by central wastewater treatment facilities through permit allocation systems.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limiting the adverse impacts of public investments on the environmental resources of the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making available adequate affordable housing for all sectors of the population of the Florida Keys.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing adequate alternatives for the protection of public safety and welfare in the event of a natural or manmade disaster and for a postdisaster reconstruction plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protecting the public health, safety, and welfare of the citizens of the Florida Keys and maintaining the Florida Keys as a unique Florida resource.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPREHENSIVE PLAN ELEMENTS AND LAND DEVELOPMENT REGULATIONS.<EmDash />The comprehensive plan elements and land development regulations approved pursuant to s. 380.05(6), (8), and (14) shall be the comprehensive plan elements and land development regulations for the Florida Keys Area.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MODIFICATION TO PLANS AND REGULATIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any land development regulation or element of a local comprehensive plan in the Florida Keys Area may be enacted, amended, or rescinded by a local government, but the enactment, amendment, or rescission becomes effective only upon approval by the state land planning agency. The state land planning agency shall review the proposed change to determine if it is in compliance with the principles for guiding development specified in chapter 27F-8, Florida Administrative Code, as amended effective August 23, 1984, and must approve or reject the requested changes within 60 days after receipt. Amendments to local comprehensive plans in the Florida Keys Area must also be reviewed for compliance with the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construction schedules and detailed capital financing plans for wastewater management improvements in the annually adopted capital improvements element, and standards for the construction of wastewater treatment and disposal facilities or collection systems that meet or exceed the criteria in s. 403.086(10) for wastewater treatment and disposal facilities or s. 381.0065(4)(l) for onsite sewage treatment and disposal systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Goals, objectives, and policies to protect public safety and welfare in the event of a natural disaster by maintaining a hurricane evacuation clearance time for permanent residents of no more than 24 hours. The hurricane evacuation clearance time shall be determined by a hurricane evacuation study conducted in accordance with a professionally accepted methodology and approved by the state land planning agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> The state land planning agency, after consulting with the appropriate local government, may, no more than once per year, recommend to the Administration Commission the enactment, amendment, or rescission of a land development regulation or element of a local comprehensive plan. Within 45 days following the receipt of such recommendation, the commission shall reject the recommendation, or accept it with or without modification and adopt it by rule, including any changes. Such local development regulation or plan must be in compliance with the principles for guiding development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 79-73; s. 4, ch. 86-170; s. 1, ch. 89-342; s. 641, ch. 95-148; s. 3, ch. 2006-223; s. 34, ch. 2010-205; s. 26, ch. 2011-4.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 7, ch. 2006-223, provides that “[i]f the designation of the Florida Keys Area as an area of critical state concern is removed, the state shall be liable in any inverse condemnation action initiated as a result of Monroe County land use regulations applicable to the Florida Keys Area as described in chapter 28-29, Florida Administrative Code, and adopted pursuant to instructions from the Administration Commission or pursuant to administrative rule of the Administration Commission, to the same extent that the state was liable on the date the Administration Commission determined that substantial progress had been made toward accomplishing the tasks of the work program as defined in s. 380.0552(4)(c), Florida Statutes. If, after the designation of the Florida Keys Area as an area of critical state concern is removed, an inverse condemnation action is initiated based upon land use regulations that were not adopted pursuant to instructions from the Administration Commission or pursuant to administrative rule of the Administration Commission and in effect on the date of the designation’s removal, the state’s liability in the inverse condemnation action shall be determined by the courts in the manner in which the state’s liability is determined in areas that are not areas of critical state concern. The state shall have standing to appear in any inverse condemnation action.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>