<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0380.0685" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State park in area of critical state concern in county which creates land authority; surcharge on admission and overnight occupancy.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection shall impose and collect a surcharge of 50 cents per person per day, or $5 per annual family auto entrance permit, on admission to all state parks in areas of critical state concern located in a county which creates a land authority pursuant to s. 380.0663(1), and a surcharge of $2.50 per night per campsite, cabin, or other overnight recreational occupancy unit in state parks in areas of critical state concern located in a county which creates a land authority pursuant to s. 380.0663(1); however, no surcharge shall be imposed or collected under this section for overnight use by nonprofit groups of organized group camps, primitive camping areas, or other facilities intended primarily for organized group use. Such surcharges shall be imposed within 90 days after any county creating a land authority notifies the Department of Environmental Protection that the land authority has been created. The proceeds from such surcharges, less a collection fee that shall be kept by the Department of Environmental Protection for the actual cost of collection, not to exceed 2 percent, shall be transmitted to the land authority of the county from which the revenue was generated. Such funds shall be used to purchase property in the area or areas of critical state concern in the county from which the revenue was generated. An amount not to exceed 10 percent may be used for administration and other costs incident to such purchases. However, the proceeds of the surcharges imposed and collected pursuant to this section in a state park or parks located wholly within a municipality, less the costs of collection as provided herein, shall be transmitted to that municipality for use by the municipality for land acquisition or for beach renourishment or restoration, including, but not limited to, costs associated with any design, permitting, monitoring, and mitigation of such work, as well as the work itself. However, these funds may not be included in any calculation used for providing state matching funds for local contributions for beach renourishment or restoration. The surcharges levied under this section shall remain imposed as long as the land authority is in existence.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-170; s. 9, ch. 88-164; s. 348, ch. 94-356; s. 2, ch. 2011-110; s. 60, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>