<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.0555" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Apalachicola Bay Area; protection and designation as area of critical state concern.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This act shall be known and cited as the “Apalachicola Bay Area Protection Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is hereby declared that the intent of the Legislature is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To protect the water quality of the Apalachicola Bay Area to ensure a healthy environment and a thriving economy for the residents of the area and the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To financially assist Franklin County and its municipalities in upgrading and expanding their sewerage systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To protect the Apalachicola Bay Area’s natural and economic resources by implementing and enforcing comprehensive plans and land development regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist Franklin County and its municipalities with technical and advisory assistance in formulating additional land development regulations and modifications to comprehensive plans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To monitor activities within the Apalachicola Bay Area to ensure the long-term protection of all the area’s resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote a broad base of economic growth which is compatible with the protection and conservation of the natural resources of the Apalachicola Bay Area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To educate the residents of the Apalachicola Bay Area in order to protect and preserve its natural resources.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DESIGNATION.<EmDash />Franklin County, as described in s. 7.19, less all federally owned lands, less all lands lying east of the line formed by the eastern boundary of State Road 319 running from the Ochlockonee River to the intersection of State Road 319 and State Road 98 and thence due south to the Gulf of Mexico, and less any lands removed under subsection (4), is hereby designated an area of critical state concern on June 18, 1985. State road, for the purpose of this section, shall be defined as in s. 334.03. For the purposes of this act, this area shall be known as the Apalachicola Bay Area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REMOVAL OF DESIGNATION.<EmDash />The state land planning agency may recommend to the Administration Commission the removal of the designation from all or part of the area specified in subsection (3), if it determines that all local land development regulations and local comprehensive plans and the administration of such regulations and plans are adequate to protect the Apalachicola Bay Area, continue to carry out the legislative intent set forth in subsection (2), and are in compliance with the principles for guiding development set forth in subsection (7). If the Administration Commission concurs with the recommendations of the state land planning agency to remove any area from the designation, it shall, within 45 days after receipt of the recommendation, initiate rulemaking to remove the designation. The state land planning agency shall make recommendations to the Administration Commission annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION OF CHAPTER 380 PROVISIONS.<EmDash />Section 380.05(1)-(6), (8)-(12), (15), (17), and (21), shall not apply to the area designated by this act for so long as the designation remains in effect. Except as otherwise provided in this act, s. 380.045 shall not apply to the area designated by this act. All other provisions of this chapter shall apply, including ss. 380.07 and 380.11, except that the “local development regulations” in s. 380.05(13) shall include the regulations set forth in subsection (8) for purposes of s. 380.05(13), and the plan or plans submitted pursuant to s. 380.05(14) shall be submitted no later than February 1, 1986. All or part of the area designated by this act may be redesignated pursuant to s. 380.05 as if it had been initially designated pursuant to that section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VESTED RIGHTS OF DEVELOPER.<EmDash />If a developer has by his or her actions in reliance on prior regulations obtained vested or other legal rights including rights obtained by approval of a development of regional impact or a substantial deviation thereof pursuant to s. 380.06 that would have prevented a local government from changing those regulations in a way adverse to the developer’s interests, nothing in this act authorizes any governmental agency to abridge those rights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRINCIPLES FOR GUIDING DEVELOPMENT.<EmDash />State, regional, and local agencies and units of government in the Apalachicola Bay Area shall coordinate their plans and conduct their programs and regulatory activities consistently with the following principles for guiding the development of the area:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land development shall be guided so that the basic functions and productivity of the Apalachicola Bay Area’s natural land and water systems will be conserved to reduce or avoid health, safety, and economic problems for present and future residents of the Apalachicola Bay Area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land development shall be consistent with a safe environment, adequate community facilities, a superior quality of life, and a desire to minimize environmental hazards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Growth and diversification of the local economy shall be fostered only if it is consistent with protecting the natural resources of the Apalachicola Bay Area through appropriate management of the land and water systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aquatic habitats and wildlife resources of the Apalachicola Bay Area shall be conserved and protected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water quantity shall be managed to conserve and protect the natural resources and the scenic beauty of the Apalachicola Bay Area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The quality of water shall be protected, maintained, and improved for public water supplies, the propagation of aquatic life, and recreational and other uses which are consistent with these uses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No wastes shall be discharged into any waters of the Apalachicola Bay Area without first being given the degree of treatment necessary to protect the water uses as set forth in paragraph (f).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stormwater discharges shall be managed in order to minimize their impacts on the bay system and protect the uses as set forth in paragraph (f).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coastal dune systems, specifically the area extending landward from the extreme high-tide line to the beginning of the pinelands of the Apalachicola Bay Area, shall be protected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public lands shall be managed, enhanced, and protected so that the public may continue to enjoy the traditional use of such lands.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPREHENSIVE PLAN ELEMENTS AND LAND DEVELOPMENT REGULATIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Local governments to administer plan elements and regulations.</Font><EmDash />The following comprehensive plan elements and land development regulations shall be administered by local governments within their jurisdiction in the Apalachicola Bay Area, as part of their local comprehensive plan and land development regulations. If a local government within the Apalachicola Bay Area has a provision in its local comprehensive plan or its land development regulations which conflicts with a provision of this paragraph or has no comparable provision, the provision of this paragraph shall control.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comprehensive plan.<EmDash />Chapter 1 of Volume I, and chapters 4, 5, 7, and 9 of Volume II of the Franklin County Comprehensive Land Use Plan adopted by Ordinance No. 81-4 on June 22, 1981, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on June 30, 1981, are incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Zoning ordinances.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 81-5 adopted June 22, 1981, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on June 30, 1981, and the following amendments are incorporated by reference and adopted herein:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ordinance 82-4, adopted June 18, 1982, and filed with the Secretary of State on July 28, 1982.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ordinance 83-4, adopted July 19, 1983, and filed with the Secretary of State on July 25, 1983.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ordinance 83-7, adopted October 4, 1983, and filed with the Secretary of State on October 6, 1983.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ordinance 84-2, adopted April 24, 1984, and filed with the Secretary of State on April 27, 1984.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subdivision regulations.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 74-1 adopted November 15, 1974, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on December 4, 1974, and December 5, 1974, and the following amendment are incorporated by reference and adopted herein: Ordinance 79-5, filed with the Secretary of State on May 30, 1979.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Flood plain management ordinance.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 83-5 adopted on July 7, 1983, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on July 15, 1983, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Septic tank ordinance.<EmDash />Ordinance 79-8 adopted on June 22, 1979, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on June 27, 1979, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construction; electrical connection.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 73-5A adopted July 3, 1973, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on March 6, 1981, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alligator Point Water Resource District Act.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 76-7 adopted on November 16, 1976, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on March 6, 1981, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coastal area building codes.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 84-1 establishing building codes for coastal areas adopted by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners on February 8, 1984, and filed with the Secretary of State on February 2, 1984, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standard building code.<EmDash />Ordinance adopting the 1976 Standard Building Code, Ordinance No. 83-1, adopted January 18, 1983, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State January 20, 1983, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local planning agency.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 77-6 adopted on June 21, 1977, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on June 22, 1977, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coastal high-hazard zones.<EmDash />Ordinance No. 80-5 adopted on May 29, 1980, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on May 30, 1980, is incorporated by reference and adopted herein.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Conflicting regulations.</Font><EmDash />In the event of any inconsistency between subparagraph (a)1. and subparagraphs (a)2.-11., subparagraph (a)1. shall control. Further, in the event of any inconsistency between subsection (7) and paragraph (a) of this subsection and a development order issued pursuant to s. 380.06, which has become final prior to June 18, 1985, or between subsection (7) and paragraph (a) and an amendment to a final development order, which amendment has been requested prior to April 2, 1985, the development order or amendment thereto shall control. However, any modification to paragraph (a) enacted by a local government and approved by the Administration Commission pursuant to subsection (9) may provide whether it shall control over an inconsistent provision of a development order or amendment thereto. A development order or any amendment thereto referred to in this paragraph shall not be subject to approval by the Administration Commission pursuant to subsection (9).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Effect of existing plans and regulations.</Font><EmDash />Legally adopted comprehensive plans and land development regulations other than those listed in this subsection shall remain in full force and effect unless inconsistent with the principles for guiding development set forth in subsection (7), the elements of the comprehensive plan listed in this subsection, or the land development regulations listed in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Developments of regional impact.</Font><EmDash />A local government shall approve a development subject to the provisions of s. 380.06 only if it also complies with the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MODIFICATION TO PLANS AND REGULATIONS.<EmDash />Any land development regulation or element of a local comprehensive plan in the Apalachicola Bay Area may be enacted, amended, or rescinded by a local government, but the enactment, amendment, or rescission becomes effective only upon the approval thereof by the Administration Commission. Further, the state land planning agency, after consulting with the appropriate local government, may, from time to time, recommend the enactment, amendment, or rescission of a land development regulation or element of a comprehensive plan. Within 45 days following the receipt of such recommendation by the state land planning agency or enactment, amendment, or rescission by a local government the commission shall reject the recommendation, enactment, amendment, or rescission or accept it with or without modification and adopt, by rule, any changes. Any such local land development regulation or comprehensive plan or part of such regulation or plan may be adopted by the commission if it finds that it is in compliance with the principles for guiding development.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REQUIREMENTS; LOCAL GOVERNMENTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alternative onsite system” means any approved onsite disposal system used in lieu of a standard subsurface system.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Critical shoreline zone” means all land within a distance of 150 feet landward of the mean high-water line in tidal areas, the ordinary high-water line in nontidal areas, or the inland wetland areas existing along the streams, lakes, rivers, bays, and sounds within the Apalachicola Bay Area.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pollution-sensitive segment of the critical shoreline” means an area which, due to its proximity to highly sensitive resources, including, but not limited to, productive shellfish beds and nursery areas, requires special regulatory attention.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Low-income family” means a group of persons residing together whose combined income does not exceed 200 percent of the 1985 Poverty Income Guidelines for all states and the District of Columbia, promulgated by the United States Department of Health and Human Services, as published in Volume 50, No. 46 of the Federal Register, pages 9517-18. Income shall be as defined in said guidelines.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall, within 60 days after a sewerage system is available for use, notify all owners and users of onsite sewage disposal systems of the availability of such a system and that connection is required within 180 days of the notice. Failure to connect to an available system within the time prescribed shall be a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in ss. 775.082 and 775.083. Further, Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall have the right to make the connection if it is not made within the prescribed time and to assess the owner of the real property on which the connection is made for the cost of such connection. Such assessments shall be levied according to law and shall become a lien against the real property, enforced according to law. Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall develop a program and implement ordinances to make available to low-income families the sewer services available upon completion of the proposed sewer projects being funded by this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall survey all septic tank soil-absorption systems in the Apalachicola Bay Area to determine their suitability as onsite sewage treatment systems. Within 6 months from June 18, 1985, Franklin County and the municipalities within it, after consultation with the Department of Health and the Department of Environmental Protection, shall develop a program designed to correct any onsite sewage treatment systems that might endanger the water quality of the bay.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall, within 9 months from June 18, 1985, enact by ordinance procedures implementing this program. These procedures shall include notification to owners of unacceptable septic tanks and procedures for correcting unacceptable septic tanks. These ordinances shall not be effective until approved by the Department of Health and the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall, within 12 months from June 18, 1985, establish by ordinance a map of “pollution-sensitive segments of the critical shoreline” within the Apalachicola Bay Area, which ordinance shall not be effective until approved by the Department of Health and the Department of Environmental Protection. Franklin County and the municipalities within it, after the effective date of these ordinances, shall no longer grant permits for onsite wastewater disposal systems in pollution-sensitive segments of the critical shoreline, except for those onsite wastewater systems that will not degrade water quality in the river or bay. These ordinances shall not become effective until approved by the resource planning and management committee. Until such ordinances become effective, the Franklin County Health Department shall not give a favorable recommendation to the granting of a septic tank variance pursuant to section (1) of Ordinance 79-8, adopted on June 22, 1979, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on June 27, 1979, or issue a permit for a septic tank or alternative waste disposal system pursuant to Ordinance 81-5, adopted on June 22, 1981, by the Franklin County Board of County Commissioners and filed with the Secretary of State on June 30, 1981, as amended as set forth in subparagraph (8)(a)2., unless the Franklin County Health Department certifies, in writing, that the use of such system will be consistent with paragraph (7)(f) and subsection (8).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall, within 9 months from June 18, 1985, enact land development regulations to protect the Apalachicola Bay Area from stormwater pollution, including provisions for development approval, before the issuance of building permits pursuant to chapter 17-25, Florida Administrative Code, Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall, within 90 days following the above deadline, survey existing stormwater management systems and discharges to determine their effect on the bay and develop a comprehensive stormwater management plan to minimize such effects. The plan will include recommendations and financing options for the retrofitting of existing systems. Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall, as part of an overall stormwater management program, inform its citizens about stormwater, its relationship to land use, and its effect upon the resources of the Apalachicola Bay Area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Franklin County and the municipalities within it shall, beginning 12 months from June 18, 1985, prepare semiannual reports on the implementation of paragraphs (b)-(e) on the environmental status of the Apalachicola Bay Area. The state land planning agency may prescribe additional detailed information required to be reported. Each report shall be delivered to the resource planning and management committee and the state land planning agency for review and recommendations. The state land planning agency shall review each report and consider such reports when making recommendations to the Administration Commission pursuant to subsection (9).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, ch. 85-360; s. 1, ch. 93-135; s. 51, ch. 93-206; s. 343, ch. 94-356; s. 1028, ch. 95-148; s. 57, ch. 96-321; s. 31, ch. 98-176; s. 72, ch. 99-8; s. 185, ch. 99-13; s. 15, ch. 2001-62.</History></Section>