<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.0667" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advisory committee; acquisitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The land authority shall establish an advisory committee which shall make recommendations regarding land acquisition to the land authority in accordance with the criteria set forth in this act. The advisory committee shall be composed of five members appointed by the land authority. The members shall serve 3-year terms, except that the initial terms may be for 1 or 2 years in order for terms to be staggered. The advisory committee shall by resolution recommend acquisitions by presenting the land authority, at the time specified by the land authority, a list of proposed acquisitions in order of recommended priority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall prioritize land acquisitions each year according to the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any parcel of undeveloped land for which an option to purchase pursuant to paragraph (b) is given to the land authority prior to January 15, 1987, shall be given priority over all other acquisitions for which no such option is given, with further priority given to parcels of land that would have been developable but for the adoption of the approved comprehensive plan and land development regulations under s. 380.05.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To qualify as an option under paragraph (a), such option shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be for a period of at least 1 year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer to sell for a net price to the offeror of no more than 115 percent of the property appraiser’s last assessment prior to June 1, 1986, or, alternatively, offer to sell at no more than appraised value if approved by the property appraiser, if the appraiser is selected by the land authority and reimbursed by the offeror.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain a provision allowing the offeror to retain his or her priority, if the option is not executed within the term of the option, by renewing said option for one or more similar terms.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The land authority shall approve the list of acquisitions, in whole or in part, in the order of priority recommended by the advisory committee. Acquisitions shall be made in the approved order of priority to the greatest extent possible.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-170; s. 6, ch. 88-164; s. 644, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>