<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.0551" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Green Swamp Area; designation as area of critical state concern.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Green Swamp Area, the boundaries of which are described in <Reference Number="1" />chapter 22F-5, Florida Administrative Code, is hereby designated an area of critical state concern effective July 1, 1979. The state land planning agency, in conjunction with the applicable local governments, shall review suggested changes to the existing boundary in the area immediately to the south of the southern boundary of the City of Clermont in Lake County and the area along the existing southern boundary around Lake Juliana and the City of Polk City in Polk County for possible deletion from the area of critical state concern. The state land planning agency shall report to, and shall make specific recommendations to, the commission relative to any proposed deletion by August 1, 1979. The commission shall take action on the recommendations of the state planning agency no later than October 1, 1979. <Reference Number="1" />Chapters 22F-5, 22F-6, and 22F-7, Florida Administrative Code, are hereby adopted and incorporated herein by reference. The boundaries described in <Reference Number="1" />chapter 22F-5, Florida Administrative Code, shall be modified pursuant to s. 380.05(12). There shall be appointed a resource planning and management committee as provided in s. 380.045.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The land development regulations contained in <Reference Number="1" />chapters 22F-6 and 22F-7, Florida Administrative Code, shall be the land development regulations for the applicable local government’s portion of the area of critical state concern until either:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicable local government complies with the provisions of s. 380.05(10); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such regulations are repealed pursuant to subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Reference Number="1" />Chapters 22F-5, 22F-6, and 22F-7, Florida Administrative Code, shall be repealed by the commission no earlier than July 1, 1980, and no later than July 1, 1982. Upon recommendation by the state land planning agency to the commission, any repeal of such rules pursuant to this subsection may be effective only for one local government’s portion of the Green Swamp Area. Such repeal shall be contingent upon approval by the state land planning agency of local land development regulations pursuant to s. 380.05(6) or (10), upon such regulations being effective for a period of 12 months, and upon adoption or modification by the applicable local government of a local government comprehensive plan pursuant to s. 380.05(14).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 79-73.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of former chapters 22F-5, 22F-6, and 22F-7 have been transferred to other sections of the Florida Administrative Code.</Text></Note></Section>