<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0380.0662" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, unless the context indicates a different meaning or intent:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land authority” means the land authority created by a county pursuant to this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” means the State of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bonds” means any bonds, debentures, notes, or other evidences of financial indebtedness issued on behalf of the land authority pursuant to this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local government” means a unit of local general-purpose government as defined in s. 218.31(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Project” means any work or improvement to real property, buildings, and any other property located in an area of critical state concern.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Real property” means all lands located in an area of critical state concern, including improvements and fixtures thereon and property of any nature appurtenant thereto or used in connection therewith, and every estate, interest, and right, legal or equitable, therein, including terms of years and liens by way of judgment, mortgage, or otherwise and the indebtedness secured by such liens.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State Bond Act” means ss. 215.57-215.83, as the same may be amended from time to time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State Board of Administration” means the State Board of Administration created by and referred to in s. 9, Art. XII of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pledged revenues” means revenues to be derived from s. 125.0108 or s. 380.0685, and any other revenues or assets that may be legally available to pay the principal of, redemption premium if any on, insurance and cash reserves for, and interest on the bonds derived from sources other than ad valorem taxation, including revenues from other sources or any combination thereof; however, in no event shall the full faith and credit of the state or any local government other than the land authority be pledged to secure such revenue bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Authorized investments” means and includes any of the following securities:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct obligations of, or obligations guaranteed by, the United States of America.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds, debentures, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness issued by any of the following: Bank for Cooperatives; federal intermediate credit banks; federal home loan banks; Export-Import Bank of the United States; federal land banks; Federal National Mortgage Association; Government National Mortgage Association; Federal Financing Bank; Small Business Administration; or any other agency or instrumentality of the United States of America, created by an Act of Congress, substantially similar to the foregoing in its legal relationship to the United States of America.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public housing bonds issued by public housing agencies and fully secured as to the payment of both principal and interest by a pledge of annual contributions under an annual contributions contract or contracts with the United States of America, and temporary notes, preliminary loan notes, or project notes issued by public housing agencies, in each case fully secured as to the payment of both principal and interest by a requisition or payment agreement with the United States of America.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest-bearing time or demand deposits, certificates of deposit, or other similar banking arrangements with any bank, trust company, national banking association, or other depository institution, including any trustee or other fiduciary with respect to the bonds of the land authority, provided:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The deposits, certificates, and other arrangements are insured to the satisfaction of the land authority by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depository institution has combined capital and surplus of at least $10 million and the deposits, certificates, and other arrangements are fully secured by obligations described in paragraphs (a)-(c), inclusive, or a combination thereof; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depository institution has combined capital and surplus of at least $25 million.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracts for the purchase and sale of obligations described in paragraphs (a) and (b), provided that if the parties with which the contracts are made are not members of the Federal Reserve System or if the parties, including members of the Federal Reserve System, are not required to set aside and otherwise identify, to the satisfaction of the agency, obligations described in paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) to such contracts as security or reserve therefor in an amount at least equal to the face value of each contract, the obligations shall be delivered to and held by a trustee or other fiduciary with respect to the bonds of the agency during the term of the contracts.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-170; s. 4, ch. 88-164; s. 300, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326.</History></Section>