<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0380.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Developments of regional impact.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITION.<EmDash />The term “development of regional impact,” as used in this section, means any development which, because of its character, magnitude, or location, would have a substantial effect upon the health, safety, or welfare of citizens of more than one county.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATEWIDE GUIDELINES AND STANDARDS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall recommend to the Administration Commission specific statewide guidelines and standards for adoption pursuant to this subsection. The Administration Commission shall by rule adopt statewide guidelines and standards to be used in determining whether particular developments shall undergo development-of-regional-impact review. The statewide guidelines and standards previously adopted by the Administration Commission and approved by the Legislature shall remain in effect unless revised pursuant to this section or superseded by other provisions of law. </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In adopting its guidelines and standards, the Administration Commission shall consider and shall be guided by:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the development would create or alleviate environmental problems such as air or water pollution or noise.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of pedestrian or vehicular traffic likely to be generated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of persons likely to be residents, employees, or otherwise present.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The size of the site to be occupied.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The likelihood that additional or subsidiary development will be generated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the development would create an additional demand for, or additional use of, energy, including the energy requirements of subsidiary developments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unique qualities of particular areas of the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With regard to the changes in the guidelines and standards authorized pursuant to this act, in determining whether a proposed development must comply with the review requirements of this section, the state land planning agency shall apply the guidelines and standards which were in effect when the developer received authorization to commence development from the local government. If a developer has not received authorization to commence development from the local government prior to the effective date of new or amended guidelines and standards, the new or amended guidelines and standards shall apply.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guidelines and standards shall be applied as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fixed thresholds.<EmDash /></Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A development that is below 100 percent of all numerical thresholds in the guidelines and standards is not required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A development that is at or above 120 percent of any numerical threshold shall be required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projects certified under s. 403.973 which create at least 100 jobs and meet the criteria of the Department of Economic Opportunity as to their impact on an area’s economy, employment, and prevailing wage and skill levels that are at or below 100 percent of the numerical thresholds for industrial plants, industrial parks, distribution, warehousing or wholesaling facilities, office development or multiuse projects other than residential, as described in s. 380.0651(3)(c) and (f) are not required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rebuttable presumption.<EmDash />It shall be presumed that a development that is at 100 percent or between 100 and 120 percent of a numerical threshold shall be required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to residential, hotel, motel, office, and retail developments, the applicable guidelines and standards shall be increased by 50 percent in urban central business districts and regional activity centers of jurisdictions whose local comprehensive plans are in compliance with part II of chapter 163. With respect to multiuse developments, the applicable individual use guidelines and standards for residential, hotel, motel, office, and retail developments and multiuse guidelines and standards shall be increased by 100 percent in urban central business districts and regional activity centers of jurisdictions whose local comprehensive plans are in compliance with part II of chapter 163, if one land use of the multiuse development is residential and amounts to not less than 35 percent of the jurisdiction’s applicable residential threshold. With respect to resort or convention hotel developments, the applicable guidelines and standards shall be increased by 150 percent in urban central business districts and regional activity centers of jurisdictions whose local comprehensive plans are in compliance with part II of chapter 163 and where the increase is specifically for a proposed resort or convention hotel located in a county with a population greater than 500,000 and the local government specifically designates that the proposed resort or convention hotel development will serve an existing convention center of more than 250,000 gross square feet built prior to July 1, 1992. The applicable guidelines and standards shall be increased by 150 percent for development in any area designated by the Governor as a rural area of critical economic concern pursuant to s. 288.0656 during the effectiveness of the designation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VARIATION OF THRESHOLDS IN STATEWIDE GUIDELINES AND STANDARDS.<EmDash />The state land planning agency, a regional planning agency, or a local government may petition the Administration Commission to increase or decrease the numerical thresholds of any statewide guideline and standard. The state land planning agency or the regional planning agency may petition for an increase or decrease for a particular local government’s jurisdiction or a part of a particular jurisdiction. A local government may petition for an increase or decrease within its jurisdiction or a part of its jurisdiction. A number of requests may be combined in a single petition.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a petition is filed, the state land planning agency shall have no more than 180 days to prepare and submit to the Administration Commission a report and recommendations on the proposed variation. The report shall evaluate, and the Administration Commission shall consider, the following criteria:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the local government has adopted and effectively implemented a comprehensive plan that reflects and implements the goals and objectives of an adopted state comprehensive plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any applicable policies in an adopted strategic regional policy plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the local government has adopted and effectively implemented both a comprehensive set of land development regulations, which regulations shall include a planned unit development ordinance, and a capital improvements plan that are consistent with the local government comprehensive plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the local government has adopted and effectively implemented the authority and the fiscal mechanisms for requiring developers to meet development order conditions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the local government has adopted and effectively implemented and enforced satisfactory development review procedures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The affected regional planning agency, adjoining local governments, and the local government shall be given a reasonable opportunity to submit recommendations to the Administration Commission regarding any such proposed variations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Administration Commission shall have authority to increase or decrease a threshold in the statewide guidelines and standards up to 50 percent above or below the statewide presumptive threshold. The commission may from time to time reconsider changed thresholds and make additional variations as it deems necessary.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Administration Commission shall adopt rules setting forth the procedures for submission and review of petitions filed pursuant to this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Variations to guidelines and standards adopted by the Administration Commission under this subsection shall be transmitted on or before March 1 to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives for presentation at the next regular session of the Legislature. Unless approved as submitted by general law, the revisions shall not become effective.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BINDING LETTER.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any developer is in doubt whether his or her proposed development must undergo development-of-regional-impact review under the guidelines and standards, whether his or her rights have vested pursuant to subsection (20), or whether a proposed substantial change to a development of regional impact concerning which rights had previously vested pursuant to subsection (20) would divest such rights, the developer may request a determination from the state land planning agency. The developer or the appropriate local government having jurisdiction may request that the state land planning agency determine whether the amount of development that remains to be built in an approved development of regional impact meets the criteria of subparagraph (15)(g)3.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless a developer waives the requirements of this paragraph by agreeing to undergo development-of-regional-impact review pursuant to this section, the state land planning agency or local government with jurisdiction over the land on which a development is proposed may require a developer to obtain a binding letter if the development is at a presumptive numerical threshold or up to 20 percent above a numerical threshold in the guidelines and standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any local government may petition the state land planning agency to require a developer of a development located in an adjacent jurisdiction to obtain a binding letter of interpretation. The petition shall contain facts to support a finding that the development as proposed is a development of regional impact. This paragraph shall not be construed to grant standing to the petitioning local government to initiate an administrative or judicial proceeding pursuant to this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request for a binding letter of interpretation shall be in writing and in such form and content as prescribed by the state land planning agency. Within 15 days of receiving an application for a binding letter of interpretation or a supplement to a pending application, the state land planning agency shall determine and notify the applicant whether the information in the application is sufficient to enable the agency to issue a binding letter or shall request any additional information needed. The applicant shall either provide the additional information requested or shall notify the state land planning agency in writing that the information will not be supplied and the reasons therefor. If the applicant does not respond to the request for additional information within 120 days, the application for a binding letter of interpretation shall be deemed to be withdrawn. Within 35 days after acknowledging receipt of a sufficient application, or of receiving notification that the information will not be supplied, the state land planning agency shall issue a binding letter of interpretation with respect to the proposed development. A binding letter of interpretation issued by the state land planning agency shall bind all state, regional, and local agencies, as well as the developer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining whether a proposed substantial change to a development of regional impact concerning which rights had previously vested pursuant to subsection (20) would divest such rights, the state land planning agency shall review the proposed change within the context of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria specified in paragraph (19)(b);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its conformance with any adopted state comprehensive plan and any rules of the state land planning agency;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rights and obligations arising out of the vested status of such development;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permit conditions or requirements imposed by the Department of Environmental Protection or any water management district created by s. 373.069 or any of their successor agencies or by any appropriate federal regulatory agency; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any regional impacts arising from the proposed change.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a proposed substantial change to a development of regional impact concerning which rights had previously vested pursuant to subsection (20) would result in reduced regional impacts, the change shall not divest rights to complete the development pursuant to subsection (20). Furthermore, where all or a portion of the development of regional impact for which rights had previously vested pursuant to subsection (20) is demolished and reconstructed within the same approximate footprint of buildings and parking lots, so that any change in the size of the development does not exceed the criteria of paragraph (19)(b), such demolition and reconstruction shall not divest the rights which had vested.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every binding letter determining that a proposed development is not a development of regional impact, but not including binding letters of vested rights or of modification of vested rights, shall expire and become void unless the plan of development has been substantially commenced within:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three years from October 1, 1985, for binding letters issued prior to the effective date of this act; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three years from the date of issuance of binding letters issued on or after October 1, 1985.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expiration date of a binding letter, established pursuant to paragraph (g), shall begin to run after final disposition of all administrative and judicial appeals of the binding letter and may be extended by mutual agreement of the state land planning agency, the local government of jurisdiction, and the developer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In response to an inquiry from a developer or the appropriate local government having jurisdiction, the state land planning agency may issue an informal determination in the form of a clearance letter as to whether a development is required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review or whether the amount of development that remains to be built in an approved development of regional impact meets the criteria of subparagraph (15)(g)3. A clearance letter may be based solely on the information provided by the developer, and the state land planning agency is not required to conduct an investigation of that information. If any material information provided by the developer is incomplete or inaccurate, the clearance letter is not binding upon the state land planning agency. A clearance letter does not constitute final agency action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZATION TO DEVELOP.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer who is required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review may undertake a development of regional impact if the development has been approved under the requirements of this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the land on which the development is proposed is within an area of critical state concern, the development must also be approved under the requirements of s. 380.05.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State or regional agencies may inquire whether a proposed project is undergoing or will be required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review. If a project is undergoing or will be required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review, any state or regional permit necessary for the construction or operation of the project that is valid for 5 years or less shall take effect, and the period of time for which the permit is valid shall begin to run, upon expiration of the time allowed for an administrative appeal of the development or upon final action following an administrative appeal or judicial review, whichever is later. However, if the application for development approval is not filed within 18 months after the issuance of the permit, the time of validity of the permit shall be considered to be from the date of issuance of the permit. If a project is required to obtain a binding letter under subsection (4), any state or regional agency permit necessary for the construction or operation of the project that is valid for 5 years or less shall take effect, and the period of time for which the permit is valid shall begin to run, only after the developer obtains a binding letter stating that the project is not required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review or after the developer obtains a development order pursuant to this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the issuance of a final development order, the developer may elect to be bound by the rules adopted pursuant to chapters 373 and 403 in effect when such development order is issued. The rules adopted pursuant to chapters 373 and 403 in effect at the time such development order is issued shall be applicable to all applications for permits pursuant to those chapters and which are necessary for and consistent with the development authorized in such development order, except that a later adopted rule shall be applicable to an application if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The later adopted rule is determined by the rule-adopting agency to be essential to the public health, safety, or welfare;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The later adopted rule is adopted pursuant to s. 403.061(27);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The later adopted rule is being adopted pursuant to a subsequently enacted statutorily mandated program;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The later adopted rule is mandated in order for the state to maintain delegation of a federal program; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The later adopted rule is required by state or federal law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of day care service facilities in developments approved pursuant to this section is permissible but is not required.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Further, in order for any developer to apply for permits pursuant to this provision, the application must be filed within 5 years from the issuance of the final development order and the permit shall not be effective for more than 8 years from the issuance of the final development order. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to alter or change any permitting agency’s authority to approve permits or to determine applicable criteria for longer periods of time.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION FOR APPROVAL OF DEVELOPMENT; CONCURRENT PLAN AMENDMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to undertaking any development, a developer that is required to undergo development-of-regional-impact review shall file an application for development approval with the appropriate local government having jurisdiction. The application shall contain, in addition to such other matters as may be required, a statement that the developer proposes to undertake a development of regional impact as required under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any local government comprehensive plan amendments related to a proposed development of regional impact, including any changes proposed under subsection (19), may be initiated by a local planning agency or the developer and must be considered by the local governing body at the same time as the application for development approval using the procedures provided for local plan amendment in s. 163.3184 and applicable local ordinances, without regard to local limits on the frequency of consideration of amendments to the local comprehensive plan. This paragraph does not require favorable consideration of a plan amendment solely because it is related to a development of regional impact. The procedure for processing such comprehensive plan amendments is as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a developer seeks a comprehensive plan amendment related to a development of regional impact, the developer must so notify in writing the regional planning agency, the applicable local government, and the state land planning agency no later than the date of preapplication conference or the submission of the proposed change under subsection (19).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When filing the application for development approval or the proposed change, the developer must include a written request for comprehensive plan amendments that would be necessitated by the development-of-regional-impact approvals sought. That request must include data and analysis upon which the applicable local government can determine whether to transmit the comprehensive plan amendment pursuant to s. 163.3184.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government must advertise a public hearing on the transmittal within 30 days after filing the application for development approval or the proposed change and must make a determination on the transmittal within 60 days after the initial filing unless that time is extended by the developer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local government approves the transmittal, procedures set forth in <Reference Number="1"/>s. 163.3184 must be followed.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Reference Number="2"/>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (11) or subsection (19), the local government may not hold a public hearing on the application for development approval or the proposed change or on the comprehensive plan amendments sooner than 30 days after reviewing agency comments are due to the local government pursuant to s. 163.3184.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government must hear both the application for development approval or the proposed change and the comprehensive plan amendments at the same hearing. However, the local government must take action separately on the application for development approval or the proposed change and on the comprehensive plan amendments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thereafter, the appeal process for the local government development order must follow the provisions of s. 380.07, and the compliance process for the comprehensive plan amendments must follow the provisions of s. 163.3184.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PREAPPLICATION PROCEDURES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before filing an application for development approval, the developer shall contact the regional planning agency having jurisdiction over the proposed development to arrange a preapplication conference. Upon the request of the developer or the regional planning agency, other affected state and regional agencies shall participate in this conference and shall identify the types of permits issued by the agencies, the level of information required, and the permit issuance procedures as applied to the proposed development. The levels of service required in the transportation methodology shall be the same levels of service used to evaluate concurrency in accordance with s. 163.3180. The regional planning agency shall provide the developer information about the development-of-regional-impact process and the use of preapplication conferences to identify issues, coordinate appropriate state and local agency requirements, and otherwise promote a proper and efficient review of the proposed development. If an agreement is reached regarding assumptions and methodology to be used in the application for development approval, the reviewing agencies may not subsequently object to those assumptions and methodologies unless subsequent changes to the project or information obtained during the review make those assumptions and methodologies inappropriate. The reviewing agencies may make only recommendations or comments regarding a proposed development which are consistent with the statutes, rules, or adopted local government ordinances that are applicable to developments in the jurisdiction where the proposed development is located.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regional planning agency shall establish by rule a procedure by which a developer may enter into binding written agreements with the regional planning agency to eliminate questions from the application for development approval when those questions are found to be unnecessary for development-of-regional-impact review. It is the legislative intent of this subsection to encourage reduction of paperwork, to discourage unnecessary gathering of data, and to encourage the coordination of the development-of-regional-impact review process with federal, state, and local environmental reviews when such reviews are required by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the application for development approval is not submitted within 1 year after the date of the preapplication conference, the regional planning agency, the local government having jurisdiction, or the applicant may request that another preapplication conference be held.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRELIMINARY DEVELOPMENT AGREEMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer may enter into a written preliminary development agreement with the state land planning agency to allow a developer to proceed with a limited amount of the total proposed development, subject to all other governmental approvals and solely at the developer’s own risk, prior to issuance of a final development order. All owners of the land in the total proposed development shall join the developer as parties to the agreement. Each agreement shall include and be subject to the following conditions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall comply with the preapplication conference requirements pursuant to subsection (7) within 45 days after the execution of the agreement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall file an application for development approval for the total proposed development within 3 months after execution of the agreement, unless the state land planning agency agrees to a different time for good cause shown. Failure to timely file an application and to otherwise diligently proceed in good faith to obtain a final development order shall constitute a breach of the preliminary development agreement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement shall include maps and legal descriptions of both the preliminary development area and the total proposed development area and shall specifically describe the preliminary development in terms of magnitude and location. The area approved for preliminary development must be included in the application for development approval and shall be subject to the terms and conditions of the final development order.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preliminary development shall be limited to lands that the state land planning agency agrees are suitable for development and shall only be allowed in areas where adequate public infrastructure exists to accommodate the preliminary development, when such development will utilize public infrastructure. The developer must also demonstrate that the preliminary development will not result in material adverse impacts to existing resources or existing or planned facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preliminary development agreement may allow development which is:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Reference Number="3" />Less than 100 percent of any applicable threshold if the developer demonstrates that such development is consistent with subparagraph 4.; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Less than 120 percent of any applicable threshold if the developer demonstrates that such development is part of a proposed downtown development of regional impact specified in subsection (22) or part of any areawide development of regional impact specified in subsection (25) and that the development is consistent with subparagraph 4.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer and owners of the land may not claim vested rights, or assert equitable estoppel, arising from the agreement or any expenditures or actions taken in reliance on the agreement to continue with the total proposed development beyond the preliminary development. The agreement shall not entitle the developer to a final development order approving the total proposed development or to particular conditions in a final development order.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement shall not prohibit the regional planning agency from reviewing or commenting on any regional issue that the regional agency determines should be included in the regional agency’s report on the application for development approval.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement shall include a disclosure by the developer and all the owners of the land in the total proposed development of all land or development within 5 miles of the total proposed development in which they have an interest and shall describe such interest.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of a breach of the agreement or failure to comply with any condition of the agreement, or if the agreement was based on materially inaccurate information, the state land planning agency may terminate the agreement or file suit to enforce the agreement as provided in this section and s. 380.11, including a suit to enjoin all development.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notice of the preliminary development agreement shall be recorded by the developer in accordance with s. 28.222 with the clerk of the circuit court for each county in which land covered by the terms of the agreement is located. The notice shall include a legal description of the land covered by the agreement and shall state the parties to the agreement, the date of adoption of the agreement and any subsequent amendments, the location where the agreement may be examined, and that the agreement constitutes a land development regulation applicable to portions of the land covered by the agreement. The provisions of the agreement shall inure to the benefit of and be binding upon successors and assigns of the parties in the agreement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for those agreements which authorize preliminary development for substantial deviations pursuant to subsection (19), a developer who no longer wishes to pursue a development of regional impact may propose to abandon any preliminary development agreement executed after January 1, 1985, including those pursuant to s. 380.032(3), provided at the time of abandonment:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final development order under this section has been rendered that approves all of the development actually constructed; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of development is less than 100 percent of all numerical thresholds of the guidelines and standards, and the state land planning agency determines in writing that the development to date is in compliance with all applicable local regulations and the terms and conditions of the preliminary development agreement and otherwise adequately mitigates for the impacts of the development to date.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In either event, when a developer proposes to abandon said agreement, the developer shall give written notice and state that he or she is no longer proposing a development of regional impact and provide adequate documentation that he or she has met the criteria for abandonment of the agreement to the state land planning agency. Within 30 days of receipt of adequate documentation of such notice, the state land planning agency shall make its determination as to whether or not the developer meets the criteria for abandonment. Once the state land planning agency determines that the developer meets the criteria for abandonment, the state land planning agency shall issue a notice of abandonment which shall be recorded by the developer in accordance with s. 28.222 with the clerk of the circuit court for each county in which land covered by the terms of the agreement is located.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency may enter into other types of agreements to effectuate the provisions of this act as provided in s. 380.032.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this subsection shall also be available to a developer who chooses to seek development approval of a Florida Quality Development pursuant to s. 380.061.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONCEPTUAL AGENCY REVIEW.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to facilitate the planning and preparation of permit applications for projects that undergo development-of-regional-impact review, and in order to coordinate the information required to issue such permits, a developer may elect to request conceptual agency review under this subsection either concurrently with development-of-regional-impact review and comprehensive plan amendments, if applicable, or subsequent to a preapplication conference held pursuant to subsection (7).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Conceptual agency review” means general review of the proposed location, densities, intensity of use, character, and major design features of a proposed development required to undergo review under this section for the purpose of considering whether these aspects of the proposed development comply with the issuing agency’s statutes and rules.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conceptual agency review is a licensing action subject to chapter 120, and approval or denial constitutes final agency action, except that the 90-day time period specified in s. 120.60(1) shall be tolled for the agency when the affected regional planning agency requests information from the developer pursuant to paragraph (10)(b). If proposed agency action on the conceptual approval is the subject of a proceeding under ss. 120.569 and 120.57, final agency action shall be conclusive as to any issues actually raised and adjudicated in the proceeding, and such issues may not be raised in any subsequent proceeding under ss. 120.569 and 120.57 on the proposed development by any parties to the prior proceeding.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A conceptual agency review approval shall be valid for up to 10 years, unless otherwise provided in a state or regional agency rule, and may be reviewed and reissued for additional periods of time under procedures established by the agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection, each water management district, and each other state or regional agency that requires construction or operation permits shall establish by rule a set of procedures necessary for conceptual agency review for the following permitting activities within their respective regulatory jurisdictions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction and operation of potential sources of water pollution, including industrial wastewater, domestic wastewater, and stormwater.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dredging and filling activities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The management and storage of surface waters.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction and operation of works of the district, only if a conceptual agency review approval is requested under subparagraph 3.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any state or regional agency may establish rules for conceptual agency review for any other permitting activities within its respective regulatory jurisdiction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency participating in conceptual agency reviews shall determine and establish by rule its information and application requirements and furnish these requirements to the state land planning agency and to any developer seeking conceptual agency review under this subsection.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency shall cooperate with the state land planning agency to standardize, to the extent possible, review procedures, data requirements, and data collection methodologies among all participating agencies, consistent with the requirements of the statutes that establish the permitting programs for each agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the conclusion of the conceptual agency review, the agency shall give notice of its proposed agency action as required by s. 120.60(3) and shall forward a copy of the notice to the appropriate regional planning council with a report setting out the agency’s conclusions on potential development impacts and stating whether the agency intends to grant conceptual approval, with or without conditions, or to deny conceptual approval. If the agency intends to deny conceptual approval, the report shall state the reasons therefor. The agency may require the developer to publish notice of proposed agency action in accordance with s. 403.815.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency’s decision to grant conceptual approval shall not relieve the developer of the requirement to obtain a permit and to meet the standards for issuance of a construction or operation permit or to meet the agency’s information requirements for such a permit. Nevertheless, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the developer is entitled to receive a construction or operation permit for an activity for which the agency granted conceptual review approval, to the extent that the project for which the applicant seeks a permit is in accordance with the conceptual approval and with the agency’s standards and criteria for issuing a construction or operation permit. The agency may revoke or appropriately modify a valid conceptual approval if the agency shows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That an applicant or his or her agent has submitted materially false or inaccurate information in the application for conceptual approval;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the developer has violated a condition of the conceptual approval; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the development will cause a violation of the agency’s applicable laws or rules.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this subsection shall modify or abridge the law of vested rights or estoppel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed to preclude an agency from adopting rules for conceptual review for developments which are not developments of regional impact.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION; SUFFICIENCY.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an application for development approval is filed with a local government, the developer shall also send copies of the application to the appropriate regional planning agency and the state land planning agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a regional planning agency determines that the application for development approval is insufficient for the agency to discharge its responsibilities under subsection (12), it shall provide in writing to the appropriate local government and the applicant a statement of any additional information desired within 30 days of the receipt of the application by the regional planning agency. The applicant may supply the information requested by the regional planning agency and shall communicate its intention to do so in writing to the appropriate local government and the regional planning agency within 5 working days of the receipt of the statement requesting such information, or the applicant shall notify the appropriate local government and the regional planning agency in writing that the requested information will not be supplied. Within 30 days after receipt of such additional information, the regional planning agency shall review it and may request only that information needed to clarify the additional information or to answer new questions raised by, or directly related to, the additional information. The regional planning agency may request additional information no more than twice, unless the developer waives this limitation. If an applicant does not provide the information requested by a regional planning agency within 120 days of its request, or within a time agreed upon by the applicant and the regional planning agency, the application shall be considered withdrawn.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regional planning agency shall notify the local government that a public hearing date may be set when the regional planning agency determines that the application is sufficient or when it receives notification from the developer that the additional requested information will not be supplied, as provided for in paragraph (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOCAL NOTICE.<EmDash />Upon receipt of the sufficiency notification from the regional planning agency required by paragraph (10)(c), the appropriate local government shall give notice and hold a public hearing on the application in the same manner as for a rezoning as provided under the appropriate special or local law or ordinance, except that such hearing proceedings shall be recorded by tape or a certified court reporter and made available for transcription at the expense of any interested party. When a development of regional impact is proposed within the jurisdiction of more than one local government, the local governments, at the request of the developer, may hold a joint public hearing. The local government shall comply with the following additional requirements:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice of public hearing shall state that the proposed development is undergoing a development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall be published at least 60 days in advance of the hearing and shall specify where the information and reports on the development-of-regional-impact application may be reviewed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall be given to the state land planning agency, to the applicable regional planning agency, to any state or regional permitting agency participating in a conceptual agency review process under subsection (9), and to such other persons as may have been designated by the state land planning agency as entitled to receive such notices.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public hearing date shall be set by the appropriate local government at the next scheduled meeting. The public hearing shall be held no later than 90 days after issuance of notice by the regional planning agency that a public hearing may be set, unless an extension is requested by the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REGIONAL REPORTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 50 days after receipt of the notice of public hearing required in paragraph (11)(c), the regional planning agency, if one has been designated for the area including the local government, shall prepare and submit to the local government a report and recommendations on the regional impact of the proposed development. In preparing its report and recommendations, the regional planning agency shall identify regional issues based upon the following review criteria and make recommendations to the local government on these regional issues, specifically considering whether, and the extent to which:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development will have a favorable or unfavorable impact on state or regional resources or facilities identified in the applicable state or regional plans. As used in this subsection, the term “applicable state plan” means the state comprehensive plan. As used in this subsection, the term “applicable regional plan” means an adopted strategic regional policy plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development will significantly impact adjacent jurisdictions. At the request of the appropriate local government, regional planning agencies may also review and comment upon issues that affect only the requesting local government.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As one of the issues considered in the review in subparagraphs 1. and 2., the development will favorably or adversely affect the ability of people to find adequate housing reasonably accessible to their places of employment if the regional planning agency has adopted an affordable housing policy as part of its strategic regional policy plan. The determination should take into account information on factors that are relevant to the availability of reasonably accessible adequate housing. Adequate housing means housing that is available for occupancy and that is not substandard.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regional planning agency report must contain recommendations that are consistent with the standards required by the applicable state permitting agencies or the water management district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the request of the regional planning agency, other appropriate agencies shall review the proposed development and shall prepare reports and recommendations on issues that are clearly within the jurisdiction of those agencies. Such agency reports shall become part of the regional planning agency report; however, the regional planning agency may attach dissenting views. When water management district and Department of Environmental Protection permits have been issued pursuant to chapter 373 or chapter 403, the regional planning council may comment on the regional implications of the permits but may not offer conflicting recommendations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regional planning agency shall afford the developer or any substantially affected party reasonable opportunity to present evidence to the regional planning agency head relating to the proposed regional agency report and recommendations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the location of a proposed development involves land within the boundaries of multiple regional planning councils, the state land planning agency shall designate a lead regional planning council. The lead regional planning council shall prepare the regional report.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CRITERIA IN AREAS OF CRITICAL STATE CONCERN.<EmDash />If the development is in an area of critical state concern, the local government shall approve it only if it complies with the land development regulations therefor under s. 380.05 and the provisions of this section. The provisions of this section shall not apply to developments in areas of critical state concern which had pending applications and had been noticed or agendaed by local government after September 1, 1985, and before October 1, 1985, for development order approval. In all such cases, the state land planning agency may consider and address applicable regional issues contained in subsection (12) as part of its area-of-critical-state-concern review pursuant to ss. 380.05, 380.07, and 380.11.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CRITERIA OUTSIDE AREAS OF CRITICAL STATE CONCERN.<EmDash />If the development is not located in an area of critical state concern, in considering whether the development shall be approved, denied, or approved subject to conditions, restrictions, or limitations, the local government shall consider whether, and the extent to which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development is consistent with the local comprehensive plan and local land development regulations;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development is consistent with the report and recommendations of the regional planning agency submitted pursuant to subsection (12); and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development is consistent with the State Comprehensive Plan. In consistency determinations the plan shall be construed and applied in accordance with s. 187.101(3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOCAL GOVERNMENT DEVELOPMENT ORDER.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate local government shall render a decision on the application within 30 days after the hearing unless an extension is requested by the developer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When possible, local governments shall issue development orders concurrently with any other local permits or development approvals that may be applicable to the proposed development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development order shall include findings of fact and conclusions of law consistent with subsections (13) and (14). The development order:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall specify the monitoring procedures and the local official responsible for assuring compliance by the developer with the development order.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall establish compliance dates for the development order, including a deadline for commencing physical development and for compliance with conditions of approval or phasing requirements, and shall include a buildout date that reasonably reflects the time anticipated to complete the development.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall establish a date until which the local government agrees that the approved development of regional impact shall not be subject to downzoning, unit density reduction, or intensity reduction, unless the local government can demonstrate that substantial changes in the conditions underlying the approval of the development order have occurred or the development order was based on substantially inaccurate information provided by the developer or that the change is clearly established by local government to be essential to the public health, safety, or welfare. The date established pursuant to this subparagraph shall be no sooner than the buildout date of the project.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall specify the requirements for the biennial report designated under subsection (18), including the date of submission, parties to whom the report is submitted, and contents of the report, based upon the rules adopted by the state land planning agency. Such rules shall specify the scope of any additional local requirements that may be necessary for the report.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May specify the types of changes to the development which shall require submission for a substantial deviation determination or a notice of proposed change under subsection (19).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall include a legal description of the property.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conditions of a development order that require a developer to contribute land for a public facility or construct, expand, or pay for land acquisition or construction or expansion of a public facility, or portion thereof, shall meet the following criteria:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The need to construct new facilities or add to the present system of public facilities must be reasonably attributable to the proposed development.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contribution of funds, land, or public facilities required from the developer shall be comparable to the amount of funds, land, or public facilities that the state or the local government would reasonably expect to expend or provide, based on projected costs of comparable projects, to mitigate the impacts reasonably attributable to the proposed development.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any funds or lands contributed must be expressly designated and used to mitigate impacts reasonably attributable to the proposed development.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construction or expansion of a public facility by a nongovernmental developer as a condition of a development order to mitigate the impacts reasonably attributable to the proposed development is not subject to competitive bidding or competitive negotiation for selection of a contractor or design professional for any part of the construction or design.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government shall not include, as a development order condition for a development of regional impact, any requirement that a developer contribute or pay for land acquisition or construction or expansion of public facilities or portions thereof unless the local government has enacted a local ordinance which requires other development not subject to this section to contribute its proportionate share of the funds, land, or public facilities necessary to accommodate any impacts having a rational nexus to the proposed development, and the need to construct new facilities or add to the present system of public facilities must be reasonably attributable to the proposed development.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government shall not approve a development of regional impact that does not make adequate provision for the public facilities needed to accommodate the impacts of the proposed development unless the local government includes in the development order a commitment by the local government to provide these facilities consistently with the development schedule approved in the development order; however, a local government’s failure to meet the requirements of subparagraph 1. and this subparagraph shall not preclude the issuance of a development order where adequate provision is made by the developer for the public facilities needed to accommodate the impacts of the proposed development. Any funds or lands contributed by a developer must be expressly designated and used to accommodate impacts reasonably attributable to the proposed development.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity and other state and regional agencies involved in the administration and implementation of this act shall cooperate and work with units of local government in preparing and adopting local impact fee and other contribution ordinances.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the adoption of a development order or the subsequent amendments to an adopted development order shall be recorded by the developer, in accordance with s. 28.222, with the clerk of the circuit court for each county in which the development is located. The notice shall include a legal description of the property covered by the order and shall state which unit of local government adopted the development order, the date of adoption, the date of adoption of any amendments to the development order, the location where the adopted order with any amendments may be examined, and that the development order constitutes a land development regulation applicable to the property. The recording of this notice shall not constitute a lien, cloud, or encumbrance on real property, or actual or constructive notice of any such lien, cloud, or encumbrance. This paragraph applies only to developments initially approved under this section after July 1, 1980.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government shall not issue permits for development subsequent to the buildout date contained in the development order unless:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed development has been evaluated cumulatively with existing development under the substantial deviation provisions of subsection (19) subsequent to the termination or expiration date;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed development is consistent with an abandonment of development order that has been issued in accordance with the provisions of subsection (26);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of regional impact is essentially built out, in that all the mitigation requirements in the development order have been satisfied, all developers are in compliance with all applicable terms and conditions of the development order except the buildout date, and the amount of proposed development that remains to be built is less than 40 percent of any applicable development-of-regional-impact threshold; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The project has been determined to be an essentially built-out development of regional impact through an agreement executed by the developer, the state land planning agency, and the local government, in accordance with s. 380.032, which will establish the terms and conditions under which the development may be continued. If the project is determined to be essentially built out, development may proceed pursuant to the s. 380.032 agreement after the termination or expiration date contained in the development order without further development-of-regional-impact review subject to the local government comprehensive plan and land development regulations or subject to a modified development-of-regional-impact analysis. As used in this paragraph, an “essentially built-out” development of regional impact means:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developers are in compliance with all applicable terms and conditions of the development order except the buildout date; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of development that remains to be built is less than the substantial deviation threshold specified in paragraph (19)(b) for each individual land use category, or, for a multiuse development, the sum total of all unbuilt land uses as a percentage of the applicable substantial deviation threshold is equal to or less than 100 percent; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency and the local government have agreed in writing that the amount of development to be built does not create the likelihood of any additional regional impact not previously reviewed.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The single-family residential portions of a development may be considered “essentially built out” if all of the workforce housing obligations and all of the infrastructure and horizontal development have been completed, at least 50 percent of the dwelling units have been completed, and more than 80 percent of the lots have been conveyed to third-party individual lot owners or to individual builders who own no more than 40 lots at the time of the determination. The mobile home park portions of a development may be considered “essentially built out” if all the infrastructure and horizontal development has been completed, and at least 50 percent of the lots are leased to individual mobile home owners.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the property is annexed by another local jurisdiction, the annexing jurisdiction shall adopt a new development order that incorporates all previous rights and obligations specified in the prior development order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREDITS AGAINST LOCAL IMPACT FEES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the development order requires the developer to contribute land or a public facility or construct, expand, or pay for land acquisition or construction or expansion of a public facility, or portion thereof, and the developer is also subject by local ordinance to impact fees or exactions to meet the same needs, the local government shall establish and implement a procedure that credits a development order exaction or fee toward an impact fee or exaction imposed by local ordinance for the same need; however, if the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission imposes any additional requirement, the local government shall not be required to grant a credit toward the local exaction or impact fee unless the local government determines that such required contribution, payment, or construction meets the same need that the local exaction or impact fee would address. The nongovernmental developer need not be required, by virtue of this credit, to competitively bid or negotiate any part of the construction or design of the facility, unless otherwise requested by the local government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local government imposes or increases an impact fee or exaction by local ordinance after a development order has been issued, the developer may petition the local government, and the local government shall modify the affected provisions of the development order to give the developer credit for any contribution of land for a public facility, or construction, expansion, or contribution of funds for land acquisition or construction or expansion of a public facility, or a portion thereof, required by the development order toward an impact fee or exaction for the same need.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government and the developer may enter into capital contribution front-ending agreements as part of a development-of-regional-impact development order to reimburse the developer, or the developer’s successor, for voluntary contributions paid in excess of his or her fair share.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to internal, onsite facilities required by local regulations or to any offsite facilities to the extent such facilities are necessary to provide safe and adequate services to the development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOCAL MONITORING.<EmDash />The local government issuing the development order is primarily responsible for monitoring the development and enforcing the provisions of the development order. Local governments shall not issue any permits or approvals or provide any extensions of services if the developer fails to act in substantial compliance with the development order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BIENNIAL REPORTS.<EmDash />The developer shall submit a biennial report on the development of regional impact to the local government, the regional planning agency, the state land planning agency, and all affected permit agencies in alternate years on the date specified in the development order, unless the development order by its terms requires more frequent monitoring. If the report is not received, the regional planning agency or the state land planning agency shall notify the local government. If the local government does not receive the report or receives notification that the regional planning agency or the state land planning agency has not received the report, the local government shall request in writing that the developer submit the report within 30 days. The failure to submit the report after 30 days shall result in the temporary suspension of the development order by the local government. If no additional development pursuant to the development order has occurred since the submission of the previous report, then a letter from the developer stating that no development has occurred shall satisfy the requirement for a report. Development orders that require annual reports may be amended to require biennial reports at the option of the local government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUBSTANTIAL DEVIATIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed change to a previously approved development which creates a reasonable likelihood of additional regional impact, or any type of regional impact created by the change not previously reviewed by the regional planning agency, shall constitute a substantial deviation and shall cause the proposed change to be subject to further development-of-regional-impact review. There are a variety of reasons why a developer may wish to propose changes to an approved development of regional impact, including changed market conditions. The procedures set forth in this subsection are for that purpose.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed change to a previously approved development of regional impact or development order condition which, either individually or cumulatively with other changes, exceeds any of the following criteria shall constitute a substantial deviation and shall cause the development to be subject to further development-of-regional-impact review without the necessity for a finding of same by the local government:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An increase in the number of parking spaces at an attraction or recreational facility by 15 percent or 500 spaces, whichever is greater, or an increase in the number of spectators that may be accommodated at such a facility by 15 percent or 1,500 spectators, whichever is greater.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A new runway, a new terminal facility, a 25 percent lengthening of an existing runway, or a 25 percent increase in the number of gates of an existing terminal, but only if the increase adds at least three additional gates.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An increase in land area for office development by 15 percent or an increase of gross floor area of office development by 15 percent or 100,000 gross square feet, whichever is greater.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An increase in the number of dwelling units by 10 percent or 55 dwelling units, whichever is greater.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An increase in the number of dwelling units by 50 percent or 200 units, whichever is greater, provided that 15 percent of the proposed additional dwelling units are dedicated to affordable workforce housing, subject to a recorded land use restriction that shall be for a period of not less than 20 years and that includes resale provisions to ensure long-term affordability for income-eligible homeowners and renters and provisions for the workforce housing to be commenced prior to the completion of 50 percent of the market rate dwelling. For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “affordable workforce housing” means housing that is affordable to a person who earns less than 120 percent of the area median income, or less than 140 percent of the area median income if located in a county in which the median purchase price for a single-family existing home exceeds the statewide median purchase price of a single-family existing home. For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “statewide median purchase price of a single-family existing home” means the statewide purchase price as determined in the Florida Sales Report, Single-Family Existing Homes, released each January by the Florida Association of Realtors and the University of Florida Real Estate Research Center.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An increase in commercial development by 60,000 square feet of gross floor area or of parking spaces provided for customers for 425 cars or a 10 percent increase, whichever is greater.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An increase in a recreational vehicle park area by 10 percent or 110 vehicle spaces, whichever is less.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A decrease in the area set aside for open space of 5 percent or 20 acres, whichever is less.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proposed increase to an approved multiuse development of regional impact where the sum of the increases of each land use as a percentage of the applicable substantial deviation criteria is equal to or exceeds 110 percent. The percentage of any decrease in the amount of open space shall be treated as an increase for purposes of determining when 110 percent has been reached or exceeded.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 15 percent increase in the number of external vehicle trips generated by the development above that which was projected during the original development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change that would result in development of any area which was specifically set aside in the application for development approval or in the development order for preservation or special protection of endangered or threatened plants or animals designated as endangered, threatened, or species of special concern and their habitat, any species protected by 16 U.S.C. ss. 668a-668d, primary dunes, or archaeological and historical sites designated as significant by the Division of Historical Resources of the Department of State. The refinement of the boundaries and configuration of such areas shall be considered under sub-subparagraph (e)2.j.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The substantial deviation numerical standards in subparagraphs 3., 6., and 9., excluding residential uses, and in subparagraph 10., are increased by 100 percent for a project certified under s. 403.973 which creates jobs and meets criteria established by the Department of Economic Opportunity as to its impact on an area’s economy, employment, and prevailing wage and skill levels. The substantial deviation numerical standards in subparagraphs 3., 4., 5., 6., 9., and 10. are increased by 50 percent for a project located wholly within an urban infill and redevelopment area designated on the applicable adopted local comprehensive plan future land use map and not located within the coastal high hazard area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Reference Number="4"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An extension of the date of buildout of a development, or any phase thereof, by more than 7 years is presumed to create a substantial deviation subject to further development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An extension of the date of buildout, or any phase thereof, of more than 5 years but not more than 7 years is presumed not to create a substantial deviation. The extension of the date of buildout of an areawide development of regional impact by more than 5 years but less than 10 years is presumed not to create a substantial deviation. These presumptions may be rebutted by clear and convincing evidence at the public hearing held by the local government. An extension of 5 years or less is not a substantial deviation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In recognition of the 2011 real estate market conditions, at the option of the developer, all commencement, phase, buildout, and expiration dates for projects that are currently valid developments of regional impact are extended for 4 years regardless of any previous extension. Associated mitigation requirements are extended for the same period unless, before December 1, 2011, a governmental entity notifies a developer that has commenced any construction within the phase for which the mitigation is required that the local government has entered into a contract for construction of a facility with funds to be provided from the development’s mitigation funds for that phase as specified in the development order or written agreement with the developer. The 4-year extension is not a substantial deviation, is not subject to further development-of-regional-impact review, and may not be considered when determining whether a subsequent extension is a substantial deviation under this subsection. The developer must notify the local government in writing by December 31, 2011, in order to receive the 4-year extension.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For the purpose of calculating when a buildout or phase date has been exceeded, the time shall be tolled during the pendency of administrative or judicial proceedings relating to development permits. Any extension of the buildout date of a project or a phase thereof shall automatically extend the commencement date of the project, the termination date of the development order, the expiration date of the development of regional impact, and the phases thereof if applicable by a like period of time.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A change in the plan of development of an approved development of regional impact resulting from requirements imposed by the Department of Environmental Protection or any water management district created by s. 373.069 or any of their successor agencies or by any appropriate federal regulatory agency shall be submitted to the local government pursuant to this subsection. The change shall be presumed not to create a substantial deviation subject to further development-of-regional-impact review. The presumption may be rebutted by clear and convincing evidence at the public hearing held by the local government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for a development order rendered pursuant to subsection (22) or subsection (25), a proposed change to a development order which individually or cumulatively with any previous change is less than any numerical criterion contained in subparagraphs (b)1.-10. and does not exceed any other criterion, or which involves an extension of the buildout date of a development, or any phase thereof, of less than 5 years is not subject to the public hearing requirements of subparagraph (f)3., and is not subject to a determination pursuant to subparagraph (f)5. Notice of the proposed change shall be made to the regional planning council and the state land planning agency. Such notice must include a description of previous individual changes made to the development, including changes previously approved by the local government, and must include appropriate amendments to the development order.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following changes, individually or cumulatively with any previous changes, are not substantial deviations:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes in the name of the project, developer, owner, or monitoring official.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes to a setback which do not affect noise buffers, environmental protection or mitigation areas, or archaeological or historical resources.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes to minimum lot sizes.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes in the configuration of internal roads which do not affect external access points.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes to the building design or orientation which stay approximately within the approved area designated for such building and parking lot, and which do not affect historical buildings designated as significant by the Division of Historical Resources of the Department of State.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes to increase the acreage in the development, if no development is proposed on the acreage to be added.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes to eliminate an approved land use, if there are no additional regional impacts.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes required to conform to permits approved by any federal, state, or regional permitting agency, if these changes do not create additional regional impacts.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any renovation or redevelopment of development within a previously approved development of regional impact which does not change land use or increase density or intensity of use.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="j">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes that modify boundaries and configuration of areas described in subparagraph (b)11. due to science-based refinement of such areas by survey, by habitat evaluation, by other recognized assessment methodology, or by an environmental assessment. In order for changes to qualify under this sub-subparagraph, the survey, habitat evaluation, or assessment must occur before the time that a conservation easement protecting such lands is recorded and must not result in any net decrease in the total acreage of the lands specifically set aside for permanent preservation in the final development order.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="k">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes that do not increase the number of external peak hour trips and do not reduce open space and conserved areas within the project except as otherwise permitted by sub-subparagraph j.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="l">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other change that the state land planning agency, in consultation with the regional planning council, agrees in writing is similar in nature, impact, or character to the changes enumerated in sub-subparagraphs a.-k. and that does not create the likelihood of any additional regional impact.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This subsection does not require the filing of a notice of proposed change but requires an application to the local government to amend the development order in accordance with the local government’s procedures for amendment of a development order. In accordance with the local government’s procedures, including requirements for notice to the applicant and the public, the local government shall either deny the application for amendment or adopt an amendment to the development order which approves the application with or without conditions. Following adoption, the local government shall render to the state land planning agency the amendment to the development order. The state land planning agency may appeal, pursuant to s. 380.07(3), the amendment to the development order if the amendment involves sub-subparagraph g., sub-subparagraph h., sub-subparagraph j., sub-subparagraph k., or sub-subparagraph l. and if the agency believes that the change creates a reasonable likelihood of new or additional regional impacts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for the change authorized by sub-subparagraph 2.f., any addition of land not previously reviewed or any change not specified in paragraph (b) or paragraph (c) shall be presumed to create a substantial deviation. This presumption may be rebutted by clear and convincing evidence.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any submittal of a proposed change to a previously approved development must include a description of individual changes previously made to the development, including changes previously approved by the local government. The local government shall consider the previous and current proposed changes in deciding whether such changes cumulatively constitute a substantial deviation requiring further development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following changes to an approved development of regional impact shall be presumed to create a substantial deviation. Such presumption may be rebutted by clear and convincing evidence.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A change proposed for 15 percent or more of the acreage to a land use not previously approved in the development order. Changes of less than 15 percent shall be presumed not to create a substantial deviation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of paragraph (b) to the contrary, a proposed change consisting of simultaneous increases and decreases of at least two of the uses within an authorized multiuse development of regional impact which was originally approved with three or more uses specified in s. 380.0651(3)(c) and (d) and residential use.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local government agrees to a proposed change, a change in the transportation proportionate share calculation and mitigation plan in an adopted development order as a result of recalculation of the proportionate share contribution meeting the requirements of s. 163.3180(5)(h) in effect as of the date of such change shall be presumed not to create a substantial deviation. For purposes of this subsection, the proposed change in the proportionate share calculation or mitigation plan may not be considered an additional regional transportation impact.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall establish by rule standard forms for submittal of proposed changes to a previously approved development of regional impact which may require further development-of-regional-impact review. At a minimum, the standard form shall require the developer to provide the precise language that the developer proposes to delete or add as an amendment to the development order.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall submit, simultaneously, to the local government, the regional planning agency, and the state land planning agency the request for approval of a proposed change.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No sooner than 30 days but no later than 45 days after submittal by the developer to the local government, the state land planning agency, and the appropriate regional planning agency, the local government shall give 15 days’ notice and schedule a public hearing to consider the change that the developer asserts does not create a substantial deviation. This public hearing shall be held within 60 days after submittal of the proposed changes, unless that time is extended by the developer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate regional planning agency or the state land planning agency shall review the proposed change and, no later than 45 days after submittal by the developer of the proposed change, unless that time is extended by the developer, and prior to the public hearing at which the proposed change is to be considered, shall advise the local government in writing whether it objects to the proposed change, shall specify the reasons for its objection, if any, and shall provide a copy to the developer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the public hearing, the local government shall determine whether the proposed change requires further development-of-regional-impact review. The provisions of paragraphs (a) and (e), the thresholds set forth in paragraph (b), and the presumptions set forth in paragraphs (c) and (d) and subparagraph (e)3. shall be applicable in determining whether further development-of-regional-impact review is required. The local government may also deny the proposed change based on matters relating to local issues, such as if the land on which the change is sought is plat restricted in a way that would be incompatible with the proposed change, and the local government does not wish to change the plat restriction as part of the proposed change.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local government determines that the proposed change does not require further development-of-regional-impact review and is otherwise approved, or if the proposed change is not subject to a hearing and determination pursuant to subparagraphs 3. and 5. and is otherwise approved, the local government shall issue an amendment to the development order incorporating the approved change and conditions of approval relating to the change. The requirement that a change be otherwise approved shall not be construed to require additional local review or approval if the change is allowed by applicable local ordinances without further local review or approval. The decision of the local government to approve, with or without conditions, or to deny the proposed change that the developer asserts does not require further review shall be subject to the appeal provisions of s. 380.07. However, the state land planning agency may not appeal the local government decision if it did not comply with subparagraph 4. The state land planning agency may not appeal a change to a development order made pursuant to subparagraph (e)1. or subparagraph (e)2. for developments of regional impact approved after January 1, 1980, unless the change would result in a significant impact to a regionally significant archaeological, historical, or natural resource not previously identified in the original development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a proposed change requires further development-of-regional-impact review pursuant to this section, the review shall be conducted subject to the following additional conditions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development-of-regional-impact review conducted by the appropriate regional planning agency shall address only those issues raised by the proposed change except as provided in subparagraph 2.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regional planning agency shall consider, and the local government shall determine whether to approve, approve with conditions, or deny the proposed change as it relates to the entire development. If the local government determines that the proposed change, as it relates to the entire development, is unacceptable, the local government shall deny the change.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local government determines that the proposed change should be approved, any new conditions in the amendment to the development order issued by the local government shall address only those issues raised by the proposed change and require mitigation only for the individual and cumulative impacts of the proposed change.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development within the previously approved development of regional impact may continue, as approved, during the development-of-regional-impact review in those portions of the development which are not directly affected by the proposed change.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When further development-of-regional-impact review is required because a substantial deviation has been determined or admitted by the developer, the amendment to the development order issued by the local government shall be consistent with the requirements of subsection (15) and shall be subject to the hearing and appeal provisions of s. 380.07. The state land planning agency or the appropriate regional planning agency need not participate at the local hearing in order to appeal a local government development order issued pursuant to this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An increase in the number of residential dwelling units shall not constitute a substantial deviation and shall not be subject to development-of-regional-impact review for additional impacts, provided that all the residential dwelling units are dedicated to affordable workforce housing and the total number of new residential units does not exceed 200 percent of the substantial deviation threshold. The affordable workforce housing shall be subject to a recorded land use restriction that shall be for a period of not less than 20 years and that includes resale provisions to ensure long-term affordability for income-eligible homeowners and renters. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “affordable workforce housing” means housing that is affordable to a person who earns less than 120 percent of the area median income, or less than 140 percent of the area median income if located in a county in which the median purchase price for a single-family existing home exceeds the statewide median purchase price of a single-family existing home. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “statewide median purchase price of a single-family existing home” means the statewide purchase price as determined in the Florida Sales Report, Single-Family Existing Homes, released each January by the Florida Association of Realtors and the University of Florida Real Estate Research Center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VESTED RIGHTS.<EmDash />Nothing in this section shall limit or modify the rights of any person to complete any development that was authorized by registration of a subdivision pursuant to former chapter 498, by recordation pursuant to local subdivision plat law, or by a building permit or other authorization to commence development on which there has been reliance and a change of position and which registration or recordation was accomplished, or which permit or authorization was issued, prior to July 1, 1973. If a developer has, by his or her actions in reliance on prior regulations, obtained vested or other legal rights that in law would have prevented a local government from changing those regulations in a way adverse to the developer’s interests, nothing in this chapter authorizes any governmental agency to abridge those rights.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of determining the vesting of rights under this subsection, approval pursuant to local subdivision plat law, ordinances, or regulations of a subdivision plat by formal vote of a county or municipal governmental body having jurisdiction after August 1, 1967, and prior to July 1, 1973, is sufficient to vest all property rights for the purposes of this subsection; and no action in reliance on, or change of position concerning, such local governmental approval is required for vesting to take place. Anyone claiming vested rights under this paragraph must notify the department in writing by January 1, 1986. Such notification shall include information adequate to document the rights established by this subsection. When such notification requirements are met, in order for the vested rights authorized pursuant to this paragraph to remain valid after June 30, 1990, development of the vested plan must be commenced prior to that date upon the property that the state land planning agency has determined to have acquired vested rights following the notification or in a binding letter of interpretation. When the notification requirements have not been met, the vested rights authorized by this paragraph shall expire June 30, 1986, unless development commenced prior to that date.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this act, the conveyance of, or the agreement to convey, property to the county, state, or local government as a prerequisite to zoning change approval shall be construed as an act of reliance to vest rights as determined under this subsection, provided such zoning change is actually granted by such government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPREHENSIVE APPLICATION; MASTER PLAN DEVELOPMENT ORDER.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a development project includes two or more developments of regional impact, a developer may file a comprehensive development-of-regional-impact application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a proposed development is planned for development over an extended period of time, the developer may file an application for master development approval of the project and agree to present subsequent increments of the development for preconstruction review. This agreement shall be entered into by the developer, the regional planning agency, and the appropriate local government having jurisdiction. The provisions of subsection (9) do not apply to this subsection, except that a developer may elect to utilize the review process established in subsection (9) for review of the increments of a master plan.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to adoption of the master plan development order, the developer, the landowner, the appropriate regional planning agency, and the local government having jurisdiction shall review the draft of the development order to ensure that anticipated regional impacts have been adequately addressed and that information requirements for subsequent incremental application review are clearly defined. The development order for a master application shall specify the information which must be submitted with an incremental application and shall identify those issues which can result in the denial of an incremental application.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The review of subsequent incremental applications shall be limited to that information specifically required and those issues specifically raised by the master development order, unless substantial changes in the conditions underlying the approval of the master plan development order are demonstrated or the master development order is shown to have been based on substantially inaccurate information.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency, by rule, shall establish uniform procedures to implement this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DOWNTOWN DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A downtown development authority may submit a development-of-regional-impact application for development approval pursuant to this section. The area described in the application may consist of any or all of the land over which a downtown development authority has the power described in s. 380.031(5). For the purposes of this subsection, a downtown development authority shall be considered the developer whether or not the development will be undertaken by the downtown development authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to information required by the development-of-regional-impact application, the application for development approval submitted by a downtown development authority shall specify the total amount of development planned for each land use category. In addition to the requirements of subsection (15), the development order shall specify the amount of development approved within each land use category. Development undertaken in conformance with a development order issued under this section does not require further review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a development is proposed within the area of a downtown development plan approved pursuant to this section which would result in development in excess of the amount specified in the development order for that type of activity, changes shall be subject to the provisions of subsection (19), except that the percentages and numerical criteria shall be double those listed in paragraph (19)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsection (9) do not apply to this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADOPTION OF RULES BY STATE LAND PLANNING AGENCY.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall adopt rules to ensure uniform review of developments of regional impact by the state land planning agency and regional planning agencies under this section. These rules shall be adopted pursuant to chapter 120 and shall include all forms, application content, and review guidelines necessary to implement development-of-regional-impact reviews. The state land planning agency, in consultation with the regional planning agencies, may also designate types of development or areas suitable for development in which reduced information requirements for development-of-regional-impact review shall apply.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional planning agencies shall be subject to rules adopted by the state land planning agency. At the request of a regional planning council, the state land planning agency may adopt by rule different standards for a specific comprehensive planning district upon a finding that the statewide standard is inadequate to protect or promote the regional interest at issue. If such a regional standard is adopted by the state land planning agency, the regional standard shall be applied to all pertinent development-of-regional-impact reviews conducted in that region until rescinded.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 6 months of the effective date of this section, the state land planning agency shall adopt rules which:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish uniform statewide standards for development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a short application for development approval form which eliminates issues and questions for any project in a jurisdiction with an adopted local comprehensive plan that is in compliance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional planning agencies that perform development-of-regional-impact and Florida Quality Development review are authorized to assess and collect fees to fund the costs, direct and indirect, of conducting the review process. The state land planning agency shall adopt rules to provide uniform criteria for the assessment and collection of such fees. The rules providing uniform criteria shall not be subject to rule challenge under s. 120.56(2) or to drawout proceedings under s. 120.54(3)(c)2., but, once adopted, shall be subject to an invalidity challenge under s. 120.56(3) by substantially affected persons. Until the state land planning agency adopts a rule implementing this paragraph, rules of the regional planning councils currently in effect regarding fees shall remain in effect. Fees may vary in relation to the type and size of a proposed project, but shall not exceed $75,000, unless the state land planning agency, after reviewing any disputed expenses charged by the regional planning agency, determines that said expenses were reasonable and necessary for an adequate regional review of the impacts of a project.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATUTORY EXEMPTIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed hospital is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed electrical transmission line or electrical power plant is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed addition to an existing sports facility complex is exempt from this section if the addition meets the following characteristics:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It would not operate concurrently with the scheduled hours of operation of the existing facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its seating capacity would be no more than 75 percent of the capacity of the existing facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sports facility complex property is owned by a public body before July 1, 1983.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This exemption does not apply to any pari-mutuel facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed addition or cumulative additions subsequent to July 1, 1988, to an existing sports facility complex owned by a state university is exempt if the increased seating capacity of the complex is no more than 30 percent of the capacity of the existing facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any addition of permanent seats or parking spaces for an existing sports facility located on property owned by a public body before July 1, 1973, is exempt from this section if future additions do not expand existing permanent seating or parking capacity more than 15 percent annually in excess of the prior year’s capacity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any increase in the seating capacity of an existing sports facility having a permanent seating capacity of at least 50,000 spectators is exempt from this section, provided that such an increase does not increase permanent seating capacity by more than 5 percent per year and not to exceed a total of 10 percent in any 5-year period, and provided that the sports facility notifies the appropriate local government within which the facility is located of the increase at least 6 months before the initial use of the increased seating, in order to permit the appropriate local government to develop a traffic management plan for the traffic generated by the increase. Any traffic management plan shall be consistent with the local comprehensive plan, the regional policy plan, and the state comprehensive plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any expansion in the permanent seating capacity or additional improved parking facilities of an existing sports facility is exempt from this section, if the following conditions exist:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sports facility had a permanent seating capacity on January 1, 1991, of at least 41,000 spectator seats;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sum of such expansions in permanent seating capacity does not exceed a total of 10 percent in any 5-year period and does not exceed a cumulative total of 20 percent for any such expansions; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The increase in additional improved parking facilities is a one-time addition and does not exceed 3,500 parking spaces serving the sports facility; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government having jurisdiction of the sports facility includes in the development order or development permit approving such expansion under this paragraph a finding of fact that the proposed expansion is consistent with the transportation, water, sewer and stormwater drainage provisions of the approved local comprehensive plan and local land development regulations relating to those provisions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any owner or developer who intends to rely on this statutory exemption shall provide to the department a copy of the local government application for a development permit. Within 45 days after receipt of the application, the department shall render to the local government an advisory and nonbinding opinion, in writing, stating whether, in the department’s opinion, the prescribed conditions exist for an exemption under this paragraph. The local government shall render the development order approving each such expansion to the department. The owner, developer, or department may appeal the local government development order pursuant to s. 380.07, within 45 days after the order is rendered. The scope of review shall be limited to the determination of whether the conditions prescribed in this paragraph exist. If any sports facility expansion undergoes development-of-regional-impact review, all previous expansions which were exempt under this paragraph shall be included in the development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expansion to port harbors, spoil disposal sites, navigation channels, turning basins, harbor berths, and other related inwater harbor facilities of ports listed in s. 403.021(9)(b), port transportation facilities and projects listed in s. 311.07(3)(b), and intermodal transportation facilities identified pursuant to s. 311.09(3) are exempt from this section when such expansions, projects, or facilities are consistent with comprehensive master plans that are in compliance with s. 163.3178.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed facility for the storage of any petroleum product or any expansion of an existing facility is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any renovation or redevelopment within the same land parcel which does not change land use or increase density or intensity of use.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waterport and marina development, including dry storage facilities, are exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed development within an urban service boundary established under s. 163.3177(14), Florida Statutes (2010), which is not otherwise exempt pursuant to subsection (29), is exempt from this section if the local government having jurisdiction over the area where the development is proposed has adopted the urban service boundary and has entered into a binding agreement with jurisdictions that would be impacted and with the Department of Transportation regarding the mitigation of impacts on state and regional transportation facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed development within a rural land stewardship area created under s. 163.3248.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The establishment, relocation, or expansion of any military installation as defined in s. 163.3175, is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any self-storage warehousing that does not allow retail or other services is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed nursing home or assisted living facility is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any development identified in an airport master plan and adopted into the comprehensive plan pursuant to <Reference Number="5"/>s. 163.3177(6)(b)4. is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any development identified in a campus master plan and adopted pursuant to s. 1013.30 is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any development in a detailed specific area plan which is prepared and adopted pursuant to s. 163.3245 is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed solid mineral mine and any proposed addition to, expansion of, or change to an existing solid mineral mine is exempt from this section. A mine owner will enter into a binding agreement with the Department of Transportation to mitigate impacts to strategic intermodal system facilities pursuant to the transportation thresholds in subsection (19) or rule 9J-2.045(6), Florida Administrative Code. Proposed changes to any previously approved solid mineral mine development-of-regional-impact development orders having vested rights are is not subject to further review or approval as a development-of-regional-impact or notice-of-proposed-change review or approval pursuant to subsection (19), except for those applications pending as of July 1, 2011, which shall be governed by s. 380.115(2). Notwithstanding the foregoing, however, pursuant to s. 380.115(1), previously approved solid mineral mine development-of-regional-impact development orders shall continue to enjoy vested rights and continue to be effective unless rescinded by the developer. All local government regulations of proposed solid mineral mines shall be applicable to any new solid mineral mine or to any proposed addition to, expansion of, or change to an existing solid mineral mine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provisions in an agreement with or among a local government, regional agency, or the state land planning agency or in a local government’s comprehensive plan to the contrary, a project no longer subject to development-of-regional-impact review under revised thresholds is not required to undergo such review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any development within a county with a research and education authority created by special act and that is also within a research and development park that is operated or managed by a research and development authority pursuant to part V of chapter 159 is exempt from this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any development in an energy economic zone designated pursuant to s. 377.809 is exempt from this section upon approval by its local governing body.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed development that is located in a local government jurisdiction that does not qualify for an exemption based on the population and density criteria in paragraph (29)(a), that is approved as a comprehensive plan amendment adopted pursuant to s. 163.3184(4), and that is the subject of an agreement pursuant to s. 288.106(5) is exempt from this section. This exemption shall only be effective upon a written agreement executed by the applicant, the local government, and the state land planning agency. The state land planning agency shall only be a party to the agreement upon a determination that the development is the subject of an agreement pursuant to s. 288.106(5) and that the local government has the capacity to adequately assess the impacts of the proposed development. The local government shall only be a party to the agreement upon approval by the governing body of the local government and upon providing at least 21 days’ notice to adjacent local governments that includes, at a minimum, information regarding the location, density and intensity of use, and timing of the proposed development. This exemption does not apply to areas within the boundary of any area of critical state concern designated pursuant to s. 380.05, within the boundary of the Wekiva Study Area as described in s. 369.316, or within 2 miles of the boundary of the Everglades Protection Area as defined in s. 373.4592(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If a use is exempt from review as a development of regional impact under paragraphs (a)-(u), but will be part of a larger project that is subject to review as a development of regional impact, the impact of the exempt use must be included in the review of the larger project, unless such exempt use involves a development of regional impact that includes a landowner, tenant, or user that has entered into a funding agreement with the Department of Economic Opportunity under the Innovation Incentive Program and the agreement contemplates a state award of at least $50 million.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AREAWIDE DEVELOPMENT OF REGIONAL IMPACT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authorized developer may submit an areawide development of regional impact to be reviewed pursuant to the procedures and standards set forth in this section. The areawide development-of-regional-impact review shall include an areawide development plan in addition to any other information required under this section. After review and approval of an areawide development of regional impact under this section, all development within the defined planning area shall conform to the approved areawide development plan and development order. Individual developments that conform to the approved areawide development plan shall not be required to undergo further development-of-regional-impact review, unless otherwise provided in the development order. As used in this subsection, the term:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Areawide development plan” means a plan of development that, at a minimum:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encompasses a defined planning area approved pursuant to this subsection that will include at least two or more developments;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maps and defines the land uses proposed, including the amount of development by use and development phasing;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Integrates a capital improvements program for transportation and other public facilities to ensure development staging contingent on availability of facilities and services;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incorporates land development regulation, covenants, and other restrictions adequate to protect resources and facilities of regional and state significance; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifies responsibilities and identifies the mechanisms for carrying out all commitments in the areawide development plan and for compliance with all conditions of any areawide development order.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Developer” means any person or association of persons, including a governmental agency as defined in s. 380.031(6), that petitions for authorization to file an application for development approval for an areawide development plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer may petition for authorization to submit a proposed areawide development of regional impact for a defined planning area in accordance with the following requirements:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition shall be submitted to the local government, the regional planning agency, and the state land planning agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public hearing or joint public hearing shall be held if required by paragraph (e), with appropriate notice, before the affected local government.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall apply the following criteria for evaluating a petition:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the developer is financially capable of processing the application for development approval through final approval pursuant to this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the defined planning area and anticipated development therein appear to be of a character, magnitude, and location that a proposed areawide development plan would be in the public interest. Any public interest determination under this criterion is preliminary and not binding on the state land planning agency, regional planning agency, or local government.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall develop and make available standard forms for petitions and applications for development approval for use under this subsection.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may submit a petition to a local government having jurisdiction over an area to be developed, requesting that government to approve that person as a developer, whether or not any or all development will be undertaken by that person, and to approve the area as appropriate for an areawide development of regional impact.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general purpose local government with jurisdiction over an area to be considered in an areawide development of regional impact shall not have to petition itself for authorization to prepare and consider an application for development approval for an areawide development plan. However, such a local government shall initiate the preparation of an application only:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After scheduling and conducting a public hearing as specified in paragraph (e); and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After conducting such hearing, finding that the planning area meets the standards and criteria pursuant to subparagraph (b)3. for determining that an areawide development plan will be in the public interest.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government shall schedule a public hearing within 60 days after receipt of the petition. The public hearing shall be advertised at least 30 days prior to the hearing. In addition to the public hearing notice by the local government, the petitioner, except when the petitioner is a local government, shall provide actual notice to each person owning land within the proposed areawide development plan at least 30 days prior to the hearing. If the petitioner is a local government, or local governments pursuant to an interlocal agreement, notice of the public hearing shall be provided by the publication of an advertisement in a newspaper of general circulation that meets the requirements of this paragraph. The advertisement must be no less than one-quarter page in a standard size or tabloid size newspaper, and the headline in the advertisement must be in type no smaller than 18 point. The advertisement shall not be published in that portion of the newspaper where legal notices and classified advertisements appear. The advertisement must be published in a newspaper of general paid circulation in the county and of general interest and readership in the community, not one of limited subject matter, pursuant to chapter 50. Whenever possible, the advertisement must appear in a newspaper that is published at least 5 days a week, unless the only newspaper in the community is published less than 5 days a week. The advertisement must be in substantially the form used to advertise amendments to comprehensive plans pursuant to s. 163.3184. The local government shall specifically notify in writing the regional planning agency and the state land planning agency at least 30 days prior to the public hearing. At the public hearing, all interested parties may testify and submit evidence regarding the petitioner’s qualifications, the need for and benefits of an areawide development of regional impact, and such other issues relevant to a full consideration of the petition. If more than one local government has jurisdiction over the defined planning area in an areawide development plan, the local governments shall hold a joint public hearing. Such hearing shall address, at a minimum, the need to resolve conflicting ordinances or comprehensive plans, if any. The local government holding the joint hearing shall comply with the following additional requirements:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice of the hearing shall be published at least 60 days in advance of the hearing and shall specify where the petition may be reviewed.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall be given to the state land planning agency, to the applicable regional planning agency, and to such other persons as may have been designated by the state land planning agency as entitled to receive such notices.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public hearing date shall be set by the appropriate local government at the next scheduled meeting.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following the public hearing, the local government shall issue a written order, appealable under s. 380.07, which approves, approves with conditions, or denies the petition. It shall approve the petitioner as the developer if it finds that the petitioner and defined planning area meet the standards and criteria, consistent with applicable law, pursuant to subparagraph (b)3.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government shall submit any order which approves the petition, or approves the petition with conditions, to the petitioner, to all owners of property within the defined planning area, to the regional planning agency, and to the state land planning agency within 30 days after the order becomes effective.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petitioner, an owner of property within the defined planning area, the appropriate regional planning agency by vote at a regularly scheduled meeting, or the state land planning agency may appeal the decision of the local government to the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission by filing a notice of appeal with the commission. The procedures established in s. 380.07 shall be followed for such an appeal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the time for appeal of the decision has run, an approved developer may submit an application for development approval for a proposed areawide development of regional impact for land within the defined planning area, pursuant to subsection (6). Development undertaken in conformance with an areawide development order issued under this section shall not require further development-of-regional-impact review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In reviewing an application for a proposed areawide development of regional impact, the regional planning agency shall evaluate, and the local government shall consider, the following criteria, in addition to any other criteria set forth in this section:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the developer has demonstrated its legal, financial, and administrative ability to perform any commitments it has made in the application for a proposed areawide development of regional impact.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the developer has demonstrated that all property owners within the defined planning area consent or do not object to the proposed areawide development of regional impact.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area and the anticipated development are consistent with the applicable local, regional, and state comprehensive plans, except as provided for in paragraph (k).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of subsection (14), a development order approving, or approving with conditions, a proposed areawide development of regional impact shall specify the approved land uses and the amount of development approved within each land use category in the defined planning area. The development order shall incorporate by reference the approved areawide development plan. The local government shall not approve an areawide development plan that is inconsistent with the local comprehensive plan, except that a local government may amend its comprehensive plan pursuant to paragraph (6)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any owner of property within the defined planning area may withdraw his or her consent to the areawide development plan at any time prior to local government approval, with or without conditions, of the petition; and the plan, the areawide development order, and the exemption from development-of-regional-impact review of individual projects under this section shall not thereafter apply to the owner’s property. After the areawide development order is issued, a landowner may withdraw his or her consent only with the approval of the local government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the developer of an areawide development of regional impact is a general purpose local government with jurisdiction over the land area included within the areawide development proposal and if no interest in the land within the land area is owned, leased, or otherwise controlled by a person, corporate or natural, for the purpose of mining or beneficiation of minerals, then:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstration of property owner consent or lack of objection to an areawide development plan shall not be required; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The option to withdraw consent does not apply, and all property and development within the areawide development planning area shall be subject to the areawide plan and to the development order conditions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a development order approving an areawide development plan is received, changes shall be subject to the provisions of subsection (19), except that the percentages and numerical criteria shall be double those listed in paragraph (19)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="26">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ABANDONMENT OF DEVELOPMENTS OF REGIONAL IMPACT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby established a process to abandon a development of regional impact and its associated development orders. A development of regional impact and its associated development orders may be proposed to be abandoned by the owner or developer. The local government in which the development of regional impact is located also may propose to abandon the development of regional impact, provided that the local government gives individual written notice to each development-of-regional-impact owner and developer of record, and provided that no such owner or developer objects in writing to the local government prior to or at the public hearing pertaining to abandonment of the development of regional impact. The state land planning agency is authorized to promulgate rules that shall include, but not be limited to, criteria for determining whether to grant, grant with conditions, or deny a proposal to abandon, and provisions to ensure that the developer satisfies all applicable conditions of the development order and adequately mitigates for the impacts of the development. If there is no existing development within the development of regional impact at the time of abandonment and no development within the development of regional impact is proposed by the owner or developer after such abandonment, an abandonment order shall not require the owner or developer to contribute any land, funds, or public facilities as a condition of such abandonment order. The rules shall also provide a procedure for filing notice of the abandonment pursuant to s. 28.222 with the clerk of the circuit court for each county in which the development of regional impact is located. Any decision by a local government concerning the abandonment of a development of regional impact shall be subject to an appeal pursuant to s. 380.07. The issues in any such appeal shall be confined to whether the provisions of this subsection or any rules promulgated thereunder have been satisfied.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of written confirmation from the state land planning agency that any required mitigation applicable to completed development has occurred, an industrial development of regional impact located within the coastal high-hazard area of a rural county of economic concern which was approved prior to the adoption of the local government’s comprehensive plan required under s. 163.3167 and which plan’s future land use map and zoning designates the land use for the development of regional impact as commercial may be unilaterally abandoned without the need to proceed through the process described in paragraph (a) if the developer or owner provides a notice of abandonment to the local government and records such notice with the applicable clerk of court. Abandonment shall be deemed to have occurred upon the recording of the notice. All development following abandonment shall be fully consistent with the current comprehensive plan and applicable zoning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="27">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RIGHTS, RESPONSIBILITIES, AND OBLIGATIONS UNDER A DEVELOPMENT ORDER.<EmDash />If a developer or owner is in doubt as to his or her rights, responsibilities, and obligations under a development order and the development order does not clearly define his or her rights, responsibilities, and obligations, the developer or owner may request participation in resolving the dispute through the dispute resolution process outlined in s. 186.509. The Department of Economic Opportunity shall be notified by certified mail of any meeting held under the process provided for by this subsection at least 5 days before the meeting.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="28">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARTIAL STATUTORY EXEMPTIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the binding agreement referenced under paragraph (24)(l) for urban service boundaries is not entered into within 12 months after establishment of the urban service boundary, the development-of-regional-impact review for projects within the urban service boundary must address transportation impacts only.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the binding agreement referenced under paragraph (24)(m) for rural land stewardship areas is not entered into within 12 months after the designation of a rural land stewardship area, the development-of-regional-impact review for projects within the rural land stewardship area must address transportation impacts only.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the binding agreement for designated urban infill and redevelopment areas is not entered into within 12 months after the designation of the area or July 1, 2007, whichever occurs later, the development-of-regional-impact review for projects within the urban infill and redevelopment area must address transportation impacts only.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government that does not wish to enter into a binding agreement or that is unable to agree on the terms of the agreement referenced under paragraph (24)(l) or paragraph (24)(m) shall provide written notification to the state land planning agency of the decision to not enter into a binding agreement or the failure to enter into a binding agreement within the 12-month period referenced in paragraphs (a), (b) and (c). Following the notification of the state land planning agency, development-of-regional-impact review for projects within an urban service boundary under paragraph (24)(l), or a rural land stewardship area under paragraph (24)(m), must address transportation impacts only.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vesting provision of s. 163.3167(5) relating to an authorized development of regional impact does not apply to those projects partially exempt from the development-of-regional-impact review process under paragraphs (a)-(d).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="29">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS FOR DENSE URBAN LAND AREAS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from this section:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed development in a municipality that has an average of at least 1,000 people per square mile of land area and a minimum total population of at least 5,000;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed development within a county, including the municipalities located in the county, that has an average of at least 1,000 people per square mile of land area and is located within an urban service area as defined in s. 163.3164 which has been adopted into the comprehensive plan;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed development within a county, including the municipalities located therein, which has a population of at least 900,000, that has an average of at least 1,000 people per square mile of land area, but which does not have an urban service area designated in the comprehensive plan; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed development within a county, including the municipalities located therein, which has a population of at least 1 million and is located within an urban service area as defined in s. 163.3164 which has been adopted into the comprehensive plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Office of Economic and Demographic Research within the Legislature shall annually calculate the population and density criteria needed to determine which jurisdictions meet the density criteria in subparagraphs 1.-4. by using the most recent land area data from the decennial census conducted by the Bureau of the Census of the United States Department of Commerce and the latest available population estimates determined pursuant to s. 186.901. If any local government has had an annexation, contraction, or new incorporation, the Office of Economic and Demographic Research shall determine the population density using the new jurisdictional boundaries as recorded in accordance with s. 171.091. The Office of Economic and Demographic Research shall annually submit to the state land planning agency by July 1 a list of jurisdictions that meet the total population and density criteria. The state land planning agency shall publish the list of jurisdictions on its Internet website within 7 days after the list is received. The designation of jurisdictions that meet the criteria of subparagraphs 1.-4. is effective upon publication on the state land planning agency’s Internet website. If a municipality that has previously met the criteria no longer meets the criteria, the state land planning agency shall maintain the municipality on the list and indicate the year the jurisdiction last met the criteria. However, any proposed development of regional impact not within the established boundaries of a municipality at the time the municipality last met the criteria must meet the requirements of this section until such time as the municipality as a whole meets the criteria. Any county that meets the criteria shall remain on the list in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph. Any jurisdiction that was placed on the dense urban land area list before June 2, 2011, shall remain on the list in accordance with the provisions of this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a municipality that does not qualify as a dense urban land area <Reference Number="6"/>pursuant to paragraph (a) designates any of the following areas in its comprehensive plan, any proposed development within the designated area is exempt from the development-of-regional-impact process:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Urban infill as defined in s. 163.3164;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community redevelopment areas as defined in s. 163.340;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Downtown revitalization areas as defined in s. 163.3164;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Urban infill and redevelopment under s. 163.2517; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Urban service areas as defined in s. 163.3164 or areas within a designated urban service boundary under s. 163.3177(14).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a county that does not qualify as a dense urban land area designates any of the following areas in its comprehensive plan, any proposed development within the designated area is exempt from the development-of-regional-impact process:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Urban infill as defined in s. 163.3164;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Urban infill and redevelopment under s. 163.2517; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Urban service areas as defined in s. 163.3164.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A development that is located partially outside an area that is exempt from the development-of-regional-impact program must undergo development-of-regional-impact review pursuant to this section. However, if the total acreage that is included within the area exempt from development-of-regional-impact review exceeds 85 percent of the total acreage and square footage of the approved development of regional impact, the development-of-regional-impact development order may be rescinded in both local governments pursuant to s. 380.115(1), unless the portion of the development outside the exempt area meets the threshold criteria of a development-of-regional-impact.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an area that is exempt under paragraphs (a)-(c), any previously approved development-of-regional-impact development orders shall continue to be effective, but the developer has the option to be governed by s. 380.115(1). A pending application for development approval shall be governed by s. 380.115(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local governments must submit by mail a development order to the state land planning agency for projects that would be larger than 120 percent of any applicable development-of-regional-impact threshold and would require development-of-regional-impact review but for the exemption from the program under paragraphs (a)-(c). For such development orders, the state land planning agency may appeal the development order pursuant to s. 380.07 for inconsistency with the comprehensive plan adopted under chapter 163.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local government that qualifies as a dense urban land area under this subsection is subsequently found to be ineligible for designation as a dense urban land area, any development located within that area which has a complete, pending application for authorization to commence development may maintain the exemption if the developer is continuing the application process in good faith or the development is approved.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not limit or modify the rights of any person to complete any development that has been authorized as a development of regional impact pursuant to this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to areas:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within the boundary of any area of critical state concern designated pursuant to s. 380.05;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within the boundary of the Wekiva Study Area as described in s. 369.316; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 2 miles of the boundary of the Everglades Protection Area as described in s. 373.4592(2).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 72-317; s. 2, ch. 74-326; s. 5, ch. 75-167; s. 1, ch. 76-69; s. 2, ch. 77-215; s. 148, ch. 79-400; s. 3, ch. 80-313; s. 22, ch. 83-222; s. 4, ch. 83-308; s. 1, ch. 84-331; s. 43, ch. 85-55; s. 15, ch. 86-191; s. 1, ch. 88-164; s. 1, ch. 89-375; s. 1, ch. 89-536; s. 52, ch. 90-331; s. 20, ch. 91-192; s. 20, ch. 91-305; s. 1, ch. 91-309; s. 15, ch. 92-129; s. 2, ch. 93-95; s. 52, ch. 93-206; s. 345, ch. 94-356; s. 1029, ch. 95-148; s. 11, ch. 95-149; s. 9, ch. 95-322; s. 3, ch. 95-412; s. 114, ch. 96-410; s. 10, ch. 96-416; s. 1, ch. 97-28; s. 7, ch. 97-253; s. 52, ch. 97-278; s. 8, ch. 98-146; ss. 26, 31, ch. 98-176; s. 71, ch. 99-251; s. 7, ch. 99-378; s. 27, ch. 2001-201; s. 95, ch. 2002-20; s. 30, ch. 2002-296; s. 1, ch. 2004-10; s. 16, ch. 2005-157; s. 4, ch. 2005-166; s. 13, ch. 2005-281; s. 17, ch. 2005-290; s. 12, ch. 2006-69; s. 8, ch. 2006-220; s. 73, ch. 2007-5; ss. 8, 9, ch. 2007-198; s. 6, ch. 2007-204; s. 17, ch. 2008-240; s. 12, ch. 2009-96; s. 16, ch. 2010-4; s. 73, ch. 2010-5; s. 90, ch. 2010-102; s. 11, ch. 2011-14; ss. 54, 80, ch. 2011-139; s. 258, ch. 2011-142; s. 4, ch. 2011-223; s. 2, ch. 2012-75; s. 60, ch. 2012-96; s. 17, ch. 2012-99.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 17, ch. 2012-99. The amendment by s. 60, ch. 2012-96, used “s. 163.3184(3)(b) and (c)” instead of “s. 163.3184.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 17, ch. 2012-99. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Subparagraph (6)(b)5. was also amended by s. 60, ch. 2012-96, and that version reads:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">5. Notwithstanding subsection (11) or subsection (19), the local government may not hold a public hearing on the application for development approval or the proposed change or on the comprehensive plan amendments sooner than 30 days after receipt of the response from the state land planning agency pursuant to s. 163.3184(3)(c)1.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="3">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 95, ch. 2002-20. The amendment by s. 30, ch. 2002-296, provides for less than or equal to 100 percent.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="4">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 14, ch. 2009-96, as reenacted by s. 12, ch. 2011-14, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Except as provided in subsection (4), and in recognition of 2009 real estate market conditions, any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, that has an expiration date of September 1, 2008, through January 1, 2012, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years following its date of expiration. This extension includes any local government-issued development order or building permit. The 2-year extension also applies to build out dates including any build out date extension previously granted under s. 380.06(19)(c), Florida Statutes. This section shall not be construed to prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project shall be extended such that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension shall notify the authorizing agency in writing no later than December 31, 2009, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension, that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except when it can be demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision shall apply to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit that lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification shall not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) Nothing in this section shall impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property, that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intention to receive the extension of time granted by this section, to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 46, ch. 2010-147, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Except as provided in subsection (4), a development order issued by a local government, a building permit, and any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or by a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, which has an expiration date from September 1, 2008, through January 1, 2012, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years after its previously scheduled date of expiration. This 2-year extension also applies to buildout dates, including any extension of a buildout date that was previously granted under s. 380.06(19)(c), Florida Statutes. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. This extension is in addition to the 2-year permit extension provided under section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project are extended so that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension must notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2010, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit which lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification does not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intent to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 47, ch. 2010-147, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The Legislature hereby reauthorizes:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) Any exemption granted for any project for which an application for development approval has been approved or filed pursuant to s. 380.06, Florida Statutes, or for which a complete development application or rescission request has been approved or is pending, and the application or rescission process is continuing in good faith, within a development that is located within an area that qualified for an exemption under s. 380.06, Florida Statutes, as amended by chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) Any 2-year extension authorized and timely applied for pursuant to section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) Any amendment to a local comprehensive plan adopted pursuant to s. 163.3184, Florida Statutes, as amended by chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, and in effect pursuant to s. 163.3189, Florida Statutes, which authorizes and implements a transportation concurrency exception area pursuant to s. 163.3180, Florida Statutes, as amended by chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Subsection (1) is intended to be remedial in nature and to reenact provisions of existing law. This section shall apply retroactively to all actions specified in subsection (1) and therefore to any such actions lawfully undertaken in accordance with chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Section 163.3189, referenced in s. 47(1)(c), ch. 2010-147, above, was repealed by s. 19, chapter 2011-139.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">D. Section 73, ch. 2011-139, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Any permit or any other authorization that was extended under section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida, is extended and renewed for an additional period of 2 years after its previously scheduled expiration date. This extension is in addition to the 2-year permit extension provided under section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. Permits that were extended by a total of 4 years pursuant to section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida, and by section 46 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida, cannot be further extended under this provision.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project shall be extended such that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension shall notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2011, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension, that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This subsection applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit that lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification may not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intention to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">E. Section 79, ch. 2011-139, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Except as provided in subsection (4), and in recognition of 2011 real estate market conditions, any building permit, and any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or by a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, which has an expiration date from January 1, 2012, through January 1, 2014, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years after its previously scheduled date of expiration. This extension includes any local government-issued development order or building permit including certificates of levels of service. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. This extension is in addition to any existing permit extension. Extensions granted pursuant to this section; section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; section 46 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; or section 74 of this act shall not exceed 4 years in total. Further, specific development order extensions granted pursuant to s. 380.06(19)(c)2., Florida Statutes, cannot be further extended by this section.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project are extended so that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension must notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2011, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit which lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification does not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intent to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The reference to “section 74 of this act” in s. 79(1), ch. 2011-139, should be to s. 73; s. 74 relates to review of issues, and s. 73 provides for a 2-year permit extension.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">F. Section 23, ch. 2012-205, provides that “[t]he holder of a valid permit or other authorization is not required to make a payment to the authorizing agency for use of an extension granted under section 73 or section 79 of chapter 2011-139, Laws of Florida, or section 24 of this act. This section applies retroactively and is effective as of June 2, 2011.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">G. Section 24, ch. 2012-205, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Any building permit, and any permit issued by the Department of Environmental Protection or by a water management district pursuant to part IV of chapter 373, Florida Statutes, which has an expiration date from January 1, 2012, through January 1, 2014, is extended and renewed for a period of 2 years after its previously scheduled date of expiration. This extension includes any local government-issued development order or building permit including certificates of levels of service. This section does not prohibit conversion from the construction phase to the operation phase upon completion of construction. This extension is in addition to any existing permit extension. Extensions granted pursuant to this section; section 14 of chapter 2009-96, Laws of Florida, as reauthorized by section 47 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; section 46 of chapter 2010-147, Laws of Florida; or section 74 or section 79 of chapter 2011-139, Laws of Florida, shall not exceed 4 years in total. Further, specific development order extensions granted pursuant to s. 380.06(19)(c)2., Florida Statutes, cannot be further extended by this section.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The commencement and completion dates for any required mitigation associated with a phased construction project are extended so that mitigation takes place in the same timeframe relative to the phase as originally permitted.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The holder of a valid permit or other authorization that is eligible for the 2-year extension must notify the authorizing agency in writing by December 31, 2012, identifying the specific authorization for which the holder intends to use the extension and the anticipated timeframe for acting on the authorization.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The extension provided for in subsection (1) does not apply to:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) A permit or other authorization under any programmatic or regional general permit issued by the Army Corps of Engineers.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) A permit or other authorization held by an owner or operator determined to be in significant noncompliance with the conditions of the permit or authorization as established through the issuance of a warning letter or notice of violation, the initiation of formal enforcement, or other equivalent action by the authorizing agency.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) A permit or other authorization, if granted an extension that would delay or prevent compliance with a court order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) Permits extended under this section shall continue to be governed by the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued, except if it is demonstrated that the rules in effect at the time the permit was issued would create an immediate threat to public safety or health. This provision applies to any modification of the plans, terms, and conditions of the permit which lessens the environmental impact, except that any such modification does not extend the time limit beyond 2 additional years.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) This section does not impair the authority of a county or municipality to require the owner of a property that has notified the county or municipality of the owner’s intent to receive the extension of time granted pursuant to this section to maintain and secure the property in a safe and sanitary condition in compliance with applicable laws and ordinances.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The reference to “section 74” in s. 24(1), ch. 2012-205, should be to s. 73. The reference to s. 74, ch. 2011-139, relates to review of issues; the intended reference to s. 73, ch. 2011-139, provides for a 2-year permit extension.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="5">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 17, ch. 2012-99. The amendment by s. 60, ch. 2012-96, used “s. 163.3177(6)(k), Florida Statutes (2010)” instead of “s. 163.3177(6)(b)4.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="6">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 17, ch. 2012-99. The amendment by s. 60, ch. 2012-96, removed the language “pursuant to s. 163.3164”; s. 17, ch. 2012-99, retained the words “pursuant to” and replaced the citation with “paragraph (a).”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>