<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0896.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rewards for private entities combating international money laundering.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting any investigation of a violation of this chapter, the Department of Law Enforcement may enter into agreements and pay a reward to any individual or entity who provides original information that leads to a recovery of a criminal fine, civil penalty, or forfeiture based in whole or in part upon a violation of federal law or the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement shall determine the amount of a reward under this section. The executive director, with written approval of the Office of the Attorney General, may exceed the limits of rewards provided in s. 896.107, when the criminal fine, civil penalty, or forfeiture amount received by the state warrants an upward departure from such limits. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rewards paid under this section shall be paid only from seized assets awarded by the court. Funds seized by the Department of Law Enforcement pursuant to this chapter shall be placed in the department’s Forfeiture and Investigative Support Trust Fund established by s. 943.362, or for funds secured through the federal forfeiture actions in the Federal Law Enforcement Trust Fund established by s. 943.365, excluding any rewards paid as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer or employee of the Federal Government, a state or local government, or a foreign government who in the performance of official duties provides information described in subsection (1) is not eligible for a reward under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of a reward does not affect the admissibility of testimony in any court proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 2009-242.</History></Section>