<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0896.104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Structuring transactions to evade reporting or registration requirements prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />For purposes of this section, the terms “structure” or “structuring” mean that a person, acting alone, or in conjunction with, or on behalf of, other persons, conducts or attempts to conduct one or more transactions in currency, in any amount, at one or more financial institutions, on one or more days, in any manner, for the purpose of evading currency transaction reporting requirements provided by state or federal law. “In any manner” includes, but is not limited to, the breaking down of a single sum of currency exceeding $10,000 into smaller sums, including sums at or below $10,000, or the conduct of a transaction, or series of currency transactions, at or below $10,000. The transaction or transactions need not exceed the $10,000 reporting threshold at any single financial institution on any single day in order to meet the definition of “structure” or “structuring” provided in this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DOMESTIC COIN AND CURRENCY TRANSACTIONS.<EmDash />A person may not, for the purpose of evading the reporting and registration requirements of chapter 560, chapter 655, or this chapter, or 31 U.S.C. s. 5313(a) or s. 5325, or any rules or regulations adopted under those chapters and sections, when some portion of the activity by that person occurs in this state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause or attempt to cause a person or financial institution in this state to fail to file an applicable report or registration required under those chapters and sections or any rule or regulation adopted under any of those chapters and sections;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause or attempt to cause a person or financial institution in this state to file an applicable report required under those chapters and sections or any rule or regulation adopted under those chapters and sections which contains a material omission or misstatement of fact; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Structure or assist in structuring, or attempt to structure or assist in structuring, any financial transaction with or involving one or more financial institutions in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTERNATIONAL MONETARY INSTRUMENT TRANSACTIONS.<EmDash />A person may not, for the purpose of evading the reporting or registration requirements of chapter 560, chapter 655, or this chapter, or 31 U.S.C. s. 5316, when some portion of the activity by that person occurs in this state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to file an applicable registration or report required by those chapters and sections, or cause or attempt to cause a person to fail to file such a report;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File or cause or attempt to cause a person to file an applicable registration or report required under those chapters and sections which contains a material omission or misstatement of fact; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Structure or assist in structuring, or attempt to structure or assist in structuring, any importation or exportation of currency or monetary instruments or funds to, from, or through financial institutions in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CRIMINAL PENALTIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section, if the violation involves:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial transactions exceeding $300 but less than $20,000 in any 12-month period, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial transactions totaling or exceeding $20,000 but less than $100,000 in any 12-month period, commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial transactions totaling or exceeding $100,000 in any 12-month period, commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the penalties authorized by s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, a person who has been found guilty of or who has pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to having violated this section may be sentenced to pay a fine not exceeding $250,000 or twice the value of the financial transactions, whichever is greater, except that for a second or subsequent violation of this section, the fine may be up to $500,000 or quintuple the value of the financial transactions, whichever is greater.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section is also liable for a civil penalty of not more than the value of the financial transactions involved or $25,000, whichever is greater.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INFERENCE.<EmDash />Proof that a person engaged for monetary consideration in the business of a money transmitter, as defined in s. 560.103, and who is transporting more than $10,000 in currency, or the foreign equivalent, without being licensed as a money transmitter or designated as an authorized vendor under chapter 560, gives rise to an inference that the transportation was done with knowledge of the licensure requirements of chapter 560 and the reporting requirements of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSTRUCTION.<EmDash />This section may not be construed to require any new or additional reporting requirements on any entity obligated to file reports under state or federal law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 2000-360; s. 1918, ch. 2003-261; s. 53, ch. 2008-177.</History></Section>