<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0629.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power of attorney.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and powers of the attorney of a reciprocal insurer shall be as provided in the power of attorney given it by the subscribers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The power of attorney must set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers of the attorney;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the attorney is empowered to accept service of process on behalf of the insurer in actions against the insurer upon contracts exchanged;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The general services to be performed by the attorney;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum amount to be deducted from advance premiums or deposits to be paid to the attorney and the general items of expense in addition to losses, to be paid by the insurer; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as to nonassessable policies, a provision for a contingent several liability of each subscriber in a specified amount, which amount shall be not less than 5 nor more than 10 times the premium or premium deposit stated in the policy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The power of attorney may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the right of substitution of the attorney and revocation of the power of attorney and rights thereunder;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose such restrictions upon the exercise of the power as are agreed upon by the subscribers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the exercise of any right reserved to the subscribers directly or through their advisory committee; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain other lawful provisions deemed advisable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms of any power of attorney or agreement collateral thereto shall be reasonable and equitable, and no such power or agreement shall be used or be effective in this state unless filed with the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 680, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 673, 681, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1317, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>