<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0629.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Organization of reciprocal insurer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five or more persons domiciled in this state may organize a domestic reciprocal insurer and make application to the office for a certificate of authority to transact insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed attorney shall fulfill the requirements of and shall execute and file with the office, when applying for a certificate of authority, a declaration setting forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the insurer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of the insurer’s principal office, which shall be the same as that of the attorney and shall be maintained within this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The kinds of insurance proposed to be transacted;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of the original subscribers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designation and appointment of the proposed attorney and a copy of the power of attorney;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of the officers and directors of the attorney, if a corporation, or of its members, if other than a corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers of the subscribers’ advisory committee, and the names and terms of office of the members thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all moneys paid to the reciprocal shall, after deducting therefrom any sum payable to the attorney, be held in the name of the insurer and for the purposes specified in the subscribers’ agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the subscribers’ agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that each of the original subscribers has in good faith applied for insurance of a kind proposed to be transacted, and that the insurer has received from each such subscriber the full premium or premium deposit required for the policy applied for, for a term of not less than 6 months at an adequate rate theretofore filed with and approved by the office;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the financial condition of the insurer, a schedule of its assets, and a statement that the surplus as required by s. 629.071 is on hand; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of each policy, endorsement, and application form it then proposes to issue or use.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such declaration shall be acknowledged by the attorney before an officer authorized to take acknowledgments.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 678, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 671, 681, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1316, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>