<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0461.013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for disciplinary action; action by the board; investigations by department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to obtain, obtaining, or renewing a license to practice podiatric medicine by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentations, or through an error of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice podiatric medicine revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of podiatric medicine or to the ability to practice podiatric medicine. Any plea of nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction for purposes of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">False, deceptive, or misleading advertising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising, practicing, or attempting to practice under a name other than one’s own.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department any person who the licensee knows is in violation of this chapter or of the rules of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, permitting, or advising any unlicensed person to practice podiatric medicine contrary to this chapter or to rule of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a licensed podiatric physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing or inducing another person to do so. Such report or records shall include only those which are signed in the capacity of a licensed podiatric physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making misleading, deceptive, untrue, or fraudulent representations in the practice of podiatric medicine or employing a trick or scheme in the practice of podiatric medicine when such scheme or trick fails to conform to the generally prevailing standards of treatment in the podiatric community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soliciting patients either personally or through an agent, unless such solicitation falls into a category of solicitations approved by rule of the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to keep written medical records justifying the course of treatment of the patient, including, but not limited to, patient histories, examination results, and test results.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on the patient or client in such a manner as to exploit the patient or client for financial gain of the licensee or of a third party which shall include, but not be limited to, the promotion or sale of services, goods, appliances, or drugs and the promoting or advertising on any prescription form of a community pharmacy unless the form shall also state “This prescription may be filled at any pharmacy of your choice.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing professional services which have not been duly authorized by the patient or client or her or his legal representative except as provided in ss. 743.064, 766.103, and 768.13.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, dispensing, administering, mixing, or otherwise preparing a legend drug, including all controlled substances, other than in the course of the podiatric physician’s professional practice. For the purposes of this paragraph, it shall be legally presumed that prescribing, dispensing, administering, mixing, or otherwise preparing legend drugs, including all controlled substances, inappropriately or in excessive or inappropriate quantities is not in the best interest of the patient and is not in the course of the podiatric physician’s professional practice, without regard to her or his intent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, dispensing, or administering any medicinal drug appearing on any schedule set forth in chapter 893 by the podiatric physician to herself or himself except those prescribed, dispensed, or administered to the podiatric physician by another practitioner authorized to prescribe, dispense, or administer them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, ordering, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, or giving any amphetamine or sympathomimetic amine drug or compound designated as a Schedule II controlled substance pursuant to chapter 893.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice podiatric medicine with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness or use of alcohol, drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other type of material or as a result of any mental or physical condition. In enforcing this paragraph the department shall, upon probable cause, have authority to compel a podiatric physician to submit to a mental or physical examination by physicians designated by the department. Failure of a podiatric physician to submit to such examination when directed shall constitute an admission of the allegations against her or him, unless the failure was due to circumstances beyond her or his control, consequent upon which a default and final order may be entered without the taking of testimony or presentation of evidence. A podiatric physician affected under this paragraph shall at reasonable intervals be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that she or he can resume the competent practice of podiatric medicine with reasonable skill and safety to patients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross or repeated malpractice or the failure to practice podiatric medicine at a level of care, skill, and treatment which is recognized by a reasonably prudent podiatric physician as being acceptable under similar conditions and circumstances. The board shall give great weight to the standards for malpractice in s. 766.102 in interpreting this section. As used in this paragraph, “repeated malpractice” includes, but is not limited to, three or more claims for medical malpractice within the previous 5-year period resulting in indemnities being paid in excess of $50,000 each to the claimant in a judgment or settlement and which incidents involved negligent conduct by the podiatric physicians. As used in this paragraph, “gross malpractice” or “the failure to practice podiatric medicine with the level of care, skill, and treatment which is recognized by a reasonably prudent similar podiatric physician as being acceptable under similar conditions and circumstances” shall not be construed so as to require more than one instance, event, or act. A recommended order by an administrative law judge or a final order of the board finding a violation under this paragraph shall specify whether the licensee was found to have committed “gross malpractice,” “repeated malpractice,” or “failure to practice podiatric medicine with that level of care, skill, and treatment which is recognized as being acceptable under similar conditions and circumstances,” or any combination thereof, and any publication by the board must so specify.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing any procedure or prescribing any therapy which, by the prevailing standards of podiatric medical practice in the community, would constitute experimentation on human subjects without first obtaining full, informed, and written consent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or offering to practice beyond the scope permitted by law or accepting and performing professional responsibilities which the licensee knows or has reason to know that she or he is not competent to perform.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating professional responsibilities to a person when the licensee delegating such responsibilities knows or has reason to know that such person is not qualified by training, experience, or licensure to perform them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="w"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a lawful order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the board or department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="x"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conspiring with another licensee or with any other person to commit an act, or committing an act, which would tend to coerce, intimidate, or preclude another licensee from lawfully advertising her or his services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="y"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, ordering, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, or giving growth hormones, testosterone or its analogs, human chorionic gonadotropin (HCG), or other hormones for the purpose of muscle building or to enhance athletic performance. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “muscle building” does not include the treatment of injured muscle. A prescription written for any of the drug products listed above may be dispensed by the pharmacist with the presumption that the prescription is for legitimate medical use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="z"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraud, deceit, or misconduct in the practice of podiatric medicine.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="aa"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department any licensee under chapter 458 or chapter 459 who the podiatric physician knows has violated the grounds for disciplinary action set out in the law under which that person is licensed and who provides health care services in a facility licensed under chapter 395, or a health maintenance organization certificated under part I of chapter 641, in which the podiatric physician also provides services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="bb"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to comply with the requirements of ss. 381.026 and 381.0261 to provide patients with information about their patient rights and how to file a patient complaint.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="cc"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not reinstate the license of a podiatric physician, or cause a license to be issued to a person the board has deemed unqualified, until such time as the board is satisfied that she or he has complied with all the terms and conditions set forth in the final order and that such person is capable of safely engaging in the practice of podiatric medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall by rule establish guidelines for the disposition of disciplinary cases involving specific types of violations. Such guidelines may include minimum and maximum fines, periods of supervision or probation, or conditions of probation or reissuance of a license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the department’s receipt from an insurer or self-insurer of a report of a closed claim against a podiatric physician pursuant to s. 627.912, or upon the receipt from a claimant of a presuit notice against a podiatric physician pursuant to s. 766.106, the department shall review each report and determine whether it potentially involved conduct by a licensee that is subject to disciplinary action, in which case the provisions of s. 456.073 shall apply. However, if it is reported that a podiatric physician has had three or more claims with indemnities exceeding $50,000 each within the previous 5-year period, the department shall investigate the occurrences upon which the claims were based and determine if action by the department against the podiatric physician is warranted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the department’s receipt from the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to s. 395.0197 of the name of the podiatric physician whose conduct may constitute grounds for disciplinary action by the department, the department shall investigate the occurrences upon which the report was based and determine if action by the department against the podiatric physician is warranted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an investigation of a podiatric physician is undertaken, the department shall promptly furnish to the podiatric physician or her or his attorney a copy of the complaint or document which resulted in the initiation of the investigation. The podiatric physician may submit a written response to the information contained in such complaint or document within 45 days after service to the podiatric physician of the complaint or document. The podiatric physician’s written response shall be considered by the probable cause panel.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-229; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 85-6; ss. 10, 12, 13, ch. 86-71; s. 39, ch. 88-1; s. 18, ch. 88-277; s. 5, ch. 90-44; s. 28, ch. 90-228; s. 65, ch. 91-220; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 42, ch. 92-149; s. 4, ch. 92-178; s. 85, ch. 92-289; s. 223, ch. 97-103; s. 74, ch. 97-264; ss. 61, 205, ch. 98-166; s. 224, ch. 99-8; s. 114, ch. 99-397; s. 120, ch. 2000-160; s. 28, ch. 2001-277; s. 29, ch. 2003-416; s. 6, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>