<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0068.087" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions to civil actions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court shall have jurisdiction over an action brought under this act against a member of the Legislature, a member of the judiciary, or a senior executive branch official if the action is based on evidence or information known to the state government when the action was brought. For purposes of this subsection, the term “senior executive branch official” means any person employed in the executive branch of government holding a position in the Senior Management Service as defined in s. 110.402.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no event may a person bring an action under s. 68.083(2) based upon allegations or transactions that are the subject of a civil action or an administrative proceeding in which the agency is already a party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court shall have jurisdiction over an action brought under this act based upon the public disclosure of allegations or transactions in a criminal, civil, or administrative hearing; in a legislative, administrative, inspector general, or Auditor General, Chief Financial Officer, or Department of Financial Services report, hearing, audit, or investigation; or from the news media, unless the action is brought by the department, or unless the person bringing the action is an original source of the information. For purposes of this subsection, the term “original source” means an individual who has direct and independent knowledge of the information on which the allegations are based and has voluntarily provided the information to the department before filing an action under this act based on the information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court shall have jurisdiction over an action where the person bringing the action under s. 68.083(2) is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acting as an attorney for state government; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee or former employee of state government,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and the action is based, in whole or in part, upon information obtained in the course or scope of government employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court shall have jurisdiction over an action where the person bringing the action under s. 68.083(2) obtained the information from an employee or former employee of state government who was not acting in the course or scope of government employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No court shall have jurisdiction over an action brought under this act against a local government. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “local government” means any county or municipality.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 94-316; s. 12, ch. 95-153; s. 105, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>