<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0496.407" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Financial report.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charitable organization or sponsor that is required to initially register or annually renew registration must file an annual financial report for the immediately preceding fiscal year upon a form prescribed by the department. The report must include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A balance sheet.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of support, revenue and expenses, and any change in the fund balance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of the charitable organizations or sponsors, professional fundraising consultant, professional solicitors, and commercial co-venturers used, if any, and the amounts received from each of them, if any.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of functional expenses that must include, but not be limited to, expenses in the following categories:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management and general.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fundraising.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of the financial report described in subsection (1), a charitable organization or sponsor may submit a copy of its Internal Revenue Service Form 990 and Schedule A filed for the preceding fiscal year, or a copy of its Form 990-EZ filed for the preceding fiscal year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charitable organization or sponsor may elect to also include a financial report that has been audited by an independent certified public accountant or an audit with opinion by an independent certified public accountant. In the event that a charitable organization or sponsor elects to file an audited financial report, this optional filing must be noted in the department’s annual report submitted pursuant to s. 496.423.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 26, ch. 91-208; ss. 4, 19, ch. 94-287.</History></Section>