<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0496.412" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclosure requirements and duties of professional solicitors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A professional solicitor must comply with and be responsible for complying or causing compliance with the following disclosures:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to orally requesting a contribution, or contemporaneously with a written request for a contribution, a professional solicitor must clearly disclose:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the professional solicitor as on file with the department.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the individual acting on behalf of the professional solicitor identifies himself or herself by name, the individual’s legal name.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and state of the principal place of business of the charitable organization or sponsor and a description of how the contributions raised by the solicitation will be used for a charitable or sponsor purpose; or, if there is no charitable organization or sponsor, a description as to how the contributions raised by the solicitation will be used for a charitable or sponsor purpose.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a solicitation campaign conducted orally, whether by telephone or otherwise, any written confirmation, receipt, or reminder sent to any person who has contributed or has pledged to contribute, shall include a clear disclosure of the information required by paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the information required by paragraph (a), any written confirmation, receipt, or reminder of contribution made pursuant to an oral solicitation and any written solicitation shall conspicuously state in capital letters:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">“A COPY OF THE OFFICIAL REGISTRATION AND FINANCIAL INFORMATION MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE DIVISION OF CONSUMER SERVICES BY CALLING TOLL-FREE WITHIN THE STATE. REGISTRATION DOES NOT IMPLY ENDORSEMENT, APPROVAL, OR RECOMMENDATION BY THE STATE.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The statement must include a toll-free number for the division that can be used to obtain the registration information. When the solicitation consists of more than one piece, the statement must be displayed prominently in the solicitation materials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If requested by the person being solicited, the professional solicitor shall inform that person in writing, within 14 days of the request, of the fixed percentage of the gross revenue or the reasonable estimate of the percentage of the gross revenue that the charitable organization or sponsor will receive as a benefit from the solicitation campaign.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If requested by the person being solicited, the professional solicitor shall inform that person in writing, within 14 days of the request, of the percentage of the contribution which may be deducted as a charitable contribution under federal income tax laws.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A professional solicitor must not represent that tickets to any event will be donated for use by another person, unless the following requirements are complied with:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The professional solicitor must have the written commitments from persons stating that they will accept donated tickets and specifying the number of tickets they are willing to accept.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written commitments are filed with the department prior to any solicitation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contributions solicited for donated tickets must not be more than the amount representing the number of ticket commitments received from persons and filed with the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 7 calendar days before the date of the event, the professional solicitor must give all donated tickets to each person that made the written commitment to accept them.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 26, ch. 91-208; ss. 8, 19, ch. 94-287; s. 563, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>