<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0496.414" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of commercial co-venturers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the commencement of any charitable or sponsor sales promotion in this state conducted by a commercial co-venturer on behalf of a charitable organization or sponsor, the commercial co-venturer must obtain the written consent of the charitable organization or sponsor whose name will be used during the charitable or sponsor sales promotion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If determined to be essential to protect the public from fraudulent or deceptive advertising, the department may, in accordance with chapter 120, adopt rules requiring disclosure in advertising for a charitable or sponsor sales promotion of information relating to the portion or amount that will benefit the charitable organization or sponsor or the charitable purpose or sponsor purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final accounting for each charitable or sponsor sales promotion must be prepared by the commercial co-venturer following the completion of the sales promotion. The final accounting must be provided to the charitable organization or sponsor on whose behalf the sales promotion was conducted within 10 days after a request by the charitable organization or sponsor. The final accounting must be kept by the commercial co-venturer for a period of 3 years, unless the commercial co-venturer and the charitable organization or sponsor mutually agree that the accounting should be kept by the charitable organization or sponsor instead of the commercial co-venturer. A copy of the final accounting must be provided to the department no later than 10 working days after the department requests it.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 26, ch. 91-208; ss. 9, 19, ch. 94-287.</History></Section>