<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0496.420" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Civil remedies and enforcement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to other remedies authorized by law, the department may bring a civil action in circuit court to enforce ss. 496.401-496.424 or s. 496.426. Upon a finding that any person has violated any of these sections, a court may make any necessary order or enter a judgment including, but not limited to, a temporary or permanent injunction, a declaratory judgment, the appointment of a general or special magistrate or receiver, the sequestration of assets, the reimbursement of persons from whom contributions have been unlawfully solicited, the distribution of contributions in accordance with the charitable or sponsor purpose expressed in the registration statement or in accordance with the representations made to the person solicited, the reimbursement of the department for investigative costs, attorney’s fees and costs, and any other equitable relief the court finds appropriate. Upon a finding that any person has violated any provision of ss. 496.401-496.424 or s. 496.426 with actual knowledge or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances, a court may enter an order imposing a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed $10,000 per violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may conduct any investigation necessary to bring a civil action under this section including, but not limited to, administering oaths and affirmations, subpoenaing witnesses or material, and collecting evidence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may terminate an investigation or an action upon acceptance of a person’s written assurance of voluntary compliance with ss. 496.401-496.424 or s. 496.426. Acceptance of an assurance may be conditioned on commitment to reimburse donors or to take other appropriate corrective action. An assurance is not evidence of a prior violation of any of these sections. However, unless an assurance has been rescinded by agreement of the parties or voided by a court for good cause, subsequent failure to comply with the terms of an assurance is prima facie evidence of a violation of one or more of these sections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys, including, but not limited to, civil penalties and attorney’s fees and costs, collected pursuant to this section and s. 496.416, shall be paid into the General Inspection Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 19, 26, ch. 91-208; ss. 13, 19, ch. 94-287; s. 3, ch. 97-250; s. 5, ch. 99-307; s. 88, ch. 2004-11.</History></Section>