<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0526.304" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Predatory practices unlawful; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any refiner engaged in commerce in this state to sell any grade or quality of motor fuel at a retail outlet below refiner cost, where the effect is to injure competition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any nonrefiner engaged in commerce in this state to sell any grade or quality of motor fuel at a retail outlet below nonrefiner cost, where the effect is to injure competition.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An isolated, inadvertent incident involving activity prohibited pursuant to subsection (1) or subsection (3) shall not be a violation of this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A refiner’s sale below refiner cost or a nonrefiner’s sale below nonrefiner cost made in good faith to meet an equally low retail price of a competitor selling motor fuel of like grade in the same relevant geographic market which can be used in the same motor vehicle, or of the same or similar items in combination with motor fuel of like grade which can be used in the same motor vehicle, is not a violation of this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, it is unlawful for a refiner, including any affiliate or agent thereof, to sell any grade of motor fuel at a retail outlet at a price that is below the price charged by that refiner to any wholesaler or dealer under written contract for the like grade and quality of motor fuel, to the extent that the wholesaler or dealer resells in the relevant geographic market where the refiner’s retail price is in effect.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 85-74; s. 2, ch. 87-158; s. 2, ch. 91-247.</History></Section>