<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0526.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement; inspection and analysis, stop-sale and disposition, regulations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall enforce the provisions of this part through the department, and may sample, inspect, analyze, and test any brake fluid manufactured, packed, or sold within this state. The department shall have free access during business hours to all premises, buildings, vehicles, cars, or vessels used in the manufacture, packing, storage, sale, or transportation of brake fluid, and may open any box, carton, parcel, or container of brake fluid and take samples for inspection and analysis or for evidence.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any brake fluid is sold in violation of any of the provisions of this part, all such brake fluid of the same brand name shall be placed under a stop-sale order by the department by serving the owner of the brand name, the distributor, or other entity responsible for selling or distributing the product in this state with the stop-sale order. The department shall withdraw its stop-sale order upon the removal of the violation or upon voluntary destruction of the product, or other disposal approved by the department, under the supervision of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to being subject to the stop-sale procedures, unregistered brake fluid shall be held by the department or its representative, at a place to be designated in the stop-sale order, until properly registered and released in writing by the department or its representative. If application has not been made for registration of such product within 30 days after issue of the stop-sale order, the department or, with the consent of the department, the representative may give the product that meets legal specifications to any tax-supported institution or agency of the state. If application has not been made for registration of the product within 30 days after issuance of the stop-order sale and the product fails to meet legal specifications, the product may be disposed of as authorized by rule of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any brake fluid which becomes the subject of a court proceeding shall be disposed of by order of the court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt and enforce such rules as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No labeling relating to any brake fluid shall contain any statement that the brake fluid has been approved by the department. However, a statement that the brake fluid has been registered by the department may be included in such labeling.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-390; s. 1, ch. 71-118; s. 80, ch. 92-291; s. 31, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>