<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0526.143" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Alternate generated power capacity for motor fuel dispensing facilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By June 1, 2007, each motor fuel terminal facility, as defined in s. 526.303(16), and each wholesaler, as defined in s. 526.303(17), which sells motor fuel in this state must be capable of operating its distribution loading racks using an alternate generated power source for a minimum of 72 hours. Pending a postdisaster examination of the equipment by the operator to determine any extenuating damage that would render it unsafe to use, the facility must have such alternate generated power source available for operation no later than 36 hours after a major disaster as defined in s. 252.34. Installation of appropriate wiring, including a transfer switch, shall be performed by a certified electrical contractor. Each business that is subject to this subsection must keep a copy of the documentation of such installation on site or at its corporate headquarters. In addition, each business must keep a written statement attesting to the periodic testing and ensured operational capacity of the equipment. The required documents must be made available, upon request, to the Division of Emergency Management and the director of the county emergency management agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each newly constructed or substantially renovated motor fuel retail outlet, as defined in s. 526.303(14), for which a certificate of occupancy is issued on or after July 1, 2006, shall be prewired with an appropriate transfer switch, and capable of operating all fuel pumps, dispensing equipment, lifesafety systems, and payment-acceptance equipment using an alternate generated power source. As used in this subsection, the term “substantially renovated” means a renovation that results in an increase of greater than 50 percent in the assessed value of the motor fuel retail outlet. Local building inspectors shall include this equipment and operations check in the normal inspection process before issuing a certificate of occupancy. Each retail outlet that is subject to this subsection must keep a copy of the certificate of occupancy on site or at its corporate headquarters. In addition, each retail outlet must keep a written statement attesting to the periodic testing of and ensured operational capability of the equipment. The required documents must be made available, upon request, to the Division of Emergency Management and the director of the county emergency management agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than June 1, 2007, each motor fuel retail outlet described in subparagraph 1., subparagraph 2., or subparagraph 3., which is located within one-half mile proximate to an interstate highway or state or federally designated evacuation route must be prewired with an appropriate transfer switch and be capable of operating all fuel pumps, dispensing equipment, lifesafety systems, and payment-acceptance equipment using an alternate generated power source:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor fuel retail outlet located in a county having a population of 300,000 or more which has 16 or more fueling positions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor fuel retail outlet located in a county having a population of 100,000 or more, but fewer than 300,000, which has 12 or more fueling positions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor fuel retail outlet located in a county having a population of fewer than 100,000 which has eight or more fueling positions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Installation of appropriate wiring and transfer switches must be performed by a certified electrical contractor. Each retail outlet that is subject to this subsection must keep a copy of the documentation of such installation on site or at its corporate headquarters. In addition, each retail outlet must keep a written statement attesting to the periodic testing of and ensured operational capacity of the equipment. The required documents must be made available, upon request, to the Division of Emergency Management and the director of the county emergency management agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (2) and (3) apply to any self-service, full-service, or combination self-service and full-service motor fuel retail outlet regardless of whether the retail outlet is located on the grounds of, or is owned by, another retail business establishment that does not engage in the business of selling motor fuel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (2) and (3) do not apply to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An automobile dealer;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who operates a fleet of motor vehicles;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who sells motor fuel exclusively to a fleet of motor vehicles; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor fuel retail outlet that has a written agreement with a public hospital, in a form approved by the Division of Emergency Management, wherein the public hospital agrees to provide the motor fuel retail outlet with an alternative means of power generation onsite so that the outlet’s fuel pumps may be operated in the event of a power outage.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporation or other entity that owns 10 or more motor fuel retail outlets located within a single county shall maintain at least one portable generator that is capable of providing an alternate generated power source as required under subsection (2) for every 10 outlets. If an entity owns more than 10 outlets or a multiple of 10 outlets plus an additional 6 outlets, the entity must provide one additional generator to accommodate such additional outlets. Each portable generator must be stored within this state, or may be stored in another state if located within 250 miles of this state, and must be available for use in an affected location within 24 hours after a disaster.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporation or other entity that owns 10 or more motor fuel retail outlets located within a single domestic security region, as determined pursuant to s. 943.0312(1), and that does not own additional outlets located outside the domestic security region shall maintain a written document of agreement with one or more similarly equipped entities for the use of portable generators that may be used to meet the requirements of paragraph (a) and that are located within this state but outside the affected domestic security region. The agreement may be reciprocal, may allow for payment for services rendered by the providing entity, and must guarantee the availability of the portable generators to an affected location within 24 hours after a disaster.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon written request, the department may temporarily waive the requirements in paragraphs (a) and (b) if the generators are used in preparation for or response to an emergency or major disaster in another state. The waiver shall be in writing and include a beginning and ending date. The waiver may provide additional conditions as deemed necessary by the department. The waiver may be modified or terminated by the department if the Governor declares an emergency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, ownership of a motor fuel retail outlet is the owner of record of the fuel storage systems operating at the location, as identified in the Department of Environmental Protection underground storage facilities registry pursuant to s. 376.303(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2006-71; s. 27, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>