<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0526.52" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Specifications; adulteration and misbranding.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish specifications for brake fluid which shall promote the public safety in the operation of automotive vehicles and may amend such specifications by regulation, but in no event shall the specifications for brake fluid fall below the minimum specifications established by the Society of Automotive Engineers for brake fluid, heavy-duty-type.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brake fluid is deemed to be adulterated if its contents have been changed after registration, without reregistration, or its quality or characteristics fall below the specification for brake fluid established by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Brake fluid is deemed to be misbranded:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its container does not bear on its side or top a label on which is printed the name and place of business of the registrant of the product, the words “brake fluid,” and a statement that the product therein equals or exceeds the minimum specification of the Society of Automotive Engineers for brake fluid, heavy-duty-type, the United States Department of Transportation Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 116, or other specified standard identified in department rule. The department may require by rule that the duty-type classification appear on the label.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the container does not bear on its side or top an accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of liquid measure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the labeling on the container is false or misleading in any particular.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The words and letters required by this section shall appear on the label in legible type, in English.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-390; s. 30, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>