<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0526.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fraud and deception in sale of liquid fuel, lubricating oil, and greases; labeling; stop-sale order; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall store, sell, offer, or expose for sale any liquid fuels, lubricating oils, greases, or other similar products in any manner whatsoever which may deceive or tend to deceive, or which has the effect of deceiving, the purchaser of such products as to the nature, quality, or quantity of the products so sold, exposed, or offered for sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Containers of reclaimed, recleaned, or reconditioned previously used lubricating oil, lubricants, or mixtures of lubricants shall be plainly labeled showing that the content thereof is a previously used product.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the storage, sale, offering, or exposing for sale of lubricating oil composed in whole or in part of previously used lubricating oil, it is unlawful to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Represent in any manner that used lubricating oil is new or unused;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to disclose clearly and conspicuously in all advertising and sales promotional material and on each front or face panel of the container that used lubricating oil has been previously used. The front or face panel means the part of the container on which the brand name is usually featured and which is customarily exposed to the view of prospective purchasers when displayed at point of retail sales; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the term “rerefined,” or any other word or term of similar import, to describe previously used lubricating oil unless the physical and chemical contaminants acquired through previous use have been removed by a refining process.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Previously used lubricating oil which has been rerefined by a refining process that has removed all the physical and chemical contaminants acquired in previous use and which meets the ASTM-SAE-API standards for fitness for its intended use is not subject to the labeling requirement of this subsection. A manufacturer of such rerefined oil shall register the product with the Department of Environmental Protection and provide an affidavit of proof that the product meets the required standards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any product stored, sold, offered, or exposed for sale which is not permanently and conspicuously labeled as provided in this section is declared to be illegal. Any such illegal product shall be placed under written stop-sale order, directed to the owner or custodian, and held by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services or its representative at a place to be designated in the stop-sale order until properly labeled by the owner or custodian and released in writing by the department or its representative. If the product is not properly labeled within 30 days after the issuance of the stop-sale order, it shall be disposed of by the department or its representative to any tax-supported institution or agency of the state, if usable, or by destruction, if unusable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The attachment of stop-sale order to any such product is notice and warning to all persons whomsoever, including, but not limited to, the owner or custodian, to scrupulously refrain from moving, altering, or interfering in any manner with any such product or altering, defacing, or in any way interfering with the stop-sale order, or permitting the same to be done by another, except with the consent of the department or its representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The violation of any of the provisions of this section is a misdemeanor, punishable under the provisions of s. 526.11.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 16083, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 7315(2); s. 1, ch. 26883, 1951; s. 1, ch. 28114, 1953; s. 1, ch. 70-77; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 65, ch. 84-338; s. 460, ch. 94-356; s. 714, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>