<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0526.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definition of terms.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Brake fluid” means the fluid intended for use as the liquid medium through which force is transmitted in the hydraulic brake system of a vehicle operated upon the highways.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sell” includes give, distribute, barter, exchange, trade, keep for sale, offer for sale or expose for sale, in any of their variant forms.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Labeling” includes all written, printed or graphic representations, in any form whatsoever, imprinted upon or affixed to any container of brake fluid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Container” means any receptacle in which brake fluid is immediately contained when sold, but does not mean a carton or wrapping in which a number of such receptacles are shipped or stored or a tank car or truck.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permit year” means a period of 12 months commencing July 1 and ending on the next succeeding June 30.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registrant” means any manufacturer, packer, distributor, seller, or other person who has registered a brake fluid with the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Brand” means the product name appearing on the label of a container of brake fluid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Formula” means the name of the chemical mixture or composition of the brake fluid product.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-390; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 79, ch. 92-291; s. 28, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>