<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0621.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Applicability of chapters 607 and 608.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 607 is applicable to a corporation organized pursuant to this act except to the extent that any of the provisions of this act are interpreted to be in conflict with the provisions of chapter 607. In such event, the provisions and sections of this act shall take precedence with respect to a corporation organized pursuant to the provisions of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 608 is applicable to a limited liability company organized pursuant to this act except to the extent that any of the provisions of this act are interpreted to be in conflict with the provisions of chapter 608. In such event, the provisions and sections of this act shall take precedence with respect to a limited liability company organized pursuant to the provisions of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A professional corporation or limited liability company heretofore or hereafter organized under this act may change its business purpose from the rendering of professional service to provide for any other lawful purpose by amending its certificate of incorporation in the manner required for an original incorporation under chapter 607 or by amending its certificate of organization in the manner required for an original organization under chapter 608. However, such an amendment, when filed with and accepted by the Department of State, shall remove such corporation or limited liability company from the provisions of this chapter including, but not limited to, the right to practice a profession. A change of business purpose shall not have any effect on the continued existence of the corporation or limited liability company.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 61-64; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 69-288; s. 210, ch. 77-104; s. 179, ch. 90-179; s. 14, ch. 93-110; s. 87, ch. 93-284; s. 20, ch. 2008-187.</History></Section>