<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0621.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Identification with individual shareholders or individual members.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of a corporation or limited liability company organized under this act may contain the last names of some or all of the individual shareholders or individual members and may contain the last names of retired or deceased former individual shareholders or individual members of the corporation, limited liability company, a predecessor corporation or limited liability company, or partnership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name shall also contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “chartered”; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a professional corporation, the words “professional association” or the abbreviation “P.A.”; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a professional limited liability company, the words “professional limited company” or the abbreviation “P.L.,” in lieu of the words “limited company” or the abbreviation “L.C.” as otherwise required under s. 608.406.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a corporation, the use of the word “company,” “corporation,” or “incorporated” or any other word, abbreviation, affix, or prefix indicating that it is a corporation in the corporate name of a corporation organized under this act, other than the word “chartered” or the words “professional association” or the abbreviation “P.A.,” is specifically prohibited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be permissible, however, for the corporation or limited liability company to render professional services and to exercise its authorized powers under a name which is identical to its name except that the word “chartered,” the words “professional association” or “professional limited company,” or the abbreviations “P.A.” or “P.L.” may be omitted, provided that the corporation or limited liability company has first registered the name to be so used in the manner required for the registration of fictitious names.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 61-64; s. 1, ch. 77-134; s. 1, ch. 87-41; s. 13, ch. 93-110; s. 86, ch. 93-284.</History></Section>