<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0315.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grant of powers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each unit is hereby authorized and empowered:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire, construct, lease, operate and maintain any port facilities either within or without or partly within and partly without the corporate limits of the unit, or within or partly within the corporate limits of any other unit on property owned or acquired by it; provided, however, that no unit shall acquire, construct, lease, operate or maintain port facilities other than channels or turning basins in any county of the state other than the county in which such unit is located without securing the prior approval or consent of the unit or units in which such port facilities are proposed to be located, which approval or consent, if given, shall be evidenced by a resolution or ordinance duly adopted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire by purchase, grant, gift or lease or by the exercise of the right of eminent domain and to hold and dispose of any property, real or personal, tangible or intangible, or any right or interest in any such property, for or in connection with any port facilities, whether or not subject to mortgage, liens, charges or other encumbrances.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To add to or extend, or cause or permit to be added to or extended, any existing lands or islands now or hereafter owned by a unit bordering on or being in any waters by the pumping of sand or earth from any land under water or by any other means of construction, as a part of or for the purpose of providing any port facilities or for the purpose of improving, creating or extending any property of the unit for use of or disposal by the unit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To construct, or cause or permit to be constructed, an island or islands in any waters by the pumping of sand or earth from any land under water or by any other means of construction, as a part of or for the purpose of providing any port facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To construct any bridge, tunnel, road or causeway, or any combination thereof, to, from or between any port facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To dredge or deepen harbors, channels and turning basins, to cooperate with the United States or any agency thereof in the dredging or deepening of any harbor, channel or turning basin, to enter into contracts with the United States or with any agency thereof concerning any such dredging or deepening project, and to pay such amounts to the United States or any agency thereof or to others as shall be required by the terms of any such contract.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fill in, extend and enlarge, or cause or permit to be filled in, extended and enlarged, any existing port facilities, to demolish and remove any and all structures thereon or constituting a part thereof, and otherwise to prepare the same for sale or lease to provide funds for financing port facilities under the provisions of this law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire any existing port facilities and to fill in, extend, enlarge or improve the same, or to cause or permit the same to be extended, enlarged or improved, for any public purpose or for sale or lease for the purpose of providing funds for the acquisition by the unit of any port facilities or for the payment of bonds, notes or other obligations of the unit for or in connection with any port facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sell at public or private sale or lease for public or private purposes all or any portion of any port facilities now or hereafter owned by the unit, including any such facilities as extended, enlarged or improved, and all or any portion of any property of the unit improved, created, extended or enlarged under the authority of this law, on such terms and subject to such conditions as the governing body shall determine to be in the best interests of the unit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract for the purchase by the unit of any port facilities to be constructed, enlarged, extended or improved by any public body, agency or instrumentality or by any private person, firm or corporation, and to provide for payment of the purchase price thereof in such manner as may be deemed by the governing body to be in the best interests of the unit, including, but without limitation, the sale or exchange of any property of the unit therefor or the issuance of bonds or other obligations of the unit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To accept loans or grants of money or materials or property at any time from the United States or the State of Florida or any agency, instrumentality, or subdivision thereof, or to participate in loan guarantees or lines of credit provided by the United States, upon such terms and conditions as the United States, the State of Florida, or such agency, instrumentality, or subdivision may impose. Any entity created pursuant to s. 163.01(7)(d) that involves at least one deepwater port may participate in the provisions of this subsection, with oversight by the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay interest or other financing-related costs on federal loan guarantees, lines of credit, or secured direct loans issued to finance eligible projects. Any entity created pursuant to s. 163.01(7)(d) that involves at least one deepwater port may participate in the provisions of this subsection, with oversight by the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council, and may establish a loan program that would provide for the reuse of loan proceeds for similar program purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council shall prepare an annual report detailing the amounts loaned, the projects financed by the loans, any interest earned, and loans outstanding. The report shall be submitted to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 1 of each year, beginning in 2004.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To exercise jurisdiction, control and supervision over any port facilities now or hereafter acquired, owned or constructed by the unit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To operate and maintain, and to fix and collect rates, rentals, fees and other charges for any of the services and facilities provided by the port facilities now or hereafter acquired, owned or constructed by the unit excluding state bar pilots.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To lease or rent, or contract with others for the operation of all or any part of any port facilities now or hereafter acquired, owned or constructed by the unit, on such terms and for such period or periods and subject to such conditions as the governing body shall determine to be in the best interests of the units.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract debts for the acquisition or construction of any port facilities or for any other purposes of this law, to borrow money, to make advances, and to issue bonds or other obligations to finance all or any part of such acquisition or construction or in the carrying out of any other purposes of this law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make advances to the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof in connection with any port facilities, including the dredging or deepening of any harbor, channel or turning basin to serve any port facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter on any lands, waters or premises, within or without the unit or within the corporate limits of any other unit, for the purpose of making surveys, soundings and examinations with relation to any existing or proposed port facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract with the United States or the State of Florida or any agency or instrumentality thereof or with any public body or political subdivision or with any private person, firm or corporation with reference to any of the powers hereby granted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To perform any of the acts hereby authorized through or by means of its own officers, agents or employees or by contract.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To do all acts and things and to enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of this law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To expend funds to finance the cost of implementing recommendations made pursuant to s. 161.161 to mitigate the adverse impacts of inlets on beaches.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 59-411; s. 1, ch. 67-137; s. 10, ch. 86-138; s. 66, ch. 2002-20; s. 78, ch. 2010-102; s. 7, ch. 2010-225.</History>
</Section>