<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0315.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trust agreement or resolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the discretion of the governing body, any bonds issued under the provisions of this law may be secured by a trust agreement by and between the unit and a corporate trustee, which may be any trust company or bank having the powers of a trust company within or without the state. Such trust agreement or the resolution providing for the issuance of such bonds may contain such provisions for protecting and enforcing the rights and remedies of the bondholders as may be reasonable and proper and not in violation of law, including covenants setting forth the duties of the unit in relation to the acquisition of property and the acquisition, construction, improvement, maintenance, repair, lease, operation and insurance of any port facilities in connection with which such bonds shall have been authorized, the custody, safeguarding or application of all moneys, and conditions or limitations with respect to the issuance of additional bonds. It shall be lawful for any bank or trust company incorporated under the laws of Florida which may act as depositary of the proceeds of bonds or of revenue or other funds to furnish such indemnifying bonds or to pledge such securities as may be required by the governing body. Any such trust agreement or resolution may set forth the rights and remedies of the bondholders and of the trustee under any such trust agreement, and may restrict the individual right of action by bondholders. In addition to the foregoing, any such trust agreement or resolution may contain such other provisions as the governing body may deem reasonable and proper for the security of the bondholders. All expenses incurred in carrying out the provisions of such trust agreement or resolution shall be treated as a part of the cost of the operation of the port facilities.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 59-411.</History></Section>