<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0315.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sources of payment and security for bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body may provide that bonds issued under the provisions of this law shall be payable from and secured by a pledge of any one or more of the following sources:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues of any one or more port facilities now owned or hereafter acquired or constructed by the unit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proceeds of the sale or lease of all or any part of any port facilities now or hereafter owned by the unit as such facilities may be extended, enlarged or improved, or of any property of the municipality improved, created, extended or enlarged or prepared for sale or lease under the authority of this law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any money received by the unit from the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof in connection with any port facilities or in repayment of any advances made by the unit for all or any part of the cost of any port facilities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body may provide that such bonds shall be general obligations of the unit for which the full faith, credit and taxing power of the unit shall be additionally secured by a pledge of revenues, sale or lease proceeds or money received by the unit from the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof as herein authorized. The governing body of such unit may provide that such bonds shall be payable as to principal and interest in the first instance from such revenues, sale or lease proceeds or money received by the unit from the United States or any agency or instrumentality. The governing body of any unit may additionally secure any such bonds by a mortgage or other encumbrance, subject to such terms and conditions as it shall provide, upon all or any part of any port facilities now or hereafter owned by the unit, as such facilities may be extended, enlarged or improved, or of any property of the unit improved, created, extended or enlarged or prepared for sale or lease under the authority of this law, and the governing body is hereby authorized to sell at public or private sale or lease any of such port facilities or property, subject to such terms and conditions and for such price, payable at one time or from time to time in installments as the governing body may provide, and to apply the proceeds of any such sale or lease, after paying all costs in connection therewith, to payment of the cost of any port facilities financed under the provisions of this law or to the payment of the principal of or the interest or redemption premiums on any bonds issued hereunder or to the payment of any other obligation or obligations herein authorized.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 59-411.</History></Section>