<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0794.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sexual battery.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consent” means intelligent, knowing, and voluntary consent and does not include coerced submission. “Consent” shall not be deemed or construed to mean the failure by the alleged victim to offer physical resistance to the offender.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mentally defective” means a mental disease or defect which renders a person temporarily or permanently incapable of appraising the nature of his or her conduct.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mentally incapacitated” means temporarily incapable of appraising or controlling a person’s own conduct due to the influence of a narcotic, anesthetic, or intoxicating substance administered without his or her consent or due to any other act committed upon that person without his or her consent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Offender” means a person accused of a sexual offense in violation of a provision of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physically helpless” means unconscious, asleep, or for any other reason physically unable to communicate unwillingness to an act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retaliation” includes, but is not limited to, threats of future physical punishment, kidnapping, false imprisonment or forcible confinement, or extortion.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Serious personal injury” means great bodily harm or pain, permanent disability, or permanent disfigurement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual battery” means oral, anal, or vaginal penetration by, or union with, the sexual organ of another or the anal or vaginal penetration of another by any other object; however, sexual battery does not include an act done for a bona fide medical purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Victim” means a person who has been the object of a sexual offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physically incapacitated” means bodily impaired or handicapped and substantially limited in ability to resist or flee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person 18 years of age or older who commits sexual battery upon, or in an attempt to commit sexual battery injures the sexual organs of, a person less than 12 years of age commits a capital felony, punishable as provided in ss. 775.082 and 921.141.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person less than 18 years of age who commits sexual battery upon, or in an attempt to commit sexual battery injures the sexual organs of, a person less than 12 years of age commits a life felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, s. 775.084, or s. 794.0115.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits sexual battery upon a person 12 years of age or older, without that person’s consent, and in the process thereof uses or threatens to use a deadly weapon or uses actual physical force likely to cause serious personal injury commits a life felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, s. 775.084, or s. 794.0115.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits sexual battery upon a person 12 years of age or older without that person’s consent, under any of the following circumstances, commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, s. 775.084, or s. 794.0115:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the victim is physically helpless to resist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the offender coerces the victim to submit by threatening to use force or violence likely to cause serious personal injury on the victim, and the victim reasonably believes that the offender has the present ability to execute the threat.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the offender coerces the victim to submit by threatening to retaliate against the victim, or any other person, and the victim reasonably believes that the offender has the ability to execute the threat in the future.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the offender, without the prior knowledge or consent of the victim, administers or has knowledge of someone else administering to the victim any narcotic, anesthetic, or other intoxicating substance which mentally or physically incapacitates the victim.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the victim is mentally defective and the offender has reason to believe this or has actual knowledge of this fact.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the victim is physically incapacitated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the offender is a law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer as defined by s. 943.10(1), (2), (3), (6), (7), (8), or (9), who is certified under the provisions of s. 943.1395 or is an elected official exempt from such certification by virtue of s. 943.253, or any other person in a position of control or authority in a probation, community control, controlled release, detention, custodial, or similar setting, and such officer, official, or person is acting in such a manner as to lead the victim to reasonably believe that the offender is in a position of control or authority as an agent or employee of government.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits sexual battery upon a person 12 years of age or older, without that person’s consent, and in the process thereof does not use physical force and violence likely to cause serious personal injury commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, s. 775.084, or s. 794.0115.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offense described in subsection (5) is included in any sexual battery offense charged under subsection (3) or subsection (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is convicted of committing a sexual battery on or after October 1, 1992, is not eligible for basic gain-time under s. 944.275. This subsection may be cited as the “Junny Rios-Martinez, Jr. Act of 1992.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without regard to the willingness or consent of the victim, which is not a defense to prosecution under this subsection, a person who is in a position of familial or custodial authority to a person less than 18 years of age and who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicits that person to engage in any act which would constitute sexual battery under paragraph (1)(h) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engages in any act with that person while the person is 12 years of age or older but less than 18 years of age which constitutes sexual battery under paragraph (1)(h) commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engages in any act with that person while the person is less than 12 years of age which constitutes sexual battery under paragraph (1)(h), or in an attempt to commit sexual battery injures the sexual organs of such person commits a capital or life felony, punishable pursuant to subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For prosecution under paragraph (4)(g), acquiescence to a person reasonably believed by the victim to be in a position of authority or control does not constitute consent, and it is not a defense that the perpetrator was not actually in a position of control or authority if the circumstances were such as to lead the victim to reasonably believe that the person was in such a position.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who falsely accuses any person listed in paragraph (4)(g) or other person in a position of control or authority as an agent or employee of government of violating paragraph (4)(g) is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-121; s. 17, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 84-86; s. 1, ch. 89-216; s. 3, ch. 92-135; s. 1, ch. 92-310; s. 3, ch. 93-156; s. 2, ch. 95-348; s. 99, ch. 99-3; s. 8, ch. 99-188; s. 1, ch. 2002-211.</History></Section>