<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0794.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Female genital mutilation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “female genital mutilation” means the circumcising, excising, or infibulating, in whole or in part, the labia majora, labia minora, or clitoris of a female person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly commits, or attempts to commit, female genital mutilation upon a female person younger than 18 years of age commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly removes, or causes or permits the removal of, a female person younger than 18 years of age from this state for purposes of committing female genital mutilation commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is a parent, a guardian, or in a position of familial or custodial authority to a female person younger than 18 years of age and who knowingly consents to or permits the female genital mutilation of that female person commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to procedures performed by or under the direction of a physician licensed under chapter 458, an osteopathic physician licensed under chapter 459, a registered nurse licensed under part I of chapter 464, a practical nurse licensed under part I of chapter 464, an advanced registered nurse practitioner licensed under part I of chapter 464, a midwife licensed under chapter 467, or a physician assistant licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 when necessary to preserve the physical health of a female person. This section also does not apply to any autopsy or limited dissection conducted pursuant to chapter 406.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent of a female person younger than 18 years of age or the consent of a parent, guardian, or person who is in a position of familial or custodial authority to the female person younger than 18 years of age is not a defense to the offense of female genital mutilation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-245.</History></Section>