<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0794.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Access to services for victims of sexual battery.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited by the popular name, the “Sexual Battery Victims’ Access to Services Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Crisis-intervention services” means advice, counseling, or consultation provided by a sexual battery counselor or trained volunteer to a victim aimed at reducing the level of emotional trauma experienced by the victim.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical intervention” means services necessary for the forensic examination of a victim or medical treatment for injuries of a victim of sexual battery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rape crisis center” means any public or private agency that provides sexual battery recovery services to victims of sexual battery and their families and is certified by the statewide nonprofit association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual battery” has the same meaning as that term has in the offenses provided in s. 794.011.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual battery counselor” means any employee of a rape crisis center whose primary purpose is the rendering of advice, counseling, or assistance to victims of sexual battery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual battery recovery services” include the following services:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For victims who have reported the offense to law enforcement:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A telephone hotline that is operated 24 hours a day and answered by a sexual battery counselor or trained volunteer, as defined in s. 90.5035.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information and referral services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crisis-intervention services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advocacy and support services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Therapy services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service coordination.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Programs to promote community awareness of available services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical intervention.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For victims who have not reported the offense to law enforcement:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A telephone hotline that is operated 24 hours a day and answered by a sexual battery counselor or trained volunteer, as defined in s. 90.5035.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information and referral services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crisis-intervention services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advocacy and support services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Therapy services.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service coordination.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Programs to promote community awareness of available services.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Statewide nonprofit association” means the federally recognized sexual assault coalition whose primary purpose is to represent and provide technical assistance to rape crisis centers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trained volunteer” means a person who volunteers at a rape crisis center, has completed 30 hours of training in assisting victims of sexual violence and related topics provided by the rape crisis center, is supervised by members of the staff of the rape crisis center, and is included on a list of volunteers which is maintained by the rape crisis center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Victim” means a person who consults a sexual battery counselor or a trained volunteer for the purpose of securing advice, counseling, or assistance concerning a mental, physical, or emotional condition caused by a sexual battery.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall contract with the statewide nonprofit association. The statewide nonprofit association shall receive 95 percent of the moneys appropriated from the Rape Crisis Program Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds received under s. 938.085 shall be used to provide sexual battery recovery services to victims and their families. Funds shall be distributed to rape crisis centers based on an allocation formula that takes into account the population and rural characteristics of each county. No more than 15 percent of the funds shall be used by the statewide nonprofit association for statewide initiatives. No more than 5 percent of the funds may be used by the department for administrative costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall ensure that funds allocated under this section are expended in a manner that is consistent with the requirements of this section. The department may require an annual audit of the expenditures and shall provide a report to the Legislature by February 1 of each year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2003-114; s. 24, ch. 2006-79; s. 7, ch. 2008-19; s. 11, ch. 2011-220.</History></Section>