<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0794.0115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dangerous sexual felony offender; mandatory sentencing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Dangerous Sexual Felony Offender Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is convicted of a violation of s. 787.025(2)(c); s. 794.011(2), (3), (4), (5), or (8); s. 800.04(4) or (5); s. 825.1025(2) or (3); s. 827.071(2), (3), or (4); or s. 847.0145; or of any similar offense under a former designation, which offense the person committed when he or she was 18 years of age or older, and the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Caused serious personal injury to the victim as a result of the commission of the offense;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Used or threatened to use a deadly weapon during the commission of the offense;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Victimized more than one person during the course of the criminal episode applicable to the offense;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committed the offense while under the jurisdiction of a court for a felony offense under the laws of this state, for an offense that is a felony in another jurisdiction, or for an offense that would be a felony if that offense were committed in this state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has previously been convicted of a violation of s. 787.025(2)(c); s. 794.011(2), (3), (4), (5), or (8); s. 800.04(4) or (5); s. 825.1025(2) or (3); s. 827.071(2), (3), or (4); s. 847.0145; of any offense under a former statutory designation which is similar in elements to an offense described in this paragraph; or of any offense that is a felony in another jurisdiction, or would be a felony if that offense were committed in this state, and which is similar in elements to an offense described in this paragraph,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is a dangerous sexual felony offender, who must be sentenced to a mandatory minimum term of 25 years imprisonment up to, and including, life imprisonment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Serious personal injury” means great bodily harm or pain, permanent disability, or permanent disfigurement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offense described in subsection (2) which is being charged must have been committed after the date of commission of the last prior conviction for an offense that is a prior conviction described in paragraph (2)(e).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is irrelevant that a factor listed in subsection (2) is an element of an offense described in that subsection. It is also irrelevant that such an offense was reclassified to a higher felony degree under s. 794.023 or any other law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 775.082(3), chapter 958, any other law, or any interpretation or construction thereof, a person subject to sentencing under this section must be sentenced to the mandatory term of imprisonment provided under this section. If the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment imposed under this section exceeds the maximum sentence authorized under s. 775.082, s. 775.084, or chapter 921, the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment under this section must be imposed. If the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment under this section is less than the sentence that could be imposed under s. 775.082, s. 775.084, or chapter 921, the sentence imposed must include the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant sentenced to a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment under this section is not eligible for statutory gain-time under s. 944.275 or any form of discretionary early release, other than pardon or executive clemency, or conditional medical release under s. 947.149, before serving the minimum sentence.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 99-188; s. 1, ch. 2002-211; s. 1, ch. 2003-115; s. 3, ch. 2006-299.</History></Section>