<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.507" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of the corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall have all the powers necessary or convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes and provisions of this part, including the following powers which are in addition to all other powers granted by other provisions of this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and be sued, to have a seal, to alter the same at pleasure and to authorize the use of a facsimile thereof, and to make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to the exercise of the powers of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To undertake and carry out studies and analyses of housing needs within the state and ways of meeting those needs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To participate in federal housing assistance and federal community development, insurance, and guarantee programs and to agree and comply with any conditions attached to federal financial assistance, including, without limitation, the waiver of exemption from federal income taxation on interest payable on its bonds, unless expressly prohibited by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide for the collection and payment of fees and charges, regardless of method of payment, in connection with its loans, commitments, and servicing, including, but not limited to, reimbursement of costs of financing by the corporation, service charges and insurance premiums as the corporation shall determine to be reasonable and as shall be approved by the corporation. The fees and charges may be paid directly by the borrower to the insurer, lender, or servicing agent or may be deducted from the interest collected by such insurer, lender, or servicing agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire real and personal property or any interest therein when such acquisition is necessary or appropriate to protect any loan or to participate in any program in which the corporation has an interest; to sell, transfer, and convey any such property to a buyer without regard to the provisions of chapters 253 and 270; and, in the event that such sale, transfer, or conveyance cannot be effected with reasonable promptness or at a reasonable price, to lease such property for occupancy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To borrow money through the issuance of bonds or from the Federal Home Loan Bank or Rural Housing Services of the United States Department of Agriculture for the purposes provided in this part, to provide for and secure the payment thereof, and to provide for the rights of the holders thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To purchase bonds of the corporation out of any funds or moneys of the corporation available therefor and to hold, cancel, or resell such bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To invest any funds held in reserves or sinking funds, or any funds not required for immediate disbursement, in such investments as may be authorized for trust funds under s. 215.47 and in any authorized investments, provided such investments will be made on behalf of the corporation by the State Board of Administration or by another trustee appointed for that purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To set standards for residential housing financed by the corporation under this chapter and to provide for inspections to determine compliance with those standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract for and to accept gifts, grants, loans, or other aid from the United States Government or any person or corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To insure and procure insurance against any loss in connection with any bonds of the corporation and the corporation’s operations or property, including without limitation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The repayment of any loans to mortgage lenders or mortgage loans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bonds of the corporation, in such amounts and from such insurers, including the Federal Government, as it may deem necessary or desirable, and to pay any premiums therefor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make rules necessary to carry out the purposes of this part and to exercise any power granted in this part pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To engage the services of private consultants on a contract basis for rendering professional and technical assistance and advice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make additional conditions respecting the grant of loans or mortgage loans pursuant to this part, including, without limitation, the regulation of eligible persons and the admission of tenants and other occupants or users of projects and residential housing, and to enter into regulatory and other agreements and contracts under the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To institute any action or proceeding against any eligible person or sponsor receiving a loan or owning any residential housing financed under the provisions of this part in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this part or the terms and provisions of any agreement or contract between the corporation and such person and, in connection with any such action or proceeding, to apply for and accept the appointment, by a court of competent jurisdiction, of a receiver to take over, manage, operate, and maintain such residential housing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To procure or require the procurement of a policy or policies of group life insurance or disability insurance, or both, to insure repayment of mortgage loans for residential housing in the event of the death or disability of the eligible person or persons liable therefor, and to pay any premiums therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To renegotiate any mortgage loan or any purchase agreement with a borrower in default; to waive any default or consent to the modification of the terms of any mortgage loan or any purchase agreement; and to commence, prosecute, and enforce a judgment in any action or proceeding to protect or enforce any right conferred upon it by law, mortgage loan, loan agreement or purchase agreement, contract, or other agreement, including without limitation foreclosure of the security interest on the property securing such a mortgage loan; provided that any such action or proceeding shall be brought in the name of the entity servicing the mortgage loan on behalf of the corporation and not in the name of the corporation, and in connection with any such proceeding, to bid for and purchase the property or acquire or take possession thereof and, in such event, complete, administer, pay the principal of and interest on any obligations incurred in connection with the property and dispose of and otherwise deal with the property in such manner as the corporation may deem advisable to protect its interests therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make and execute contracts for the administration, servicing, or collection of any mortgage loan or loan agreement or purchase agreement with a mortgage lender or servicing agent for the duration of the loan or agreement and pay the reasonable value of services rendered to the corporation pursuant to such contracts. The fees and charges for such services may be paid directly by the borrower to the lender or servicing agent or may be deducted from the interest collected by such lender or servicing agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fix, revise from time to time, charge, and collect fees and other charges in connection with the making of mortgage loans, the purchasing of mortgage loans, and any other services rendered by the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make and execute agreements, contracts, and other instruments necessary or convenient in the exercise of the powers and functions of the corporation under this part, including contracts with any person, firm, corporation, local government, or other entity; and all local governments established under the laws of the state are hereby authorized to enter into and do all things necessary to perform such contracts and otherwise cooperate with the corporation to facilitate the accomplishment of the purposes of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review all reverse mortgage provisions proposed to be used by an individual lender or a consortium to determine that such provisions are consistent with the purposes and intent of this act. If the corporation finds that the provisions are consistent, it shall approve those provisions. If the corporation finds that the provisions are inconsistent, it shall state its objections and give the parties an opportunity to amend the provisions to overcome such objections. In approving these provisions, the corporation must determine:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the mortgagee is licensed pursuant to part II of chapter 494 or specifically exempt from part III of chapter 494.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the mortgagee has sufficient resources to finance such mortgages.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop and administer the State Apartment Incentive Loan Program. In developing and administering that program, the corporation may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make first, second, and other subordinated mortgage loans including variable or fixed rate loans subject to contingent interest for all State Apartment Incentive Loans provided in this chapter based upon available cash flow of the projects. The corporation shall make loans exceeding 25 percent of project cost only to nonprofit organizations and public bodies that are able to secure grants, donations of land, or contributions from other sources and to projects meeting the criteria of subparagraph 1. Mortgage loans shall be made available at the following rates of interest:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Zero to 3 percent interest for sponsors of projects that set aside at least 80 percent of their total units for residents qualifying as farmworkers, commercial fishing workers, the homeless as defined in s. 420.621, or persons with special needs as defined in s. 420.0004(13) over the life of the loan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Zero to 3 percent interest based on the pro rata share of units set aside for homeless residents or persons with special needs if the total of such units is less than 80 percent of the units in the borrower’s project.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One to 9 percent interest for sponsors of projects targeted at populations other than farmworkers, commercial fishing workers, the homeless, or persons with special needs.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make loans exceeding 25 percent of project cost when the project serves extremely-low-income persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forgive indebtedness for a share of the loan attributable to the units in a project reserved for extremely-low-income persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Geographically and demographically target the utilization of loans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Underwrite credit, and reject projects which do not meet the established standards of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Negotiate with governing bodies within the state after a loan has been awarded to obtain local government contributions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspect any records of a sponsor at any time during the life of the loan or the agreed period for maintaining the provisions of s. 420.5087.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish, by rule, the procedure for evaluating, scoring, and competitively ranking all applications based on the criteria set forth in s. 420.5087(6)(c); determining actual loan amounts; making and servicing loans; and exercising the powers authorized in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a loan loss insurance reserve to be used to protect the outstanding program investment in case of a default, deed in lieu of foreclosure, or foreclosure of a program loan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop and administer the Florida Homeownership Assistance Program. In developing and administering the program, the corporation may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make subordinated loans to eligible borrowers for down payments or closing costs related to the purchase of the borrower’s primary residence.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make permanent loans to eligible borrowers related to the purchase of the borrower’s primary residence.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make subordinated loans to nonprofit sponsors or developers of housing for purchase of property, for construction, or for financing of housing to be offered for sale to eligible borrowers as a primary residence at an affordable price.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a loan loss insurance reserve to supplement existing sources of mortgage insurance with appropriated funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Geographically and demographically target the utilization of loans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defer repayment of loans for the term of the first mortgage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish flexible terms for loans with an interest rate not to exceed 3 percent per annum and which are nonamortizing for the term of the first mortgage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require repayment of loans upon sale, transfer, refinancing, or rental of secured property, unless otherwise approved by the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accelerate a loan for monetary default, for failure to provide the benefits of the loans to eligible borrowers, or for violation of any other restriction placed upon the loan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules for the program and exercise the powers authorized in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To do any and all things necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of, and exercise the powers given and granted in, this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop and administer the Florida Affordable Housing Guarantee Program. In developing and administering the program, the corporation may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop criteria for determining the priority for expending the moneys in the State Housing Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Select affordable housing debt to be guaranteed or additionally secured by amounts on deposit in the Affordable Housing Guarantee Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules for the program and exercise the powers authorized in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop and administer the Predevelopment Loan Program. In developing and administering the program, the corporation may make loans and grants as provided in ss. 420.521-420.529.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 282 and part I of chapter 287, to establish guidelines for and to implement the purchase and procurement of materials and services for use by the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="28"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To expend amounts advanced from the State Housing Trust Fund for the purposes of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="29"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To own real and personal property for the purposes of this part, to mortgage such property, and to sell the property without regard to the provisions of chapters 253 and 270.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="30"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prepare and submit to the executive director of the department a budget request for purposes of the corporation, which request shall, notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 216 and in accordance with s. 216.351, contain a request for operational expenditures and separate requests for other authorized corporation programs. The request need not contain information on the number of employees, salaries, or any classification thereof, and the approved operating budget therefor need not comply with s. 216.181(8)-(10). The executive director may include within the department’s budget request the corporation’s budget request in the form as authorized by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="31"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 216.301, to retain any unused operational expenditure appropriation for other lawful purposes of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="32"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay pensions and establish pension plans, pension trusts, and benefit and incentive plans for any and all of its current or former employees and agents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="33"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive federal funding in connection with the corporation’s programs directly from the Federal Government and to receive federal funds for which no corresponding program has been created in statute and establish selection criteria for such funds by request for proposals or other competitive solicitation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="34"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish the corporation’s fiscal year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="35"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To preclude from further participation in any of the corporation’s programs, for a period of up to 2 years, any applicant or affiliate of an applicant which has made a material misrepresentation or engaged in fraudulent actions in connection with any application for a corporation program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="36"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide for the development of infrastructure improvements and rehabilitation primarily in connection with residential housing consistent with the applicable local government comprehensive plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="37"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide by rule, in connection with any corporation competitive program, for the reservation of future allocation or funding to provide a remedy for a litigant which is ultimately successful in its litigation regarding a competitive application, and to establish a date certain by which, if litigation is not resolved, the successful litigant will be funded from a subsequent year’s available allocation or funding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="38"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To designate private activity allocation for tax-exempt bonds received by the corporation pursuant to part VI of chapter 159 between single-family and multifamily projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="39"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To create recognition programs to honor individuals, community-based development organizations, units of local government, or others who have demonstrated the ideals of community stewardship and increased access to housing for low-income households, including their stewardship in economically distressed areas. Such programs may incorporate certificates of recognition by the Governor and may include presentation by the Governor or his or her representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="40"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish subsidiary business entities for the purpose of taking title to and managing and disposing of property acquired by the corporation. Such subsidiary business entities shall be public business entities wholly owned by the corporation; shall be entitled to own, mortgage, and sell property on the same basis as the corporation; and shall be deemed business entities primarily acting as an agent of the state, within the meaning of s. 768.28, on the same basis as the corporation. Any subsidiary business entity created by the corporation shall be subject to chapters 119, 120, and 286 to the same extent as the corporation. The subsidiary business entities shall have authority to make rules necessary to conduct business and to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="41"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conduct and fund, solely from funds derived from amounts other than those deposited into the State Housing Trust Fund, demonstration programs and projects which further the statutory purposes of the corporation, including the power to establish selection criteria by rule or by means of requests for proposals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="42"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide information, assistance, and facilities needed by the Affordable Housing Study Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="43"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop and administer the Affordable Housing Catalyst Program under s. 420.531.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="44"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt rules for the intervention and negotiation of terms or other actions necessary to further program goals or avoid default of a program loan. Such rules must consider fiscal program goals and the preservation or advancement of affordable housing for the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="45"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish by rule requirements for periodic reporting of data, including, but not limited to, financial data, housing market data, detailed economic and physical occupancy on multifamily projects, and demographic data on all housing financed through corporation programs and for participation in a housing locator system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="46"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require, as a condition of financing a multifamily rental project, that an agreement be recorded in the official records of the county where the real property is located, which requires that the project be used for housing defined as affordable in s. 420.0004(3) by persons defined in s. 420.0004(9), (11), (12), and (17). Such an agreement is a state land use regulation that limits the highest and best use of the property within the meaning of s. 193.011(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="47"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide by rule, in connection with any corporation competitive program, criteria establishing, where all other competitive elements are equal, a preference for developers and general contractors who demonstrate the highest rate of Florida job creation in the development and construction of affordable housing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="48"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To use up to 10 percent of its annual allocation of low-income housing tax credits, nontaxable revenue bonds, and State Apartment Incentive Loan Program funds appropriated by the Legislature and available to allocate by request for proposals or other competitive solicitation funding for high-priority affordable housing projects, such as housing to support economic development and job-creation initiatives, housing for veterans and their families, and other special needs populations in communities throughout the state as determined by the corporation on an annual basis.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-161; s. 3, ch. 84-251; s. 7, ch. 88-376; s. 6, ch. 89-121; s. 55, ch. 91-245; s. 21, ch. 92-317; s. 8, ch. 93-181; s. 11, ch. 97-167; s. 6, ch. 98-56; s. 75, ch. 2000-153; s. 10, ch. 2000-353; s. 59, ch. 2001-62; s. 29, ch. 2001-201; s. 3, ch. 2002-4; s. 2, ch. 2002-160; s. 18, ch. 2004-243; ss. 45, 53, ch. 2006-26; s. 17, ch. 2006-69; s. 13, ch. 2007-198; s. 22, ch. 2009-96; s. 1, ch. 2009-164; s. 65, ch. 2009-241; s. 8, ch. 2011-15; s. 11, ch. 2011-189; s. 64, ch. 2012-96; s. 4, ch. 2012-127.</History></Section>