<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.5093" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State Housing Tax Credit Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the State Housing Tax Credit Program for the purposes of stimulating creative private sector initiatives to increase the supply of affordable housing in urban areas, including specifically housing for the elderly, and to provide associated commercial facilities associated with such housing facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Housing Finance Corporation shall determine those qualified projects which shall be considered designated projects under s. 220.185 and eligible for the corporate tax credit under that section. The corporation shall establish procedures necessary for proper allocation and distribution of state housing tax credits, including the establishment of criteria for any single-family or commercial component of a project, and may exercise all powers necessary to administer the allocation of such credits. The board of directors of the corporation shall administer the allocation procedures and determine allocations on behalf of the corporation. The corporation shall prepare an annual plan, which must be approved by the Governor, containing general guidelines for the allocation and distribution of credits to designated projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall adopt allocation procedures that will ensure the maximum use of available tax credits in order to encourage development of low-income housing and associated mixed-use projects in urban areas, taking into consideration the timeliness of the application, the location of the proposed project, the relative need in the area of revitalization and low-income housing and the availability of such housing, the economic feasibility of the project, and the ability of the applicant to proceed to completion of the project in the calendar year for which the credit is sought.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A taxpayer who wishes to participate in the State Housing Tax Credit Program must submit an application for tax credit to the corporation. The application shall identify the project and its location and include evidence that the project is a qualified project as defined in s. 220.185. The corporation may request any information from an applicant necessary to enable the corporation to make tax credit allocations according to the guidelines set forth in subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation’s approval of an applicant as a designated project shall be in writing and shall include a statement of the maximum credit allowable to the applicant. A copy of this approval shall be transmitted to the executive director of the Department of Revenue, who shall apply the tax credit to the tax liability of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of implementing this program and assessing the property for ad valorem taxation under s. 193.011, neither the tax credits nor financing generated by tax credits shall be considered as income to the property, and the actual rental income from rent-restricted units in a state housing tax credit development shall be recognized by the property appraiser. In considering or using the market or cost approaches under s. 193.011, neither the costs paid for by tax credits nor the costs paid for by additional financing proceeds received because the property is in the program shall be included in the valuation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the further purpose of implementing this program in Florida and in assessing the property for ad valorem taxation under s. 193.011, any extended low income housing agreement and all amendments and supplements thereto which are recorded and filed in the official public records of the county where the property is located shall be deemed a land use regulation during the term of any such agreement, amendment, or supplement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is authorized to expend fees received in conjunction with the allocation of state housing tax credits only for the purpose of administration of the program, including private legal services which relate to interpretation of s. 42 of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 99-378; s. 12, ch. 2002-18.</History></Section>