<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.123" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Stockholders; loan requirement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any financial institution may request membership in the corporation by making application to the board of directors on such form and in such manner as the board of directors may require, and membership shall become effective upon acceptance of the application in the manner designated by the board. Each member stockholder of the corporation shall make loans to the corporation as and when called upon by it to do so on such terms and other conditions as shall be approved from time to time by the board of directors, except that the total amount outstanding on loans to the corporation made by any member at any one time, when added to the amount of the investment in the capital stock of the corporation then held by such member, shall not exceed the following limit, to be determined as of the time such member becomes a member on the basis of the audited balance sheet of such member at the close of its fiscal year immediately preceding its application for membership or, in the case of an insurance company, its last annual statement to the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission: 5 percent of the capital and surplus of commercial banks and trust companies; 5 percent of the total outstanding loans made by savings and loan associations and building and loan associations; 5 percent of the capital and unassigned surplus of stock insurance companies, except fire insurance companies; 5 percent of the unassigned surplus of mutual insurance companies, except fire insurance companies; 0.2 percent of the assets of fire insurance companies; and such limits as may be approved by the board of directors of the corporation for other financial institutions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each call made by the corporation shall be prorated among the members of the corporation in substantially the same proportion that the adjusted loan limit of each member bears to the aggregate of the adjusted loan limits of all members, except that the amount, if any, prorated to a member shall be based upon the member’s concurrence with the proposed duration of the loan and financial ability to make a loan to the corporation as determined by the member at the time of the call. The adjusted loan limit of a member shall be the amount of such member’s loan limit, reduced by the balance of outstanding loans made by it to the corporation and the investment in capital stock of the corporation held by such member at the time of the call.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All loans to the corporation by members shall be evidenced by bonds, debentures, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness of the corporation, which shall be freely transferable at all times, and which shall bear interest at a rate determined by the board of directors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-172; s. 10, ch. 79-176; s. 2, ch. 80-108; s. 460, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>