<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0420.628" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Affordable housing for children and young adults leaving foster care; legislative findings and intent.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that there are many young adults who, through no fault of their own, live in foster families, group homes, and institutions, and face numerous barriers to a successful transition to adulthood. Young adults who are leaving the child welfare system may enter adulthood lacking the knowledge, skills, attitudes, habits, and relationships that will enable them to become productive members of society.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature further finds that the main barriers to safe and affordable housing for such young adults are cost, lack of availability, the unwillingness of landlords to rent to such youth due to perceived regulatory barriers, and a lack of knowledge about how to be a good tenant. These barriers cause young adults to be at risk of becoming homeless.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature also finds that young adults who leave the child welfare system are disproportionately represented in the homeless population. Without the stability of safe and affordable housing, all other services, training, and opportunities provided to such young adults may not be effective. Making affordable housing available will decrease the chance of homelessness and may increase the ability of such young adults to live independently.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature intends that the Florida Housing Finance Corporation, agencies within the State Housing Initiative Partnership Program, local housing finance agencies, public housing authorities, and their agents, and other providers of affordable housing coordinate with the Department of Children and Family Services, their agents, and community-based care providers who provide services under s. 409.1671 to develop and implement strategies and procedures designed to make affordable housing available whenever and wherever possible to young adults who leave the child welfare system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Young adults who leave the child welfare system meet the definition of eligible persons under ss. 420.503(17) and 420.9071(10) for affordable housing, and are encouraged to participate in federal, state, and local affordable housing programs. Students deemed to be eligible occupants under 26 U.S.C. s. 42(i)(3)(D) shall be considered eligible persons for purposes of all projects funded under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 2009-96; s. 5, ch. 2009-164; s. 97, ch. 2010-5; s. 11, ch. 2011-15.</History>
</Section>