<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0420.9079" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local Government Housing Trust Fund.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created in the State Treasury the Local Government Housing Trust Fund, which shall be administered by the corporation on behalf of the department according to the provisions of ss. 420.907-420.9076 and this section. There shall be deposited into the fund a portion of the documentary stamp tax revenues as provided in s. 201.15, moneys received from any other source for the purposes of ss. 420.907-420.9076 and this section, and all proceeds derived from the investment of such moneys. Moneys in the fund that are not currently needed for the purposes of the programs administered pursuant to ss. 420.907-420.9076 and this section shall be deposited to the credit of the fund and may be invested as provided by law. The interest received on any such investment shall be credited to the fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall administer the fund exclusively for the purpose of implementing the programs described in ss. 420.907-420.9076 and this section. With the exception of monitoring the activities of counties and eligible municipalities to determine local compliance with program requirements, the corporation shall not receive appropriations from the fund for administrative or personnel costs. For the purpose of implementing the compliance monitoring provisions of s. 420.9075(9), the corporation may request a maximum of one-quarter of 1 percent of the annual appropriation per state fiscal year. When such funding is appropriated, the corporation shall deduct the amount appropriated prior to calculating the local housing distribution pursuant to ss. 420.9072 and 420.9073.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 92-317; s. 40, ch. 97-167; s. 16, ch. 98-56; s. 25, ch. 2006-69; s. 11, ch. 2009-2; s. 32, ch. 2009-96; s. 18, ch. 2011-15.</History>
</Section>