<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0420.0004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, unless the context otherwise indicates:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adjusted for family size” means adjusted in a manner which results in an income eligibility level which is lower for households with fewer than four people, or higher for households with more than four people, than the base income eligibility determined as provided in subsection (9), subsection (11), subsection (12), or subsection (17), based upon a formula as established by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adjusted gross income” means all wages, assets, regular cash or noncash contributions or gifts from persons outside the household, and such other resources and benefits as may be determined to be income by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development, adjusted for family size, less deductions allowable under s. 62 of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Affordable” means that monthly rents or monthly mortgage payments including taxes, insurance, and utilities do not exceed 30 percent of that amount which represents the percentage of the median adjusted gross annual income for the households as indicated in subsection (9), subsection (11), subsection (12), or subsection (17).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporation” means the Florida Housing Finance Corporation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community-based organization” or “nonprofit organization” means a private corporation organized under chapter 617 to assist in the provision of housing and related services on a not-for-profit basis and which is acceptable to federal and state agencies and financial institutions as a sponsor of low-income housing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Disabling condition” means a diagnosable substance abuse disorder, serious mental illness, developmental disability, or chronic physical illness or disability, or the co-occurrence of two or more of these conditions, and a determination that the condition is:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expected to be of long-continued and indefinite duration; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not expected to impair the ability of the person with special needs to live independently with appropriate supports.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Elderly” describes persons 62 years of age or older.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Extremely-low-income persons” means one or more natural persons or a family whose total annual household income does not exceed 30 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the state. The Florida Housing Finance Corporation may adjust this amount annually by rule to provide that in lower income counties, extremely low income may exceed 30 percent of area median income and that in higher income counties, extremely low income may be less than 30 percent of area median income.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local public body” means any county, municipality, or other political subdivision, or any housing authority as provided by chapter 421, which is eligible to sponsor or develop housing for farmworkers and very-low-income and low-income persons within its jurisdiction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Low-income persons” means one or more natural persons or a family, the total annual adjusted gross household income of which does not exceed 80 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the state, or 80 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the metropolitan statistical area (MSA) or, if not within an MSA, within the county in which the person or family resides, whichever is greater.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Moderate-income persons” means one or more natural persons or a family, the total annual adjusted gross household income of which is less than 120 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the state, or 120 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the metropolitan statistical area (MSA) or, if not within an MSA, within the county in which the person or family resides, whichever is greater.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person with special needs” means an adult person requiring independent living services in order to maintain housing or develop independent living skills and who has a disabling condition; a young adult formerly in foster care who is eligible for services under s. 409.1451(5); a survivor of domestic violence as defined in s. 741.28; or a person receiving benefits under the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) program or the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) program or from veterans’ disability benefits.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Student” means any person not living with his or her parent or guardian who is eligible to be claimed by his or her parent or guardian as a dependent under the federal income tax code and who is enrolled on at least a half-time basis in a secondary school, career center, community college, college, or university.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substandard” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any unit lacking complete plumbing or sanitary facilities for the exclusive use of the occupants;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit which is in violation of one or more major sections of an applicable housing code and where such violation poses a serious threat to the health of the occupant; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit that has been declared unfit for human habitation but that could be rehabilitated for less than 50 percent of the property value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substantial rehabilitation” means repair or restoration of a dwelling unit where the value of such repair or restoration exceeds 40 percent of the value of the dwelling.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Very-low-income persons” means one or more natural persons or a family, not including students, the total annual adjusted gross household income of which does not exceed 50 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the state, or 50 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the metropolitan statistical area (MSA) or, if not within an MSA, within the county in which the person or family resides, whichever is greater.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 88-376; s. 1, ch. 89-121; s. 13, ch. 90-275; s. 72, ch. 2000-153; s. 36, ch. 2004-357; ss. 44, 53, ch. 2006-26; s. 14, ch. 2006-69; s. 323, ch. 2011-142; s. 7, ch. 2011-189.</History>
</Section>