<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.524" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to Predevelopment Loan Program Act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of ss. 420.521-420.529, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community-based organization” or “not-for-profit organization” means any group incorporated under chapter 617 to provide housing and other services on a not-for-profit basis, and which is acceptable to federal and state agencies and financial institutions as a sponsor of affordable housing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible housing project” means a housing project proposed by an eligible sponsor which will ensure that a minimum of 20 percent of the completed housing units are rented or sold to very-low-income persons or that a minimum of 50 percent of the completed housing units are rented or sold to low-income households or low-income farmworker households.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Low-income persons” means one or more natural persons or a family, not including students, whose total annual household income does not exceed 80 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the state, or 80 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the metropolitan statistical area (MSA) or, if not within an MSA, within the county in which the person or family resides, whichever is greater.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sponsor” means a unit of local government, a housing authority as established pursuant to chapter 421, a community-based or not-for-profit organization, or a limited partnership if its general partner is a community-based or not-for-profit organization that applies for and is awarded predevelopment expenses from the fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Student” means any person not living with that person’s parent or guardian who is eligible to be claimed by that person’s parent or guardian as a dependent under the federal income tax code and who is enrolled on at least a half-time basis in a secondary school, career center, community college, college, or university. The term does not include a person participating in an educational or training program approved by the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Target population” means farmworkers, very-low-income persons and families, and low-income persons and families.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Very-low-income persons” means one or more natural persons or a family, not including students, whose total annual household income does not exceed 50 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the state, or 50 percent of the median annual adjusted gross income for households within the metropolitan statistical area (MSA) or, if not within an MSA, within the county in which the person or family resides, whichever is greater. “Very-low-income persons” also means, in projects for which the sponsor intends to use the federal low-income housing tax credit, persons or households having incomes that meet the eligibility requirements of s. 42 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 88-376; s. 12, ch. 92-317; s. 3, ch. 93-181; s. 77, ch. 2000-153; s. 37, ch. 2004-357.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 420.306.</Text></Note></Section>