<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Business plan; strategic plan; annual report.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall develop a business plan for the provision of affordable housing for the state. The plan shall not be inconsistent with the strategic plan prepared pursuant to subsection (2) and shall contain performance measures and specific performance targets for the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability of low-income and moderate-income Floridians to access housing that is decent and affordable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The continued availability and affordability of housing financed by the corporation to target populations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The availability of affordable financing programs, including equity and debt products, and programs that reduce gaps in conventional financing, to increase individual access to housing and stimulate private production of affordable housing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The establishment and maintenance of efficiencies in the delivery of affordable housing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other measures as directed by the corporation’s board of directors.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The corporation shall also compile data on the stimulus of economic activity created by the affordable housing finance programs administered by the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation, in equal partnership with the department, shall develop annually a strategic plan for the provision of affordable housing in Florida as part of the department’s agency strategic plan required pursuant to <Reference Number="1" />chapter 186. In part, the plan shall include provisions that maximize the abilities of the corporation and the department to implement the state housing strategy established under s. 420.0003, to respond to federal housing initiatives, and to develop programs in a manner that is more responsive to the needs of public and private partners. The plan shall be developed on a schedule consistent with that established by s. 186.021. For purposes of this act, the executive director or his or her designee shall serve as the corporation’s representative to achieve a coordinated and integrated planning relationship with the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall submit to the Governor and the presiding officers of each house of the Legislature, within 2 months after the end of its fiscal year, a complete and detailed report setting forth:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its operations and accomplishments;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its receipts and expenditures during its fiscal year in accordance with the categories or classifications established by the corporation for its operating and capital outlay purposes;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its assets and liabilities at the end of its fiscal year and the status of reserve, special, or other funds;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A schedule of its bonds outstanding at the end of its fiscal year, together with a statement of the principal amounts of bonds issued and redeemed during the fiscal year; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information relating to the corporation’s activities in implementing the provisions of ss. 420.5087, 420.5088, and 420.5095.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of people served, delineated by income, age, family size, and racial characteristics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of units produced under each program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average cost of producing units under each program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average sales price of single-family units financed under s. 420.5088.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average amount of rent charged based on unit size on units financed under s. 420.5087.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of persons in rural communities served under each program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of farmworkers served under each program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of homeless persons served under each program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of elderly persons served under each program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which geographic distribution has been achieved in accordance with the provisions of s. 420.5087.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The success of the Community Workforce Housing Innovation Pilot Program in meeting the housing needs of eligible areas.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information the corporation deems appropriate.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall submit, with the annual report required by this section, a copy of an annual financial audit of its accounts and records and an annual compliance audit of its programs conducted by an independent certified public accountant performed in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards and government auditing standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Both the corporation’s business plan and annual report shall recognize the different fiscal periods under which the corporation, the state, the Federal Government, and local governments operate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-161; s. 10, ch. 88-376; s. 4, ch. 91-220; s. 21, ch. 97-167; s. 11, ch. 98-56; s. 7, ch. 2001-98; s. 26, ch. 2007-105; s. 16, ch. 2007-198.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Strategic plans” in chapter 186 were redesignated “long-range program plans” by ch. 2000-371.</Text></Note></Section>