<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.525" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Housing Predevelopment Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is authorized to be established by the corporation with a qualified public depository meeting the requirements of chapter 280 a separate fund to be named the “Housing Predevelopment Fund” which shall be administered by the corporation according to the provisions of ss. 420.521-420.529. Any amounts held in the Housing Predevelopment Trust Fund for such purposes as of January 1, 1998, must be transferred to the corporation for deposit in the Housing Predevelopment Fund, whereupon the Housing Predevelopment Trust Fund must be closed. There shall be deposited into the fund moneys from the State Housing Trust Fund as created by s. 420.0005 or moneys received from any other source, for the purpose of this program and all proceeds derived from the use of such moneys. Administrative and personnel costs incurred in implementing the provisions of ss. 420.521-420.529 may be paid from the fund. Expenditures from the Housing Predevelopment Fund shall not be required to be included in the corporation’s budget request or be subject to appropriation by the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All unencumbered funds, loan repayments, proceeds from the sale of any property, existing funds remaining in the following programs, and any other proceeds that would otherwise accrue pursuant to the activities conducted under this program and the provisions of the following programs shall be deposited in the fund and shall not revert to the General Revenue Fund:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Rural Housing Land Acquisition and Site Development Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Farmworker Housing Assistance Act; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Community-Based Organization Loan Program created by the Affordable Housing Planning and Community Assistance Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 88-376; s. 13, ch. 92-317; s. 4, ch. 93-181; s. 27, ch. 97-167; s. 78, ch. 2000-153.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 420.307.</Text></Note></Section>