<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the following words and terms have the following meanings unless the context indicates another or different meaning or intent:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board of directors” means the board of directors of the corporation created pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consortium” means two or more mortgagees who jointly negotiate and agree to provide home equity conversion plans to elderly homeowners, on agreed-upon terms and conditions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consumer housing cooperative” means a corporation incorporated pursuant to the provisions of the Florida General Corporation Law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporation,” as used in this part, means the Florida Housing Development Corporation created pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Development costs” means the costs which have been approved by the Florida Housing Finance Corporation as appropriate expenditures, including but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legal, organizational, marketing, and administrative expenses;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of fees for preliminary feasibility studies and advances for planning, engineering, and architectural work;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses for surveys as to need and market analyses;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Necessary application and other fees to federal and other government agencies; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other expenses as the Florida Housing Finance Corporation may deem appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Financial institution” means any banking corporation or trust company, savings and loan association, insurance company, or related corporation, partnership, foundation, or other institution engaged primarily in lending or investing funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home equity conversion mortgage” means a reverse mortgage loan made to an elderly homeowner which is secured by a lien on real property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lending institution” means a mortgage lender, including any bank or trust company, savings bank, national banking association, state or federal savings and loan association, or building and loan association maintaining an office in this state or any insurance company authorized to transact business in this state or a corporation composed of such institutions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Low-income or moderate-income persons” means families and persons who cannot afford, as defined by federal law, to pay the amounts at which private enterprise is providing a substantial supply of decent, safe, and sanitary housing and fall within income limitations set by the Florida Housing Finance Corporation in its rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonprofit housing corporation” means a nonprofit housing corporation incorporated pursuant to the provisions of Florida law relating to corporations not for profit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Project” means a specific work or improvement, including land, buildings, improvements, real and personal property, or any interest therein, acquired, owned, constructed, reconstructed, rehabilitated, or improved with the financial assistance of the Florida Housing Finance Corporation, including the construction of low-income and moderate-income housing facilities and facilities incident or appurtenant thereto, such as streets, sewers, utilities, parks, site preparation, landscaping, and such other administrative, community, and recreational facilities as the Florida Housing Finance Corporation determines to be necessary, convenient, or desirable appurtenances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Real property” means lands, structures, franchises, and interests in land, including lands under water and riparian rights, space and air rights, and any and all other interests and rights usually included within such term. Real property also means and includes any and all interests in such property less than full title, such as easements, incorporeal hereditaments, and every estate, interest, or right, legal or equitable, including terms for years and liens thereon by way of judgments, mortgages, or otherwise, and also all claims for damages for such real estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secured loan” means a loan secured by a mortgage or a security interest in a project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” means the State of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stockholder” means any financial institution authorized to do business within this state which undertakes to lend money to the corporation created pursuant to this part, upon its call, and in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-172; ss. 1, 4, ch. 76-249; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 84-251; s. 21, ch. 88-376; s. 73, ch. 2000-153; s. 5, ch. 2000-342.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 420.011.</Text></Note></Section>