<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.5099" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Allocation of the low-income housing tax credit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Housing Finance Corporation is designated the housing credit agency for the state within the meaning of s. 42(h)(7)(A) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and shall have the responsibility and authority to establish procedures necessary for proper allocation and distribution of low-income housing tax credits and shall exercise all powers necessary to administer the allocation of such credits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall adopt allocation procedures that will ensure the maximum use of available tax credits in order to encourage development of low-income housing in the state, taking into consideration the timeliness of the application, the location of the proposed housing project, the relative need in the area for low-income housing and the availability of such housing, the economic feasibility of the project, and the ability of the applicant to proceed to completion of the project in the calendar year for which the credit is sought.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may request such information from applicants as will enable it to make the allocations according to the guidelines set forth in subsection (2), including, but not limited to, the information required to be provided the corporation by chapter 67, Florida Administrative Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the corporation shall administer the allocation procedures and determine allocations on behalf of the corporation. Any applicant disputing the amount of an allocation or the denial of a request for an allocation may request an appeal to the board of directors of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of implementing this program in Florida and in assessing the property for ad valorem taxation under s. 193.011, neither the tax credits, nor financing generated by tax credits, shall be considered as income to the property, and the actual rental income from rent restricted units in a low-income tax credit development shall be recognized by the property appraiser. In considering or using the market or cost approaches under s. 193.011, neither the costs paid for by tax credits nor the costs paid for by additional financing proceeds received because the property is in the program shall be included in the valuation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the further purpose of implementing this program in Florida and in assessing the property for ad valorem taxation under s. 193.011, any extended low income housing agreement and all amendments and supplements thereto which are recorded and filed in the official public records of the county where the property is located shall be deemed a land use regulation during the term of any such agreement, amendment, or supplement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is authorized to expend fees received in conjunction with the allocation of low-income housing tax credits only for the purpose of administration of the program, including private legal services which relate to interpretation of s. 42 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 87-106; s. 3, ch. 95-383; s. 19, ch. 97-167; s. 11, ch. 2000-353; s. 13, ch. 2002-18.</History></Section>