<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0420.623" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local coalitions for the homeless.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ESTABLISHMENT.<EmDash />The department shall establish local coalitions to plan, network, coordinate, and monitor the delivery of services to the homeless. Appropriate local groups and organizations involved in providing services for the homeless and interested business groups and associations shall be given an opportunity to participate in such coalitions, including, but not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organizations and agencies providing mental health and substance abuse treatment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County health departments and community health centers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organizations and agencies providing food, shelter, or other services targeted to the homeless.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local law enforcement agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional workforce boards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County and municipal governments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local public housing authorities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local school districts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local organizations and agencies serving specific subgroups of the homeless population, including, but not limited to, those serving veterans, victims of domestic violence, person with HIV/AIDS, and runaway youth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local community-based care alliances.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNCTIONS OF LOCAL COALITIONS.<EmDash />Major functions of the local coalitions are to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop or assist with the development of the local homeless continuum of care plan, as described in s. 420.624, for the catchment area containing the county or region served by the local homeless coalition. Unless otherwise specified in the plan or as a result of an agreement with another coalition in the same catchment area, the local coalition shall serve as the lead agency for the local homeless assistance continuum of care.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discuss local issues related to homelessness and the needs of the homeless.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inventory all local resources for the homeless, including, but not limited to, food assistance, clothing, emergency shelter, low-cost housing, emergency medical care, counseling, training, and employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and assess all services and programs in support of the homeless and identify unmet needs of the homeless.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitate the delivery of multiagency services for the homeless to eliminate duplication of services and to maximize the use of limited existing resources for the homeless.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop new programs and services to fill critical service gaps, if necessary, through reallocation of existing resources for the homeless.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a community resource directory of services available to the homeless for use by agencies, volunteers, information and referral systems, and homeless persons.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop public education and outreach initiatives to make homeless persons aware of the services available to them through community agencies and organizations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify and explore new approaches to shelter care for the homeless.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitor and evaluate local homeless initiatives to assess their impact, to determine the adequacy of services available through such initiatives, and to identify additional unmet needs of homeless persons.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect and compile information relating to the homeless population served and report on a regular basis, but at least annually, such information to the department, as directed by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop an annual report detailing the coalition’s goals and activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop spending plans pursuant to the grant-in-aid program created under s. 420.625. Spending plans shall include a competitive ranking of applications from local agencies eligible for funding pursuant to the provisions of s. 420.625.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a strategy for increasing support and participation from local businesses in the coalition’s programs and activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT GUIDELINES.<EmDash />The department shall develop guidelines for coalition activities, coalition reports, and development of local plans of action.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 13, ch. 87-106; s. 3, ch. 88-303; ss. 27, 29, ch. 88-376; s. 39, ch. 95-210; s. 140, ch. 97-101; s. 11, ch. 2001-98; s. 138, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>