<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.55" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Housing; response to disasters.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Housing Finance Corporation is authorized to provide funds to eligible entities for affordable housing recovery in those areas of the state which sustained housing damage due to hurricanes during 2004 and 2005. The Florida Housing Finance Corporation shall utilize data provided by the Federal Emergency Management Agency to assist in its allocation of funds to local jurisdictions. To administer these programs, the Florida Housing Finance Corporation shall be guided by the “Hurricane Housing Work Group Recommendations to Assist in Florida’s Long Term Housing Recovery Efforts” report dated February 16, 2005, and may adopt emergency rules pursuant to s. 120.54. The Legislature finds that emergency rules adopted pursuant to this section meet the health, safety, and welfare requirement of s. 120.54(4). The Legislature finds that such emergency rulemaking power is necessary for the preservation of the rights and welfare of the people in order to provide additional funds to assist those areas of the state that sustained housing damage due to hurricanes during 2004 and 2005. Therefore, in adopting such emergency rules, the corporation need not make the findings required by s. 120.54(4)(a). Emergency rules adopted under this section are exempt from s. 120.54(4)(c). The sum of $75.9 million is appropriated from the Local Government Housing Trust Fund to the Florida Housing Finance Corporation for the Rental Recovery Loan Program. The sum of $15 million is appropriated from the State Housing Trust Fund to the Florida Housing Finance Corporation for the Farmworker Housing Recovery Program and the Special Housing Assistance and Development Program, and the sum of $17 million is appropriated from the State Housing Trust Fund to the Florida Housing Finance Corporation for the Rental Recovery Program. The sum of $100,000 is appropriated from the State Housing Trust Fund to the Florida Housing Finance Corporation for technical and training assistance.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 48, 53, ch. 2006-26; s. 31, ch. 2006-69.</History></Section>