<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0420.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public corporation; creation, membership, terms, expenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Economic Opportunity a public corporation and a public body corporate and politic, to be known as the “Florida Housing Finance Corporation.” It is declared to be the intent of and constitutional construction by the Legislature that the Florida Housing Finance Corporation constitutes an entrepreneurial public corporation organized to provide and promote the public welfare by administering the governmental function of financing or refinancing housing and related facilities in Florida and that the corporation is not a department of the executive branch of state government within the scope and meaning of s. 6, Art. IV of the State Constitution, but is functionally related to the Department of Economic Opportunity in which it is placed. The executive function of state government to be performed by the executive director of the Department of Economic Opportunity in the conduct of the business of the Florida Housing Finance Corporation must be performed pursuant to a contract to monitor and set performance standards for the implementation of the business plan for the provision of housing approved for the corporation as provided in s. 420.0006. This contract shall include the performance standards for the provision of affordable housing in Florida established in the business plan described in s. 420.511.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is constituted as a public instrumentality, and the exercise by the corporation of the power conferred by this act is considered to be the performance of an essential public function. The corporation is an agency for the purposes of s. 120.52 and is a state agency for purposes of s. 159.807(4). The corporation is subject to chapter 119, subject to exceptions applicable to the corporation, and to the provisions of chapter 286; however, the corporation shall be entitled to provide notice of internal review committee meetings for competitive proposals or procurement to applicants by mail, facsimile, or publication on an Internet website, rather than by means of publication. The corporation is not governed by chapter 607 or chapter 617, but by the provisions of this part. If for any reason the establishment of the corporation is deemed in violation of law, such provision is severable and the remainder of this act remains in full force and effect.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is a separate budget entity and is not subject to control, supervision, or direction by the Department of Economic Opportunity in any manner, including, but not limited to, personnel, purchasing, transactions involving real or personal property, and budgetary matters. The corporation shall consist of a board of directors composed of the executive director of the Department of Economic Opportunity as an ex officio and voting member, or a senior-level agency employee designated by the director, and eight members appointed by the Governor subject to confirmation by the Senate from the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One citizen actively engaged in the residential home building industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One citizen actively engaged in the banking or mortgage banking industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One citizen who is a representative of those areas of labor engaged in home building.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One citizen with experience in housing development who is an advocate for low-income persons.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One citizen actively engaged in the commercial building industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One citizen who is a former local government elected official.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two citizens of the state who are not principally employed as members or representatives of any of the groups specified in paragraphs (a)-(f).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the corporation shall be appointed for terms of 4 years, except that any vacancy shall be filled for the unexpired term.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to removal or reinstatement of the member by the Senate, the Governor may suspend a member for cause, including, but not limited to, failure to attend at least 3 meetings of the board during any 12-month period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair and a vice chair shall be elected annually by the members thereof. Any additional officers, who need not be members, as may be deemed necessary by the members of the corporation may be designated and elected by the members thereof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the board of directors of the corporation shall receive no compensation for his or her services but shall be entitled to the necessary expenses, including per diem and travel expenses, incurred in the discharge of his or her duties, as provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board of directors of the corporation shall file full and public disclosure of financial interests at the times and places and in the same manner required of elected constitutional officers under s. 8, Art. II of the State Constitution and any law implementing s. 8, Art. II of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is a corporation primarily acting as an instrumentality of the state, within the meaning of s. 768.28.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-161; s. 48, ch. 81-167; s. 51, ch. 83-55; s. 19, ch. 85-265; s. 6, ch. 88-376; s. 7, ch. 93-181; s. 1, ch. 96-332; s. 1045, ch. 97-103; s. 7, ch. 97-167; ss. 4, 17, ch. 98-56; s. 49, ch. 2003-1; s. 71, ch. 2005-2; s. 10, ch. 2007-198; s. 330, ch. 2011-142; s. 9, ch. 2011-189.</History>
</Section>