<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0420.6015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative findings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the findings and declarations in ss. 420.0002, 420.502, 421.02, 422.02, and 423.01, which are hereby reaffirmed, the Legislature finds that:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Decent, safe, and sanitary housing for persons of very low income, low income, and moderate income are a critical need in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">New and rehabilitated housing must be provided at a cost affordable to such persons in order to alleviate this critical need.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The private sector housing construction industry primarily produces housing units for middle-income households and upper-income households and often has limited experience in housing development which provides quality housing for low-income persons in economically declining or distressed areas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Among other things, the high cost of project financing tends to restrict the development of housing affordable to very-low-income persons, low-income persons, and moderate-income persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For these reasons, private capital and existing state housing programs do not provide an adequate remedy to this situation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special programs are needed to stimulate private enterprise to build and rehabilitate housing in order to help eradicate slum conditions and provide housing for very-low-income persons, low-income persons, and moderate-income persons as a matter of public purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public-private partnerships are an essential means of bringing together resources to provide affordable housing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall facilitate the mobilization of public and private resources to provide affordable housing through its responsibilities in the areas of housing, comprehensive planning, and community assistance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-192; s. 28, ch. 92-317; s. 6, ch. 2000-342; s. 20, ch. 2004-243.</History></Section>