<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0420.615" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Affordable housing land donation density bonus incentives.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government may provide density bonus incentives pursuant to the provisions of this section to any landowner who voluntarily donates fee simple interest in real property to the local government for the purpose of assisting the local government in providing affordable housing. Donated real property must be determined by the local government to be appropriate for use as affordable housing and must be subject to deed restrictions to ensure that the property will be used for affordable housing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the terms “affordable,” “extremely-low-income persons,” “low-income persons,” “moderate-income persons,” and “very-low-income persons” have the same meaning as in s. 420.0004.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The density bonus may be applied to any land within the local government’s jurisdiction provided that residential use is an allowable use on the receiving land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The density bonus, identification of receiving land for the bonus, and any other conditions associated with the donation of the land for affordable housing are the subject of review and approval by the local government. The award of density bonus pursuant to this section, the legal description of the land receiving the bonus, and any other conditions associated with the bonus shall be memorialized in a development agreement or other binding agreement and recorded with the clerk of court in the county where the donated land and receiving land are located.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government, as part of the approval process, shall adopt a comprehensive plan amendment, pursuant to part II of chapter 163, for the receiving land that incorporates the density bonus. Such amendment shall be adopted in the manner as required for small-scale amendments pursuant to s. 163.3187 and is not subject to the requirements of s. 163.3184(4)(b)-(d).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The deed restrictions required pursuant to subsection (1) for an affordable housing unit must also prohibit the unit from being sold at a price that exceeds the threshold for housing that is affordable for low-income or moderate-income persons or to a buyer who is not eligible due to his or her income under this chapter. The deed restriction may allow affordable housing units created under subsection (1) to be rented to extremely-low-income, very-low-income, low-income, or moderate-income persons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government may transfer all or a portion of the donated land to a nonprofit housing organization, such as a community land trust, housing authority, or community redevelopment agency, to be used for the production and preservation of permanently affordable housing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 2006-69; s. 65, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>