<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0420.0006" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority to contract with corporation; contract requirements; nonperformance.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the department shall contract, notwithstanding part I of chapter 287, with the Florida Housing Finance Corporation on a multiyear basis to stimulate, provide, and foster affordable housing in the state. The contract must incorporate the performance measures required by s. 420.511 and must be consistent with the provisions of the corporation’s strategic plan prepared in accordance with s. 420.511. The contract must provide that, in the event the corporation fails to comply with any of the performance measures required by s. 420.511, the executive director shall notify the Governor and shall refer the nonperformance to the department’s inspector general for review and determination as to whether such failure is due to forces beyond the corporation’s control or whether such failure is due to inadequate management of the corporation’s resources. Advances shall continue to be made pursuant to s. 420.0005 during the pendency of the review by the department’s inspector general. If such failure is due to outside forces, it shall not be deemed a violation of the contract. If such failure is due to inadequate management, the department’s inspector general shall provide recommendations regarding solutions. The Governor is authorized to resolve any differences of opinion with respect to performance under the contract and may request that advances continue in the event of a failure under the contract due to inadequate management. The Chief Financial Officer shall approve the request absent a finding by the Chief Financial Officer that continuing such advances would adversely impact the state; however, in any event the Chief Financial Officer shall provide advances sufficient to meet the debt service requirements of the corporation and sufficient to fund contracts committing funds from the State Housing Trust Fund so long as such contracts are in accordance with the laws of this state.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 97-167; s. 2, ch. 98-56; s. 458, ch. 2003-261; s. 8, ch. 2011-189; s. 67, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>