<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0474.213" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lead the public to believe that such person is licensed as a veterinarian, or is engaged in the licensed practice of veterinary medicine, without such person holding a valid, active license pursuant to this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the name or title “veterinarian” when the person has not been licensed pursuant to this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as her or his own the license of another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give false or forged evidence to the board or a member thereof for the purpose of obtaining a license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a veterinarian’s license which has been suspended or revoked;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly employ unlicensed persons in the practice of veterinary medicine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly conceal information relative to violations of this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtain or attempt to obtain a license to practice veterinary medicine by fraudulent representation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice veterinary medicine in this state, unless the person holds a valid, active license to practice veterinary medicine pursuant to this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell or offer to sell a diploma conferring a degree from a veterinary school or college, or a license issued pursuant to this chapter, or procure such diploma or license with the intent that it shall be used as evidence of that which the document stands for by a person other than the one upon whom it was conferred or to whom it was granted; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly operate a veterinary establishment or premises without having a premise permit issued under s. 474.215.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates any provision of this section commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-228; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 5, 15, 16, ch. 85-291; s. 7, ch. 91-176; s. 105, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 131, ch. 94-119; s. 63, ch. 95-144; s. 357, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>