<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0474.202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Animal” means any mammal other than a human being or any bird, amphibian, fish, or reptile, wild or domestic, living or dead.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Veterinary Medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Client” means the owner or caretaker of an animal who arranges for its veterinary care.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Immediate supervision” or words of similar purport mean a licensed doctor of veterinary medicine is on the premises whenever veterinary services are being provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited-service veterinary medical practice” means offering or providing veterinary services at any location that has a primary purpose other than that of providing veterinary medical service at a permanent or mobile establishment permitted by the board; provides veterinary medical services for privately owned animals that do not reside at that location; operates for a limited time; and provides limited types of veterinary medical services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mobile veterinary establishment” and “mobile clinic” mean a mobile unit which contains the same treatment facilities as are required of a permanent veterinary establishment or which has entered into a written agreement with another veterinary establishment to provide any required facilities not available in the mobile unit. The terms do not refer to the use of a car, truck, or other motor vehicle by a veterinarian making a house call.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Patient” means any animal for which the veterinarian practices veterinary medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of veterinary medicine” means diagnosing the medical condition of animals and prescribing, dispensing, or administering drugs, medicine, appliances, applications, or treatment of whatever nature for the prevention, cure, or relief of a wound, fracture, bodily injury, or disease thereof; performing any manual procedure for the diagnosis of or treatment for pregnancy or fertility or infertility of animals; or representing oneself by the use of titles or words, or undertaking, offering, or holding oneself out, as performing any of these functions. The term includes the determination of the health, fitness, or soundness of an animal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Responsible supervision” or words of similar purport mean the control, direction, and regulation by a licensed doctor of veterinary medicine of the duties involving veterinary services which she or he delegates to unlicensed personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Veterinarian” means a health care practitioner who is licensed to engage in the practice of veterinary medicine in Florida under the authority of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Veterinarian/client/patient relationship” means a relationship where the veterinarian has assumed the responsibility for making medical judgments regarding the health of the animal and its need for medical treatment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Veterinary medicine” includes, with respect to animals, surgery, acupuncture, obstetrics, dentistry, physical therapy, radiology, theriogenology, and other branches or specialties of veterinary medicine.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-228; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 15, 16, ch. 85-291; s. 1, ch. 91-176; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 127, ch. 94-119; s. 157, ch. 94-218; s. 353, ch. 97-103; s. 43, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>