<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0474.2125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary license.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
	<Subsection Id="1">
	<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules providing for the issuance of a temporary license to a licensed veterinarian of another state for the purpose of enabling her or him to provide veterinary medical services in this state for the animals of a specific owner or, as may be needed in an emergency as defined in s. 252.34(3), for the animals of multiple owners, provided the applicant would qualify for licensure by endorsement under s. 474.217. No temporary license shall be valid for more than 30 days after its issuance, and no license shall cover more than the treatment of the animals of one owner except in an emergency as defined in s. 252.34(3). After the expiration of 30 days, a new license is required.</Text>
</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application for a temporary license shall state the names of all persons who are to enter this state and shall be accompanied by a fee in an amount established by the board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon certification of the applicant by the board, the department shall issue a temporary license to the applicant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application for a temporary license shall constitute the appointment of the Department of State as an agent of the applicant for service of process in any action or proceeding against the applicant arising out of any transaction or operation connected with, or incidental to, the practice of veterinary medicine for which the temporary license was issued.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 16, ch. 85-291; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 130, ch. 94-119; s. 356, ch. 97-103; s. 65, ch. 2012-5.</History>
</Section>