<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.506" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Facilities in pool.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following facilities shall be entered into the pool:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All existing state-owned facilities under the jurisdiction of the Department of Management Services shall be entered into the pool upon the creation of the pool.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each facility the acquisition of which is financed under this act and which has not already been entered into the pool shall be entered into the pool upon the earlier of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The completion of such acquisition; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement of accrual of rent for all or any portion of such facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agency may submit all, but not less than all, of the eligible facilities under its jurisdiction for entry into the pool. Each of such eligible facilities which is determined by the Department of Management Services to be a qualified facility shall be entered into the pool upon such determination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agency which requests the issuance of obligations under this act for the financing of the acquisition of a facility shall submit all, but not less than all, of the eligible facilities under its jurisdiction for entry into the pool. Each of such eligible facilities which is determined by the Department of Management Services to be a qualified facility shall be entered into the pool upon such a determination.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 85-349; s. 189, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 26, ch. 98-279.</History></Section>