<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special contracts with charitable youth organizations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state, or the governing body of any political subdivision of the state, is authorized, but not required, to contract for public service work such as highway and park maintenance, notwithstanding competitive sealed bid procedures required under this chapter or chapter 287, upon compliance with this section.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contractor or supplier must meet the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contractor or supplier must be a not-for-profit corporation incorporated under chapter 617 and in good standing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contractor or supplier must hold exempt status under s. 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code, as an organization described in s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporate charter of the contractor or supplier must state that the corporation is organized as a charitable youth organization exclusively for at-risk youths enrolled in a work-study program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrative salaries and benefits for any such corporation shall not exceed 15 percent of gross revenues. Field supervisors shall not be considered administrative overhead.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract, if approved by authorized agency personnel of the state, or the governing body of a political subdivision, as appropriate, must provide at a minimum that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Labor shall be performed exclusively by at-risk youth and their direct supervisors; and shall not be subject to subcontracting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment must be production-based.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract will terminate should the contractor or supplier no longer qualify under subsection (1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supplier or contractor has instituted a drug-free workplace program substantially in compliance with the provisions of s. 287.087.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contractor or supplier agrees to be subject to review and audit at the discretion of the Auditor General in order to ensure that the contractor or supplier has complied with this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No contract under this section may exceed the annual sum of $250,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Should a court find that a contract purporting to have been entered into pursuant to this section does not so qualify, the court may order that the contract be terminated on reasonable notice to the parties. The court shall not require disgorgement of any moneys earned for goods or services actually delivered or supplied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall excuse any person from compliance with ss. 287.132-287.134.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-113.</History></Section>