<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State construction management contracting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Construction management entity” means a licensed general contractor or a licensed building contractor, as defined in s. 489.105, who coordinates and supervises a construction project from the conceptual development stage through final construction, including the scheduling, selection, contracting with, and directing of specialty trade contractors, and the value engineering of a project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Construction project” means any planned or unforeseen fixed capital outlay activity authorized under s. 255.31. A construction project may include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A grouping of minor construction, rehabilitation, or renovation activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A grouping of substantially similar construction, rehabilitation, or renovation activities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Continuing contract” means a contract with a construction management entity for work during a defined time period on construction projects described by type, which may or may not be identified at the time of entering into the contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Management Services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist in the management of state construction projects, the department may select and contract with construction management entities that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are competitively selected by the department pursuant to s. 287.055; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agree to follow the advertising and competitive bidding procedures that the department is required to follow if the department is managing the construction project directly.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department’s authority under subsection (2) includes entering into a continuing contract for construction projects in which the estimated construction cost of each individual project under the contract does not exceed $2 million.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require the construction management entity, after having been selected for a construction project and after competitive negotiations, to offer a guaranteed maximum price and a guaranteed completion date. If so required, the construction management entity must secure an appropriate surety bond pursuant to s. 255.05 and must hold construction subcontracts. If a project solicited by the department pursuant to s. 287.055 includes a grouping of construction, rehabilitation, or renovation activities or substantially similar construction, rehabilitation, or renovation activities costing up to $1 million, the department may require the construction management entity to provide a separate guaranteed maximum price and a separate guaranteed completion date for each grouping included in the project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules for state agencies using the services of construction management entities under contract with the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2009-227.</History></Section>