<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.2501" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lease of space financed with local government obligations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except when specifically authorized by the Appropriations Act, no executive agency, department, public officer or employee shall enter any contract on behalf of the state, the term of which contract is more than 5 years, including any and all renewal periods and including any and all leases which constitute a series of leases, for the lease, lease-purchase, sale-leaseback, purchase, or rental of any office space, building, real property and improvements thereto, or any other fixed capital outlay project, any of which is or is to be financed with local government obligations of any type.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No lease, lease-purchase, sale-leaseback, purchase, or rental of any office space, building, real property and improvements thereto, or any other fixed capital outlay project that is or is to be financed with local government obligations of any type shall be requested for approval in the Appropriations Act unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction for such project is to be or has been competitively bid unless the certificate of occupancy for such project was issued more than 3 years prior to the time such request is made;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive branch agency or department making the request has competitively bid its space needs prior to making such request and the project for which approval is sought was the lowest and best bidder for such needs; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rent, lease payment, lease-purchase payment, or other payment for such project is not greater than an amount equal to the same proportion of the debt service on the local government obligations to be issued to finance or which are outstanding that financed, as the case may be, the facility or project for which approval is sought that the executive agency or department seeking such approval will utilize under the lease, lease-purchase, sale-leaseback, purchase, or rental of the project in the facility or project as compared to the entire facility or project that is to be or was financed. This paragraph shall not apply when the certificate of occupancy for a facility or project was issued more than 3 years prior to the time such request is made.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any project approved pursuant to this section shall be subject to the requirements of ss. 255.2502 and 255.2503.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contract entered on behalf of the state by any executive agency, department, public officer or employee in violation of this section shall be null and void.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 88-409.</History></Section>