<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reconveyance of lands not used for purpose specified.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event any party owning adjoining land conveys real property, without receipt of valuable consideration, to any municipality or county for a specific purpose or use and if such county or municipality fails to use such property for such purpose for a period of 60 consecutive months or, with respect to property conveyed on or after October 1, 1984, fails to use such property for such purpose for a period of 60 consecutive months or identify during the 60-month period the proposed use of such property in a comprehensive plan or other public facilities plan, then, upon written demand of the grantor, or grantor’s successors in title owning such adjoining land, the municipality or county may execute and deliver a quitclaim deed to the party making such demand provided such party is the owner of land adjoining such property on at least one side. No such quitclaim deed shall be delivered hereunder unless the specific purpose or use to be made of the property was disclosed to the grantee at the time of delivery of the conveyance or appeared in the conveyance or in an official record of the county; provided, however, that as to any such conveyance after July 1, 1967, the specific purpose or use must appear of record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the purpose for which the property was conveyed required physical improvement or construction on such property or the maintenance thereof, any such municipality or county that fails to construct, improve, or maintain such property for the period specified in subsection (1) shall be conclusively deemed to have abandoned the property for the purpose for which it was conveyed, unless, with respect to property conveyed on or after October 1, 1984, the proposed use of such property has been identified in a comprehensive plan or other public facilities plan of the municipality or county during the 60-month period specified in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 67-383; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 84-366; s. 42, ch. 93-164; s. 3, ch. 94-175; s. 3, ch. 95-297; s. 16, ch. 95-310.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of s. 255.22 and former s. 255.23.</Text></Note></Section>