<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.255" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Life-cycle costs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules and procedures, including energy conservation performance guidelines based on sustainable building ratings, for conducting a life-cycle cost analysis of alternative architectural and engineering designs and alternative major items of energy-consuming equipment to be retrofitted in existing state-owned facilities and for developing energy performance indices to evaluate the efficiency of energy utilization for competing designs in the construction of state-financed and leased facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such life-cycle costs shall be the sum of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonably expected fuel costs over the life of the building, as determined by the department, that are required to maintain illumination, power, temperature, humidity, and ventilation and all other energy-consuming equipment in a facility, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonable costs of probable maintenance, including labor and materials, and operation of the building.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To determine the life-cycle costs as defined in paragraph (2)(b), the department shall promulgate rules that shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The orientation and integration of the facility with respect to its physical site.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and type of glass employed in the facility and the directions of exposure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect of insulation incorporated into the facility design and the effect on solar utilization of the properties of external surfaces.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The variable occupancy and operating conditions of the facility and subportions of the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An energy consumption analysis of the major equipment of the facility’s heating, ventilating, and cooling system, lighting system, hot water system, and all other major energy-consuming equipment and systems as appropriate. This analysis shall include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The comparison of alternative systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A projection of the annual energy consumption of major energy-consuming equipment and systems for a range of operation of the facility over the life of the facility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The evaluation of the energy consumption of component equipment in each system, considering the operation of such components at other than full or rated outputs.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such rules shall be based on the best currently available methods of analysis, including such as those of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and other federal agencies and professional societies and materials developed by the department. Provisions shall be made for an annual updating of rules and standards as required.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 74-187; s. 5, ch. 85-256; s. 4, ch. 90-320; s. 16, ch. 98-279; s. 20, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>