<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.29" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Construction contracts; department rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall establish, through the adoption of administrative rules as provided in chapter 120:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for determining the qualifications and responsibility of potential bidders prior to advertisement for and receipt of bids for building construction contracts, including procedures for the rejection of bidders who are reasonably determined from prior experience to be unqualified or irresponsible to perform the work required by a proposed contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for awarding each state agency construction project to the lowest qualified bidder as well as procedures to be followed in cases in which the Department of Management Services declares a valid emergency to exist which would necessitate the waiver of the rules governing the awarding of state construction contracts to the lowest qualified bidder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures to govern negotiations for construction contracts and modifications to contract documents when such negotiations are determined by the secretary of the Department of Management Services to be in the best interest of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for entering into performance-based contracts for the development of public facilities when the Department of Management Services determines the use of such contracts to be in the best interest of the state. The procedures shall include, but are not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prequalification of bidders;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria to be used in developing requests for proposals which may provide for singular responsibility for design and construction, developer flexibility in material selection, construction techniques, and application of state-of-the-art improvements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accelerated scheduling, including the development of plans, designs, and construction simultaneously; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation of proposals and award of contracts considering such factors as price, quality, and concept of the proposal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 75-243; s. 10, ch. 84-321; s. 184, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 10, ch. 97-100.</History></Section>