<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.047" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Publicly owned or operated convention centers, sports stadiums, sports arenas, coliseums, or auditoriums; booking business records; confidentiality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Booking business records” means client calendars, client lists, exhibitor lists, and marketing files. The term does not include contract negotiation documents, lease agreements, rental rates, event invoices, event work orders, ticket sales information, box office records, attendance figures, payment schedules, certificates of insurance, accident reports, incident reports, or correspondence specific to a confirmed event.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Client calendar” means a schedule of events and a listing of the space reserved for such events that have been scheduled or tentatively scheduled to be held on a date more than 24 months in the future from whatever date is the current date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Client list” means a list of names, addresses, and contact persons for selected, prequalified, and potential clients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exhibitor list” means a list of names, addresses, and contact persons for individual exhibitors at an exhibition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marketing file” means proprietary information on the booking history, location, attendance, space requirement, and other qualifying information for a potential client.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The booking business records of a publicly owned or publicly operated convention center, sports stadium, sports arena, coliseum, or auditorium are exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Department of Revenue from obtaining any booking business records or related information at the department’s request if necessary for the department to administer its duties.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-63; s. 1, ch. 95-118; s. 110, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>