<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0255.2575" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Energy-efficient and sustainable buildings.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature declares that there is an important state interest in promoting the construction of energy-efficient and sustainable buildings. Government leadership in promoting these standards is vital to demonstrate the state’s commitment to energy conservation, saving taxpayers money, and raising public awareness of energy rating systems.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All county, municipal, school district, water management district, state university, community college, and state court buildings shall be constructed to comply with a sustainable building rating system or a national model green building code. This section applies to all county, municipal, school district, water management district, state university, community college, and state court buildings the architectural plans of which are commenced after July 1, 2008.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">St. Petersburg College may work with the Florida Community College System and may consult with the University of Florida to provide training and educational opportunities that will ensure that green building rating system certifying agents (accredited professionals who possess a knowledge and understanding of green building processes, practices, and principles) are available to work with the entities specified in subsection (2) as they construct public buildings to meet green building rating system standards. St. Petersburg College may work with the construction industry to develop an online continuing education curriculum for use statewide by builders constructing energy-efficient and sustainable public sector buildings and students interested in the college’s Green/Sustainability Track in its Management and Organization Leadership area of study. The curriculum developed may be offered by St. Petersburg College or in cooperation with other programs at other community colleges.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2008-227; s. 6, ch. 2011-222.</History>
</Section>