<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.28" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department authority to acquire land with or for facility thereon.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means any state board, commission, department, division, or bureau.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Party” means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other business entity which is licensed by the Department of State to do business in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building” or “facility” means those construction projects under the purview of the Department of Management Services. It shall not include environmentally endangered land, recreational land, or roads and highway construction under the purview of the Department of Transportation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Management Services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may acquire lands by gift, donation, or dedication or otherwise enter into agreements with any person, the Federal Government, or any other agency for acquiring such lands for constructing a building or other state facility thereon. Lands shall be acquired by the department in accordance with acquisition procedures for state lands provided for in s. 253.025.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In administering such authority, the department may enter into a contract with a party who shall be authorized to assist in the purchase of land containing, or to be used for constructing, a building or other facility thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe, by administrative rule, procedures for adequate public notice concerning all acquisitions of land or construction of a building or facility by any state agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 6, 7, ch. 75-243; s. 11, ch. 79-255; s. 183, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326.</History></Section>