<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.073" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Timely payment for purchases of construction services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in ss. 255.072-255.078, s. 215.422 governs the timely payment for construction services by a public entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a public entity disputes a portion of a payment request, the undisputed portion must be timely paid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a contractor receives payment from a public entity for labor, services, or materials furnished by subcontractors and suppliers hired by the contractor, the contractor shall remit payment due to those subcontractors and suppliers within 10 days after the contractor’s receipt of payment. When a subcontractor receives payment from a contractor for labor, services, or materials furnished by subcontractors and suppliers hired by the subcontractor, the subcontractor shall remit payment due to those subcontractors and suppliers within 7 days after the subcontractor’s receipt of payment. This subsection does not prohibit a contractor or subcontractor from disputing, pursuant to the terms of the relevant contract, all or any portion of a payment alleged to be due to another party if the contractor or subcontractor notifies the party whose payment is disputed, in writing, of the amount in dispute and the actions required to cure the dispute. The contractor or subcontractor must pay all undisputed amounts due within the time limits imposed by this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All payments due for the purchase of construction services and not made within the applicable time limits shall bear interest at the rate specified in s. 215.422. After July 1, 2006, such payments shall bear interest at the rate of 1 percent per month, to the extent that the Chief Financial Officer’s replacement project for the state’s accounting and cash management systems is operational for the particular affected public entity. After January 1, 2007, all such payments due from public entity shall bear interest at the rate of 1 percent per month.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2005-230.</History></Section>