<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0255.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority to the Department of Management Services to manage construction projects for state and local governments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The design, construction, erection, alteration, modification, repair, and demolition of all public and private buildings are governed by the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code, which are to be enforced by local jurisdictions or local enforcement districts unless specifically exempted as provided in s. 553.80. However, the Department of Management Services shall provide the project management and administration services for the construction, renovation, repair, modification, or demolition of buildings, utilities, parks, parking lots, or other facilities or improvements for projects for which the funds are appropriated to the department; provided that, with the exception of facilities constructed under the authority of chapters 944, 945, and 985; the Governor’s mansion and grounds thereof, as described in s. 272.18; and the Capitol Building and environs, being that part of the City of Tallahassee bounded on the north by Pensacola and Jefferson Streets, on the east by Monroe Street, on the south by Madison Street, and on the west by Duval Street, the department may not conduct plans reviews or inspection services for consistency with the Florida Building Code. The department’s fees for such services shall be paid from such appropriations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services may, upon request, enter into contracts with other state agencies under which the department may provide the project management, administration services, or assistance for the construction, renovation, repair, modification, or demolition of buildings, utilities, parks, parking lots, or other facilities or improvements for projects for which the funds are appropriated to other state agencies, provided that the department does not conduct plans reviews or inspection services for consistency with the Florida Building Code. The contracts shall provide for payment of fees to the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed to be in derogation of any authority conferred on the department by other provisions of law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-112; s. 14, ch. 95-143; s. 19, ch. 98-279; s. 15, ch. 2000-141; ss. 3, 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 2, ch. 2001-267; s. 1, ch. 2001-283; s. 3, ch. 2001-372.</History></Section>