<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0255.249" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Management Services; responsibility; department rules.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have responsibility and authority for the custodial and preventive maintenance, repair, and allocation of space of all buildings in the Florida Facilities Pool and the grounds located adjacent thereto.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require any state agency planning to terminate a lease for the purpose of occupying space in a new state-owned office building, the funds for which are appropriated after June 30, 2000, to state why the proposed relocation is in the best interest of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, to the extent feasible, coordinate the vacation of privately owned leased space with the expiration of the lease on that space and, when a lease is terminated before expiration of its base term, will make a reasonable effort to place another state agency in the space vacated. Any state agency may lease the space in any building that was subject to a lease terminated by a state agency for a period of time equal to the remainder of the base term without the requirement of competitive solicitation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop and implement a strategic leasing plan. The strategic leasing plan shall forecast space needs for all state agencies and identify opportunities for reducing costs through consolidation, relocation, reconfiguration, capital investment, and the building or acquisition of state-owned space.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall annually publish a master leasing report. The department shall furnish the master leasing report to the Executive Office of the Governor and the Legislature by September 15 of each year which provides the following information:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list, by agency and by geographic market, of all leases that are due to expire within 24 months.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Details of each lease, including location, size, cost per leased square foot, lease-expiration date, and a determination of whether sufficient state-owned office space will be available at the expiration of the lease to accommodate affected employees.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of amendments and supplements to and waivers of terms and conditions in lease agreements that have been approved pursuant to s. 255.25(2)(a) during the previous 12 months and an associated comprehensive analysis, including financial implications, showing that any amendment, supplement, or waiver is in the state’s long-term best interest.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial impacts to the pool rental rate due to the sale, removal, acquisition, or construction of pool facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes in occupancy rate, maintenance costs, and efficiency costs of leases in the state portfolio. Changes to occupancy costs in leased space by market and changes to space consumption by agency and by market.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An analysis of portfolio supply and demand.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cost-benefit analyses of acquisition, build, and consolidation opportunities, recommendations for strategic consolidation, and strategic recommendations for disposition, acquisition, and building.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The updated plan required by s. 255.25(4)(c).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By June 30 of each year, each state agency shall annually provide to the department all information regarding agency programs affecting the need for or use of space by that agency, reviews of lease-expiration schedules for each geographic area, active and planned full-time equivalent data, business case analyses related to consolidation plans by an agency, a telework program, and current occupancy and relocation costs, inclusive of furnishings, fixtures and equipment, data, and communications.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules pursuant to chapter 120 providing:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Methods for accomplishing the duties outlined in subsection (1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for soliciting and accepting competitive solicitations for leased space of 5,000 square feet or more in privately owned buildings, for evaluating the proposals received, for exemption from competitive solicitations requirements of any lease the purpose of which is the provision of care and living space for persons or emergency space needs as provided in s. 255.25(10), and for the securing of at least three documented quotes for a lease that is not required to be competitively solicited.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A standard method for determining square footage or any other measurement used as the basis for lease payments or other charges.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Methods of allocating space in both state-owned office buildings and privately owned buildings leased by the state based on use, personnel, and office equipment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acceptable terms and conditions for inclusion in lease agreements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such terms and conditions shall include, at a minimum, the following clauses, which may not be amended, supplemented, or waived:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As provided in s. 255.2502, “The State of Florida’s performance and obligation to pay under this contract is contingent upon an annual appropriation by the Legislature.”</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“The Lessee shall have the right to terminate, without penalty, this lease in the event a State-owned building becomes available to the Lessee for occupancy upon giving 6 months’ advance written notice to the Lessor by Certified Mail, Return Receipt Requested.”</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maximum rental rates, by geographic areas or by county, for leasing privately owned space.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A standard method for the assessment of rent to state agencies and other authorized occupants of state-owned office space, notwithstanding the source of funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For full disclosure of the names and the extent of interest of the owners holding a 4-percent or more interest in any privately owned property leased to the state or in the entity holding title to the property, for exemption from such disclosure of any beneficial interest which is represented by stock in any corporation registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission or registered pursuant to chapter 517, which stock is for sale to the general public, and for exemption from such disclosure of any leasehold interest in property located outside the territorial boundaries of the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For full disclosure of the names of all public officials, agents, or employees holding any interest in any privately owned property leased to the state or in the entity holding title to the property, and the nature and extent of their interest, for exemption from such disclosure of any beneficial interest which is represented by stock in any corporation registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission or registered pursuant to chapter 517, which stock is for sale to the general public, and for exemption from such disclosure of any leasehold interest in property located outside the territorial boundaries of the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method for reporting leases for nominal or no consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a lease of less than 5,000 square feet, a method for certification by the agency head or the agency head’s designated representative that all criteria for leasing have been fully complied with and for the filing of a copy of such lease and all supporting documents with the department for its review and approval as to technical sufficiency and whether it is in the best interests of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A standardized format for state agency reporting of the information required by paragraph (3)(d).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare a form listing all conditions and requirements adopted pursuant to this chapter which must be met by any state agency leasing any building or part thereof. Before executing any lease, this form shall be certified by the agency head or the agency head’s designated representative and submitted to the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may contract for real estate consulting or tenant brokerage services in order to carry out its duties relating to the strategic leasing plan. The contract shall be procured pursuant to s. 287.057. The vendor that is awarded the contract shall be compensated by the department, subject to the provisions of the contract, and such compensation is subject to appropriation by the Legislature. The real estate consultant or tenant broker may not receive compensation directly from a lessor for services that are rendered pursuant to the contract. Moneys paid by a lessor to the department under a facility-leasing arrangement are not subject to the charges imposed under s. 215.20.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 75-70; s. 2, ch. 78-166; s. 168, ch. 81-259; s. 34, ch. 85-349; s. 2, ch. 90-224; s. 148, ch. 95-148; s. 1, ch. 95-342; s. 11, ch. 98-279; s. 21, ch. 99-399; s. 2, ch. 2000-172; s. 19, ch. 2006-26; ss. 16, 17, 54, ch. 2007-73; s. 2, ch. 2007-220; s. 15, ch. 2008-227; s. 2, ch. 2009-77; s. 10, ch. 2010-151; s. 14, ch. 2012-215.</History>
</Section>