<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0657.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shares may be paid for and transferred in such manner as the bylaws prescribe. At such intervals and for such periods as the board of directors may authorize, and after provisions are made for the required reserves, the board of directors may declare dividends, to be paid from the undivided earnings at such rates and upon such classes of shares as are determined by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The credit union may require not more than 60 days’ notice of a member’s intention to withdraw shares and deposits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may receive deposits from its members and contract to pay interest thereon, subject to conditions the board of directors establishes and subject to rules of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The credit union shall have a lien and right of setoff on the shares, deposits, and accumulated dividends or interest in any member’s individual, joint, or trust account for any sum due the credit union from that member.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When there has not been any activity generated by the member on the account for 12 months, such account shall be considered a dormant account and shall be placed under an accounting control system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the owner of a dormant account, a person named on the account, or the beneficiary of the account has not had any activity with a credit union for 5 years and the whereabouts of those interested parties are unknown to the credit union, that account is unclaimed or abandoned property and shall be maintained pursuant to chapter 717.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may receive shares and deposits from its members and other credit unions; however, a credit union may not receive shares or deposits from persons, other than credit unions, who are not members of the credit union, except to a joint account in which at least one of the tenants is a member of the credit union.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may participate in systems that allow the transfer, withdrawal, or deposit of funds of credit unions or credit union members by automated or electronic means and hold membership in entities established to promote and effectuate these systems, if such participation is not inconsistent with those rules of the commission adopted to further service to the members and to protect members’ funds against unreasonable risks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union shall obtain and maintain insurance of accounts through the National Credit Union Administration.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 80-258; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 90, ch. 92-303; s. 1748, ch. 2003-261; s. 19, ch. 2005-181.</History></Section>