<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0657.066" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conversion from state credit union to federal credit union and conversely.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any credit union organized under this chapter may convert into a federal credit union and any federal credit union may convert into a credit union organized pursuant to this chapter upon approval of the authority under the supervision of which the converted credit union will operate and upon compliance with applicable laws.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action by the board of directors proposing conversion shall be by resolution and shall require the affirmative vote of an absolute majority of the board of directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors shall cause to be transmitted to the authority under the supervision of which the converted credit union will operate a copy of the resolution adopted by the board of directors and a conversion application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the written approval of the authority under the supervision of which the converting credit union is to operate, the converting credit union shall become a credit union under this chapter or under the laws of the United States, as the case may be, and thereupon all assets shall become the property of the converted credit union, subject to all existing liabilities against the credit union. All shares and deposits shall remain intact. Any federal credit union seeking to convert to a state-chartered credit union shall pay a nonrefundable filing fee of $500. The office may conduct an examination of any converting federal credit union before approving the conversion and the converting credit union shall pay a nonrefundable examination fee as provided in s. 655.411(1)(b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the approval of the authority under the supervision of which the converted credit union will operate, a copy of the resolution shall be provided to each member, together with a notice setting forth the time, location, and purpose of a meeting of the membership which shall be held not less than 10 or more than 30 days following the transmission of the notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A ballot allowing an affirmative or negative vote on the proposed conversion shall also be provided to each member. Any ballot received by the credit union prior to the meeting called to consider the conversion shall be counted along with the votes cast at the meeting. Each member shall have one vote. A majority of the votes cast by the members is required to approve the conversion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 days after the approval by the membership, the board of directors shall cause to be transmitted to the authority under the supervision of which the converted credit union will operate a copy of the resolution adopted by the board of directors and approved by the membership with confirmation of the vote.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every conversion must be completed within 90 days after the approval of the authority under the supervision of which the converted credit union will operate. Upon receiving its certificate of authorization or charter from the authority under the supervision of which the converted credit union will operate, the old certificate of authorization or charter shall be returned to the proper authority and shall be canceled.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In consummation of the conversion, the old credit union may execute, acknowledge, and deliver to the newly chartered credit union the instruments of transfer necessary to accomplish the transfer of any property and all right, title, and interest therein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 80-258; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 13, 46, ch. 82-214; s. 1, ch. 91-307; s. 1, ch. 92-303; s. 11, ch. 93-111; s. 1758, ch. 2003-261; s. 147, ch. 2004-5; s. 28, ch. 2005-181.</History></Section>