<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0657.005" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for authority to organize a credit union; investigation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed organizers of the proposed credit union shall file with the office an application, upon such form as the commission may, by rule, prescribe.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any five or more residents of this state who represent a limited field of membership may apply to the office for permission to organize a credit union. The fact that individuals within the proposed limited field of membership have credit union services available to them through another limited field of membership shall not preclude the granting of a certificate of authorization to engage in the business of a credit union.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be submitted to the office on forms and in the manner prescribed by rules adopted by the commission and shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable filing fee of $250. Such application shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed name and the proposed location where the proposed credit union is to have its principal place of business and where legal service must be served.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designation of the par value of each share of the credit union.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designation of at least five persons who agree to serve on the board of directors, and at least three other persons who agree to serve on the supervisory committee or audit committee, with a signed agreement to serve in these capacities until the first annual meeting or until the election of their successors, whichever is later, executed by those who so agree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information required by the commission or office to be submitted to the National Credit Union Administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bylaws of the credit union, which bylaws shall be in the form and substance as required by the commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall have the power of investigation to the extent necessary to make the finding required under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be approved if the office determines that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a showing of sufficient interest on the part of the proposed limited field of membership;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The qualifications of the proposed board of directors and committee members are such as to indicate a reasonable likelihood that the affairs of the proposed credit union will be administered consistently with applicable laws and sound financial and credit union practices;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization of the credit union would benefit its members; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited field of membership is of sufficient financial viability to indicate reasonable promise of successful operation of the proposed credit union. In determining the financial viability of the proposed limited field of membership and chances for reasonable promise of success of the proposed credit union, the office shall consider:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The size of the proposed limited field of membership, excluding potential members based upon familial relationships; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other evidence that tends to indicate the reasonable promise of success of the proposed credit union.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the organization of a proposed credit union would result in an overlapping limited field of membership, the office may disapprove the application if it finds that the formation of the proposed credit union will result in a substantial, adverse financial impact to an existing credit union having the same or substantially the same limited field of membership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Concurrently with submission of the application to the office, the applicant shall apply for insurance of accounts with the National Credit Union Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall not accept any payments for credit to share or deposit accounts, or commence business operations as a credit union, until the certificate of authorization and the insurance certificate have been delivered to the credit union.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall perform a preopening examination to verify good faith compliance with all the requirements of law. If the office finds that such requirements have been met, it shall issue and deliver the certificate of authorization to transact business. Any credit union which fails to open for business within 6 months after the issuance of such certificate will forfeit its existence as a credit union, and the certificate of authorization shall be revoked. For good cause shown, the office may extend the opening date for an additional 6 months on its own motion or at the request of the credit union.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All preopening costs and expenses in connection with the organization of the credit union and preparation for opening for business may be paid only from funds provided by the organizers or a sponsor. However, the credit union may record, as an operating expense, costs for forms, supplies, insurance, rent, and other expenses applicable to or consumed in the period after opening in accordance with rules adopted by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt and the office shall provide a form certificate of authorization and bylaws consistent with this chapter which shall be used by applicants for credit unions.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 80-258; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 12, 51, ch. 84-216; ss. 8, 58, ch. 85-82; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 79, ch. 92-303; s. 1741, ch. 2003-261; s. 8, ch. 2005-181.</History></Section>