<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0657.038" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Loan powers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may extend credit to members for such purpose and upon such security and terms as the credit committee, credit manager, or loan officer approves, pursuant to written loan policies established by the board of directors, or as may otherwise be provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For credit unions that have been opened for 5 years or more, the total unsecured obligations outstanding from any member must not exceed the greater of $500 or 15 percent of the equity of the credit union. However, the total obligations outstanding from any member must not exceed the greater of $1,000 or 25 percent of the equity of the credit union. The limitations provided in this subsection do not apply to loans that are fully secured by assignment of shares or deposits in the lending credit union.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For credit unions that have been opened for less than 5 years, the limitation on total obligations outstanding to any member is 10 percent of the credit union’s capital. The limitations provided in this subsection do not apply to loans that are fully secured by assignment of shares or deposits in the lending credit union.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The credit committee or credit manager may approve in advance, upon request of a member, a line of credit, and disbursements may be granted to such member within the limit of such line of credit. When a line of credit has been approved, no additional credit applications are required as long as the aggregate obligation does not exceed the limit of such line of credit; however, no additional disbursements may be made to any member whose existing extensions of credit are in default or are subject to adverse classification without receiving current financial information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loans secured by mortgages on real property must be made in accordance with written policies of the board of directors and rules of the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In computing a person’s total obligations outstanding, all loans endorsed or guaranteed as to repayment by that person and any related interest of such person must be included. The credit union must also include all of the person’s potential liabilities and obligations resulting from the person’s derivatives transactions, repurchase agreements, securities lending and borrowing transactions, credit default swaps, and similar contracts.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A loan may be made to any corporation in which the credit union holds an equity interest.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The loan limitations stated in this section shall not be enlarged by the provision of any other section of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any approval of extension of credit requiring approval of the board of directors shall be recorded in the minutes of the board, including the borrower’s account number or other code, the amount of the loan, the maturity of the loan, and the general type of security.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules to provide for minimum documentation and safe lending procedures necessary to protect the members’ funds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may participate in extensions of credit jointly with other credit unions, corporations, or financial institutions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may participate in guaranteed loan programs of the federal and state governments, provided the borrower is a member of the credit union.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If approved by the board of directors, a credit union may extend credit to other credit unions in an amount not greater than 25 percent of the capital of the lending credit union.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may purchase the conditional sales contracts, notes, and similar instruments of its members, provided that the credit union could have originally made the loan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A credit union may issue credit cards and debit cards to allow members to obtain access to their shares, deposits, and extensions of credit, if such issuance is not inconsistent with the rules of the commission. The commission may, by rule, allow the use of devices similar to credit cards and debit cards to allow members to obtain access to their shares, deposits, and extensions of credit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 80-258; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 16, 50, 51, ch. 84-216; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 91, ch. 92-303; s. 537, ch. 97-102; s. 1750, ch. 2003-261; s. 20, ch. 2005-181; s. 15, ch. 2011-194.</History>
</Section>