<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0402.281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gold Seal Quality Care program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established within the department the Gold Seal Quality Care Program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child care facility, large family child care home, or family day care home that is accredited by a nationally recognized accrediting association approved by the department under subsection (3) and meets all other requirements shall, upon application to the department, receive a separate “Gold Seal Quality Care” designation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing Gold Seal Quality Care accreditation standards based on the applicable accrediting standards of the National Association for the Education of Young Children (NAEYC), the National Association of Family Child Care, and the National Early Childhood Program Accreditation Commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to be approved by the department for participation in the Gold Seal Quality Care program, an accrediting association must apply to the department and demonstrate that it:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a nationally recognized accrediting association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has accrediting standards that substantially meet or exceed the Gold Seal Quality Care standards adopted by the department under subsection (2).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In approving accrediting associations, the department shall consult with the Department of Education, the Florida Head Start Directors Association, the Florida Association of Child Care Management, the Florida Family Day Care Association, the Florida Children’s Forum, the Early Childhood Association of Florida, the Child Development Education Alliance, providers receiving exemptions under s. 402.316, and parents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to obtain and maintain a designation as a Gold Seal Quality Care provider, a child care facility, large family child care home, or family day care home must meet the following additional criteria:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child care provider must not have had any class I violations, as defined by rule, within the 2 years preceding its application for designation as a Gold Seal Quality Care provider. Commission of a class I violation shall be grounds for termination of the designation as a Gold Seal Quality Care provider until the provider has no class I violations for a period of 2 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child care provider must not have had three or more class II violations, as defined by rule, within the 2 years preceding its application for designation as a Gold Seal Quality Care provider. Commission of three or more class II violations within a 2-year period shall be grounds for termination of the designation as a Gold Seal Quality Care provider until the provider has no class II violations for a period of 1 year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child care provider must not have been cited for the same class III violation, as defined by rule, three or more times and failed to correct the violation within 1 year after the date of each citation, within the 2 years preceding its application for designation as a Gold Seal Quality Care provider. Commission of the same class III violation three or more times and failure to correct within the required time during a 2-year period may be grounds for termination of the designation as a Gold Seal Quality Care provider until the provider has no class III violations for a period of 1 year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall adopt rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 which provide criteria and procedures for reviewing and approving accrediting associations for participation in the Gold Seal Quality Care program, conferring and revoking designations of Gold Seal Quality Care providers, and classifying violations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 72, ch. 96-175; s. 5, ch. 99-304; s. 17, ch. 2000-337; s. 26, ch. 2001-170; s. 1, ch. 2006-91; s. 7, ch. 2010-210; s. 1, ch. 2011-75; s. 282, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>