<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0402.3125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Display and appearance of license; posting of violations; information to be provided to parents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a license issued under s. 402.308 or s. 402.309, the child care facility shall display such license in a conspicuous place within the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to posting the license as required under paragraph (a), the child care facility shall post with the license:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each citation for a violation of any standard or requirement of ss. 402.301-402.319 that has resulted in disciplinary action under s. 402.310 or s. 402.312.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An explanation, written in simple language, of each citation.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description, written in simple language, of the corrective action, if any, taken by the facility for each citation. Included in the description shall be the dates on which the corrective action was taken.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each citation, explanation, and description of corrective action shall remain posted for 1 year after the citation’s effective date.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall ensure that every license it issues under s. 402.308 or s. 402.309 bears the distinctive seals of the State of Florida and of the department and is clearly recognizable by its size, color, seals, and contents to be a state license or provisional license for a child care facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local licensing agency shall ensure that every license it issues under s. 402.308 or s. 402.309 bears the distinctive seals of the issuing county and of the department and is clearly recognizable by its size, color, seals, and contents to be a county license or provisional license for a child care facility. Noncompliance by a local licensing agency shall be deemed by the department to be failure to meet minimum state standards and shall result in the department immediately assuming licensure authority in the county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any license issued pursuant to subsection (2) or subsection (3) shall include the name, address, and telephone number of the licensing agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a model brochure for distribution by the department and by local licensing agencies to every child care facility in the state. Pursuant thereto:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of such brochures, each child care facility shall provide a copy of same to every parent, guardian, or other person having entered a child in such facility. Thereafter, a copy of such brochure shall be provided to every parent, guardian, or other person entering a child in such facility upon entrance of the child or prior thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each child care facility shall certify to the department or local licensing agency, whichever is appropriate, that it has so provided and will continue to so provide such brochures, which certification shall operate as a condition upon issuance and renewal of licensure. Noncompliance by any child care facility shall be grounds for sanction as provided in ss. 402.310 and 402.312.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The brochure shall, at a minimum, contain the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the facility is licensed and has met state standards for licensure as established by s. 402.305 or that the facility is licensed by a local licensing agency and has met or exceeded the state standards, pursuant to ss. 402.306 and 402.307. Such statement shall include a listing of specific standards that licensed facilities must meet pursuant to s. 402.305.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement indicating that information about the licensure status of the child care facility can be obtained by telephoning the department office or the office of the local licensing agency issuing the license at a telephone number or numbers which shall be printed upon or otherwise affixed to the brochure.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statewide toll-free telephone number of the central abuse hotline, together with a notice that reports of suspected and actual cases of child physical abuse, sexual abuse, and neglect are received and referred for investigation by the hotline.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date that the current license for the facility was issued and the date of its scheduled expiration if it is not renewed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information relating to competent child care that the department deems would be helpful to parents and other caretakers in their selection of a child care facility.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare a brochure containing substantially the same information as specified in paragraph (c) and shall make such brochure available to all interested persons, including physicians and other health professionals; mental health professionals; school teachers or other school personnel; social workers or other professional child care, foster care, residential, or institutional workers; and law enforcement officers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 19, ch. 84-551; s. 43, ch. 87-225; s. 61, ch. 90-306; ss. 1, 2, ch. 93-115; s. 1, ch. 95-329; s. 95, ch. 2000-349.</History></Section>