<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0402.310" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary actions; hearings upon denial, suspension, or revocation of license or registration; administrative fines.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or local licensing agency may administer any of the following disciplinary sanctions for a violation of any provision of ss. 402.301-402.319, or the rules adopted thereunder:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose an administrative fine not to exceed $100 per violation, per day. However, if the violation could or does cause death or serious harm, the department or local licensing agency may impose an administrative fine, not to exceed $500 per violation per day in addition to or in lieu of any other disciplinary action imposed under this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Convert a license or registration to probation status and require the licensee or registrant to comply with the terms of probation. A probation-status license or registration may not be issued for a period that exceeds 6 months and the probation-status license or registration may not be renewed. A probation-status license or registration may be suspended or revoked if periodic inspection by the department or local licensing agency finds that the probation-status licensee or registrant is not in compliance with the terms of probation or that the probation-status licensee or registrant is not making sufficient progress toward compliance with ss. 402.301-402.319.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deny, suspend, or revoke a license or registration.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the appropriate disciplinary action to be taken for a violation as provided in paragraph (a), the following factors shall be considered:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The severity of the violation, including the probability that death or serious harm to the health or safety of any person will result or has resulted, the severity of the actual or potential harm, and the extent to which the provisions of ss. 402.301-402.319 have been violated.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken by the licensee or registrant to correct the violation or to remedy complaints.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous violations of the licensee or registrant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the grounds under which the department may deny, suspend, or revoke a license or registration or place a licensee or registrant on probation status for violations of ss. 402.301-402.319.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a uniform system of procedures to impose disciplinary sanctions for violations of ss. 402.301-402.319. The uniform system of procedures must provide for the consistent application of disciplinary actions across districts and a progressively increasing level of penalties from predisciplinary actions, such as efforts to assist licensees or registrants to correct the statutory or regulatory violations, and to severe disciplinary sanctions for actions that jeopardize the health and safety of children, such as for the deliberate misuse of medications. The department shall implement this subparagraph on January 1, 2007, and the implementation is not contingent upon a specific appropriation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disciplinary sanctions set forth in this section apply to licensed child care facilities, licensed large family child care homes, and licensed or registered family day care homes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department has reasonable cause to believe that grounds exist for the denial, suspension, or revocation of a license or registration; the conversion of a license or registration to probation status; or the imposition of an administrative fine, it shall determine the matter in accordance with procedures prescribed in chapter 120. When the local licensing agency has reasonable cause to believe that grounds exist for the denial, suspension, or revocation of a license or registration; the conversion of a license or registration to probation status; or the imposition of an administrative fine, it shall notify the applicant, registrant, or licensee in writing, stating the grounds upon which the license or registration is being denied, suspended, or revoked or an administrative fine is being imposed. If the applicant, registrant, or licensee makes no written request for a hearing to the local licensing agency within 15 days after receipt of the notice, the license shall be deemed denied, suspended, or revoked; the license or registration shall be converted to probation status; or an administrative fine shall be imposed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a request for a hearing is made to the local licensing agency, a hearing shall be held within 30 days and shall be conducted by an individual designated by the county commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant, registrant, or licensee shall have the right to appeal a decision of the local licensing agency to a representative of the department. Any required hearing shall be held in the county in which the child care facility, family day care home, or large family child care home is being operated or is to be established. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 74-113; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-117; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 19, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 6, 7, ch. 83-248; s. 9, ch. 84-551; s. 42, ch. 87-225; s. 37, ch. 90-306; ss. 1, 2, ch. 93-115; s. 24, ch. 2000-153; s. 3, ch. 2006-91.</History></Section>