<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0402.308" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL LICENSING.<EmDash />Every child care facility in the state shall have a license which shall be renewed annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHANGE OF OWNERSHIP.<EmDash />Every child care facility shall reapply for and receive a license prior to the time a new owner assumes responsibility for the facility. The department shall grant or deny the reapplication for license within 45 days from the date upon which the child care facility reapplies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATE ADMINISTRATION OF LICENSING.<EmDash />In any county in which the department has the authority to issue licenses, the following procedures shall be applied:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for a license or for a renewal of a license to operate a child care facility shall be made in the manner and on the forms prescribed by the department. The applicant’s social security number shall be included on the form submitted to the department. Pursuant to the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, each applicant is required to provide his or her social security number in accordance with this section. Disclosure of social security numbers obtained through this requirement shall be limited to the purpose of administration of the Title IV-D program for child support enforcement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the renewal of a license, the department shall reexamine the child care facility, including in that process the examination of the premises and those records of the facility as required under s. 402.305, to determine that minimum standards for licensing continue to be met.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall coordinate all inspections of child care facilities. A child care facility is not required to implement a recommendation of one agency that is in conflict with a recommendation of another agency if such conflict arises due to uncoordinated inspections. Any conflict in recommendations shall be resolved by the secretary of the department within 15 days after written notice that such conflict exists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue or renew a license upon receipt of the license fee and upon being satisfied that all standards required by ss. 402.301-402.319 have been met. A license may be issued if all the screening materials have been timely submitted; however, a license may not be issued or renewed if any of the child care personnel at the applicant facility have failed the screening required by ss. 402.305(2) and 402.3055.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOCAL ADMINISTRATION OF LICENSING.<EmDash />In any county in which there is a local licensing agency approved by the department, the following procedures shall apply:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for a license or for renewal of license to operate a child care facility shall be made in the manner and on the forms prescribed by the local licensing agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the renewal of a license, the agency shall reexamine the child care facility, including in that process the examination of the premises and records of the facility as required in s. 402.305 to determine that minimum standards for licensing continue to be met.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local agency shall coordinate all inspections of child care facilities. A child care facility is not required to implement a recommendation of one agency that is in conflict with a recommendation of another agency if such conflict arises due to uncoordinated inspections. Any conflict in recommendations shall be resolved by the county commission or its representative within 15 days after written notice that such conflict exists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local licensing agency shall issue a license or renew a license upon being satisfied that all standards required by ss. 402.301-402.319 have been met. A license may be issued or renewed if all the screening materials have been timely submitted; however, the local licensing agency shall not issue or renew a license if any of the child care personnel at the applicant facility have failed the screening required by ss. 402.305(2) and 402.3055.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ISSUANCE OF LOCAL OCCUPATIONAL LICENSES.<EmDash />No county or municipality shall issue an occupational license which is being obtained for the purpose of operating a child care facility regulated under this act without first ascertaining that the applicant has been licensed to operate such facility at the specified location or locations by the department or local licensing agency. The department or local licensing agency shall furnish to local agencies responsible for issuing occupational licenses sufficient instruction for making the above required determinations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 74-113; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 6, 7, ch. 83-248; s. 7, ch. 84-551; s. 26, ch. 85-54; s. 25, ch. 87-238; ss. 1, 2, ch. 93-115; s. 44, ch. 97-170; s. 225, ch. 99-13.</History></Section>