<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0402.312" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License required; injunctive relief.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation of a child care facility without a license, a family day care home without a license or registration, or a large family child care home without a license is prohibited. If the department or the local licensing agency discovers that a child care facility is being operated without a license, a family day care home is being operated without a license or registration, or a large family child care home is being operated without a license, the department or local licensing agency is authorized to seek an injunction in the circuit court where the facility is located to enjoin continued operation of such facility, family day care home, or large family child care home. When the court is closed for the transaction of judicial business, the department or local licensing agency is authorized to seek an emergency injunction to enjoin continued operation of such unlicensed facility, unregistered or unlicensed family day care home, or unlicensed large family child care home, which injunction shall be continued, modified, or revoked on the next day of judicial business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other grounds for seeking an injunction to close a child care facility, family day care home, or a large family child care home are that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is any violation of the standards applied under ss. 402.301-402.319 which threatens harm to any child in the child care facility, a family day care home, or large family child care home.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee or registrant has repeatedly violated the standards provided for under ss. 402.301-402.319.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child care facility, family day care home, or large family child care home continues to have children in attendance after the closing date established by the department or the local licensing agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or local licensing agency may impose an administrative fine on any child care facility, family day care home, or large family child care home operating without a license or registration, consistent with the provisions of s. 402.310.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 74-113; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 6, 7, ch. 83-248; s. 11, ch. 84-551; s. 61, ch. 90-306; ss. 1, 2, ch. 93-115; s. 2, ch. 2003-131.</History></Section>