<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0402.40" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Child welfare training and certification.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />In order to enable the state to provide a systematic approach to staff development and training for persons providing child welfare services that will meet the needs of such staff in their discharge of duties, it is the intent of the Legislature that the Department of Children and Family Services work in collaboration with the child welfare stakeholder community, including department-approved third-party credentialing entities, to ensure that staff have the knowledge, skills, and abilities necessary to competently provide child welfare services. It is the intent of the Legislature that each person providing child welfare services in this state earns and maintains a professional certification from a professional credentialing entity that is approved by the Department of Children and Family Services. The Legislature further intends that certification and training programs will aid in the reduction of poor staff morale and of staff turnover, will positively impact on the quality of decisions made regarding children and families who require assistance from programs providing child welfare services, and will afford better quality care of children who must be removed from their families.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child welfare certification” means a professional credential awarded by a department-approved third-party credentialing entity to individuals demonstrating core competency in any child welfare practice area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child welfare services” means any intake, protective investigations, preprotective services, protective services, foster care, shelter and group care, and adoption and related services program, including supportive services and supervision provided to children who are alleged to have been abused, abandoned, or neglected or who are at risk of becoming, are alleged to be, or have been found dependent pursuant to chapter 39.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Core competency” means the minimum knowledge, skills, and abilities necessary to carry out work responsibilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person providing child welfare services” means a person who has a responsibility for supervisory, direct care, or support-related work in the provision of child welfare services pursuant to chapter 39.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preservice curriculum” means the minimum statewide training content based upon the core competencies which is made available to all persons providing child welfare services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Third-party credentialing entity” means a department-approved nonprofit organization that has met nationally recognized standards for developing and administering professional certification programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THIRD-PARTY CREDENTIALING ENTITIES.<EmDash />The department shall approve one or more third-party credentialing entities for the purpose of developing and administering child welfare certification programs for persons who provide child welfare services. A third-party credentialing entity shall request such approval in writing from the department. In order to obtain approval, the third-party credentialing entity must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish professional requirements and standards that applicants must achieve in order to obtain a child welfare certification and to maintain such certification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and apply core competencies and examination instruments according to nationally recognized certification and psychometric standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a professional code of ethics and a disciplinary process that apply to all persons holding child welfare certification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a database, accessible to the public, of all persons holding child welfare certification, including any history of ethical violations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require annual continuing education for persons holding child welfare certification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer a continuing education provider program to ensure that only qualified providers offer continuing education opportunities for certificateholders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHILD WELFARE TRAINING TRUST FUND.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the State Treasury a Child Welfare Training Trust Fund to be used by the Department of Children and Family Services for the purpose of funding the professional development of persons providing child welfare services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One dollar from every noncriminal traffic infraction collected pursuant to s. 318.14(10)(b) or s. 318.18 shall be deposited into the Child Welfare Training Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the funds generated by paragraph (b), the trust fund shall receive funds generated from an additional fee on birth certificates and dissolution of marriage filings, as specified in ss. 382.0255 and 28.101, respectively, and may receive funds from any other public or private source.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds that are not expended by the end of the budget cycle or through a supplemental budget approved by the department shall revert to the trust fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CORE COMPETENCIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall approve the core competencies and related preservice curricula that ensures that each person delivering child welfare services obtains the knowledge, skills, and abilities to competently carry out his or her work responsibilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification of these core competencies and development of preservice curricula shall be a collaborative effort that includes professionals who have expertise in child welfare services, department-approved third-party credentialing entities, and providers that will be affected by the curriculum, including, but not limited to, representatives from the community-based care lead agencies, sheriffs’ offices conducting child protection investigations, and child welfare legal services providers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community-based care agencies, sheriffs’ offices, and the department may contract for the delivery of preservice and any additional training for persons delivering child welfare services if the curriculum satisfies the department-approved core competencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department-approved credentialing entities shall, for a period of at least 12 months after implementation of the third-party child welfare certification programs, grant reciprocity and award a child welfare certification to individuals who hold current department-issued child welfare certification in good standing, at no cost to the department or the certificateholder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADOPTION OF RULES.<EmDash />The Department of Children and Family Services shall adopt rules necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 105, 106, ch. 86-220; s. 4, ch. 87-108; s. 68, ch. 91-221; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 79, ch. 95-143; s. 815, ch. 95-148; s. 83, ch. 96-175; s. 111, ch. 97-237; s. 150, ch. 99-8; ss. 40, 60, ch. 2000-139; s. 89, ch. 2000-165; s. 28, ch. 2001-89; s. 4, ch. 2003-146; s. 8, ch. 2006-296; s. 110, ch. 2010-102; s. 31, ch. 2010-151; s. 1, ch. 2011-163.</History>
</Section>