<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0569.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Posting of a sign stating that the sale of tobacco products to persons under 18 years of age is unlawful; enforcement; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dealer that sells tobacco products shall post a clear and conspicuous sign in each place of business where such products are sold which substantially states the following:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">THE SALE OF TOBACCO PRODUCTS TO PERSONS UNDER THE AGE OF 18 IS AGAINST FLORIDA LAW. PROOF OF AGE IS REQUIRED FOR PURCHASE.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall make available to dealers of tobacco products signs that meet the requirements of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dealer that sells tobacco products shall provide at the checkout counter in a location clearly visible to the dealer, the dealer’s agent or employee, instructional material in a calendar format or similar format to assist in determining whether a person is of legal age to purchase tobacco products. This point of sale material must contain substantially the following language:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">IF YOU WERE NOT BORN BEFORE THIS DATE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">(insert date and applicable year)</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">YOU CANNOT BUY TOBACCO PRODUCTS.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Upon approval by the division, in lieu of a calendar a dealer may use card readers, scanners, or other electronic or automated systems that can verify whether a person is of legal age to purchase tobacco products. Failure to comply with the provisions contained in this subsection shall result in imposition of administrative penalties as provided in s. 569.006.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division, through its agents and inspectors, shall enforce this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to comply with subsection (1) is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 89-259; s. 12, ch. 92-285; s. 252, ch. 94-218; s. 10, ch. 97-162.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 859.061.</Text></Note></Section>