<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0569.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction; tobacco product enforcement officers or agents; enforcement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, any law enforcement officer certified under s. 943.10(1), (6), or (8) shall enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county or municipality may designate certain of its employees or agents as tobacco product enforcement officers. The training and qualifications of the employees or agents for such designation shall be determined by the county or the municipality. Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the carrying of firearms or other weapons by a tobacco product enforcement agent, nor does designation as a tobacco product enforcement officer provide the employee or agent with the power of arrest or subject the employee or agent to the provisions of ss. 943.085-943.255. Nothing in this section amends, alters, or contravenes the provisions of any state-administered retirement system or any state-supported retirement system established by general law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tobacco product enforcement officer is authorized to issue a citation to a person under the age of 18 when, based upon personal investigation, the officer has reasonable cause to believe that the person has committed a civil infraction in violation of s. 386.212 or s. 569.11.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A correctional probation officer as defined in s. 943.10(3) is authorized to issue a citation to a person under the age of 18 when, based upon personal investigation, the officer has reasonable cause to believe that the person has committed a civil infraction in violation of s. 569.11.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A citation issued to any person violating the provisions of s. 569.11 shall be in a form prescribed by the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation and shall contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and time of issuance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person to whom the citation is issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and time the civil infraction was committed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facts constituting reasonable cause.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of the Florida statute violated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and authority of the citing officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedure for the person to follow in order to contest the citation, perform the required community service, attend the required anti-tobacco program, or to pay the civil penalty.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 97-162.</History></Section>