<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0569.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” is synonymous with the term “retail tobacco products dealer.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permit” is synonymous with the term “retail tobacco products dealer permit.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail tobacco products dealer” means the holder of a retail tobacco products dealer permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail tobacco products dealer permit” means a permit issued by the division pursuant to s. 569.003.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tobacco products” includes loose tobacco leaves, and products made from tobacco leaves, in whole or in part, and cigarette wrappers, which can be used for smoking, sniffing, or chewing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Any person under the age of 18” does not include any person under the age of 18 who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has had his or her disability of nonage removed under chapter 743;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in the military reserve or on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is otherwise emancipated by a court of competent jurisdiction and released from parental care and responsibility; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is acting in his or her scope of lawful employment with an entity licensed under the provisions of chapter 210 or this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 92-285; s. 222, ch. 94-218; s. 4, ch. 97-162; s. 1, ch. 98-172.</History></Section>