<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0567.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Results of election.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of those legally voting at any election under s. 567.01 cast their votes “Against Selling Intoxicating Liquors, Wines, or Beer” on question number 1, then no intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer shall be sold in the county in which the election was held until otherwise determined by an election, which shall not be held oftener than once in every 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of those legally voting at any such election cast their votes “For Selling Intoxicating Liquors, Wines, or Beer” on question number 1 and a majority of votes legally cast on question number 2 be cast “For Sales by the Package Only,” then:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer shall be sold in said county that are not contained in sealed containers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer shall be consumed in said county on the premises where such intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer are sold or on any other premise under the control, either directly or indirectly, of the licensee, until otherwise determined in an election, which shall not be held oftener than once in every 2 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the expiration of 2 years, an election pursuant to s. 567.01(2)(b) may be held to determine the sole question of whether intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer may be sold by the drink for consumption on premises. If a majority of those legally voting cast their votes for selling intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer by the drink for consumption on premises, such alcoholic beverages may be sold as otherwise provided by law in that county until otherwise determined in an election, which shall not be held oftener than once every 2 years. If a majority of those legally voting cast their vote against the sale of intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer by the drink for consumption on premises, sales by the package only shall continue.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event a majority of those legally voting in any such election cast their vote “For Selling Intoxicating Liquors, Wines, or Beer” on question number 1 and a majority of the votes legally cast on question number 2 be not cast “For Sales by the Package Only,” then intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer may be sold as otherwise provided by law in said county until otherwise determined in an election, which shall not be held oftener than once in every 2 years.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 3700, 1887; RS 863; GS 1215; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(202); s. 3, ch. 23747, 1947; s. 11, ch. 25035, 1949; s. 3, ch. 85-161; s. 3, ch. 99-380; s. 69, ch. 2000-154.</History></Section>