<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0567.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Form of ballot; canvassing votes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the election under s. 567.01, the ballot used shall be printed on one side of a plain white piece of paper in the form following:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">OFFICIAL BALLOT NO.<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> 
<HorizontalRule Type="Full" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">OFFICIAL BALLOT NO.<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> 
<HorizontalRule Type="Full" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">OFFICIAL ELECTION BALLOT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Month)</Directions>, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Day)</Directions>, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Year)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">PRECINCT NUMBER <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">INSTRUCTIONS: Local Option Election on</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">TWO QUESTIONS:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">QUESTION NUMBER 1 is to decide whether the sale of intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer containing more than 6.243 percent of alcohol by volume shall be prohibited or permitted in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">QUESTION NUMBER 2 is to decide whether the sale of intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer shall be restricted to sales made in sealed containers, for consumption off the premises where sold, such sales being described as “Sales by the package.” The results on question number 2 shall be effective and binding only in the event a majority of those voting at the election shall cast their votes “For Selling Intoxicating Liquors, Wines, or Beer” containing more than 6.243 percent of alcohol by volume on question number 1.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Vote on both questions!</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">If you fail to vote on question number 1, your vote on question number 2 will not be counted!</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">To vote, make a crossmark (X) at the right of your choice on each question:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">QUESTION NO. 1:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For Selling Intoxicating Liquors,</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Wines, or Beer containing more than 6.243 percent of alcohol by volume<FlushRight />☐  </Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Against Selling Intoxicating Liquors,</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Wines, or Beer containing more than 6.243 percent of alcohol by volume<FlushRight />☐  </Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">QUESTION NO. 2:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For Sales by the Package and Drink<FlushRight />☐  </Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For Sales by the Package Only<FlushRight />☐  </Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No vote on question number 2 shall be counted or considered in determining the results on said question unless the elector casting said vote shall have voted also upon question number 1; provided that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a majority of those legally voting at said election cast their votes on question number 1, the vote of said majority shall be determinative of said question and the votes cast on question number 2 shall in no way affect or nullify the result of the vote on question number 1; provided that</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of votes legally cast on question number 2 shall be determinative of said question and the number of votes cast on question number 1 shall in no way affect or nullify the result of the vote on question number 2 unless a majority of the votes legally cast at said election shall be “Against Selling Intoxicating Liquors, Wines, or Beer”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provided, further, that voting machines may be used in counties which have adopted voting machines for use in general elections.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, for a local option election authorized by s. 567.01(2)(b) on the sole question of whether intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer may be sold by the drink for consumption on premises, ballot instructions shall be presented in the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">INSTRUCTIONS: Local Option Election on the Following Question:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">THE QUESTION BEFORE THE ELECTORATE is to decide whether intoxicating liquors, wines, or beer, containing more than 6.243 percent of alcohol by volume, may be sold by the drink for consumption on premises in (   ) County, Florida.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true"> For Sales by the Drink:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">followed by the word “yes” and also by the word “no,” and shall be styled in such a manner that a “yes” vote will indicate approval of the question and a “no” vote will indicate rejection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 3700, 1887; RS 862; GS 1214; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(201); s. 2, ch. 23747, 1947; s. 2, ch. 85-161; s. 8, ch. 93-134; s. 2, ch. 99-380.</History></Section>