<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.730" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Merger with intermediate holding company.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mutual insurance holding company may, pursuant to a plan and agreement of merger approved by the office, in accordance with s. 628.715(2)(b), merge into its intermediate holding company. The surviving intermediate holding company shall assume all of the assets and liabilities of the mutual insurance holding company, and all of the stock of the intermediate holding company owned by the mutual insurance holding company immediately prior to the merger shall be distributed to existing persons who were members of the mutual insurance holding company at any time within the 3-year period preceding the date of such merger.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The distributive share of each such member shall be determined:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For domestic mutual insurance holding companies owning solely life and health insurance subsidiaries, by a formula based upon such reasonable classifications of members as the office may approve.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all other domestic insurance holding companies, based upon the ratio that the total amount of paid premiums paid by such member for policies of insurance during the 3-year period or part of such period preceding the date of such merger during which such recipient was a member bears to the total amount of paid premiums paid by all members entitled to receive a distributive share as a result of such merger during such entire 3-year period and upon such reasonable classifications of members as the department may approve, unless the domestic mutual insurance holding company submits another fair formula that is approved by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of creating a public market for the shares of the intermediate holding company, the mutual insurance holding company may, immediately prior to the merger, sell or cause the intermediate holding company to sell to the public up to 25 percent of its capital stock representing no more than 25 percent of the voting stock of the intermediate holding company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall hold a public hearing to allow public comment on the plan and agreement of merger. The hearing must be held within 90 days after receipt of the office of the proposed plan and agreement of merger.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan and agreement of merger shall be submitted to the members of the mutual holding company for their approval and shall take effect only if approved by a majority of the members of the mutual insurance holding company who vote either in person or by proxy on such merger at a meeting called for the purpose of voting on such merger, pursuant to reasonable notice and procedures as approved by the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2000-273; s. 5, ch. 2003-76; s. 1307, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>