<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Incorporation of domestic insurer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five or more individuals, none of whom is less than 18 years of age, may incorporate a stock insurer; 10 or more individuals, none of whom is less than 18 years of age, may incorporate a mutual insurer. At least a majority of the incorporators shall be citizens of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The incorporators shall execute articles of incorporation in triplicate. At least three of them shall acknowledge execution before an officer authorized to take acknowledgments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation shall state the purpose for which the corporation is formed and shall state and show:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration of its existence, which may be perpetual.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The kinds of insurance which the corporation is formed to transact.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a stock corporation, its authorized capital stock, the number of shares of stock into which divided, and the par value of each such share, which par value shall be at least $1 but not more than $100.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a mutual corporation, the maximum contingent liability of its members, other than as to nonassessable policies, for payment of losses and expenses incurred; such liability shall be as stated in the articles of incorporation but shall not be less than 3 nor more than 10 times the premium for the member’s policy at the annual premium rate for a term of 1 year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of directors, not less than five, who shall constitute the board of directors and conduct the affairs of the corporation. The term of office of initial directors shall not be for more than 1 year after the date of incorporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the county, and the city, town, or place within the county, in which its principal office or principal place of business is to be located in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other provisions, not inconsistent with law, deemed appropriate by the incorporators.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and residence address of each incorporator and the citizenship of each incorporator who is not a citizen of the United States.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 628, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 58, ch. 77-121; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 637, 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 68, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>