<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.431" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mutualization of stock insurers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A stock insurer other than a title insurer may become a mutual insurer under such plan and procedure as may be approved by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall not approve any such plan, procedure, or mutualization unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is equitable to stockholders and policyholders;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is subject to approval by the holders of not less than three-fourths of the insurer’s outstanding capital stock having voting rights and by not less than two-thirds of the insurer’s policyholders who vote on such plan in person, by proxy, or by mail pursuant to such notice and procedure as may be approved by the office;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a life insurer, the right to vote thereon is limited to holders of policies other than term or group policies, and whose policies have been in force for more than 1 year;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mutualization will result in retirement of shares of the insurer’s capital stock at a price not in excess of the fair market value thereof as determined by competent disinterested appraisers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan provides for the purchase of the shares of any nonconsenting stockholder in the same manner and subject to the same applicable conditions as provided by <Reference Number="1" />s. 607.247, as to rights of nonconsenting stockholders, with respect to consolidation or merger of private corporations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan provides for definite conditions to be fulfilled by a designated early date upon which such mutualization will be deemed effective; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mutualization leaves the insurer with surplus funds reasonably adequate for the security of its policyholders and to enable it to continue successfully in business in the states in which it is then authorized to transact insurance, and for the kinds of insurance included in its certificates of authority in such states.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to mutualization under order of court pursuant to rehabilitation or reorganization of an insurer under chapter 631.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 663, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; s. 12, ch. 79-9; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1280, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 189, ch. 90-179.</Text></Note></Section>