<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.471" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mergers; mutual insurers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A domestic mutual insurer shall not merge with a stock insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A domestic mutual insurer may merge with another mutual insurer under the applicable procedures prescribed by the statutes of this state applying to corporations formed for profit, except as hereinbelow provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan and agreement for merger shall be submitted to and approved by at least two-thirds of the members of each mutual insurer voting thereon at meetings called for the purpose pursuant to such reasonable notice and procedure as has been approved by the office. If a life insurer, the right to vote may be limited to members whose policies are other than term and group policies and have been in effect for more than 1 year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No such merger shall be effectuated unless in advance thereof the plan and agreement therefor have been filed with the office and approved by it. The office shall give such approval unless it finds such plan or agreement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is inequitable to the policyholders of any domestic insurer involved; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Would substantially reduce the security of and service to be rendered to policyholders of the domestic insurer in this state and elsewhere.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 667, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 74, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1285, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>