<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0628.906" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application requirements; restrictions on eligibility of officers and directors.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To evidence competence and trustworthiness of its officers and directors, the application for a license to act as a captive insurance company or captive reinsurance company shall include, but not be limited to, background investigations, biographical affidavits, and fingerprint cards for all officers and directors. Fingerprints must be taken by a law enforcement agency or other entity approved by the office, be accompanied by the fingerprint processing fee specified in s. 624.501, and processed in accordance with s. 624.34.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may deny, suspend, or revoke the license to transact captive insurance or captive reinsurance in this state if any person who was an officer or director of an insurer, reinsurer, captive insurance company, captive reinsurance company, financial institution, or financial services business doing business in the United States, any state, or under the law of any other country and who served in that capacity within the 2-year period prior to the date the insurer, reinsurer, captive insurance company, captive reinsurance company, financial institution, or financial services business became insolvent, serves as an officer or director of a captive insurance company or officer or director of a captive reinsurance company licensed in this state unless the officer or director demonstrates that his or her personal actions or omissions were not a contributing cause to the insolvency or unless the officer or director is immediately removed from the captive insurance company or captive reinsurance company.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may deny, suspend, or revoke the license to transact insurance or reinsurance in this state of a captive insurance company or captive reinsurance company if any officer or director, any stockholder that owns 10 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities of the captive insurance company or captive reinsurance company, or incorporator has been found guilty of, or has pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to, any felony or crime involving moral turpitude, including a crime of dishonesty or breach of trust, punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of the United States or any state thereof or under the law of any other country without regard to whether a judgment of conviction has been entered by the court having jurisdiction in such case. However, in the case of a captive insurance company or captive reinsurance company operating under a subsisting license, the captive insurance company or captive reinsurance company shall remove any such person immediately upon discovery of the conditions set forth in this subsection when applicable to such person or upon the order of the office, and the failure to so act shall be grounds for revocation or suspension of the captive insurance company’s or captive reinsurance company’s license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 2012-151.</History>
</Section>