<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.231" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The affairs of every domestic insurer shall be managed by not less than five directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directors must be elected by the members or stockholders of a domestic insurer at the annual meeting of stockholders or members. Directors may be elected for terms of not more than 3 years each and until their successors are elected and have qualified; and, if to be elected for terms of more than 1 year, the insurer’s bylaws shall provide for a staggered-terms system under which the terms of a proportionate part of the members of the board of directors will expire on the date of each annual meeting of stockholders or members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the directors must be citizens of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If so provided in a stock insurer’s bylaws, a director of such stock insurer shall be a stockholder thereof; and, if so provided in a mutual insurer’s bylaws, a director of such mutual insurer shall be a policyholder thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In discharging his or her duties, a director may consider such factors as the directors deem relevant, including, but not limited to, the long-term prospects and interests of the corporation and its shareholders, the social, economic, legal, or other effects of any action on the employees, suppliers, or policyholders of the corporation or its subsidiaries, the communities and society in which the corporation or its subsidiaries operate, and the economy of the state and the nation. The director may also consider the short-term and long-term interests of the insurer, including, but not limited to, benefits that may accrue to the insured from the insurer’s long-term plans, the possibility that such interests may be best served by the continued independence of the insurer, the resources, intent, and past, present, and potential conduct of any person seeking to acquire control of the insurer, and any other relevant factors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 643, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 651, 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 2000-273.</History></Section>