<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assessment of stockholders or members.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurer receiving the notice of the office mentioned in s. 628.411(1):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a stock insurer, by resolution of its board of directors and subject to any limitations upon assessment contained in its certificate of incorporation, may assess its stockholders for amounts necessary to cure the deficiency and provide the insurer with a reasonable amount of surplus in addition. If any stockholder fails to pay a lawful assessment after notice given to him or her in person or by advertisement in such time and manner as approved by the office, the insurer may require the return of the original certificate of stock held by the stockholder and, in cancellation and in lieu thereof, issue a new certificate for such number of shares as the stockholder may then be entitled to, upon the basis of the stockholder’s proportionate interest in the amount of the insurer’s capital stock as determined by the office to be remaining at the time of determination of the amount of impairment under s. 628.411, after deducting from such proportionate interest the amount of such unpaid assessment. The insurer may pay for or issue fractional shares under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a mutual insurer, shall levy such an assessment upon members as is provided for under <Reference Number="1" />s. 628.321.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither this section nor s. 628.411 shall be deemed to prohibit the insurer from curing any such deficiency through any lawful means other than those referred to in such sections.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 662, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 383, ch. 97-102; s. 1279, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 185, ch. 91-108.</Text></Note></Section>