<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amendment of articles of incorporation; mutual insurer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A domestic mutual insurer may amend its articles of incorporation by vote of a majority of those members present or represented by proxy at a lawful meeting of its members, if the notice given members included due notice of the proposal to amend.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon adoption of the amendment, the insurer shall make in triplicate under its corporate seal a certificate thereof, setting forth the amendment and the date and manner of the adoption thereof, which certificate shall be executed by the insurer’s president or vice president and secretary or assistant secretary and acknowledged before an officer authorized to take acknowledgments. The insurer shall deliver the triplicate originals of the certificate to the office, together with the filing fee specified in s. 624.501.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall promptly examine the certificate of amendment; and, if it finds that the certificate and the amendment comply with law, it shall endorse its approval upon each of the triplicate originals, place one on file in its office, and return the remaining sets to the insurer. The insurer shall forthwith file such endorsed certificates of amendment with the Department of State. The amendment shall be effective when filed with and approved by the Department of State.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the office finds that the proposed amendment or certificate does not comply with the law, it shall not approve the same, and shall return the triplicate certificate of amendment to the insurer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 631, ch. 59-205; ss. 10, 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 640, 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1263, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>