<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.291" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unauthorized transactions in other states.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No domestic insurer shall enter into a contract of insurance upon the life or person of a resident of a reciprocal state or covering property or risks located in a reciprocal state, unless the insurer is authorized pursuant to the laws of such reciprocal state to do business therein, subject to the following exceptions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracts entered into when the prospective insured is personally present and signs the application in the state in which the insurer is authorized to do business;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of certificates under any lawfully transacted group life or group health policy if the master policy is entered into in a state in which the insurer is authorized to do business;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracts made pursuant to a pension or retirement plan of an employer when such contracts are applied for in a state where the employer is personally present or doing business and the insurer is authorized to do business; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The renewal, reinstatement, conversion, or continuance in force with or without modification of contracts otherwise lawfully entered into and which were not originally entered into in violation of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “reciprocal state” as used in this section means a state the laws of which prohibit an insurer organized under the laws of that state from insuring the lives or property of persons resident or located in this state, unless such insurer is authorized pursuant to the laws of this state to do business in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 649, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 658, 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; s. 5, ch. 90-248; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>