<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0628.491" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mergers and consolidations; mutual insurers; agreement of bulk reinsurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A domestic mutual insurer may reinsure all or substantially all its business in force, or all or substantially all of a major class thereof, with another insurer, stock or mutual, by an agreement of bulk reinsurance after compliance with this section. No such agreement shall become effective unless filed with the office and approved by it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall approve such agreement if it finds it to be fair and equitable to each domestic insurer involved, and that such reinsurance if effectuated would not substantially reduce the protection or service to its policyholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan and agreement for such reinsurance must be approved by vote of not less than two-thirds of each domestic mutual insurer’s members voting thereon at meetings of members called for the purpose, pursuant to such reasonable notice and procedure as the office may approve. If a life insurer, the right to vote may be limited to members whose policies are other than term or group policies and have been in effect for more than 1 year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If for reinsurance of a mutual insurer in a stock insurer, the agreement must provide for payment in cash to each member of the insurer entitled thereto, as upon conversion of such insurer pursuant to s. 628.441, of his or her equity in the business reinsured as determined under a fair formula approved by the office, which equity shall be based upon such member’s equity in the reserves, assets (whether or not admitted assets), and surplus, if any, of the mutual insurer to be taken over by the stock insurer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 669, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 665, 809(1st), ch. 82-243; ss. 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 385, ch. 97-102; s. 1287, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>