<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0202.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Communications services” means the transmission, conveyance, or routing of voice, data, audio, video, or any other information or signals, including video services, to a point, or between or among points, by or through any electronic, radio, satellite, cable, optical, microwave, or other medium or method now in existence or hereafter devised, regardless of the protocol used for such transmission or conveyance. The term includes such transmission, conveyance, or routing in which computer processing applications are used to act on the form, code, or protocol of the content for purposes of transmission, conveyance, or routing without regard to whether such service is referred to as voice-over-Internet-protocol services or is classified by the Federal Communications Commission as enhanced or value-added. The term does not include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Installation or maintenance of wiring or equipment on a customer’s premises.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale or rental of tangible personal property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of advertising, including, but not limited to, directory advertising.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bad check charges.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Late payment charges.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Billing and collection services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Internet access service, electronic mail service, electronic bulletin board service, or similar online computer services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” means a person registered with the department as a provider of communications services in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Revenue.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct-to-home satellite service” has the meaning ascribed in the Communications Act of 1934, 47 U.S.C. s. 303(v).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Information service” means the offering of a capability for generating, acquiring, storing, transforming, processing, retrieving, using, or making available information via communications services, including, but not limited to, electronic publishing, web-hosting service, and end-user 900 number service. The term does not include video service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Internet access service” has the same meaning as ascribed to the term “Internet access” by s. 1105(5) of the Internet Tax Freedom Act, 47 U.S.C. s. 151 note, as amended by Pub. L. No. 110-108.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mobile communications service” means commercial mobile radio service, as defined in 47 C.F.R. s. 20.3 as in effect on June 1, 1999. The term does not include air-ground radiotelephone service as defined in 47 C.F.R. s. 22.99 as in effect on June 1, 1999.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” has the meaning ascribed in s. 212.02.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prepaid calling arrangement” means the separately stated retail sale by advance payment of communications services that consist exclusively of telephone calls originated by using an access number, authorization code, or other means that may be manually, electronically, or otherwise entered and that are sold in predetermined units or dollars of which the number declines with use in a known amount.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Purchaser” means the person paying for or obligated to pay for communications services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail sale” means the sale of communications services for any purpose other than for resale or for use as a component part of or for integration into communications services to be resold in the ordinary course of business. However, any sale for resale must comply with s. 202.16(2) and the rules adopted thereunder.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sale” means the provision of communications services for a consideration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sales price” means the total amount charged in money or other consideration by a dealer for the sale of the right or privilege of using communications services in this state, including any property or other service, not described in paragraph (a), which is part of the sale and for which the charge is not separately itemized on a customer’s bill or separately allocated under subparagraph (b)8. The sales price of communications services may not be reduced by any separately identified components of the charge which constitute expenses of the dealer, including, but not limited to, sales taxes on goods or services purchased by the dealer, property taxes, taxes measured by net income, and universal-service fund fees.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sales price of communications services includes, whether or not separately stated, charges for any of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The connection, movement, change, or termination of communications services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The detailed billing of communications services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of directory listings in connection with a communications service.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Central office and custom calling features.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Voice mail and other messaging service.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directory assistance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service of sending or receiving a document commonly referred to as a facsimile or “fax,” except when performed during the course of providing professional or advertising services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sales price of communications services does not include charges for any of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An excise tax, sales tax, or similar tax levied by the United States or any state or local government on the purchase, sale, use, or consumption of any communications service, including, but not limited to, a tax imposed under this chapter or chapter 203 which is permitted or required to be added to the sales price of such service, if the tax is stated separately.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fee or assessment levied by the United States or any state or local government, including, but not limited to, regulatory fees and emergency telephone surcharges, which must be added to the price of the service if the fee or assessment is separately stated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Communications services paid for by inserting coins into coin-operated communications devices available to the public.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale or recharge of a prepaid calling arrangement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of air-to-ground communications services, defined as a radio service provided to a purchaser while on board an aircraft.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer’s internal use of communications services in connection with its business of providing communications services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Charges for property or other services that are not part of the sale of communications services, if such charges are stated separately from the charges for communications services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Charges for goods or services that are not subject to tax under this chapter, including Internet access services but excluding any item described in paragraph (a), that are not separately itemized on a customer’s bill, but that can be reasonably identified from the selling dealer’s books and records kept in the regular course of business. The dealer may support the allocation of charges with books and records kept in the regular course of business covering the dealer’s entire service area, including territories outside this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service address” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of the communications equipment from which communications services originate or at which communications services are received by the customer;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a communications service paid through a credit or payment mechanism that does not relate to a service address, such as a bank, travel, debit, or credit card, and in the case of third-number and calling-card calls, the term “service address” means the address of the central office, as determined by the area code and the first three digits of the seven-digit originating telephone number; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the location of the equipment described in subparagraph 1. is not known and subparagraph 2. is inapplicable, the term “service address” means the location of the customer’s primary use of the communications service. For purposes of this subparagraph, the location of the customer’s primary use of a communications service is the residential street address or the business street address of the customer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of video services and direct-to-home satellite services, the location where the customer receives the services in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of mobile communications services, the customer’s place of primary use.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unbundled network element” means a network element, as defined in 47 U.S.C. s. 153(29), to which access is provided on an unbundled basis pursuant to 47 U.S.C. s. 251(c)(3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private communications service” means a communications service that entitles the subscriber or user to exclusive or priority use of a communications channel or group of channels between or among channel termination points, regardless of the manner in which such channel or channels are connected, and includes switching capacity, extension lines, stations, and any other associated services that are provided in connection with the use of such channel or channels.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Customer” means:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person or entity that contracts with the home service provider for mobile communications services; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the end user of mobile communications services is not the contracting party, the end user of the mobile communications service. This subparagraph only applies for the purpose of determining the place of primary use.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Customer” does not include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reseller of mobile communications services; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A serving carrier under an agreement to serve the customer outside the home service provider’s licensed service area.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enhanced zip code” means a United States postal zip code of 9 or more digits.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home service provider” means the facilities-based carrier or reseller with which the customer contracts for the provision of mobile communications services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed service area” means the geographic area in which the home service provider is authorized by law or contract to provide mobile communications service to the customer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Place of primary use” means the street address representative of where the customer’s use of the mobile communications service primarily occurs, which must be:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The residential street address or the primary business street address of the customer; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within the licensed service area of the home service provider.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reseller” means a provider who purchases communications services from another communications service provider and then resells, uses as a component part of, or integrates the purchased services into a mobile communications service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reseller” does not include a serving carrier with which a home service provider arranges for the services to its customers outside the home service provider’s licensed service area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Serving carrier” means a facilities-based carrier providing mobile communications service to a customer outside a home service provider’s or reseller’s licensed service area.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Video service” means the transmission of video, audio, or other programming service to a purchaser, and the purchaser interaction, if any, required for the selection or use of a programming service, regardless of whether the programming is transmitted over facilities owned or operated by the video service provider or over facilities owned or operated by another dealer of communications services. The term includes point-to-point and point-to-multipoint distribution services through which programming is transmitted or broadcast by microwave or other equipment directly to the purchaser’s premises, but does not include direct-to-home satellite service. The term includes basic, extended, premium, pay-per-view, digital video, two-way cable, and music services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 58, ch. 2000-260; ss. 2, 38, ch. 2001-140; s. 1, ch. 2003-254; ss. 1, 14, ch. 2005-187; s. 6, ch. 2005-280; s. 3, ch. 2007-29; s. 2, ch. 2012-70.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve">Section 11, ch. 2012-70, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“The following changes made in this act are intended to be remedial in nature and apply retroactively, but do not provide a basis for an assessment of any tax not paid or create a right to a refund or credit of any tax paid before the general effective date of this act:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The changes made in section 2 of this act to subsection (13) of s. 202.11, Florida Statutes.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The changes made in section 6 of this act to s. 202.22, Florida Statutes.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>