<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0202.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person seeking to engage in business as a dealer of communications services must file with the department an application for a certificate of registration. Registration under this section does not constitute registration with a municipality or county for the purpose of placing and maintaining communications facilities in municipal or county rights-of-way, as described in s. 337.401.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not engage in the business of providing communications services without first obtaining a certificate of registration. The failure or refusal to submit an application by any person required to register, as required by this section, is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Any person who fails or refuses to register shall pay an initial registration fee of $100. However, this fee may be waived by the department if the failure is due to reasonable cause.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a certificate of registration must be completed by the dealer of communications services before engaging in business. The application for a certificate of registration must contain the information required by rule of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, upon receipt of a completed application, shall grant to the applicant a certificate of registration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application required by paragraph (3)(a) must set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name under which the person will transact business within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of his or her principal office or place of business within this state and of the location where records are available for inspection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and complete residence address of the owner or the names and residence addresses of the partners, if the applicant is a partnership, or of the principal officers, if the applicant is a corporation or association. If the applicant is a corporation organized under the laws of another state, territory, or country, he or she must also file with the application a certified copy of the certificate or license issued by the Department of State showing that the corporation is authorized to transact business in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other data required by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certificates of registration issued by the department are not assignable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the certificate of registration, the department shall provide to each newly registered dealer an initial resale certificate that is valid for the remainder of the period of issuance. The department shall provide to each active dealer an annual resale certificate. As used in this section, the term “active dealer” means a person who is registered with the department and who is required to file a return at least once during each applicable reporting period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of registration issued by the department may be revoked by the department or its designated agent when a dealer fails to comply with this chapter or chapter 203. Before revoking a dealer’s certificate of registration, the department must schedule an informal conference at which the dealer may present evidence regarding the department’s intended revocation or enter into a compliance agreement with the department. The department must notify the dealer of its intended action and of the time, place, and date of the scheduled informal conference by written notification sent by United States mail to the dealer’s last known address of record furnished by the dealer on a form prescribed by the department. The dealer must attend the informal conference and present evidence refuting the department’s intended revocation or enter into a compliance agreement with the department which resolves the dealer’s failure to comply with this chapter or chapter 203. The department shall issue an administrative complaint under s. 120.60 if the dealer fails to attend the department’s informal conference, fails to enter into a compliance agreement with the department resolving the dealer’s noncompliance with this chapter, or fails to comply with the executed compliance agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to subject to the provisions of this chapter all sellers of communications services that have established a sufficient connection with this state to permit the state constitutionally to require compliance with this chapter. Activities of a seller of communications services that may subject such a seller to the provisions of this chapter include, but are not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining an office or other place of business within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicitation of business from one or more Florida locations through employees, agents, independent contractors, or other representatives of such seller.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 58, ch. 2000-260; ss. 7, 38, ch. 2001-140; ss. 4, 19, ch. 2005-187.</History></Section>