<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0202.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of taxes by electronic funds transfer; filing of returns by electronic data interchange.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer of communications services is required to remit taxes by electronic funds transfer, in the manner prescribed by the department, when the amount of tax paid by the dealer under this chapter, chapter 203, or chapter 212 in the previous state fiscal year was $20,000 or more.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer who is required to remit taxes by electronic funds transfer shall make a return in a manner that is initiated through an electronic data interchange. The department shall prescribe the acceptable method of transfer; the method, form, and content of the electronic data interchange, giving due regard to developing uniform standards for formats as adopted by the American National Standards Institute; the circumstances under which an electronic data interchange will serve as a substitute for the filing of another form of return; and the means, if any, by which taxpayers will be provided with acknowledgments. The department must accept such returns as timely if initiated and accepted on or before the 20th day of the month. If the 20th day falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or federal or state legal holiday, returns are timely if initiated and accepted on the next succeeding workday.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may waive the requirement to make a return through an electronic data interchange when problems arise with respect to the taxpayer’s computer capabilities, data systems changes, or operating procedures. To obtain a waiver, the taxpayer must prove to the department that such problems exist.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall design, prepare, print, and furnish to all dealers, except dealers filing through electronic data interchange, or make available or prescribe to the dealers all necessary forms for filing returns and instructions to ensure a full collection from dealers and an accounting for the taxes due, but failure of any dealer to secure such forms does not relieve the dealer of the obligation to pay the tax at the time and in the manner required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe the format and instructions necessary for filing returns in a manner that is initiated through an electronic data interchange to ensure a full collection from dealers and an accounting for the taxes due. The failure of any dealer to use such format does not relieve the dealer of the obligation to pay the tax at the time and in the manner required.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 22, 58, ch. 2000-260; s. 38, ch. 2001-140; s. 14, ch. 2007-106.</History></Section>