<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0202.33" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Taxes declared to be government funds; penalties for failure to remit taxes; warrants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxes collected under this chapter become government funds from the moment of collection by the dealer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who, with intent to unlawfully deprive or defraud the state or a local government of its moneys or the use or benefit thereof, fails to remit taxes collected under this chapter is guilty of the theft of government funds, punishable as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the total amount of stolen revenue is less than $300, the offense is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. For a second offense, the offender is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. For a third or subsequent offense, the offender is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the total amount of stolen revenue is $300 or more, but less than $20,000, the offense is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the total amount of stolen revenue is $20,000 or more, but less than $100,000, the offense is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the total amount of stolen revenue is $100,000 or more, the offense is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All taxes collected under this chapter must be remitted to the department. In addition to criminal sanctions, the department shall, when any tax becomes delinquent or is otherwise in jeopardy under this chapter, issue a warrant for the full amount of the tax due or estimated to be due, with the interest, penalties, and cost of collection, directed to the sheriffs of the state, and mail the warrant to the clerk of the circuit court of the county where any property of the taxpayer is located. Upon receipt of the warrant, the clerk of the circuit court shall record it, and thereupon the amount of the warrant becomes a lien on any real or personal property of the taxpayer in the same manner as a recorded judgment. The department may issue a tax execution to enforce the collection of taxes imposed by this chapter and deliver it to any sheriff. The sheriff shall thereupon proceed in the same manner as prescribed by law for executions and shall be entitled to the same fees for his or her services in executing the warrant to be collected. The department may also have a writ of garnishment with respect to any indebtedness due to the delinquent dealer by a third person in any goods, money, chattels, or effects of the delinquent dealer in the hands, possession, or control of the third person. Upon payment of the execution, warrant, judgment, or garnishment, the department shall satisfy the lien of record within 30 days. If there is jeopardy to the revenue and jeopardy is asserted in or with an assessment, the department shall proceed in the manner specified for jeopardy assessments in s. 213.732.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 25, 58, ch. 2000-260; s. 38, ch. 2001-140.</History></Section>