<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0216.348" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fixed capital outlay grants and aids appropriations to certain nonprofit entities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a bill appropriating a fixed capital outlay grants and aids appropriation requires compliance with this section, the following conditions shall apply, except to the extent that such bill modifies these conditions:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administering agency” means the governmental agency or entity which is charged by the bill appropriating the fixed capital outlay grants and aids appropriation to a grantee with administering that appropriation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Grant” means a fixed capital outlay grants and aids appropriation to a nonprofit entity other than a governmental entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Grantee” means a nonprofit entity, other than a governmental entity, to which the Legislature has appropriated over $50,000 pursuant to a fixed capital outlay grants and aids appropriation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the receipt of any grant money from the administering agency, a grantee must provide the administering agency with an affidavit by an officer or director of the grantee certifying under oath that the grantee is a nonprofit entity and must execute a written agreement with the administering agency, in a form approved by the administering agency, pursuant to subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the grantee is acquiring real property with the grant, or if the grantee owns the real property upon which an improvement is being constructed, renovated, altered, modified, or maintained with the grant, the grantee must execute, deliver, and record in the county in which the subject property is located an agreement that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">States a correct legal description of the real property.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sets forth with specificity the buildings, appurtenances, fixtures, fixed equipment, structures, improvements, renovations, and personalty to be purchased pursuant to the grant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the term of the agreement, prohibits the grantee from selling, transferring, mortgaging, or assigning the grantee’s interest in the real property, unless the administering agency approves the sale, transfer, mortgage, or assignment; and, in the case of sale, transfer, or assignment, the purchaser, transferor, or assignee must fully assume, in writing, all of the terms and conditions of the agreement required by this subsection. The administering agency may not agree to subordinate a mortgage.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the grantee is not acquiring real property, or does not own the real property being improved, the agreement shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify the leasehold or other real property interest the grantee has in the real property.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State the name of the owner of the real property.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe the relationship between the owner of the real property and the grantee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth with specificity the improvements, renovations, and personalty to be purchased pursuant to the grant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the term of the agreement, prohibit the grantee from selling, transferring, mortgaging, or assigning the grantee’s interest in the leasehold, improvements, renovations, or personalty, unless the administering agency approves the sale, transfer, mortgage, or assignment; and, in the case of sale, transfer, or assignment, the purchaser, transferor, or assignee must fully assume, in writing, all of the terms and conditions of the agreement required by this subsection. Additionally, the grantee shall execute and deliver a security instrument, financing statement, or other appropriate document securing the interest of the administering agency in the improvements, renovations, and personalty associated with the grant. The administering agency may not subordinate or modify a security interest.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All agreements required by this subsection shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the grantee to continue the operation, maintenance, repair, and administration of the property in accordance with the purposes for which the funds were originally appropriated and for the period of time expressly specified by the bill appropriating the grant. If the bill appropriating the grant does not specify a time period, the administering agency shall determine a reasonable period of time.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide that if the grantee fails, during the term of the agreement, to operate, maintain, repair, and administer the property in accordance with the purposes for which the funds were originally granted, the grantee shall return to the administering agency, no later than upon demand by the administering agency, an amount calculated as follows:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the bill appropriating the grant states a specific repayment formula, that formula shall be used;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the bill appropriating the grant states a specific period of time but does not specify a repayment formula, the amount to be returned shall be calculated on a pro rata basis for that period of time; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the bill appropriating the grant does not state a specific period of time or formula, the amount to be returned shall be specified by the administering agency, which shall be no less than the full amount of the grant less $100,000 or 10 percent of the grant, whichever is more, for each full year for which the property was used for such purposes.</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The administering agency shall deposit all funds returned by the grantee into the state fund from which the grant was originally made.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that the grantee adopt an accounting system, in compliance with generally accepted accounting principles, which shall provide for a complete record of the use of the grant money. In addition, the provisions of s. 215.97 shall apply.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide that the grantee shall indemnify, defend, and hold the administering agency harmless from and against any and all claims or demands for damages resulting from personal injury, including death or damage to property, arising out of or relating to the subject property or the use of the grant money. The agreement shall require the grantee to purchase and maintain insurance on behalf of directors, officers, and employees of the grantee against any personal liability or accountability by reason of actions taken while acting within the scope of their authority. The administering agency shall be immune from civil or criminal liability resulting from acts or omissions of the grantee and the grantee’s agents, employees, or assigns.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the grantee to return any portion of the grant money received that is not necessary to the purchase of the land, or to the cost of the improvements, renovations, and personalty, for which the grant was awarded.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administering agency may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require that, during any term or period of construction, or until such time as the grant money is fully and properly spent according to the bill appropriating the grant, the grantee obtain a blanket fidelity bond, in the amount of the grant, issued by a company authorized and licensed to do business in this state, which will reimburse the administering agency in the event that anyone handling the grant moneys either misappropriates or absconds with the grant moneys. All employees handling the grant moneys must be covered by the bond.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include any other term or condition the administering agency deems reasonable and necessary for the effective and efficient administration of the grant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Modify any condition required by this subsection, provided the administering agency deems that such modification is necessary in order to best effectuate the purpose of the grant and provided the bill appropriating the grant, or applicable law, does not otherwise require.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement must provide that the administering agency shall execute a satisfaction of the agreement in recordable form upon full compliance by the grantee with the terms of the agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 2000-371; s. 6, ch. 2001-61.</History></Section>