<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0216.222" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Budget Stabilization Fund; criteria for withdrawing moneys.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the Budget Stabilization Fund may be transferred to the General Revenue Fund for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offsetting a deficit in the General Revenue Fund. A deficit is deemed to occur when the official estimate of funds available in the General Revenue Fund for a fiscal year falls below the total amount appropriated from the General Revenue Fund for that fiscal year. Such a transfer must be made pursuant to s. 216.221, or pursuant to an appropriation by law.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the requirements of s. 216.221, if, after consultation with the Revenue Estimating Conference, the Chief Financial Officer believes that a deficit will occur in the General Revenue Fund and if:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fewer than 30 but more than 4 days are left in the fiscal year, the Legislature is not in session, and neither the Legislature nor the Legislative Budget Commission is scheduled to meet before the end of the fiscal year, or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fewer than 5 days are left in the fiscal year and the Governor and the Chief Justice, the Legislature, or the Legislative Budget Commission have not implemented measures to resolve the deficit,</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the deficit to the Governor, the Chief Justice, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and may thereafter withdraw funds from the Budget Stabilization Fund to offset the projected deficit in the General Revenue Fund. The Chief Financial Officer shall consult with the Governor and the chair and vice chair of the Legislative Budget Commission before any funds may be withdrawn from the Budget Stabilization Fund. At the beginning of the next fiscal year, the Chief Financial Officer shall promptly determine the General Revenue Fund balance to be carried forward. The Chief Financial Officer shall immediately repay the Budget Stabilization Fund for the withdrawn amount, up to the amount of the balance. If the General Revenue Fund balance carried forward is not sufficient to fully repay the Budget Stabilization Fund, the repayment of the remainder of the withdrawn funds shall be as provided in s. 215.32(2)(c)3.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing funding for an emergency as defined in s. 252.34. The emergency must have been declared by the Governor pursuant to s. 252.36 or declared by law. Such a transfer must be made pursuant to s. 252.37, subject to the conditions in that section, or pursuant to an appropriation by law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing temporary transfers to the General Revenue Fund pursuant to s. 215.18.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the Budget Stabilization Fund may be transferred to the State Risk Management Trust Fund to provide funding for an emergency. For purposes of this subsection, an emergency exists when uninsured losses to state property exceed $2 million per occurrence or $5 million annual aggregate, as this constitutes an unanticipated financial need that the Legislature has found must be funded to serve an essential state responsibility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At such time that the Division of Risk Management certifies that uninsured property losses exceed $2 million per occurrence or $5 million annual aggregate, the division shall request a budget amendment through the procedures set out in s. 216.181. Transfers into the State Risk Management Trust Fund pursuant to this paragraph may not exceed $38 million in any fiscal year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-250; s. 1, ch. 2001-376; s. 243, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2004-239.</History></Section>