<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0216.0153" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Comprehensive state-owned real property system.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whereas, the Legislature finds that it is in the best interest of the state to identify surplus property and dispose of such property owned by the state that is unnecessary to achieving the state’s responsibilities, that may cost more to maintain than the revenue generated, that does not serve any public purpose, or from which the state may derive a substantially similar public purpose under private ownership.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection shall create, administer, and maintain a comprehensive system for all state lands and real property leased, owned, rented, and otherwise occupied or maintained by any state agency, by the judicial branch, and by any water management district. The comprehensive state-owned real property system shall allow the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund to perform its statutory responsibilities and the Division of State Lands in the Department of Environmental Protection to conduct strategic analyses and prepare annual valuation and disposition analyses and recommendations for all state real property assets.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The comprehensive state-owned real property system must contain a database that includes an accurate inventory of all real property that is leased, owned, rented, occupied, or managed by the state, the judicial branch, or the water management districts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of State Lands in the Department of Environmental Protection shall be the statewide custodian of the real property information and shall be accountable for its accuracy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state agencies and water management districts shall enter required real property information in the comprehensive system according to standards published by the Division of State Lands.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The comprehensive state-owned real property system must accomplish the following objectives:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eliminate the need for redundant state real property information collection processes and state agency information systems.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce the need to lease or acquire additional real property as a result of an annual surplus valuation, utilization, and disposition analysis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enable regional planning as a tool for cost-effective buy, sell, and lease decisions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Increase state revenues and maximize operational efficiencies by annually identifying those state-owned real properties that are the best candidates for surplus or disposition.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure all state real property is identified by collaborating and integrating with the Department of Revenue data as submitted by the county property appraisers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implement required functionality and processes for state agencies to electronically submit all applicable real property information using a web browser application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By October 1, 2010, and annually thereafter, the Division of State Lands in the Department of Environmental Protection shall submit to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a report that lists the state-owned real property recommended for disposition, including a report by the Department of Management Services of surplus buildings recommended for disposition. The report shall include specific information that documents the valuation and analysis process used to identify the specific state-owned real property recommended for disposition.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 10, ch. 2010-280; SJR 8-A, 2010 Special Session A.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 8, ch. 2010-280, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“Implementation of the comprehensive state-owned real property system.<EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The development of the comprehensive state-owned real property system must be composed of the following implementation timeframes and initial deliverables:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) By November 1, 2010, the Department of Environmental Protection shall submit an updated feasibility study for the Lands Inventory Tracking System, which shall include in its scope the comprehensive state-owned real property system. The feasibility study shall be submitted to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) By February 1, 2011, the executive steering committee shall complete the business process analysis and documentation of both the detailed system requirements and the overall system architecture and submit this information to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) By March 1, 2011, the facility inventory components of the comprehensive state-owned real property system must be fully operational.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(d) By September 1, 2012, the remaining real property and land inventory components of the comprehensive state-owned real property system must be fully operational.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(e) Within 12 months after the comprehensive system becomes operational, state agencies shall retire any real property databases or systems that duplicate the functionality or capability of the comprehensive system unless such systems are specifically required by law.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The Department of Environmental Protection shall implement the project governance structure until such time as the comprehensive state-owned real property system is successfully completed, suspended, or terminated.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The project sponsor for the comprehensive state-owned real property system is the Secretary of Environmental Protection or an appointed designee.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(4) The project shall be governed by an executive steering committee composed of the following voting members or their designees:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) The Secretary of Environmental Protection, who shall serve as chair of the committee.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) The executive director or secretary of the Department of Management Services.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) The executive director of the Department of Revenue.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(d) The Chief Financial Officer.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(e) A property appraiser appointed by the Florida Association of Property Appraisers, Inc.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(f) A property appraiser appointed by the Property Appraisers’ Association of Florida, Inc.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(g) The executive director of the Agency for Enterprise Information Technology.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(5) The executive steering committee shall take action by majority vote of its members and has the overall management responsibility for ensuring that the system meets the main business objectives identified in s. 216.0153(2), Florida Statutes. The executive steering committee is specifically responsible for:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) Providing management direction and support to the project management team.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) Reviewing, approving, or disapproving project deliverables and any changes to the project’s scope, schedule, or costs.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) Preparing an update to the feasibility study for the Lands Inventory Tracking System, including the scope of the real property system. The feasibility study shall include, but need not be limited to, a description of the overall scope of the comprehensive state-owned real property system. In determining the overall scope, the study shall address whether a single, comprehensive database of state-owned real property should replace existing real property databases and whether the comprehensive real property system should accept data from and send data to existing databases. The feasibility study update shall comply with the Schedule IV-B guidelines for the 2010-2011 fiscal year, published by the Technology Review Workgroup pursuant to s. 216.023, Florida Statutes.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“1. At a minimum, the following database systems shall be included in this review and analysis:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“a. The Public Lands Inventory of the Department of Environmental Protection, the statewide public lands inventory, the Board of Trustees Land Document Systems, and the Lands Information Tracking System.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“b. The property tax rolls of the Department of Revenue.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“c. The state facilities inventory of the Department of Management Services.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“d. The risk management database of the Department of Financial Services.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“2. Further functions must include:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“a. Identification of the role and responsibilities of the county property appraisers in a comprehensive system of state-owned real property which includes the integration of their real property data.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“b. A description of the methods for maintaining and updating the system and conducting strategic analyses, including valuation and real property surplus or disposition analysis.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“c. Specifications describing all functional and technical requirements of the comprehensive system.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“d. Reliable estimates of the initial and ongoing state and local effort required to implement the comprehensive system of state-owned real property.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“e. Identification of the business processes that county property appraisers and state agencies will use to keep the comprehensive system data complete, current, and accurate.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“f. Identification of state agency system usage requirements and responsibilities.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“g. Cost-benefit analysis documenting the specific direct and indirect costs, savings, and qualitative and quantitative benefits involved in or resulting from the implementation of the comprehensive state-owned real property system.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(d) Identifying and recommending to the Governor and the chair of the House Full Appropriations Council on General Government &amp; Health Care and the chair of the Senate Policy and Steering Committee on Ways and Means any fiscal and substantive policy changes that are needed to implement and maintain the comprehensive system as documented in the feasibility study.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(6) The project management team shall be established no later than 30 days after this act becomes law and shall work under the direction of the executive steering committee. A memorandum of agreement between the Department of Environmental Protection, the Department of Management Services, the Department of Revenue, and the Department of Financial Services may be executed to clearly define the roles and responsibilities of the project management team. The project management team must be headed by a full-time project manager and consist of senior managers and personnel appointed by members of the executive steering committee. The project management team is responsible for:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) Providing daily planning, management, and implementation resources and capabilities for the project.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) Developing an operational work plan for the project and providing to the executive steering committee proposed updates to the work plan whenever necessary. The plan must specify project milestones, deliverables, a development and implementation schedule, and expenditures necessary to achieve the main objectives identified in s. 216.0153(2), Florida Statutes.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(c) Submitting written monthly project status reports to the executive steering committee which describe:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“1. Planned project costs versus actual project costs.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“2. Completion status of major milestones and deliverables according to the project schedule.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“3. Any issues requiring resolution, the proposed resolution for the issues, and information regarding the status of the resolution.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“4. Specific risks that must be managed and methods for their management.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“5. Recommendations for necessary changes in the project’s scope, schedule, or costs. All recommendations must be reviewed by project stakeholders before submission to the executive steering committee in order to ensure that the recommendations meet required acceptance criteria.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(d) Preparing the feasibility study required in subsection (1) under the direction of the executive steering committee.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(e) Preparing project work plans and project status reports, which shall also be provided to the Governor and the chair of the House Full Appropriations Council on General Government &amp; Health Care and the chair of the Senate Policy and Steering Committee on Ways and Means.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>