<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0216.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appropriations; undisbursed balances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As of June 30th of each year, for appropriations for operations only, each department and the judicial branch shall identify in the state’s financial system any incurred obligation which has not been disbursed, showing in detail the commitment or to whom obligated and the amounts of such commitments or obligations. Any appropriation not identified as an incurred obligation effective June 30th shall revert to the fund from which it was appropriated and shall be available for reappropriation by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The undisbursed release balance of any authorized appropriation, except an appropriation for fixed capital outlay, for any given fiscal year remaining on June 30 of the fiscal year shall be carried forward in an amount equal to the incurred obligations identified in paragraph (a). Any such incurred obligations remaining undisbursed on September 30 shall revert to the fund from which appropriated and shall be available for reappropriation by the Legislature. The Chief Financial Officer will monitor changes made to incurred obligations prior to the September 30 reversion to ensure generally accepted accounting principles and legislative intent are followed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event an appropriate identification of an incurred obligation is not made and an incurred obligation is proven to be legal, due, and unpaid, then the incurred obligation shall be paid and charged to the appropriation for the current fiscal year of the state agency or judicial branch affected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each department and the judicial branch shall maintain the integrity of the General Revenue Fund. Appropriations from the General Revenue Fund contained in the original approved budget may be transferred to the proper trust fund for disbursement. Any reversion of appropriation balances from programs which receive funding from the General Revenue Fund and trust funds shall be transferred to the General Revenue Fund within 15 days after such reversion, unless otherwise provided by federal or state law, including the General Appropriations Act. The Executive Office of the Governor or the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court shall determine the state agency or judicial branch programs which are subject to this paragraph. This determination shall be subject to the legislative consultation and objection process in this chapter. The Education Enhancement Trust Fund shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The balance of any appropriation for fixed capital outlay which is not disbursed but expended, contracted, or committed to be expended prior to February 1 of the second fiscal year of the appropriation, or the third fiscal year if it is for an educational facility as defined in chapter 1013 or for a construction project of a state university, shall be certified by the head of the affected state agency or judicial branch on February 1 to the Executive Office of the Governor, showing in detail the commitment or to whom obligated and the amount of the commitment or obligation. The Executive Office of the Governor for the executive branch and the Chief Justice for the judicial branch shall review and approve or disapprove, consistent with criteria jointly developed by the Executive Office of the Governor and the legislative appropriations committees, the continuation of such unexpended balances. The Executive Office of the Governor shall, no later than February 28 of each year, furnish the Chief Financial Officer, the legislative appropriations committees, and the Auditor General a report listing in detail the items and amounts reverting under the authority of this subsection, including the fund to which reverted and the agency affected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certification required in this subsection shall be in the form and on the date approved by the Executive Office of the Governor. Any balance that is not certified shall revert to the fund from which it was appropriated and be available for reappropriation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The balance of any appropriation for fixed capital outlay certified forward under paragraph (a) which is not disbursed but expended, contracted, or committed to be expended prior to the end of the second fiscal year of the appropriation, or the third fiscal year if it is for an educational facility as defined in chapter 1013 or for a construction project of a state university, and any subsequent fiscal year, shall be certified by the head of the affected state agency or the legislative or judicial branch on or before August 1 of each year to the Executive Office of the Governor, showing in detail the commitment or to whom obligated and the amount of such commitment or obligation. On or before September 1 of each year, the Executive Office of the Governor shall review and approve or disapprove, consistent with legislative policy and intent, any or all of the items and amounts certified by the head of the affected state agency and shall approve all items and amounts certified by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court and by the legislative branch and shall furnish the Chief Financial Officer, the legislative appropriations committees, and the Auditor General a detailed listing of the items and amounts approved as legal encumbrances against the undisbursed balances of such appropriations. If such certification is not made and the balance of the appropriation has reverted and the obligation is proven to be legal, due, and unpaid, the obligation shall be presented to the Legislature for its consideration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 69-106; s. 8, ch. 69-82; s. 19, ch. 71-354; s. 5, ch. 75-243; s. 19, ch. 77-352; s. 16, ch. 81-169; s. 22, ch. 83-49; s. 9, ch. 83-332; s. 65, ch. 87-548; s. 9, ch. 90-203; s. 89, ch. 91-45; s. 25, ch. 91-109; s. 73, ch. 92-142; s. 26, ch. 95-269; s. 923, ch. 2002-387; s. 250, ch. 2003-261; ss. 39, 40, ch. 2005-152; s. 36, ch. 2006-122.</History></Section>