<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0216.052" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community budget requests; appropriations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local, county, or regional governmental entity, private organization, or nonprofit organization may submit a request for a state appropriation for a program, service, or capital outlay initiative that is local or regional in scope, is intended to meet a documented need, addresses a statewide interest, is intended to produce measurable results, and has tangible community support to members of the Legislature, a state agency, or the Governor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For requests submitted to members of the Legislature, community budget requests shall be submitted in the form and manner prescribed jointly by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. If the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives do not agree on a form and manner of submission to be used by both houses, each may prescribe a form and manner of submission to be used in his or her house.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community budget requests shall be submitted to the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees in accordance with the schedule established jointly by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. If the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives do not agree on a schedule to be used by both houses, each may prescribe a schedule to be used in his or her house.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Executive Office of the Governor shall prescribe the form and manner of submission of requests to state agencies and to the Governor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The retention of interest earned on state funds or the amount of interest income earned shall be applied against the state entity’s obligation to pay the appropriated amount.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 92-142; s. 1158, ch. 95-147; s. 11, ch. 2000-371; s. 17, ch. 2005-152.</History></Section>