<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0216.0113" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preferred pricing clauses in state contracts; compliance required.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state agency, as defined in s. 216.011, shall review its contracts and, for any contract with a preferred-pricing clause, the agency shall ensure that the contractor complies with such clause.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each contract executed, renewed, extended, or modified on or after July 1, 2010, which includes a preferred-pricing clause, must require an affidavit from an authorized representative of the contractor attesting that the contract is in compliance with the preferred-pricing clause. Such affidavit must be submitted at least annually. A contractor’s failure to comply with a preferred-pricing clause is grounds for terminating the contract at the state agency’s sole discretion.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “preferred-pricing clause” means a contractual provision under which the state is offered the most favorable price that the contractor offers to any client.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 48, ch. 2010-151.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 47, ch. 2010-151, provides that “[e]ach state agency, as defined in s. 216.011, Florida Statutes, shall review existing contract renewals and reprocurements with private providers and public-private providers in an effort to reduce contract payments by at least 3 percent. It is the statewide goal to achieve substantial savings; however, it is the intent of the Legislature that the level and quality of services not be affected. Each agency shall renegotiate and reprocure contracts consistent with this section. Any savings that accrue through renegotiating the renewal or reprocurement of an existing contract shall be placed in reserve by the Executive Office of the Governor.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>