<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0216.0152" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inventory of state-owned facilities or state-occupied facilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall develop and maintain an automated inventory of all facilities owned, leased, rented, or otherwise occupied or maintained by any agency of the state, the judicial branch, or the water management districts. The inventory data shall be provided by the owning or operating agency and shall include the location, occupying agency, ownership, size, condition assessment, valuations, operating costs, maintenance record, age, parking and employee facilities, building uses, full-time equivalent occupancy, known restrictions or historic designations, leases or subleases, associated revenues, and other information as required in a rule adopted by the department. The department shall use this data for determining maintenance needs, conducting strategic analyses, including, but not limited to, analyzing and identifying candidates for surplus, valuation, and disposition, and life-cycle cost evaluations of the facility. Inventory data shall be provided to the department on or before July 1 of each year by the owning or operating agency in a format prescribed by the department. The inventory need not include a condition assessment or maintenance record of facilities not owned by a state agency, the judicial branch, or a water management district. The term “facility,” as used in this section, means buildings, structures, and building systems, but does not include transportation facilities of the state transportation system. For reporting purposes, the Department of Transportation shall develop and maintain an inventory of transportation facilities of the state transportation system. The Department of Transportation shall also identify and dispose of surplus property pursuant to ss. 337.25 and 339.04. The Board of Governors of the State University System and the Department of Education, respectively, shall develop and maintain an inventory, in the manner prescribed by the Department of Management Services, of all state university and community college facilities and shall make the data available in a format acceptable to the Department of Management Services. By March 15, 2011, the department shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536 and 120.54 to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of assessing needed repairs and renovations of facilities, the Department of Management Services shall update its inventory with condition information for facilities of 3,000 square feet or more and cause to be updated the other inventories required by subsection (1) at least once every 5 years, but the inventories shall record acquisitions of new facilities and significant changes in existing facilities as they occur. The Department of Management Services shall provide each agency and the judicial branch with the most recent inventory applicable to that agency or to the judicial branch. Each agency and the judicial branch shall, in the manner prescribed by the Department of Management Services, report significant changes in the inventory as they occur. Items relating to the condition and life-cycle cost of a facility shall be updated at least every 5 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall, every 3 years, publish a complete report detailing this inventory and shall publish an annual update of the report. The department shall furnish the updated report to the Executive Office of the Governor and the Legislature no later than September 15 of each year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 84-321; s. 1, ch. 89-301; s. 33, ch. 92-142; s. 155, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 14, ch. 97-95; s. 4, ch. 2000-371; s. 25, ch. 2007-217; ss. 4, 10, ch. 2010-280; SJR 8-A, 2010 Special Session A.</History>
</Section>