<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Labels; requirements; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any commercial feed distributed in this state, except a customer-formula feed and feed distributed through an integrated poultry operation or by a cooperative to its members, shall be accompanied by a legible label bearing all information required by the federal Food and Drug Administration and the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accurate statement of the net weight.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and principal address of the registrant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The brand name and product name, if any, under which the commercial feed is distributed. The word “medicated” shall be incorporated as part of the brand or product name if the commercial feed contains a drug.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require feeding directions and precautionary statements to be placed on the label for the safe and effective use of medicated and other feed as deemed necessary.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Labels on medicated feed shall include all of the following:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any feeding directions prescribed by the department to ensure safe usage.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The stated purpose of the medication contained in the feed as stated in the claim statement.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The established name of each active drug ingredient.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The level of each drug used in the final mixture expressed in metric units as well as the required avoirdupois.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of manufacture or expiration date of commercial feed sold at retail as the department may by rule require.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guaranteed analysis stated in terms that advise the consumer of the composition of the feed or feedstuff or support claims made in the labeling. In all cases, the elements or compounds listed in the analysis must be determinable by laboratory methods approved by the department.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guaranteed analysis, listing the minimum percentage of crude protein, minimum percentage of crude fat, and maximum percentage of crude fiber and, when more than 10 percent mineral ingredients are present, the minimum or maximum percentages of mineral elements or compounds as provided by rule.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vitamin ingredients, when guaranteed, shall be shown in amounts and terms provided by rule. For mineral feed, the list shall include the following: maximum or minimum percentages of calcium (Ca), phosphorus (P), salt (NaCl), iron (Fe), copper (Cu), cobalt (Co), magnesium (Mg), manganese (Mn), potassium (K), selenium (Se), zinc (Zn), and fluorine (F) if ingredients used as sources of any of these constituents are declared. All mixtures that contain mineral or vitamin ingredients generally regarded as dietary factors essential for the normal nutrition of animals and that are sold or represented for the primary purpose of supplying these minerals or vitamins as additions to rations in which these same mineral or vitamin factors may be deficient shall be classified as mineral or vitamin supplements. Products sold solely as mineral or vitamin supplements and guaranteed as specified in this section need not show guarantees for protein, fat, and fiber.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other nutritional substances or elements determinable by laboratory methods may be guaranteed by permission of, or shall be guaranteed at the request of, the department as may be provided by rule.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common or usual name of each ingredient used in the manufacture of the commercial feed; however, for all commercial feed except horse feed, the department by rule may permit the use of collective terms for a group of ingredients which perform a similar nutritional function.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Customer-formula feed shall be accompanied by a label, invoice, delivery slip, or other shipping document, bearing all information required by the federal Food and Drug Administration and the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the manufacturer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the customer ordering the feed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of delivery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The product name and net weight of each commercial feed and each other ingredient used in the mixture.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adequate directions and precautionary statements for the safe and effective use of all customer-formula feed that is medicated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Feed distributed by an integrated poultry operation or by a cooperative to its members shall be accompanied by a legible label bearing information required by the federal Food and Drug Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a commercial feed is distributed in this state in bags or other containers, a label shall be placed on or affixed to each container; when a commercial feed is distributed in bulk, a label shall accompany delivery and be furnished to the customer at time of delivery.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of $100 shall be paid to the department as penalty for the distribution of any commercial feed that is not accompanied with the label required under this chapter. The proceeds from any such penalty payments shall be deposited by the department in the General Inspection Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 29755, 1955; s. 4, ch. 61-440; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 4, ch. 69-62; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 75-140; s. 3, ch. 86-112; s. 1, ch. 87-81; s. 4, ch. 90-323; s. 2, ch. 91-178; s. 33, ch. 92-143; ss. 6, 7, ch. 93-90; ss. 4, 16, ch. 94-282; s. 28, ch. 2001-279.</History></Section>