<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Master registration; fee; refusal or cancellation of registration; reporting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each distributor of commercial feed must annually obtain a master registration before her or his brands are distributed in this state. The department shall furnish the registration forms requiring the distributor to state that the distributor will comply with all provisions of this chapter and applicable rules. The registration form shall identify the manufacturer’s or guarantor’s name and place of business and the location of each manufacturing facility in the state and shall be signed by the owner; by a partner, if a partnership; or by an authorized officer or agent, if a corporation. All registrations expire on June 30 of each year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registration form shall be accompanied by a fee that shall be based on tons of feed distributed in this state during the previous year. If a distributor has been in business less than 1 year, the tonnage shall be estimated by the distributor for the first year and based on actual tonnage thereafter. These fees shall be as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">SALES IN TONS<FlushRight />FEE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Zero, up to and including 25<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$40</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">More than 25, up to and including 50<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$75</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">More than 50, up to and including 100<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$150</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">More than 100, up to and including 300<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$375</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">More than 300, up to and including 600<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$600</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">More than 600, up to and including 1,000<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$900</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">More than 1,000, up to and including<NewLine />2,000<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$1,250</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">More than 2,000, up to and including<NewLine />5,000<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$2,000</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">More than 5,000<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$3,500</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration shall be conditioned on the distributor’s compliance with all provisions of this chapter and rules adopted under this chapter, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting samples of manufactured feed for testing by laboratories that have been certified by the department or obtaining an exemption from the certified laboratory testing requirement, as provided by this chapter and rules thereof.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining a bookkeeping system and records necessary to indicate accurately the type and tonnage of commercial feeds sold in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reporting within 30 days after the end of each quarter, in the format prescribed by the department, the number of tons of feed distributed in the state during each of the following reporting periods: July through September, October through December, January through March, and April through June.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allowing the department to verify the accuracy of reported type and tonnage and to otherwise examine pertinent records at reasonable times.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall mail a copy of the master registration to the registrant to signify that administrative requirements have been met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of any distributor to comply with registration shall be considered prima facie evidence of an attempt to violate this chapter, and the department shall have full authority to assess penalties where violations are found for any commercial feed or feedstuff distributed in the state prior to registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may refuse, suspend, or cancel the master registration of, or impose one or more of the penalties provided in s. 580.121 against, any distributor or registrant who violates or fails to comply with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 29755, 1955; s. 3, ch. 61-440; ss. 2, 3, ch. 69-62; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 78-95; s. 2, ch. 86-112; s. 1, ch. 91-178; s. 33, ch. 92-143; ss. 3, 6, 7, ch. 93-90; ss. 3, 16, ch. 94-282; s. 915, ch. 97-103; s. 8, ch. 2008-107; s. 30, ch. 2012-190.</History></Section>