<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties; duties of law enforcement officers; injunctive relief.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may impose one or more of the following penalties against any person who violates any provision of this chapter:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a warning letter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine, by the department, of not more than $1,000 per occurrence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of the master registration, laboratory certification, or quality-assurance/quality-control plan approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Probation for up to 6 months.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, the severity of the penalty imposed shall be commensurate with the degree of risk to human or animal safety or the level of financial harm to the consumer that is created by the violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cases where the department has determined a pattern of noncompliance with the provisions of this chapter, penalties may be imposed in accordance with subsection (1). Such penalties are in addition to any penalty or penalties that might be imposed under any other portion of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this chapter commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all prosecutions under this chapter involving the composition of a lot of commercial feed or feedstuff, a certified copy of the certified laboratory analysis signed by the authorized agent of the laboratory or, when available, the analysis reported by the department shall be accepted by the court as prima facie evidence of the composition. Each state or county law enforcement officer shall make an arrest for violation of this chapter when such officer is notified of such violation by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as requiring the department to report for prosecution or for the institution of seizure proceedings as a result of minor violations of the chapter when it believes that the public interests will be best served by the imposition of one or more of the penalties set forth in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is hereby authorized to apply for, and the court may grant upon sufficient evidence, a temporary or permanent injunction, without bond, restraining any person from violating or continuing to violate any of the provisions of this chapter, notwithstanding the existence of other remedies at law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The receipts from any penalty payments under this section shall be deposited into the General Inspection Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 29755, 1955; s. 11, ch. 61-440; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 597, ch. 71-136; s. 8, ch. 79-66; s. 11, ch. 86-112; s. 2, ch. 88-210; s. 149, ch. 91-224; s. 33, ch. 92-143; ss. 6, 7, ch. 93-90; ss. 11, 16, ch. 94-282.</History></Section>