<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Adulteration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall distribute an adulterated commercial feed or feedstuff. A commercial feed or feedstuff shall be deemed to be adulterated:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it bears or contains any poisonous, deleterious, or nonnutritive substance that may render it injurious to animal or human health. However, if the substance is not an additive, the feed shall not be considered adulterated if the quantity of the substance does not ordinarily render it injurious to animal or human health;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it bears or contains any food additive or added poisonous, deleterious, or nonnutritive substance that is unsafe within the meaning of s. 406 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, other than a pesticide chemical in or on a raw agricultural commodity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is, or it bears or contains, any food additive or color additive that is unsafe within the meaning of s. 409 or s. 512 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, respectively;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a raw agricultural commodity and it bears or contains a pesticide chemical that is unsafe within the meaning of s. 408(a) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; however, where a pesticide chemical has been used in or on a raw agricultural commodity in conformity with an exemption granted or a tolerance prescribed under s. 408 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and that raw agricultural commodity has been subjected to processing such as canning, cooking, freezing, dehydrating, or milling, the processed feed will result, or is likely to result, in pesticide residue in the edible product of the animal which is unsafe within the meaning of s. 408(a) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is, or it bears or contains, any new animal drug that is unsafe within the meaning of s. 512 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it contains viable weed seeds in amounts exceeding the limits that the department establishes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it contains a drug and the methods, facilities, and controls used in its manufacture, processing, or packaging do not conform to current good management practices to ensure that the drug meets the requirement of this chapter as to safety and has the identity and strength and meets the quality and purity characteristics that it purports or is represented to possess.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any valuable constituent has been in whole or in part omitted or removed, or any less valuable substance has been substituted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its composition or quality falls below or differs from that which it is purported or is represented to possess by its labeling.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 29755, 1955; s. 6, ch. 61-440; s. 1, ch. 67-526; s. 6, ch. 69-62; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 79-66; s. 5, ch. 86-112; s. 33, ch. 92-143; ss. 6, 7, ch. 93-90; ss. 6, 16, ch. 94-282.</History></Section>