<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Laboratory certifications; application; fees; requirements; reporting; refusal or cancellation of certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department by rule shall establish the standards that a laboratory must meet to become certified in any of the following areas of testing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nutrient.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mycotoxins.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Microbiological organisms.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pesticide residues.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drugs.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall be guided by the methods published by the Association of Official Analytical Chemists, the United States Environmental Protection Agency, the United States Food and Drug Administration, or other generally recognized authorities in developing the standards for these laboratory certifications.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any laboratory wanting to be certified by the department in any of the testing categories must complete and return an application with a $100 application fee and a $300 fee for each of the desired certifications. A single application may be used to apply for more than one certification. The department shall furnish the application forms, which must require the distributor to state that the laboratory will comply with all provisions of this chapter and applicable rules. The registration form shall identify the laboratory’s name, the name of the owner or owners of the business, the location of the laboratory, and other information as required by rule of the department. The form shall be signed by the owner, a partner, if a partnership, or an authorized officer or agent, if a corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall mail a certificate for each certification granted to the laboratory to signify that administrative requirements have been met.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each laboratory that is certified in any area of testing must renew each certification annually. Renewal must be submitted on a form provided by the department at least 30 days prior to the expiration date of the current certificate. The laboratory must complete and return the renewal form with the appropriate fee for the desired annual certification as indicated on the form. Failure to timely renew certification shall result in the expiration of the certification on the date stated on the certificate. Any renewal received after the expiration date on the certificate shall be accompanied by a $50 late charge. Any renewal received 30 days or more beyond the expiration date on the certificate shall be returned to the laboratory, and the laboratory shall apply to the department as if it were the initial application for certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification shall be conditioned on the laboratory’s compliance with all provisions of this chapter and rules thereof, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting quarterly reports to the department containing the results of the commercial feed and feedstuff analyses for that quarter, including, but not limited to, the results of each sample submitted for analysis by each registrant, the registration number of the registrant submitting the samples, the number of violative samples, and any additional information the department may require by rule.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reporting immediately to the department each sample that is found to be in violation of the standards in this chapter and in the rules thereof.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participating in the quarterly check-sample program administered by the department, when required.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining a bookkeeping system and records that will allow the department to verify the accuracy of the reports required in this chapter and to examine such records at reasonable times.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to submit reports as required in this subsection may result in the suspension or revocation of one or more of the laboratory’s testing certifications.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may operate a check-sample program for all testing certifications. If 30 percent or more of a laboratory’s check-sample results are outside the acceptable variation established by rule for each check-sample test, the laboratory must pay a $100 fine and shall be placed on probation for the next quarter. The laboratory may be required to process additional check samples during the probationary period. If 20 percent or more of the results of the laboratory’s check samples are outside the acceptable variation level during the probationary period, that test category certification shall be revoked and the laboratory may not apply again for the same certification for 1 year after the date of the revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may refuse, suspend, or revoke the certification of any laboratory that violates or fails to comply with this chapter or rules adopted pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 94-282; s. 29, ch. 2001-279.</History></Section>