<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Detained commercial feed and feedstuff.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STOP-SALE, STOP-USE, REMOVAL, OR HOLD ORDERS.<EmDash />When the department has cause to believe any lot of commercial feed or feedstuff is being distributed in violation of this chapter or of any of the prescribed rules under this chapter, it may issue and enforce a written or printed stop-sale, stop-use, removal, or hold order, warning the possessor not to dispose of the commercial feed or feedstuff in any manner until written permission is given by the department or a court of competent jurisdiction. The department shall release the commercial feed or feedstuff so withdrawn when the provisions and rules have been complied with and all costs and expenses incurred in the withdrawal have been paid. The department may permit any lot of commercial feed or feedstuff under stop-sale, stop-use, removal, or hold order to be sold to a consumer who shall sign a statement at the time of purchase professing knowledge of the violation. If compliance is not obtained within 30 days, the department may begin proceedings for condemnation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONDEMNATION AND CONFISCATION.<EmDash />Any lot of commercial feed or feedstuff not in compliance with this chapter or rules promulgated hereunder shall be subject to seizure on complaint of the department to the circuit court of the circuit in which the commercial feed or feedstuff is located. In the event the court finds the commercial feed or feedstuff to be in violation of this chapter or rules promulgated hereunder and orders the condemnation of the commercial feed or feedstuff, it shall be disposed of in the manner provided by the circuit court in the order of condemnation. In no instance shall the disposition of the commercial feed or feedstuff be ordered by the court without first giving the claimant an opportunity to apply to the court for release of the commercial feed or feedstuff or to apply for permission to process or relabel the commercial feed or feedstuff to bring it into compliance with this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 29755, 1955; s. 10, ch. 61-440; s. 8, ch. 69-62; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 79-66; s. 9, ch. 86-112; s. 33, ch. 92-143; ss. 6, 7, ch. 93-90; ss. 9, 16, ch. 94-282.</History></Section>