<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection; sampling; analysis; exemption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may inspect, sample, or analyze commercial feed and feedstuff to ascertain compliance with this chapter and rules adopted pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to enter upon any public or business premises and any transport vehicle during regular business hours in order to have access to commercial feed or feedstuff and records relating to its origin, transport, manufacture, distribution, and sale.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All registrants must have samples of their feed and feed ingredients tested by a laboratory that has been certified by the department or must be exempt from the certified laboratory testing requirements, as provided in this chapter, to ensure that all commercial feed and feedstuff comply with the provisions of this chapter. The sampling frequency and analysis requirements shall be determined by rule of the department for poultry, dairy cow, beef cattle, horse, swine, and other feed.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in this chapter, the department shall not require distributors of 300 tons or less of poultry, dairy cow, beef cattle, horse, swine, or other feed per year to submit more than one sample of each such feed per year for analysis.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a registrant distributes more than one type of commercial feed, the sampling requirement for mycotoxins shall be determined by the combined tonnage of feed distributed by that registrant and shall be the most stringent of the sampling requirements for the types of feed distributed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Integrated poultry operations and cooperatives shall not be required to submit their feed samples for nutrient analysis. However, poultry and dairy feed sold by enterprises other than integrated poultry operations or cooperatives shall be subject to nutrient analysis as required by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding provisions to the contrary in this subsection, if the department finds that circumstances exist which threaten the health of commercial livestock or the public, the department may require more frequent analysis of feed. In such case, the department must notify affected registrants of the need for additional analysis and the estimated time period for which the analysis will be required to protect animal or public health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall work with registrants in the feed industry to develop a system of reporting commercial feed or feedstuff that has been rejected due to adulteration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall encourage the use of good management practices and hazard-analysis critical-control-point programs in the manufacture, distribution, transportation, sampling, inspection, and analysis of commercial feed and feedstuff.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If critical control points have been identified and good management practices have been implemented, the department shall conduct an onsite evaluation of the program to ensure the application of the established program. Registrants demonstrating adequate control of feed manufacture, distribution, transportation, and sampling processes and infrequent adulteration or other violations shall be subject to reduced sampling frequencies and analysis requirements that the department shall establish by rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require periodic reports to document the continued and appropriate use of good management practices and hazard analysis of critical control points. The department shall work with the industry in determining the appropriate level of such reporting.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sampling and analysis must be conducted in accordance with methods published by the Association of Official Analytical Chemists, the United States Environmental Protection Agency, the United States Food and Drug Administration, or other generally recognized authorities. In any instance where methods do not exist, the department shall adopt by rule the methods that are to be official in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registrant may apply for an exemption from the certified laboratory testing requirements by submitting its quality-assurance/quality-control plan, including laboratory testing protocols, to the department for review and approval or disapproval. The department shall furnish the form for requesting the exemption, which form shall require the registrant to comply with all applicable provisions of this chapter and related rules.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of a registrant’s quality-assurance/quality-control plan, the department shall send the registrant a letter of exemption if it finds that adequate measures are in place to assure compliance with the material submitted and with this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registrant’s quality-assurance/quality-control plan shall be subject to evaluation every 3 years. Application for renewal must be submitted on a form provided by the department at least 30 days prior to the expiration date of the current approval letter. Any renewal application received after the expiration date on the approval letter shall be accompanied by a $50 late charge. Failure to timely renew certification shall result in the expiration of the approval and imposition of the requirement to have all feed samples tested by a department-certified laboratory.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall charge a fee for any evaluation, in an amount to cover the direct and indirect costs associated with such evaluation and approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registrants with approved programs must comply with all applicable provisions of this chapter and rules, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining records of all laboratory test results for 3 years or as required by federal regulation, whichever is longer.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allowing department personnel access to records and laboratory facilities during reasonable hours for inspection purposes.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing to the department the results of any check-sample program the registrant may be using.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 29755, 1955; s. 8, ch. 61-440; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 79-66; s. 7, ch. 86-112; s. 2, ch. 87-81; s. 2, ch. 89-245; ss. 30, 33, ch. 92-143; ss. 5, 6, 7, ch. 93-90; ss. 8, 16, ch. 94-282; s. 30, ch. 2001-279.</History></Section>