<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0580.131" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalty payable to consumer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any consumer who purchases without notice a commercial feed or feedstuff that is distributed in violation of this chapter or rules adopted under this chapter shall, in any legal or administrative action that may be instituted, recover penalties as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a certified laboratory analysis shows that any feed bearing a guarantee of 20 percent protein or less falls more than 1 percent protein below the guarantee, or if the analysis shows that any feed bearing a guarantee of more than 20 percent protein falls more than 2 percent protein below the guarantee, $4 per ton for each percent protein deficiency shall be assessed against the manufacturer or distributor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a certified laboratory analysis shows that any feed is deficient in fat by more than 0.5 percent fat, $4 per ton for each percent fat deficiency shall be assessed against the manufacturer or distributor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a certified laboratory analysis shows that any feed bearing a maximum guarantee of not more than 20 percent fiber exceeds this guarantee by more than 1 percent fiber, or if the analysis shows that any feed bearing a maximum guarantee of more than 20 percent fiber exceeds this guarantee by more than 2 percent fiber, $4 per ton for each percent fiber excess shall be assessed against the manufacturer or distributor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a certified laboratory analysis shows that any commercial feed is deficient or excessive in the required drug, mineral, or nutritive guarantees other than protein, fat, or fiber, a penalty of $4 per ton shall be assessed against the manufacturer or distributor for each deficiency or excessive level found.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a certified laboratory analysis shows that any commercial feed or feedstuff is found to be adulterated as provided in s. 580.071, a penalty of $4 per ton shall be assessed against the manufacturer or distributor for each violation found.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any feed is found by the department to be short in weight, 4 times the invoice value of the actual shortage shall be assessed against the manufacturer or distributor, but in no instance shall the penalty be less than $25. The department by rule may establish variations for short weight.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> Any penalty assessed under this section, regardless of the monetary value of the violation, must be at least $10.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 60 days after the department notifies a registrant in writing of any penalty assessed under this section, the registrant shall pay the penalty to the consumer. If the consumer’s identity cannot be determined, the registrant shall, within the 60-day period, pay the assessed penalty to the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registrant who, within the 60-day period, fails to pay the full amount of the assessed penalty to the consumer or the department, as applicable, in addition to the penalty assessed under this section, is also subject to the penalties provided in s. 580.121.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds from any penalties paid to the department under this section shall be deposited into the department’s General Inspection Trust Fund and be used by the department for the exclusive purpose of administering this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 29755, 1955; s. 2, ch. 61-119; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 9, ch. 79-66; s. 12, ch. 86-112; s. 3, ch. 87-81; s. 3, ch. 88-210; s. 4, ch. 91-178; s. 33, ch. 92-143; ss. 6, 7, ch. 93-90; ss. 12, 16, ch. 94-282; s. 31, ch. 2012-190.</History></Section>