<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0332.007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration and financing of aviation and airport programs and projects; state plan.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal funding of individual local airport projects shall continue to be wholly between the local airport sponsors and the appropriate federal agencies; however, the Department of Transportation is authorized to receive federal grants for statewide projects when no local sponsor is available.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation shall prepare and continuously update an aviation and airport work program in accordance with subsections (6) and (7) based on a collection of the local sponsors’ proposed projects to be included in the work program of the department developed pursuant to s. 339.135. The airport work program shall separately identify development projects and discretionary capacity improvement projects.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The aviation and airport work program shall be consistent with the statewide aviation system plan and, to the maximum extent feasible, consistent with approved local government comprehensive plans. Projects involving funds administered by the department to be undertaken and implemented by the airport sponsor shall be included in the aviation and airport work program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assistance pursuant to the provisions of this section shall only be provided for projects which are included in the department’s adopted work program developed pursuant to s. 339.135.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual legislative budget request for aviation and airport development projects shall be based on the funding required for development projects in the aviation and airport work program. The department shall provide priority funding in support of the planning, design, and construction of proposed projects by local sponsors, with special emphasis on projects for runways and taxiways, including the painting and marking of runways and taxiways, lighting, other related airside activities, and airport access transportation facility projects on airport property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projects which provide for construction of an automatic weather observation station are eligible for the use of funds provided for herein.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No single airport shall secure airport or aviation development project funds in excess of 25 percent of the total airport or aviation development project funds available in any given budget year. However, any airport which receives discretionary capacity improvement project funds in a given fiscal year shall not receive greater than 10 percent of total aviation and airport development project funds appropriated in that fiscal year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless prohibited by the appropriations act or general legislation, the department may transfer funds for an airport and aviation development project to other airport and aviation development projects to maximize the aviation services or federal aid available to this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only those projects or programs provided for in this act that will contribute to the implementation of the state aviation system plan, that are consistent with and will contribute to the implementation of any airport master plan or layout plan, and that are consistent, to the maximum extent feasible, with the approved local government comprehensive plans of the units of government in which the airport is located are eligible for the expenditure of state funds in accordance with fund participation rates and priorities established herein.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the availability of appropriated funds, the department may participate in the capital cost of eligible public airport and aviation development projects in accordance with the following rates, unless otherwise provided in the General Appropriations Act or the substantive bill implementing the General Appropriations Act:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may fund up to 50 percent of the portion of eligible project costs which are not funded by the Federal Government, except that the department may initially fund up to 75 percent of the cost of land acquisition for a new airport or for the expansion of an existing airport which is owned and operated by a municipality, a county, or an authority, and shall be reimbursed to the normal statutory project share when federal funds become available or within 10 years after the date of acquisition, whichever is earlier. Due to federal budgeting constraints, the department may also initially fund the federal portion of eligible project costs subject to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department receiving adequate assurance from the Federal Government or local sponsor that this amount will be reimbursed to the department; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department having adequate funds in the work program to fund the project.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such projects must be contained in the Federal Government’s Airport Capital Improvement Program, and the Federal Government must fund, or have funded, the first year of the project.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may retroactively reimburse cities, counties, or airport authorities up to 50 percent of the nonfederal share for land acquisition when such land is needed for airport safety, expansion, tall structure control, clear zone protection, or noise impact reduction. No land purchased prior to July 1, 1990, or purchased prior to executing the required department agreements shall be eligible for reimbursement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When federal funds are not available, the department may fund up to 80 percent of master planning and eligible aviation development projects at publicly owned, publicly operated airports. If federal funds are available, the department may fund up to 80 percent of the nonfederal share of such projects. Such funding is limited to airports that have no scheduled commercial service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to fund up to 100 percent of the cost of an eligible project that is statewide in scope or that involves more than one county where no other governmental entity or appropriate jurisdiction exists.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the availability of appropriated funds in addition to aviation fuel tax revenues, the department may participate in the capital cost of eligible public airport and aviation discretionary capacity improvement projects. The annual legislative budget request shall be based on the funding required for discretionary capacity improvement projects in the aviation and airport work program.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide priority funding in support of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land acquisition which provides additional capacity at the qualifying international airport or at that airport’s supplemental air carrier airport.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Runway and taxiway projects that add capacity or are necessary to accommodate technological changes in the aviation industry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Airport access transportation projects that improve direct airport access and are approved by the airport sponsor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">International terminal projects that increase international gate capacity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No single airport shall secure discretionary capacity improvement project funds in excess of 50 percent of the total discretionary capacity improvement project funds available in any given budget year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless prohibited by the General Appropriations Act or by law, the department may transfer funds within each category of the airport and aviation discretionary capacity improvement program to maximize the aviation services or federal aid available to this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may fund up to 50 percent of the portion of eligible project costs which are not funded by the Federal Government except that the department may initially fund up to 75 percent of the cost of land acquisition for a new airport or for the expansion of an existing airport which is owned and operated by a municipality, a county, or an authority, and shall be reimbursed to the normal statutory project share when federal funds become available or within 10 years after the date of acquisition, whichever is earlier.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the department is authorized to fund security projects at publicly owned public-use airports. For projects in the current adopted work program, or projects added using the available budget of the department, airports may request the department change the project purpose in accordance with this provision notwithstanding the provisions of s. 339.135(7). For purposes of this subsection, the department may fund up to 100 percent of eligible project costs that are not funded by the Federal Government. This subsection shall expire on June 30, 2012.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, any airport with direct intercontinental passenger service that is located in a county with a population under 400,000 as of July 1, 2002, and that has a loan from the Department of Transportation due in August of 2002 shall have such loan extended until September 18, 2008.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may also fund eligible projects performed by not-for-profit organizations that represent a majority of public airports in this state. Eligible projects may include activities associated with aviation master planning, professional education, safety and security planning, enhancing economic development and efficiency at airports in this state, or other planning efforts to improve the viability of airports in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 261, ch. 84-309; s. 5, ch. 84-320; s. 1, ch. 85-149; s. 5, ch. 85-180; s. 1, ch. 86-206; s. 25, ch. 86-243; s. 1, ch. 87-279; s. 23, ch. 88-557; s. 10, ch. 89-301; s. 68, ch. 90-136; s. 18, ch. 94-237; s. 18, ch. 95-257; s. 46, ch. 96-323; s. 1, ch. 2001-349; s. 75, ch. 2002-20; s. 60, ch. 2003-286; s. 2, ch. 2005-281; s. 25, ch. 2007-196; ss. 45, 46, ch. 2009-82; ss. 46, 47, ch. 2010-153.</History>
</Section>