<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0787.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">False imprisonment; false imprisonment of child under age 13, aggravating circumstances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “false imprisonment” means forcibly, by threat, or secretly confining, abducting, imprisoning, or restraining another person without lawful authority and against her or his will.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Confinement of a child under the age of 13 is against her or his will within the meaning of this section if such confinement is without the consent of her or his parent or legal guardian.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits the offense of false imprisonment is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits the offense of false imprisonment upon a child under the age of 13 and who, in the course of committing the offense, commits any offense enumerated in subparagraphs 1.-5., commits a felony of the first degree, punishable by imprisonment for a term of years not exceeding life or as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aggravated child abuse, as defined in s. 827.03;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual battery, as defined in chapter 794, against the child;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lewd or lascivious battery, lewd or lascivious molestation, lewd or lascivious conduct, or lewd or lascivious exhibition, in violation of s. 800.04 or s. 847.0135(5);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of s. 796.03 or s. 796.04, relating to prostitution, upon the child; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exploitation of the child or allowing the child to be exploited, in violation of s. 450.151.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to s. 775.021(4), nothing contained herein shall be construed to prohibit the imposition of separate judgments and sentences for the first degree offense described in paragraph (a) and for each separate offense enumerated in subparagraphs (a)1.-5.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 43, sub-ch. 3, ch. 1637, 1868; RS 2399; GS 3225; RGS 5057; CGL 7159; s. 783, ch. 71-136; s. 23, ch. 74-383; s. 13, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 84-238; s. 2, ch. 90-120; s. 1, ch. 93-156; ss. 2, 18, ch. 93-227; s. 9, ch. 96-322; s. 1814, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 99-201; s. 3, ch. 2000-246; s. 19, ch. 2008-172.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 805.01.</Text></Note></Section>