<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0787.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Luring or enticing a child.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Structure” means a building of any kind, either temporary or permanent, which has a roof over it, together with the curtilage thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dwelling” means a building or conveyance of any kind, either temporary or permanent, mobile or immobile, which has a roof over it and is designed to be occupied by people lodging together therein at night, together with the curtilage thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Conveyance” means any motor vehicle, ship, vessel, railroad car, trailer, aircraft, or sleeping car.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Convicted” means a determination of guilt which is the result of a trial or the entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person 18 years of age or older who intentionally lures or entices, or attempts to lure or entice, a child under the age of 12 into a structure, dwelling, or conveyance for other than a lawful purpose commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person 18 years of age or older who, having been previously convicted of a violation of paragraph (a), intentionally lures or entices, or attempts to lure or entice, a child under the age of 12 into a structure, dwelling, or conveyance for other than a lawful purpose commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person 18 years of age or older who, having been previously convicted of a violation of chapter 794, s. 800.04, or s. 847.0135(5), or a violation of a similar law of another jurisdiction, intentionally lures or entices, or attempts to lure or entice, a child under the age of 12 into a structure, dwelling, or conveyance for other than a lawful purpose commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is an affirmative defense to a prosecution under this section that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person reasonably believed that his or her action was necessary to prevent the child from being seriously injured.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person lured or enticed, or attempted to lure or entice, the child under the age of 12 into a structure, dwelling, or conveyance for a lawful purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person’s actions were reasonable under the circumstances and the defendant did not have any intent to harm the health, safety, or welfare of the child.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 95-228; s. 8, ch. 99-201; s. 3, ch. 2000-246; s. 1, ch. 2006-299; s. 20, ch. 2008-172.</History></Section>