<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0517.072" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Viatical settlement investments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemptions provided for by ss. 517.051(6), (8), and (10) do not apply to a viatical settlement investment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offering of a viatical settlement investment is not an exempt transaction under s. 517.061(2), (3), (8), (11), and (18), regardless of whether the offering otherwise complies with the conditions of that section, unless such offering is to a qualified institutional buyer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registration provisions of ss. 517.07 and 517.12 do not apply to any of the following transactions in viatical settlement investments; however, such transactions in viatical settlement investments are subject to the provisions of ss. 517.301, 517.311, and 517.312:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transfer or assignment of an interest in a previously viaticated policy from a natural person who transfers or assigns no more than one such interest in a single calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of stop-loss coverage to a viatical settlement provider, financing entity, or related provider trust, as those terms are defined in s. 626.9911, by an authorized or eligible insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transfer or assignment of a viaticated policy from a licensed viatical settlement provider to another licensed viatical settlement provider, a related provider trust, a financing entity, or a special purpose entity, as those terms are defined in s. 626.9911, or to a contingency insurer, provided such transfer or assignment is not the direct or indirect promotion of any scheme or enterprise with the intent of violating or evading any provision of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transfer or assignment of a viaticated policy to a bank, trust company, savings institution, insurance company, dealer, investment company as defined in the Investment Company Act of 1940, pension or profit-sharing trust, or qualified institutional buyer as defined in United States Securities and Exchange Commission Rule 144A, 17 C.F.R. s. 230.144A(a), or to an accredited investor as defined by Rule 501 of Regulation D of the Securities Act Rules, provided such transfer or assignment is not for the direct or indirect promotion of any scheme or enterprise with the intent of violating or evading any provision of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transfer or assignment of a viaticated policy by a conservator of a viatical settlement provider appointed by a court of competent jurisdiction who transfers or assigns ownership of viaticated policies pursuant to that court’s order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-237; s. 3, ch. 2009-242.</History></Section>