<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0517.1215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements, rules of conduct, and prohibited business practices for investment advisors and their associated persons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall specify by rule requirements for investment advisors deemed to have custody of client funds which concern the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notification of custody of, maintenance of, and safeguards for client funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Communications with clients and independent representatives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for investment advisers who have custody of pooled investments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exceptions to the custody requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In adopting the rules, the commission shall consider the rules and regulations of the federal regulatory authority and the North American Securities Administrators Association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall by rule establish rules of conduct and prohibited business practices for investment advisers and their associated persons. In adopting the rules, the commission shall consider general industry standards as expressed in the rules and regulations of the various federal and self-regulatory agencies and regulatory associations, including, but not limited to, the United States Securities and Exchange Commission, the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority, and the North American Securities Administrators Association.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2005-237; s. 6, ch. 2009-242.</History></Section>