<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0517.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation, denial, or suspension of registration of dealer, investment adviser, associated person, or branch office.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration under s. 517.12 may be denied or any registration granted may be revoked, restricted, or suspended by the office if the office determines that such applicant or registrant; any member, principal, or director of the applicant or registrant or any person having a similar status or performing similar functions; or any person directly or indirectly controlling the applicant or registrant:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has violated any provision of this chapter or any rule or order made under this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made a material false statement in the application for registration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been guilty of a fraudulent act in connection with rendering investment advice or in connection with any sale of securities, has been or is engaged or is about to engage in making fictitious or pretended sales or purchases of any such securities or in any practice involving the rendering of investment advice or the sale of securities which is fraudulent or in violation of the law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made a misrepresentation or false statement to, or concealed any essential or material fact from, any person in the rendering of investment advice or the sale of a security to such person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to account to persons interested for all money and property received;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not delivered, after a reasonable time, to persons entitled thereto securities held or agreed to be delivered by the dealer, broker, or investment adviser, as and when paid for, and due to be delivered;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is rendering investment advice or selling or offering for sale securities through any associated person not registered in compliance with the provisions of this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has demonstrated unworthiness to transact the business of dealer, investment adviser, or associated person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has exercised management or policy control over or owned 10 percent or more of the securities of any dealer or investment adviser that has been declared bankrupt, or had a trustee appointed under the Securities Investor Protection Act; or is, in the case of a dealer or investment adviser, insolvent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been convicted of, or has entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, regardless of whether adjudication was withheld, a crime against the laws of this state or any other state or of the United States or of any other country or government which relates to registration as a dealer, investment adviser, issuer of securities, associated person, or branch office; which relates to the application for such registration; or which involves moral turpitude or fraudulent or dishonest dealing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has had a final judgment entered against her or him in a civil action upon grounds of fraud, embezzlement, misrepresentation, or deceit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is of bad business repute;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been the subject of any decision, finding, injunction, suspension, prohibition, revocation, denial, judgment, or administrative order by any court of competent jurisdiction, administrative law judge, or by any state or federal agency, national securities, commodities, or option exchange, or national securities, commodities, or option association, involving a violation of any federal or state securities or commodities law or any rule or regulation promulgated thereunder, or any rule or regulation of any national securities, commodities, or options exchange or national securities, commodities, or options association, or has been the subject of any injunction or adverse administrative order by a state or federal agency regulating banking, insurance, finance or small loan companies, real estate, mortgage brokers or lenders, money transmitters, or other related or similar industries. For purposes of this subsection, the office may not deny registration to any applicant who has been continuously registered with the office for 5 years after the date of entry of such decision, finding, injunction, suspension, prohibition, revocation, denial, judgment, or administrative order provided such decision, finding, injunction, suspension, prohibition, revocation, denial, judgment, or administrative order has been timely reported to the office pursuant to the commission’s rules; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Made payment to the office for a registration or notice filing with a check or electronic transmission of funds that is dishonored by the applicant’s, registrant’s, or notice filer’s financial institution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment or anticipated payment of any amount from the Securities Guaranty Fund in settlement of a claim or in satisfaction of a judgment against an applicant or registrant constitutes prima facie grounds for the denial of the applicant’s application for registration or the revocation of the registrant’s registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the office determines to deny an application or revoke a registration, it shall enter a final order with its findings on the register of dealers and associated persons; and denial, suspension, or revocation of the registration of a dealer or investment adviser shall also deny, suspend, or revoke the registration of all her or his associated persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be sufficient cause for denial of an application or revocation of registration, in the case of a partnership, corporation, or unincorporated association, if any member of the partnership or any officer, director, or ultimate equitable owner of the corporation or association has committed any act or omission which would be cause for denying, revoking, restricting, or suspending the registration of an individual dealer, investment adviser, or associated person. As used in this subsection, “ultimate equitable owner” means a natural person who directly or indirectly owns or controls an ownership interest in the corporation, partnership, association, or other legal entity however organized, regardless of whether such natural person owns or controls such ownership interest through one or more proxies, powers of attorney, nominees, corporations, associations, partnerships, trusts, joint stock companies, or other entities or devices, or any combination thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may deny any request to terminate or withdraw any application or registration if the office believes that an act which would be a ground for denial, suspension, restriction, or revocation under this chapter has been committed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration under s. 517.12 may be denied or any registration granted may be suspended or restricted if an applicant or registrant is charged, in a pending enforcement action or pending criminal prosecution, with any conduct that would authorize denial or revocation under subsection (1). Registration under s. 517.12 may be suspended or restricted if a registrant is arrested for any conduct that would authorize revocation under subsection (1).</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any denial of registration ordered under this subsection shall be without prejudice to the applicant’s ability to reapply for registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any order of suspension or restriction under this subsection shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take effect only after a hearing, unless no hearing is requested by the registrant or unless the suspension or restriction is made in accordance with s. 120.60(6).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain a finding that evidence of a prima facie case supports the charge made in the enforcement action or criminal prosecution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operate for no longer than 10 days beyond receipt of notice by the office of termination with respect to the registrant of the enforcement action or criminal prosecution.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “enforcement action” means any judicial proceeding or any administrative proceeding where such judicial or administrative proceeding is brought by an agency of the United States or of any state to enforce or restrain violation of any state or federal law, or any disciplinary proceeding maintained by the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority, the National Futures Association, or any other similar self-regulatory organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An enforcement action is pending at any time after notice to the applicant or registrant of such action and is terminated at any time after entry of final judgment or decree in the case of judicial proceedings, final agency action in the case of administrative proceedings, and final disposition by a self-regulatory organization in the case of disciplinary proceedings.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A criminal prosecution is pending at any time after criminal charges are filed and is terminated at any time after conviction, acquittal, or dismissal.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-435; s. 5, ch. 80-254; s. 393, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 8, ch. 84-159; s. 11, ch. 85-165; s. 10, ch. 86-85; s. 5, ch. 87-316; ss. 13, 14, 15, ch. 90-362; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 7, ch. 92-45; s. 243, ch. 96-410; s. 1169, ch. 97-103; s. 10, ch. 98-221; s. 601, ch. 2003-261; s. 39, ch. 2006-213; s. 9, ch. 2009-242.</History></Section>