<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0517.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cease and desist orders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may issue and serve upon a person a cease and desist order whenever the office has reason to believe that such person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this chapter, any rule or order promulgated by the commission or office, or any written agreement entered into with the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the office finds that conduct described in subsection (1) presents an immediate danger to the public requiring an immediate final order, it may issue an emergency cease and desist order reciting with particularity the facts underlying such findings. The emergency cease and desist order is effective immediately upon service of a copy of the order on the respondent named therein and remains effective for 90 days. If the office begins nonemergency cease and desist proceedings under subsection (1), the emergency cease and desist order remains effective until conclusion of the proceedings under ss. 120.569 and 120.57.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may impose and collect an administrative fine against any person found to have violated any provision of this chapter, any rule or order promulgated by the commission or office, or any written agreement entered into with the office in an amount not to exceed $10,000 for each such violation. All fines collected hereunder shall be deposited as received in the Anti-Fraud Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may bar, permanently or for a specific time period, any person found to have violated any provision of this chapter, any rule or order adopted by the commission or office, or any written agreement entered into with the office from submitting an application or notification for a license or registration with the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-435; s. 5, ch. 80-254; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 11, ch. 86-85; ss. 14, 15, ch. 90-362; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 244, ch. 96-410; s. 606, ch. 2003-261; s. 12, ch. 2009-242.</History></Section>