<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0517.302" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal penalties; alternative fine; Anti-Fraud Trust Fund; time limitation for criminal prosecution.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever violates any of the provisions of this chapter is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of s. 517.312(1) by obtaining money or property of an aggregate value exceeding $50,000 from five or more persons is guilty of a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of a fine otherwise authorized by law, a person who has been convicted of or who has pleaded guilty or no contest to having engaged in conduct in violation of this chapter may be sentenced to pay a fine that does not exceed the greater of three times the gross value gained or three times the gross loss caused by such conduct, plus court costs and the costs of investigation and prosecution reasonably incurred.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the office a trust fund to be known as the Anti-Fraud Trust Fund. Any amounts assessed as costs of investigation and prosecution under this subsection shall be deposited in the trust fund. Funds deposited in the trust fund must be used, when authorized by appropriation, for investigation and prosecution of administrative, civil, and criminal actions arising under this chapter. Funds may also be used to improve the public’s awareness and understanding of prudent investing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal prosecution for offenses under this chapter is subject to the time limitations in s. 775.15.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-102; s. 488, ch. 71-136; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 4, 5, ch. 80-254; s. 397, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 13, ch. 86-85; ss. 12, 14, 15, ch. 90-362; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 97-90; s. 11, ch. 98-221; s. 609, ch. 2003-261; s. 151, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>