<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0553.98" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Development of building codes for radon-resistant buildings; funding; rules for radon-resistant passive construction standards; ordinances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall be provided funds for activities incidental to the development and implementation of the building codes for radon-resistant buildings and for such other building code-related activities as directed by the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules for radon-resistant passive construction standards proposed by the department for residential buildings are hereby approved by the Legislature. The rules for radon-resistant commercial building standards shall be submitted by the department to the Legislature prior to becoming effective.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local jurisdictions may enact ordinances for radon-resistant building construction only pursuant to this subsection. A county governing authority and the governing bodies of the municipalities representing at least a majority of the county’s municipal population shall enter into an interlocal agreement to adopt by ordinance the department’s radon-resistant passive construction standards as a code for residential radon-resistant building construction. The standards shall apply uniformly to the entire jurisdictions that adopt the standards. No local jurisdiction may adopt any requirement for radon-resistant building construction other than the rules of the department, nor enact any other requirements relating to environmental radiation caused by the radon decay series other than the rules of the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 88-285; s. 20, ch. 93-120; s. 3, ch. 94-284; s. 3, ch. 95-339.</History></Section>