<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0553.5041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Parking spaces for persons who have disabilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is not intended to expand or diminish the defenses available to a place of public accommodation under the Americans with Disabilities Act and the federal Americans with Disabilities Act Standards for Accessible Design, including, but not limited to, the readily achievable standard, and the standards applicable to alterations to places of public accommodation and commercial facilities. Subject to the exceptions described in subsections (2), (4), (5), and (6), if the parking and loading zone requirements of the federal standards and related regulations provide increased accessibility, those requirements are adopted and incorporated by reference as the law of this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State agencies and political subdivisions having jurisdiction over street parking or publicly owned or operated parking facilities are not required to provide a greater right-of-way width than would otherwise be planned under regulations, guidelines, or practices normally applied to new development.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designated accessible spaces shall be designed and marked for the exclusive use of individuals who have a severe physical disability and have permanent or temporary mobility problems that substantially impair their ability to ambulate and who have been issued a disabled parking permit under s. 316.1958 or s. 320.0848 or a license plate under s. 320.084, s. 320.0842, s. 320.0843, or s. 320.0845.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of accessible parking spaces must comply with the parking requirements in s. 208 of the standards and the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There must be one accessible parking space in the immediate vicinity of a publicly owned or leased building that houses a governmental entity or a political subdivision, including, but not limited to, state office buildings and courthouses, if parking for the public is not provided on the premises of the building.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There must be one accessible parking space for each 150 metered on-street parking spaces provided by state agencies and political subdivisions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of parking spaces for persons who have disabilities must be increased on the basis of demonstrated and documented need.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accessible perpendicular and diagonal accessible parking spaces and loading zones must be designed and located to conform to ss. 502 and 503 of the standards.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All spaces must be located on an accessible route that is at least 44 inches wide so that users are not compelled to walk or wheel behind parked vehicles except behind his or her own vehicle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there are multiple entrances or multiple retail stores, the parking spaces must be dispersed to provide parking at the nearest accessible entrance. If a theme park or an entertainment complex as defined in s. 509.013(9) provides parking in several lots or areas from which access to the theme park or entertainment complex is provided, a single lot or area may be designated for parking by persons who have disabilities, if the lot or area is located on the shortest accessible route to an accessible entrance to the theme park or entertainment complex or to transportation to such an accessible entrance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each parking space must be at least 12 feet wide. Parking access aisles must be at least 5 feet wide and must be part of an accessible route to the building or facility entrance. The access aisle must be striped diagonally to designate it as a no-parking zone.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parking access aisles are reserved for the temporary exclusive use of persons who have disabled parking permits and who require extra space to deploy a mobility device, lift, or ramp in order to exit from or enter a vehicle. Parking is not allowed in an access aisle. Violators are subject to the same penalties imposed for illegally parking in parking spaces that are designated for persons who have disabilities. A vehicle may not be parked in an access aisle even if the vehicle owner or passenger is disabled or owns a disabled parking permit.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, a theme park or an entertainment complex as defined in s. 509.013 in which continuous attendant services are provided for directing individuals to marked accessible parking spaces or designated lots for parking by persons who have disabilities, may, in lieu of the required parking space design, provide parking spaces that comply with ss. 208 and 502 of the standards.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On-street parallel parking spaces must be designed to conform to ss. 208 and 502 of the standards, except that access aisles are not required. Curbs adjacent to such spaces must be of a height that does not interfere with the opening and closing of motor vehicle doors. This subsection does not relieve the owner of the responsibility to comply with the parking requirements of ss. 208 and 502 of the standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The removal of architectural barriers from a parking facility in accordance with 28 C.F.R. s. 36.304 or with s. 553.508 must comply with this section unless compliance would cause the barrier removal not to be readily achievable. If compliance would cause the barrier removal not to be readily achievable, a facility may provide parking spaces at alternative locations for persons who have disabilities and provide appropriate signage directing such persons to the alternative parking if readily achievable. The facility may not reduce the required number or dimensions of those spaces or unreasonably increase the length of the accessible route from a parking space to the facility. The removal of an architectural barrier must not create a significant risk to the health or safety of a person who has a disability or to others.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that is making alterations under s. 553.507(2) must comply with this section to the maximum extent feasible. If compliance with parking location requirements is not feasible, the facility may provide parking spaces at alternative locations for persons who have disabilities and provide appropriate signage directing such persons to alternative parking. The facility may not reduce the required number or dimensions of those spaces, or unnecessarily increase the length of the accessible route from a parking space to the facility. The alteration must not create a significant risk to the health or safety of a person who has a disability or to others.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each such parking space must be striped in a manner that is consistent with the standards of the controlling jurisdiction for other spaces and prominently outlined with blue paint, and must be repainted when necessary, to be clearly distinguishable as a parking space designated for persons who have disabilities. The space must be posted with a permanent above-grade sign of a color and design approved by the Department of Transportation, which is placed on or at least 60 inches above the finished floor or ground surface measured to the bottom of the sign and which bears the international symbol of accessibility meeting the requirements of s. 703.7.2.1 of the standards and the caption “PARKING BY DISABLED PERMIT ONLY.” Such a sign erected after October 1, 1996, must indicate the penalty for illegal use of the space. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in a theme park or an entertainment complex as defined in s. 509.013 in which accessible parking is located in designated lots or areas, the signage indicating the lot as reserved for accessible parking may be located at the entrances to the lot in lieu of a sign at each parking place. This subsection does not relieve the owner of the responsibility of complying with the signage requirements of s. 502.6 of the standards.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 66, ch. 2000-141; s. 24, ch. 2011-222; s. 12, ch. 2012-13.</History>
</Section>