<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0553.75" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Organization of commission; rules and regulations; meetings; staff; fiscal affairs; public comment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall meet on call of the secretary. The commission shall annually elect from its appointive members such officers as it may choose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall meet at the call of its chair, at the request of a majority of its membership, at the request of the department, or at such times as may be prescribed by its rules. The members shall be notified in writing of the time and place of a regular or special meeting at least 7 days in advance of the meeting. A majority of members of the commission shall constitute a quorum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall be responsible for the provision of administrative and staff support services relating to the functions of the commission. With respect to matters within the jurisdiction of the commission, the department shall be responsible for the implementation and faithful discharge of all decisions of the commission made pursuant to its authority under the provisions of this part. The department is specifically authorized to use communications media technology in conducting meetings of the commission or any meetings held in conjunction with meetings of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meetings of the commission shall be conducted so as to encourage participation by interested persons in attendance. At a minimum, the commission shall provide one opportunity for interested members of the public in attendance at a meeting to comment on each proposed action of the commission before a final vote is taken on any motion.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 74-167; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 2, 3, 4, ch. 81-7; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 5, 6, ch. 91-172; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 804, ch. 97-103; s. 42, ch. 98-287; s. 12, ch. 2008-191.</History></Section>