<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0553.902" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exempted building” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any building or portion thereof whose peak design rate of energy usage for all purposes is less than 1 watt (3.4 Btu per hour) per square foot of floor area for all purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any building which is neither heated nor cooled by a mechanical system designed to control or modify the indoor temperature and powered by electricity or fossil fuels.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any building for which federal mandatory standards preempt state energy codes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any historical building as described in s. 267.021(3).</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Florida Building Commission may recommend to the Legislature additional types of buildings which should be exempted from compliance with the Florida Energy Efficiency Code for Building Construction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“HVAC” means a system of heating, ventilating, and air-conditioning.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Renovated building” means a residential or nonresidential building undergoing alteration that varies or changes insulation, HVAC systems, water heating systems, or exterior envelope conditions, provided the estimated cost of renovation exceeds 30 percent of the assessed value of the structure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local enforcement agency” means the agency of local government which has the authority to make inspections of buildings and to enforce the Florida Building Code. It includes any agency within the definition of s. 553.71(5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exterior envelope physical characteristics” means the physical nature of those elements of a building which enclose conditioned spaces through which energy may be transferred to or from the exterior.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Energy performance level” means the indicator of the energy-related performance of a building, including, but not limited to, the levels of insulation, the amount and type of glass, and the HVAC and water heating system efficiencies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-128; s. 3, ch. 80-193; ss. 2, 5, ch. 81-226; s. 2, ch. 82-197; s. 82, ch. 83-55; s. 2, ch. 88-213; s. 94, ch. 2000-141; ss. 32, 33, ch. 2001-63; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372.</History></Section>