<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0553.792" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Building permit application to local government.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 days of an applicant submitting an application to the local government, the local government shall advise the applicant what information, if any, is needed to deem the application properly completed in compliance with the filing requirements published by the local government. If the local government does not provide written notice that the applicant has not submitted the properly completed application, the application shall be automatically deemed properly completed and accepted. Within 45 days after receiving a completed application, a local government must notify an applicant if additional information is required for the local government to determine the sufficiency of the application, and shall specify the additional information that is required. The applicant must submit the additional information to the local government or request that the local government act without the additional information. While the applicant responds to the request for additional information, the 120-day period described in this subsection is tolled. Both parties may agree to a reasonable request for an extension of time, particularly in the event of a force major or other extraordinary circumstance. The local government must approve, approve with conditions, or deny the application within 120 days following receipt of a completed application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedures set forth in subsection (1) apply to the following building permit applications: accessory structure; alarm permit; nonresidential buildings less than 25,000 square feet; electric; irrigation permit; landscaping; mechanical; plumbing; residential units other than a single family unit; multifamily residential not exceeding 50 units; roofing; signs; site-plan approvals and subdivision plats not requiring public hearings or public notice; and lot grading and site alteration associated with the permit application set forth in this subsection. The procedures set forth in subsection (1) do not apply to permits for any wireless communications facilities or when a law, agency rule, or local ordinance specify different timeframes for review of local building permit applications.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 2005-147; s. 63, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>