<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0553.971" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification statements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufacturers of products covered by this part shall certify to the department that such products are in compliance with the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (3), the manufacturer shall submit a certification statement to the department for each model, containing the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name and address of manufacturer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Type of product.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Brand name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Model number, as it appears on the product name plate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name and address of laboratory where test for efficiency was performed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Date of test for efficiency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Results of the test for efficiency, expressed in terms consistent with the applicable test procedure identified in s. 553.961.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient information about the model number or other identification by which the date of manufacture can be readily ascertained.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A declaration that the product model complies with the standards established by this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every certification statement shall be dated and signed by the manufacturer attesting to its truth and accuracy under penalty of perjury. If the manufacturer is either a corporation or a business association, the certification statement shall be dated, signed, and attested to by an officer thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 45 days after receipt of a certification statement, the department shall forward to the manufacturer an acknowledgment that the statement has been received and that it is complete and accurate on its face.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufacturers or distributors of covered products that participate in a nationally recognized product certification program are exempt from the requirements of subsection (2), except that sufficient information about the model number or identification by which the date of manufacture can be readily ascertained shall be provided to the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following information shall appear on each product:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer’s or distributor’s name or brand name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The model number as used in certifying compliance with the provisions of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of manufacture, which may be coded into the model or serial number for the product.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require, by rule, other information necessary to permit the determination that products covered by this part comply with the standards established herein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-271.</History></Section>