<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0553.512" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Modifications and waivers; advisory council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Building Commission shall provide by regulation criteria for granting individual modifications of, or exceptions from, the literal requirements of this part upon a determination of unnecessary, unreasonable, or extreme hardship, provided such waivers shall not violate federal accessibility laws and regulations and shall be reviewed by the Accessibility Advisory Council. The commission shall establish by rule a fee to be paid upon submitting a request for a waiver as provided in this section. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, if an applicant for a waiver demonstrates economic hardship in accordance with 28 C.F.R. s. 36.403(f)(1), a waiver shall be granted. The commission may not consider waiving any of the requirements of s. 553.5041 unless the applicant first demonstrates that she or he has applied for and been denied waiver or variance from all local government zoning, subdivision regulations, or other ordinances that prevent compliance therewith. Further, the commission may not waive the requirement of s. 553.5041(5)(a) and (c)1. governing the minimum width of accessible routes and minimum width of accessible parking spaces.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Accessibility Advisory Council shall consist of the following seven members, who shall be knowledgeable in the area of accessibility for persons with disabilities. The Secretary of Business and Professional Regulation shall appoint the following: a representative from the Advocacy Center for Persons with Disabilities, Inc.; a representative from the Division of Blind Services; a representative from the Division of Vocational Rehabilitation; a representative from a statewide organization representing the physically handicapped; a representative from the hearing impaired; a representative from the President, Florida Council of Handicapped Organizations; and a representative of the Paralyzed Veterans of America. The terms for the first three council members appointed subsequent to October 1, 1991, shall be for 4 years, the terms for the next two council members appointed shall be for 3 years, and the terms for the next two members shall be for 2 years. Thereafter, all council member appointments shall be for terms of 4 years. No council member shall serve more than two 4-year terms subsequent to October 1, 1991. Any member of the council may be replaced by the secretary upon three unexcused absences. Upon application made in the form provided, an individual waiver or modification may be granted by the commission so long as such modification or waiver is not in conflict with more stringent standards provided in another chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided by s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meetings of the advisory council shall be held in conjunction with the regular meetings of the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 78-333; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 25, ch. 86-220; s. 5, ch. 89-97; ss. 1, 5, 6, ch. 91-172; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 93-183; s. 10, ch. 97-76; s. 68, ch. 2000-141; s. 61, ch. 2000-154; s. 13, ch. 2002-293; s. 30, ch. 2010-176; s. 412, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 553.49.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>