<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0553.74" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Building Commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Building Commission is created and located within the Department of Business and Professional Regulation for administrative purposes. Members shall be appointed by the Governor subject to confirmation by the Senate. The commission shall be composed of 25 members, consisting of the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One architect registered to practice in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The American Institute of Architects, Florida Section, is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One structural engineer registered to practice in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Engineering Society is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One air-conditioning or mechanical contractor certified to do business in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Air Conditioning Contractors Association, the Florida Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Contractors Association, and the Mechanical Contractors Association of Florida are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One electrical contractor certified to do business in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Electrical Contractors Association and the National Electrical Contractors Association, Florida Chapter, are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member from fire protection engineering or technology who is actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Chapter of the Society of Fire Protection Engineers and the Florida Fire Marshals and Inspectors Association are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One general contractor certified to do business in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Associated Builders and Contractors of Florida, the Florida Associated General Contractors Council, and the Union Contractors Association are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One plumbing contractor licensed to do business in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Association of Plumbing, Heating, and Cooling Contractors is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One roofing or sheet metal contractor certified to do business in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Roofing, Sheet Metal, and Air Conditioning Contractors Association and the Sheet Metal and Air Conditioning Contractors National Association are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One residential contractor licensed to do business in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Home Builders Association is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members who are municipal or district codes enforcement officials, one of whom is also a fire official. The Building Officials Association of Florida and the Florida Fire Marshals and Inspectors Association are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who represents the Department of Financial Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a county codes enforcement official. The Building Officials Association of Florida is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member of a Florida-based organization of persons with disabilities or a nationally chartered organization of persons with disabilities with chapters in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member of the manufactured buildings industry who is licensed to do business in this state and is actively engaged in the industry. The Florida Manufactured Housing Association is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One mechanical or electrical engineer registered to practice in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Engineering Society is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a representative of a municipality or a charter county. The Florida League of Cities and the Florida Association of Counties are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member of the building products manufacturing industry who is authorized to do business in this state and is actively engaged in the industry. The Florida Building Material Association, the Florida Concrete and Products Association, and the Fenestration Manufacturers Association are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a representative of the building owners and managers industry who is actively engaged in commercial building ownership or management. The Building Owners and Managers Association is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a representative of the insurance industry. The Florida Insurance Council is encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a representative of public education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a swimming pool contractor licensed to do business in this state and actively engaged in the profession. The Florida Swimming Pool Association and the United Pool and Spa Association are encouraged to recommend a list of candidates for consideration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a representative of the green building industry and who is a third-party commission agent, a Florida board member of the United States Green Building Council or Green Building Initiative, a professional who is accredited under the International Green Construction Code (IGCC), or a professional who is accredited under Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who shall be the chair.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person serving on the commission under paragraph (c) or paragraph (h) on October 1, 2003, and who has served less than two full terms is eligible for reappointment to the commission regardless of whether he or she meets the new qualification.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All appointments shall be for terms of 4 years. Each person who is a member of the Board of Building Codes and Standards on the effective date of this act shall serve the remainder of their term as a member of the Florida Building Commission. Any member who shall, during his or her term, cease to meet the qualifications for original appointment, through ceasing to be a practicing member of the profession indicated or otherwise, shall thereby forfeit membership on the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided by s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each appointed member is accountable to the Governor for the proper performance of the duties of the office. The Governor shall cause to be investigated any complaint or unfavorable report received concerning an action of the commission or any member and shall take appropriate action thereon. The Governor may remove from office any appointed member for malfeasance, misfeasance, neglect of duty, incompetence, permanent inability to perform official duties, or pleading guilty or nolo contendere to, or being found guilty of, a felony.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 112.313 or any other provision of law, a member of any of the commission’s technical advisory committees or a member of any other advisory committee or workgroup of the commission, does not have an impermissible conflict of interest when representing clients before the commission or one of its committees or workgroups. However, the member, in his or her capacity as member of the committee or workgroup, may not take part in any discussion on or take action on any matter in which he or she has a direct financial interest.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 74-167; s. 2, ch. 77-365; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-231; ss. 1, 3, 4, ch. 81-7; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 3, 5, 6, ch. 91-172; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 803, ch. 97-103; s. 41, ch. 98-287; s. 76, ch. 2000-141; s. 63, ch. 2000-154; s. 15, ch. 2002-293; ss. 664, 665, ch. 2003-261; s. 11, ch. 2008-191; s. 33, ch. 2010-176; s. 415, ch. 2011-142; s. 31, ch. 2011-222.</History>
</Section>