<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0553.381" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Manufacturer certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before manufacturing buildings to be located within this state or selling manufactured buildings within this state, whichever occurs later, a manufacturer must be certified by the department. The department shall certify a manufacturer upon receipt from the manufacturer and approval and verification by the department of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer’s internal quality control procedures and manuals, including any amendments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence that the manufacturer has product liability insurance for the safety and welfare of the public in amounts determined by rule of the department; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee established by the department under s. 553.37(8).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may revoke any certification upon the failure of the manufacturer to comply with the Florida Building Code or other requirements of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification of manufacturers under this section shall be for a period of 3 years, subject to renewal by the manufacturer. Upon application for renewal, the manufacturer must submit the information described in subsection (1) or a sworn statement that there has been no change in the status or content of that information since the manufacturer’s last submittal. Fees for renewal of manufacturers’ certification shall be established by the department by rule.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 84-32; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 802, ch. 97-103; ss. 61, 62, ch. 2000-141; s. 30, ch. 2001-63; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372; s. 7, ch. 2008-191.</History></Section>