<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0553.835" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Implied warranties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the courts have reached different conclusions concerning the scope and extent of the common law doctrine or theory of implied warranty of fitness and merchantability or habitability for improvements immediately supporting the structure of a new home, which creates uncertainty in the state’s fragile real estate and construction industry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to affirm the limitations to the doctrine or theory of implied warranty of fitness and merchantability or habitability associated with the construction and sale of a new home.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “offsite improvement” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street, road, driveway, sidewalk, drainage, utilities, or any other improvement or structure that is not located on or under the lot on which a new home is constructed, excluding such improvements that are shared by and part of the overall structure of two or more separately owned homes that are adjoined or attached whereby such improvements affect the fitness and merchantability or habitability of one or more of the other adjoining structures; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street, road, driveway, sidewalk, drainage, utilities, or any other improvement or structure that is located on or under the lot but that does not immediately and directly support the fitness and merchantability or habitability of the home itself.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is no cause of action in law or equity available to a purchaser of a home or to a homeowners’ association based upon the doctrine or theory of implied warranty of fitness and merchantability or habitability for damages to offsite improvements. However, this section does not alter or limit the existing rights of purchasers of homes or homeowners’ associations to pursue any other cause of action arising from defects in offsite improvements based upon contract, tort, or statute, including, but not limited to, ss. 718.203 and 719.203.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2012-161.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 3, ch. 2012-161, provides that “[t]his act shall take effect July 1, 2012, and applies to all cases accruing before, pending on, or filed after that date.”</Text></Note></Section>