<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0553.76" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">General powers of the commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is authorized to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue memoranda of procedure for its internal management and control. The commission may adopt rules related to its consensus-based decisionmaking process, including, but not limited to, super majority voting requirements for commission actions relating to the adoption of the Florida Building Code or amendments to the code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into contracts and do such things as may be necessary and incidental to the discharge of its responsibilities under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of the Florida Building Code and the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and promote, in consultation with state and local governments, other boards, advisory councils, and commissions, such recommendations as are deemed appropriate to determine and ensure consistent, effective, and efficient enforcement and compliance with the Florida Building Code, including, but not limited to, voluntary professional standards for the operation of building departments and for personnel development. Recommendations shall include, but not be limited to, provisions for coordination among and between local offices with review responsibilities and their coordination with state or regional offices with special expertise.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 74-167; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-7; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 5, 6, ch. 91-172; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 184, ch. 98-200; ss. 43, 44, ch. 98-287; s. 131, ch. 2000-141; s. 35, ch. 2001-186; s. 4, ch. 2001-372; s. 34, ch. 2010-176.</History>
</Section>