<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0253.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sale or lease of phosphate, clay, minerals, etc., in or under state lands.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund may sell or lease any phosphate, earth or clay, sand, gravel, shell, mineral, metal, timber or water, or any other substance similar to the foregoing, in, on, or under, any land the title to which is vested in the state, the Department of Management Services, the Department of Environmental Protection, the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, the State Board of Education, or any other state board, department, or agency; provided that the board of trustees may not grant such a sale or lease on the land of any other state board, department, or agency without first obtaining approval therefrom. No sale or lease provided for in this section shall be allowed on hard-surfaced beaches that are used for bathing or driving and areas contiguous thereto out to a mean low-water depth of 3 feet and landward to the nearest paved public road. Any sale or lease provided for in this section shall be conducted by competitive bidding as provided for in ss. 253.52, 253.53, and 253.54. The proceeds of such sales or leases are to be credited to the board of trustees, board, department, or agency which has title or control of the land involved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund or any other state agency authorized to grant leases under this section shall specify in each such lease, in clear and precise terms, the particular minerals for which the lessee is permitted to drill or mine and the manner in which the same may be extracted.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 9289, 1923; ss. 1, 2, ch. 9315, 1923; s. 1, ch. 13670, 1929; CGL 1936 Supp. 1438(1); s. 1, ch. 59-178; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 69-181; s. 1, ch. 69-239; s. 1, ch. 69-369; ss. 22, 25, 27, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 173, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 75, ch. 94-356; s. 73, ch. 99-245.</History></Section>