<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0253.0325" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Modernization of state lands records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection shall initiate an ongoing computerized information systems program to modernize its state lands records and documents that relate to all lands that have been acquired by all agencies under the Florida Preservation 2000 Act pursuant to s. 259.101 or the Florida Forever Act pursuant to s. 259.105. All recipients of Florida Forever funds shall annually submit their records for lands acquired for compilation of state lands records by the department. The program shall include, at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A document management component to automate the storage and retrieval of information contained in state lands records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A land records management component to organize the records by key elements present in the data.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An evaluation component which includes the collection of resource and environmental data.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mapping component to generate and store maps of state-owned parcels using data from the land records management and evaluation components.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At all stages of its records modernization program, the department shall seek to ensure information systems compatibility within the department and with other state, local, and regional governmental agencies. The department also shall seek to promote standardization in the collection of information regarding state-owned lands by federal, state, regional, and local agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information collected and stored as a result of the department’s modernization of state lands records shall not be considered a final or complete accounting of lands which the state owns or to which the state may claim ownership.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 90-217; s. 68, ch. 94-356; s. 4, ch. 2008-229.</History></Section>