<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0253.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of trustees may exchange lands.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section apply to all lands owned by, vested in, or titled in the name of the board whether the lands were acquired by the state as a purchase, or through gift, donation, or any other conveyance for which no consideration was paid.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees may exchange any lands owned by, vested in, or titled in the name of the board for other lands in the state owned by counties, local governments, individuals, or private or public corporations, and may fix the terms and conditions of any such exchange. Any nonconservation lands that were acquired by the state through gift, donation, or any other conveyance for which no consideration was paid must first be offered at no cost to a county or local government unless otherwise provided in a deed restriction of record or other legal impediment, and so long as the use proposed by the county or local government is for a public purpose. For conservation lands acquired by the state through gift, donation, or any other conveyance for which no consideration was paid, the state may request land of equal conservation value from the county or local government but no other consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In exchanging state-owned lands not acquired by the state through gift, donation, or any other conveyance for which no consideration was paid, with counties or local governments, the board shall require an exchange of equal value. Equal value is defined as the conservation benefit of the lands being offered for exchange by a county or local government being equal or greater in conservation benefit than the state-owned lands. Such exchanges may include cash transactions if based on an appropriate measure of value of the state-owned land, but must also include the determination of a net-positive conservation benefit by the Acquisition and Restoration Council, irrespective of appraised value.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall select and agree upon the state lands to be exchanged and the lands to be conveyed to the state and shall pay or receive any sum of money deemed necessary by the board for the purpose of equalizing the value of the exchanged property. The board is authorized to make and enter into contracts or agreements for such purpose or purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 8525, 1921; CGL 1432; s. 2, ch. 61-119; ss. 27, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 2003-394.</History></Section>