<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0253.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Riparian rights defined; certain submerged bottoms subject to private ownership.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Riparian rights are those incident to land bordering upon navigable waters. They are rights of ingress, egress, boating, bathing, and fishing and such others as may be or have been defined by law. Such rights are not of a proprietary nature. They are rights inuring to the owner of the riparian land but are not owned by him or her. They are appurtenant to and are inseparable from the riparian land. The land to which the owner holds title must extend to the ordinary high watermark of the navigable water in order that riparian rights may attach. Conveyance of title to or lease of the riparian land entitles the grantee to the riparian rights running therewith whether or not mentioned in the deed or lease of the upland.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Navigable waters in this state shall not be held to extend to any permanent or transient waters in the form of so-called lakes, ponds, swamps or overflowed lands, lying over and upon areas which have heretofore been conveyed to private individuals by the United States or by the state without reservation of public rights in and to said waters.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The submerged lands of any nonmeandered lake shall be deemed subject to private ownership where the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund of Florida conveyed the same more than 50 years ago without any deductions for water and without any reservation for public use and when taxes have been levied and collected on said submerged lands since conveyance by the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where private ownership of submerged bottoms outward from the shore has originated in a Spanish or other land grant approved by the Congress specifically describing an area in which was included navigable water, or by patent out of the United States prior to the date on which Florida became a state likewise containing a description including navigable water, or upon a valid conveyance out of the state, the submerged land included in such grant, patent, or conveyance shall be subject to taxes lawfully imposed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 28262, 1953; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 31, ch. 82-226; s. 200, ch. 85-342; s. 140, ch. 95-148.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 192.61(1)-(4), 271.09, 197.315(3), 197.228.</Text></Note></Section>