<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0253.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Internal Improvement Trust Fund established.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">So much of the 500,000 acres of land granted to this state for internal improvement purposes by an Act of Congress passed March 3, A. D. 1845, as remains unsold, and the proceeds of the sales of such lands heretofore sold as now remain on hand and unappropriated, and all proceeds that may hereafter accrue from the sales of such lands; and all the swampland or lands subject to overflow granted this state by an Act of Congress approved September 28, A. D. 1850, together with all the proceeds that have accrued or may hereafter accrue to the state from the sale of such lands, are set apart, and declared a separate and distinct fund called the Internal Improvement Trust Fund of the state, and are to be strictly applied according to the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All revenues received from application fees charged by the Division of State Lands for the use in any manner, lease, conveyance, or release of any interest in or for the sale of state lands, except revenues from such fees charged by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services for aquaculture leases under ss. 253.71(2) and 597.010, must be deposited into the Internal Improvement Trust Fund. The fees charged by the division for reproduction of records relating to state lands must also be placed into the fund. Revenues received by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services for aquaculture leases under ss. 253.71(2) and 597.010 shall be deposited in the General Inspection Trust Fund of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary, if title to any state-owned lands is vested in the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund and the lands are located within the Everglades Agricultural Area, then all proceeds from the sale of any such lands shall be deposited into the Internal Improvement Trust Fund. The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to those lands acquired pursuant to s. 607.0505 and former s. 620.192 or chapter 895.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All revenues accruing from sources designated by law for deposit in the Internal Improvement Trust Fund shall be used for the acquisition, management, administration, protection, and conservation of state-owned lands.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 610, 1854; RS 428; GS 616; RGS 1054; CGL 1384; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 82-185; s. 13, ch. 84-330; s. 23, ch. 89-175; s. 3, ch. 89-279; s. 16, ch. 89-324; s. 3, ch. 91-80; s. 1, ch. 91-187; s. 2, ch. 91-286; s. 1, ch. 92-109; s. 41, ch. 93-164; s. 489, ch. 94-356; s. 2, ch. 2000-364; ss. 40, 53, ch. 2001-254; s. 4, ch. 2003-2; s. 26, ch. 2006-1; s. 40, ch. 2007-73; s. 34, ch. 2008-153; s. 7, ch. 2010-4.</History>
</Section>