<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0253.77" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State lands; state agency authorization for use prohibited without consent of agency in which title vested; concurrent processing requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not commence any excavation, construction, or other activity involving the use of sovereign or other lands of the state, the title to which is vested in the board of trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund under this chapter, until the person has received the required lease, license, easement, or other form of consent authorizing the proposed use.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For applications that are processed concurrently under s. 373.427, the applicant must submit, as part of the application under this part, any information necessary to satisfy the requirements for issuance of any required:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Environmental resource permit or dredge and fill permit under part IV of chapter 373;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coastal construction permit under s. 161.041;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coastal construction control line permit under s. 161.053; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waiver or variance of the setback requirements under s. 161.052.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Authorization under this section may not be issued unless the requirements for issuance of any additional required authorizations, permits, waivers, variances, and approvals described in paragraphs (a)-(d) are also satisfied. The final action on an authorization issued under this subsection shall be subject to s. 373.4275.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, a riparian owner may selectively trim or alter mangroves on adjacent, publicly owned submerged lands, if the selective trimming or alteration is in compliance with the requirements of <Reference Number="1" />ss. 403.93-403.938, including any required permit under <Reference Number="1" />ss. 403.93-403.938.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, chapter 373, or chapter 403, for activities authorized by a permit or exemption pursuant to chapter 373 or chapter 403, ports listed in s. 403.021(9)(b) and inland navigation districts created pursuant to s. 374.975(3) shall not be required to pay any fees for activities involving the use of sovereign lands, including leases, easements, or consents of use, except application fees including, but not limited to, those required by this chapter, chapter 161, chapter 373, or chapter 403. Further, any federal, state, or local agency or political subdivision that otherwise qualifies for an exemption under chapter 373 or chapter 403 shall be granted a consent of use or public easement for land owned by the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund or any water management district upon request and legal description of the affected land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 76-245; s. 11, ch. 80-66; s. 12, ch. 84-79; s. 3, ch. 93-34; ss. 79, 495, ch. 94-356; s. 67, ch. 99-251.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Some sections within this range have been repealed; ss. 403.93-403.936 were repealed by s. 13, ch. 95-299. Section 403.938 was amended and transferred to s. 403.9333 by s. 12, ch. 95-299.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>