<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0253.55" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitation on term of lease.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the further provisions hereof, each lease shall be for a primary term prescribed by the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund not to exceed 10 years from the date of the lease, and shall provide that such lease, upon which operations are being carried on in good faith and in a skillful and diligent manner with no cessation of more than 30 consecutive days, or oil or gas is being produced therefrom in paying quantities, shall remain in force and effect. The lease shall provide that if, after production is obtained therefrom, such production should cease, the lease may be maintained, if it is within the primary term, by commencing or resuming the payment of rentals or commencing operations for drilling or reworking said land, in good faith and in a skillful and diligent manner, on or before the rental payment date next ensuing after the expiration of 60 days, or, if it be after the expiration of the primary term, the lease may be maintained in force and effect by commencing and continuing operations for drilling or reworking said land for the development and production of oil or gas on or before 60 days after the cessation of production and prosecuting same with diligence and in a skillful manner with no cessation for more than 30 consecutive days, and if such operations within a reasonable time thereafter result in the production of oil or gas from such leased land in paying quantities, the lease shall remain in effect thereafter as long as oil or gas is produced therefrom in paying quantities. The provisions of this section shall not be construed to permit the automatic renewal of a lease by option after the expiration of the primary term, nor to permit the continuance of any lease except in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each lease shall provide for its termination in the absence of drilling or reworking operations or production of oil or gas therefrom in paying quantities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 22824, 1945; s. 1, ch. 69-238; ss. 27, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 69-369; s. 124, ch. 83-217; s. 5, ch. 88-278; s. 2, ch. 89-358; s. 142, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>