<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0253.0341" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Surplus of state-owned lands to counties or local governments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Counties and local governments may submit surplusing requests for state-owned lands directly to the board of trustees. County or local government requests for the state to surplus conservation or nonconservation lands, whether for purchase or exchange, shall be expedited throughout the surplusing process. Property jointly acquired by the state and other entities shall not be surplused without the consent of all joint owners.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decision to surplus state-owned nonconservation lands may be made by the board without a review of, or a recommendation on, the request from the Acquisition and Restoration Council or the Division of State Lands. Such requests for nonconservation lands shall be considered by the board within 60 days of the board’s receipt of the request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County or local government requests for the surplusing of state-owned conservation lands are subject to review of, and recommendation on, the request to the board by the Acquisition and Restoration Council. Requests to surplus conservation lands shall be considered by the board within 120 days of the board’s receipt of the request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government may request that state lands be specifically declared surplus lands for the purpose of providing alternative water supply and water resource development projects as defined in s. 373.019, public facilities such as schools, fire and police facilities, and affordable housing. The request shall comply with the requirements of subsection (1) if the lands are nonconservation lands or subsection (2) if the lands are conservation lands. Surplus lands that are conveyed to a local government for affordable housing shall be disposed of by the local government under the provisions of s. 125.379 or s. 166.0451.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the requirements of this section and the requirements of s. 253.034 which provides a surplus process for the disposal of state lands, the board shall convey to Miami-Dade County title to the property on which the Graham Building, which houses the offices of the Miami-Dade State Attorney, is located. By January 1, 2008, the board shall convey fee simple title to the property to Miami-Dade County for a consideration of one dollar. The deed conveying title to Miami-Dade County must contain restrictions that limit the use of the property for the purpose of providing workforce housing as defined in s. 420.5095, and to house the offices of the Miami-Dade State Attorney. Employees of the Miami-Dade State Attorney and the Miami-Dade Public Defender who apply for and meet the income qualifications for workforce housing shall receive preference over other qualified applicants.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2003-394; s. 10, ch. 2006-69; s. 7, ch. 2007-198; s. 6, ch. 2008-229.</History></Section>