<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0318.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amount of penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalties required for a noncriminal disposition pursuant to s. 318.14 or a criminal offense listed in s. 318.17 are as follows:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifteen dollars for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All infractions of pedestrian regulations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All infractions of s. 316.2065, unless otherwise specified.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other violations of chapter 316 by persons 14 years of age or under who are operating bicycles, regardless of the noncriminal traffic infraction’s classification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirty dollars for all nonmoving traffic violations and:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all violations of s. 322.19.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all violations of ss. 320.0605, 320.07(1), 322.065, and 322.15(1). Any person who is cited for a violation of s. 320.07(1) shall be charged a delinquent fee pursuant to s. 320.07(4).</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person who is cited for a violation of s. 320.0605 or s. 320.07 can show proof of having a valid registration at the time of arrest, the clerk of the court may dismiss the case and may assess a dismissal fee of up to $10. A person who finds it impossible or impractical to obtain a valid registration certificate must submit an affidavit detailing the reasons for the impossibility or impracticality. The reasons may include, but are not limited to, the fact that the vehicle was sold, stolen, or destroyed; that the state in which the vehicle is registered does not issue a certificate of registration; or that the vehicle is owned by another person.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person who is cited for a violation of s. 322.03, s. 322.065, or s. 322.15 can show a driver’s license issued to him or her and valid at the time of arrest, the clerk of the court may dismiss the case and may assess a dismissal fee of up to $10.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person who is cited for a violation of s. 316.646 can show proof of security as required by s. 627.733, issued to the person and valid at the time of arrest, the clerk of the court may dismiss the case and may assess a dismissal fee of up to $10. A person who finds it impossible or impractical to obtain proof of security must submit an affidavit detailing the reasons for the impracticality. The reasons may include, but are not limited to, the fact that the vehicle has since been sold, stolen, or destroyed; that the owner or registrant of the vehicle is not required by s. 627.733 to maintain personal injury protection insurance; or that the vehicle is owned by another person.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all violations of ss. 316.2935 and 316.610. However, for a violation of s. 316.2935 or s. 316.610, if the person committing the violation corrects the defect and obtains proof of such timely repair by an affidavit of compliance executed by the law enforcement agency within 30 days from the date upon which the traffic citation was issued, and pays $4 to the law enforcement agency, thereby completing the affidavit of compliance, then upon presentation of said affidavit by the defendant to the clerk within the 30-day time period set forth under s. 318.14(4), the fine must be reduced to $10, which the clerk of the court shall retain.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all violations of s. 316.126(1)(b), unless otherwise specified.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, $60 for all moving violations not requiring a mandatory appearance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For moving violations involving unlawful speed, the fines are as follows:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For speed exceeding the limit by:<FlushRight />Fine:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">1-5 m.p.h<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />Warning</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">6-9 m.p.h<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$25</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">10-14 m.p.h<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$100</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">15-19 m.p.h<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$150</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">20-29 m.p.h<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$175</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceBelow="true">30 m.p.h. and above<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$250</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (b), a person cited for exceeding the speed limit by up to 5 m.p.h. in a legally posted school zone will be fined $50. A person exceeding the speed limit in a school zone or designated school crossing shall pay a fine double the amount listed in paragraph (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person cited for exceeding the speed limit in a posted construction zone, which posting must include notification of the speed limit and the doubling of fines, shall pay a fine double the amount listed in paragraph (b). The fine shall be doubled for construction zone violations only if construction personnel are present or operating equipment on the road or immediately adjacent to the road under construction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person cited for exceeding the speed limit in an enhanced penalty zone shall pay a fine amount of $50 plus the amount listed in paragraph (b). Notwithstanding paragraph (b), a person cited for exceeding the speed limit by up to 5 m.p.h. in a legally posted enhanced penalty zone shall pay a fine amount of $50.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a violation of s. 316.1301 or s. 316.1303(1) results in an injury to the pedestrian or damage to the property of the pedestrian, an additional fine of up to $250 shall be paid. This amount must be distributed pursuant to s. 318.21.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person cited for exceeding the speed limit within a zone posted for any electronic or manual toll collection facility shall pay a fine double the amount listed in paragraph (b). However, no person cited for exceeding the speed limit in any toll collection zone shall be subject to a doubled fine unless the governmental entity or authority controlling the toll collection zone first installs a traffic control device providing warning that speeding fines are doubled. Any such traffic control device must meet the requirements of the uniform system of traffic control devices.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person cited for a second or subsequent conviction of speed exceeding the limit by 30 miles per hour and above within a 12-month period shall pay a fine that is double the amount listed in paragraph (b). For purposes of this paragraph, the term “conviction” means a finding of guilt as a result of a jury verdict, nonjury trial, or entry of a plea of guilty. Moneys received from the increased fine imposed by this paragraph shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue and deposited into the Department of Health Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund to provide financial support to certified trauma centers to assure the availability and accessibility of trauma services throughout the state. Funds deposited into the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund under this section shall be allocated as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent shall be allocated equally among all Level I, Level II, and pediatric trauma centers in recognition of readiness costs for maintaining trauma services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent shall be allocated among Level I, Level II, and pediatric trauma centers based on each center’s relative volume of trauma cases as reported in the Department of Health Trauma Registry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalty imposed under s. 316.545 shall be determined by the officer in accordance with the provisions of ss. 316.535 and 316.545.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred dollars for a violation of s. 316.172(1)(a), failure to stop for a school bus. If, at a hearing, the alleged offender is found to have committed this offense, the court shall impose a minimum civil penalty of $100. In addition to this penalty, for a second or subsequent offense within a period of 5 years, the department shall suspend the driver’s license of the person for not less than 90 days and not more than 6 months.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two hundred dollars for a violation of s. 316.172(1)(b), passing a school bus on the side that children enter and exit when the school bus displays a stop signal. If, at a hearing, the alleged offender is found to have committed this offense, the court shall impose a minimum civil penalty of $200. In addition to this penalty, for a second or subsequent offense within a period of 5 years, the department shall suspend the driver’s license of the person for not less than 180 days and not more than 1 year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the penalty under paragraph (a) or paragraph (b), $65 for a violation of s. 316.172(1)(a) or (b). If the alleged offender is found to have committed the offense, the court shall impose the civil penalty under paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) plus an additional $65. The additional $65 collected under this paragraph shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund of the Department of Health to be used as provided in s. 395.4036.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred dollars or the fine amount designated by county ordinance, plus court costs for illegally parking, under s. 316.1955, in a parking space provided for people who have disabilities. However, this fine shall be waived if a person provides to the law enforcement agency or parking enforcement specialist or agency that issued the citation for such a violation proof that the person committing the violation has a valid parking permit or license plate issued pursuant to s. 316.1958, s. 320.0842, s. 320.0843, s. 320.0845, or s. 320.0848 or a signed affidavit that the owner of the disabled parking permit or license plate was present at the time the violation occurred, and that such a parking permit or license plate was valid at the time the violation occurred. The law enforcement officer or agency or the parking enforcement specialist or agency, upon determining that all required documentation has been submitted verifying that the required parking permit or license plate was valid at the time of the violation, must sign an affidavit of compliance. Upon provision of the affidavit of compliance and payment of a dismissal fee of up to $7.50 to the clerk of the circuit court, the clerk shall dismiss the citation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mandatory $100 fine for each violation of s. 316.1001 plus the amount of the unpaid toll shown on the traffic citation for each citation issued. The clerk of the court shall forward $25 of the $100 fine received, plus the amount of the unpaid toll that is shown on the citation, to the governmental entity that issued the citation for citations issued by toll enforcement officers or to the entity administering the tolls at the facility where the violation occurred for citations issued by law enforcement officers. However, a person may elect to pay $30 to the clerk of the court, plus the amount of the unpaid toll that is shown on the citation, in which case adjudication is withheld, and no points may be assessed under s. 322.27. Upon receipt of the $30 and unpaid toll amount, the clerk of the court shall retain $5 for administrative purposes and shall forward the remaining $25, plus the amount of the unpaid toll shown on the citation, to the governmental entity that issued the citation for citations issued by toll enforcement officers or to the entity administering the tolls at the facility where the violation occurred for citations issued by law enforcement officers. Additionally, adjudication shall be withheld and no points shall be assessed under s. 322.27, except when adjudication is imposed by the court after a hearing pursuant to s. 318.14(5). If a plea arrangement is reached prior to the date set for a scheduled evidentiary hearing and, as a result of the plea, adjudication is withheld, there shall be a mandatory fine assessed per citation of not less than $50 and not more than $100, plus the amount of the unpaid toll for each citation issued. The clerk of the court shall forward $25 of the fine imposed plus the amount of the unpaid toll that is shown on the citation to the governmental entity that issued the citation for citations issued by toll enforcement officers or to the entity administering the tolls at the facility where the violation occurred for citations issued by law enforcement officers. The court shall have specific authority to consolidate issued citations for the same defendant for the purpose of sentencing and aggregate jurisdiction. In addition, the court may direct the department to suspend for 60 days the driver’s license of a person who is convicted of 10 violations of s. 316.1001 within a 36-month period. Any funds received by a governmental entity for this violation may be used for any lawful purpose related to the operation or maintenance of a toll facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to comply with the court’s requirements or who fails to pay the civil penalties specified in this section within the 30-day period provided for in s. 318.14 must pay an additional civil penalty of $16, $6.50 of which must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit in the General Revenue Fund, and $9.50 of which must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit in the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund. Of this additional civil penalty of $16, $4 is not revenue for purposes of s. 28.36 and may not be used in establishing the budget of the clerk of the court under that section or s. 28.35. The department shall contract with the Florida Association of Court Clerks, Inc., to design, establish, operate, upgrade, and maintain an automated statewide Uniform Traffic Citation Accounting System to be operated by the clerks of the court which shall include, but not be limited to, the accounting for traffic infractions by type, a record of the disposition of the citations, and an accounting system for the fines assessed and the subsequent fine amounts paid to the clerks of the court. On or before December 1, 2001, the clerks of the court must provide the information required by this chapter to be transmitted to the department by electronic transmission pursuant to the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person has been ordered to pay a civil penalty for a noncriminal traffic infraction and the person is unable to comply with the court’s order due to demonstrable financial hardship, the court shall allow the person to satisfy the civil penalty by participating in community service until the civil penalty is paid.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a court orders a person to perform community service, the person shall receive credit for the civil penalty at the specified hourly credit rate per hour of community service performed, and each hour of community service performed shall reduce the civil penalty by that amount.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term “specified hourly credit rate” means the wage rate that is specified in 29 U.S.C. s. 206(a)(1) under the federal Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, that is then in effect, and that an employer subject to such provision must pay per hour to each employee subject to such provision.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, if a person ordered to perform community service has a trade or profession for which there is a community service need, the specified hourly credit rate for each hour of community service performed by that person shall be the average prevailing wage rate for the trade or profession that the community service agency needs.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The community service agency supervising the person shall record the number of hours of community service completed and the date the community service hours were completed. The community service agency shall submit the data to the clerk of court on the letterhead of the community service agency, which must also bear the notarized signature of the person designated to represent the community service agency.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the number of community service hours completed by the person equals the amount of the civil penalty, the clerk of court shall certify this fact to the court. Thereafter, the clerk of court shall record in the case file that the civil penalty has been paid in full.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community service” means uncompensated labor for a community service agency.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community service agency” means a not-for-profit corporation, community organization, charitable organization, public officer, the state or any political subdivision of the state, or any other body the purpose of which is to improve the quality of life or social welfare of the community and which agrees to accept community service from persons unable to pay civil penalties for noncriminal traffic infractions.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the noncriminal infraction has caused or resulted in the death of another, the person who committed the infraction may perform 120 community service hours under s. 316.027(4), in addition to any other penalties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred dollars for a violation of s. 316.1575.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five dollars for a violation of s. 316.2074.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the stated fine, court costs must be paid in the following amounts and shall be deposited by the clerk into the fine and forfeiture fund established pursuant to s. 142.01:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">For pedestrian infractions<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$4.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">For nonmoving traffic infractions<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$18.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">For moving traffic infractions<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$35.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the court cost required under paragraph (a), up to $3 for each infraction shall be collected and distributed by the clerk in those counties that have been authorized to establish a criminal justice selection center or a criminal justice access and assessment center pursuant to the following special acts of the Legislature:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 87-423, Laws of Florida, for Brevard County.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 89-521, Laws of Florida, for Bay County.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 94-444, Laws of Florida, for Alachua County.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 97-333, Laws of Florida, for Pinellas County.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Funds collected by the clerk pursuant to this paragraph shall be distributed to the centers authorized by those special acts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the court cost required under paragraph (a), a $2.50 court cost must be paid for each infraction to be distributed by the clerk to the county to help pay for criminal justice education and training programs pursuant to s. 938.15. Funds from the distribution to the county not directed by the county to fund these centers or programs shall be retained by the clerk and used for funding the court-related services of the clerk.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the court cost required under paragraph (a), a $3 court cost must be paid for each infraction to be distributed as provided in s. 938.01 and a $2 court cost as provided in s. 938.15 when assessed by a municipality or county.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two hundred dollars for a violation of s. 316.520(1) or (2). If, at a hearing, the alleged offender is found to have committed this offense, the court shall impose a minimum civil penalty of $200. For a second or subsequent adjudication within a period of 5 years, the department shall suspend the driver’s license of the person for not less than 1 year and not more than 2 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any penalties imposed for noncriminal traffic infractions pursuant to this chapter or imposed for criminal violations listed in s. 318.17, a board of county commissioners or any unit of local government that is consolidated as provided by s. 9, Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1885, as preserved by s. 6(e), Art. VIII of the Constitution of 1968:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May impose by ordinance a surcharge of up to $30 for any infraction or violation to fund state court facilities. The court shall not waive this surcharge. Up to 25 percent of the revenue from such surcharge may be used to support local law libraries provided that the county or unit of local government provides a level of service equal to that provided prior to July 1, 2004, which shall include the continuation of library facilities located in or near the county courthouse or any annex to the courthouse.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May, if such board or unit imposed increased fees or service charges by ordinance under s. 28.2401, s. 28.241, or s. 34.041 for the purpose of securing payment of the principal and interest on bonds issued by the county before July 1, 2003, to finance state court facilities, impose by ordinance a surcharge for any infraction or violation for the exclusive purpose of securing payment of the principal and interest on bonds issued by the county before July 1, 2003, to fund state court facilities until the date of stated maturity. The court shall not waive this surcharge. Such surcharge may not exceed an amount per violation calculated as the quotient of the maximum annual payment of the principal and interest on the bonds as of July 1, 2003, divided by the number of traffic citations for county fiscal year 2002-2003 certified as paid by the clerk of the court of the county. Such quotient shall be rounded up to the next highest dollar amount. The bonds may be refunded only if savings will be realized on payments of debt service and the refunding bonds are scheduled to mature on the same date or before the bonds being refunded. Notwithstanding any of the foregoing provisions of this subparagraph that limit the use of surcharge revenues, if the revenues generated as a result of the adoption of this ordinance exceed the debt service on the bonds, the surplus revenues may be used to pay down the debt service on the bonds; fund other state-court-facility construction projects as may be certified by the chief judge as necessary to address unexpected growth in caseloads, emergency requirements to accommodate public access, threats to the safety of the public, judges, staff, and litigants, or other exigent circumstances; or support local law libraries in or near the county courthouse or any annex to the courthouse.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May impose by ordinance a surcharge for any infraction or violation for the exclusive purpose of securing payment of the principal and interest on bonds issued by the county on or after July 1, 2009, to fund state court facilities until the stated date of maturity. The court may not waive this surcharge. The surcharge may not exceed an amount per violation calculated as the quotient of the maximum annual payment of the principal and interest on the bonds, divided by the number of traffic citations certified as paid by the clerk of the court of the county on August 15 of each year. The quotient shall be rounded up to the next highest dollar amount. The bonds may be refunded if savings are realized on payments of debt service and the refunding bonds are scheduled to mature on or before the maturity date of the bonds being refunded. If the revenues generated as a result of the adoption of the ordinance exceed the debt service on the bonds, the surplus revenues may be used to pay the debt service on the bonds; to fund other state court facility construction projects certified by the chief judge as necessary to address unexpected growth in caseloads, emergency requirements to accommodate public access, threats to the safety of the public, judges, staff, and litigants, or other exigent circumstances; or to support local law libraries in or near the county courthouse or any annex to the courthouse.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county may impose a surcharge under subparagraph (a)1., subparagraph(a)2., or subparagraph(a)3., but may not impose more than one surcharge under this subsection. A county may elect to impose a different authorized surcharge but may not impose more than one surcharge at a time. The clerk of court shall report, no later than 30 days after the end of the quarter, the amount of funds collected under this subsection during each quarter of the fiscal year. The clerk shall submit the report, in an electronic format developed by the Florida Clerks of Court Operations Corporation, to the chief judge of the circuit and to the Florida Clerks of Court Operations Corporation. The corporation shall submit the report in an electronic format to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the board of county commissioners.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any penalties imposed for noncriminal traffic infractions under this chapter or imposed for criminal violations listed in s. 318.17, any unit of local government that is consolidated as provided by s. 9, Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1885, as preserved by s. 6(e), Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1968, and that is granted the authority in the State Constitution to exercise all the powers of a municipal corporation, and any unit of local government operating under a home rule charter adopted pursuant to ss. 10, 11, and 24, Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1885, as preserved by s. 6(e), Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1968, that is granted the authority in the State Constitution to exercise all the powers conferred now or hereafter by general law upon municipalities, may impose by ordinance a surcharge of up to $15 for any infraction or violation. Revenue from the surcharge shall be transferred to such unit of local government for the purpose of replacing fine revenue deposited into the clerk’s fine and forfeiture fund under s. 142.01. The court may not waive this surcharge. Proceeds from the imposition of the surcharge authorized in this subsection shall not be used for the purpose of securing payment of the principal and interest on bonds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred and fifty-eight dollars for a violation of s. 316.074(1) or s. 316.075(1)(c)1. when a driver has failed to stop at a traffic signal and when enforced by a law enforcement officer. Sixty dollars shall be distributed as provided in s. 318.21, $30 shall be distributed to the General Revenue Fund, $3 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Brain and Spinal Cord Injury Trust Fund, and the remaining $65 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund of the Department of Health.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred and fifty-eight dollars for a violation of s. 316.074(1) or s. 316.075(1)(c)1. when a driver has failed to stop at a traffic signal and when enforced by the department’s traffic infraction enforcement officer. One hundred dollars shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund, $45 shall be distributed to the county for any violations occurring in any unincorporated areas of the county or to the municipality for any violations occurring in the incorporated boundaries of the municipality in which the infraction occurred, $10 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Department of Health Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund for distribution as provided in s. 395.4036(1), and $3 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Brain and Spinal Cord Injury Trust Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred and fifty-eight dollars for a violation of s. 316.074(1) or s. 316.075(1)(c)1. when a driver has failed to stop at a traffic signal and when enforced by a county’s or municipality’s traffic infraction enforcement officer. Seventy-five dollars shall be distributed to the county or municipality issuing the traffic citation, $70 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund, $10 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Department of Health Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund for distribution as provided in s. 395.4036(1), and $3 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Brain and Spinal Cord Injury Trust Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amounts deposited into the Brain and Spinal Cord Injury Trust Fund pursuant to this subsection shall be distributed quarterly to the Miami Project to Cure Paralysis and shall be used for brain and spinal cord research.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person who is cited for a violation of s. 316.074(1) or s. 316.075(1)(c)1., as enforced by a traffic infraction enforcement officer under s. 316.0083, presents documentation from the appropriate governmental entity that the traffic citation was in error, the clerk of court may dismiss the case. The clerk of court shall not charge for this service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual may not receive a commission or per-ticket fee from any revenue collected from violations detected through the use of a traffic infraction detector. A manufacturer or vendor may not receive a fee or remuneration based upon the number of violations detected through the use of a traffic infraction detector.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds deposited into the Department of Health Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund under this subsection shall be distributed as provided in s. 395.4036(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred dollars for a violation of s. 316.622(3) or (4), for a vehicle that fails to display a sticker authorizing it to transport migrant or seasonal farm workers or fails to display standardized notification instructions requiring passengers to fasten their seat belts. Two hundred dollars for a violation of s. 316.622(1) or (2), for operating a farm labor vehicle that fails to conform to vehicle safety standards or lacks seat belt assemblies at each passenger position.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any penalties imposed, a surcharge of $3 must be paid for all criminal offenses listed in s. 318.17 and for all noncriminal moving traffic violations under chapter 316. Revenue from the surcharge shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue and deposited quarterly into the State Agency Law Enforcement Radio System Trust Fund of the Department of Management Services for the state agency law enforcement radio system, as described in s. 282.709, and to provide technical assistance to state agencies and local law enforcement agencies with their statewide systems of regional law enforcement communications, as described in s. 282.7101. This subsection expires July 1, 2021. The Department of Management Services may retain funds sufficient to recover the costs and expenses incurred for managing, administering, and overseeing the Statewide Law Enforcement Radio System, and providing technical assistance to state agencies and local law enforcement agencies with their statewide systems of regional law enforcement communications. The Department of Management Services working in conjunction with the Joint Task Force on State Agency Law Enforcement Communications shall determine and direct the purposes for which these funds are used to enhance and improve the radio system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any penalties imposed, an administrative fee of $12.50 must be paid for all noncriminal moving and nonmoving violations under chapters 316, 320, and 322. Revenue from the administrative fee shall be deposited by the clerk of court into the fine and forfeiture fund established pursuant to s. 142.01.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any penalties imposed, an Article V assessment of $10 must be paid for all noncriminal moving and nonmoving violations under chapters 316, 320, and 322. The assessment is not revenue for purposes of s. 28.36 and may not be used in establishing the budget of the clerk of the court under that section or s. 28.35. Of the funds collected under this subsection:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sum of $5 shall be deposited in the State Courts Revenue Trust Fund for use by the state courts system;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sum of $3.33 shall be deposited in the State Attorneys Revenue Trust Fund for use by the state attorneys; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sum of $1.67 shall be deposited in the Public Defenders Revenue Trust Fund for use by the public defenders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalty, $65 for a violation of s. 316.191, prohibiting racing on highways, or s. 316.192, prohibiting reckless driving. The additional $65 collected under this subsection shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund of the Department of Health to be used as provided in s. 395.4036.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred dollars for a violation of s. 316.1951 for a vehicle that is unlawfully displayed for sale, hire, or rental. Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, fines collected under this subsection shall be retained by the governing authority that authorized towing of the vehicle. Fines collected by the department shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-377; s. 38, ch. 76-31; s. 3, ch. 79-27; s. 1, ch. 80-179; s. 195, ch. 81-259; s. 2, ch. 82-58; s. 2, ch. 84-73; s. 15, ch. 84-359; s. 25, ch. 85-167; s. 3, ch. 85-250; s. 2, ch. 85-255; s. 6, ch. 85-309; s. 4, ch. 85-337; s. 3, ch. 86-49; s. 7, ch. 86-154; s. 4, ch. 86-185; s. 3, ch. 86-260; s. 2, ch. 87-108; s. 2, ch. 87-167; ss. 2, 5, ch. 88-50; s. 2, ch. 88-305; ss. 61, 72, ch. 88-381; s. 6, ch. 89-212; s. 2, ch. 90-141; s. 8, ch. 90-290; ss. 10, 26, ch. 90-330; s. 3, ch. 91-136; s. 3, ch. 91-200; s. 1, ch. 92-192; s. 21, ch. 93-164; s. 14, ch. 94-306; s. 2, ch. 96-185; s. 8, ch. 96-200; s. 47, ch. 96-350; s. 2, ch. 97-10; s. 9, ch. 97-76; s. 13, ch. 97-225; ss. 3, 4, ch. 97-300; s. 4, ch. 98-202; s. 6, ch. 98-223; s. 8, ch. 98-251; s. 3, ch. 98-319; ss. 9, 252, ch. 99-248; s. 42, ch. 2000-152; s. 10, ch. 2001-122; s. 4, ch. 2001-196; s. 107, ch. 2002-20; s. 4, ch. 2002-217; s. 6, ch. 2002-235; s. 99, ch. 2003-402; s. 60, ch. 2004-265; s. 3, ch. 2005-194; s. 48, ch. 2005-236; s. 4, ch. 2006-81; s. 24, ch. 2006-290; s. 3, ch. 2006-296; s. 1, ch. 2007-71; s. 21, ch. 2007-196; s. 33, ch. 2008-111; s. 1, ch. 2008-137; s. 1, ch. 2008-205; s. 3, ch. 2009-6; s. 1, ch. 2009-14; s. 12, ch. 2009-61; s. 32, ch. 2009-80; s. 1, ch. 2009-138; s. 16, ch. 2009-204; s. 58, ch. 2010-5; s. 12, ch. 2010-80; s. 3, ch. 2010-161; s. 24, ch. 2010-162; s. 5, ch. 2010-198; s. 13, ch. 2010-223; s. 14, ch. 2010-225; s. 15, ch. 2012-100; s. 7, ch. 2012-123; s. 6, ch. 2012-141; s. 1, ch. 2012-157; ss. 18, 75, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>