<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0318.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction; limitations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hearing officers shall be empowered to accept pleas from and decide the guilt or innocence of any person, adult or juvenile, charged with any civil traffic infraction and shall be empowered to adjudicate or withhold adjudication of guilt in the same manner as a county court judge under the statutes, rules, and procedures presently existing or as subsequently amended, except that hearing officers shall not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have the power to hold a defendant in contempt of court, but shall be permitted to file a motion for order of contempt with the appropriate state trial court judge;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hear a case involving a crash resulting in injury or death;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hear a criminal traffic offense case or a case involving a civil traffic infraction issued in conjunction with a criminal traffic offense; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have the power to suspend or revoke a defendant’s driver’s license pursuant to s. 316.655(2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit a county court judge from exercising concurrent jurisdiction with a civil traffic hearing officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the request of the defendant contained in a Notice of Appearance or a written plea, the case shall be assigned to a county court judge regularly assigned to hear traffic matters.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 89-337; s. 1, ch. 91-152; s. 4, ch. 94-202; s. 255, ch. 99-248; s. 51, ch. 2005-236; s. 26, ch. 2006-290.</History></Section>