<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0318.143" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sanctions for infractions by minors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that a minor has committed a violation of any of the provisions of chapter 316, the court may also impose one or more of the following sanctions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may reprimand or counsel the minor and his or her parents or guardian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may require the minor to attend, for a reasonable period, a traffic school conducted by a public authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may order the minor to remit to the general fund of the local governmental body a sum not exceeding the maximum fine applicable to an adult for a like offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may order the minor to participate in public service or a community work project for a minimum number of hours. A minor who participates in such a work program is considered an employee of the state for the purposes of chapter 440.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may impose a curfew or other restriction on the liberty of the minor for a period not to exceed 6 months.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may require the minor and his or her parents or guardians to participate in a registered youthful driver monitoring service as described in s. 318.1435.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with one or more of the sanctions imposed by the court constitutes contempt of court. Upon a finding by the court, after notice and a hearing, that a minor is in contempt of court for failure to comply with court-ordered sanctions, the court may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a first offense, order the minor to serve up to 5 days in a staff-secure shelter as defined in chapter 984 or chapter 985 or, if space in a staff-secure shelter is unavailable, in a secure juvenile detention center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second or subsequent offense, the court may order a minor to serve up to 15 days in a staff-secure shelter or, if space in a staff-secure shelter is unavailable, in a secure juvenile detention center.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for a conviction of a violation of s. 316.027, a minor may not be imprisoned in an adult detention facility. If a minor is imprisoned for a violation of s. 316.027, the minor may not be placed in the same cell as an adult. The receiving facility must have adequate staff to supervise and monitor the minor’s activities at all times. This subsection does not prohibit placing two or more minors in the same cell.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the first conviction for a violation of s. 316.193, the court may order the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to revoke the minor’s driver’s license until the minor is 18 years of age. For a second or subsequent conviction for such a violation, the court may order the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to revoke the minor’s driver’s license until the minor is 21 years of age.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minor who is arrested for a violation of s. 316.193 may be released from custody as soon as:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor is no longer under the influence of alcoholic beverages, of any chemical substance set forth in s. 877.111, or of any substance controlled under chapter 893, and is not affected to the extent that his or her normal faculties are impaired;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor’s blood-alcohol level is less than 0.05 percent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Six hours have elapsed after the minor’s arrest.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 45, ch. 96-350; s. 28, ch. 98-280; s. 21, ch. 2006-290.</History></Section>