<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.1165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Executive branch personnel errors; limitation of actions for compensation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency of the executive branch, including the State University System, shall establish procedures for the receipt, consideration, and disposition of a claim regarding pay or benefits brought by an employee when that employee is damaged as a result of being provided with erroneous written information by the employing agency regarding his or her pay or benefits, and the employee detrimentally relies upon such written information. In order to qualify for the relief provided by this section, the employee’s reliance on the representation must have been reasonable and based only upon the written representations made by those persons authorized by the agency head to make such representations. Furthermore, the erroneous calculation and payment of an employee’s salary, wages, or benefits is not among the written representations which will trigger relief under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency of the executive branch, including the State University System, is authorized to take such action as may be appropriate to provide a remedy for an employee concerning his or her claim regarding detrimental reliance on erroneous written information provided by the employing agency relating to pay and benefits, provided such remedy is within the purview of the agency’s authority. The agency has no authority whatsoever to modify the state retirement system or the state insurance program. Any monetary remedy afforded by the agency must fall within the agency’s budgetary authority. Any person dissatisfied with the outcome of this process may file either a grievance pursuant to the agency’s internal grievance process or an appeal to the Division of Administrative Hearings pursuant to chapter 120, but not both.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time limit to file any action to recover compensation, including, but not limited to, salaries, wages, overtime pay, fringe benefits, or damages or penalties relating to errors in such compensation from, by, or on behalf of a state officer or employee is 2 years from the date of the alleged error in payment of such compensation. The time limit applies in all disputes over compensation for work performed by state officers or employees, and is not confined to cases arising under subsections (1) and (2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 96-198; s. 7, ch. 97-296; s. 6, ch. 99-155.</History></Section>