<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0110.123" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State group insurance program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “State Group Insurance Program Law.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Management Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enrollee” means all state officers and employees, retired state officers and employees, surviving spouses of deceased state officers and employees, and terminated employees or individuals with continuation coverage who are enrolled in an insurance plan offered by the state group insurance program. “Enrollee” includes all state university officers and employees, retired state university officers and employees, surviving spouses of deceased state university officers and employees, and terminated state university employees or individuals with continuation coverage who are enrolled in an insurance plan offered by the state group insurance program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Full-time state employees” includes all full-time employees of all branches or agencies of state government holding salaried positions and paid by state warrant or from agency funds, and employees paid from regular salary appropriations for 8 months’ employment, including university personnel on academic contracts, but in no case shall “state employee” or “salaried position” include persons paid from other-personal-services (OPS) funds. “Full-time employees” includes all full-time employees of the state universities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health maintenance organization” or “HMO” means an entity certified under part I of chapter 641.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health plan member” means any person participating in a state group health insurance plan, a TRICARE supplemental insurance plan, or a health maintenance organization plan under the state group insurance program, including enrollees and covered dependents thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Part-time state employee” means any employee of any branch or agency of state government paid by state warrant from salary appropriations or from agency funds, and who is employed for less than the normal full-time workweek established by the department or, if on academic contract or seasonal or other type of employment which is less than year-round, is employed for less than 8 months during any 12-month period, but in no case shall “part-time” employee include a person paid from other-personal-services (OPS) funds. “Part-time state employee” includes any part-time employee of the state universities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retired state officer or employee” or “retiree” means any state or state university officer or employee who retires under a state retirement system or a state optional annuity or retirement program or is placed on disability retirement, and who was insured under the state group insurance program at the time of retirement, and who begins receiving retirement benefits immediately after retirement from state or state university office or employment. The term also includes any state officer or state employee who retires under the Florida Retirement System Investment Plan established under part II of chapter 121 if he or she:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the age and service requirements to qualify for normal retirement as set forth in s. 121.021(29); or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has attained the age specified by s. 72(t)(2)(A)(i) of the Internal Revenue Code and has 6 years of creditable service.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State agency” or “agency” means any branch, department, or agency of state government. “State agency” or “agency” includes any state university for purposes of this section only.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State group health insurance plan or plans” or “state plan or plans” mean the state self-insured health insurance plan or plans offered to state officers and employees, retired state officers and employees, and surviving spouses of deceased state officers and employees pursuant to this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State-contracted HMO” means any health maintenance organization under contract with the department to participate in the state group insurance program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State group insurance program” or “programs” means the package of insurance plans offered to state officers and employees, retired state officers and employees, and surviving spouses of deceased state officers and employees pursuant to this section, including the state group health insurance plan or plans, health maintenance organization plans, TRICARE supplemental insurance plans, and other plans required or authorized by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State officer” means any constitutional state officer, any elected state officer paid by state warrant, or any appointed state officer who is commissioned by the Governor and who is paid by state warrant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surviving spouse” means the widow or widower of a deceased state officer, full-time state employee, part-time state employee, or retiree if such widow or widower was covered as a dependent under the state group health insurance plan, a TRICARE supplemental insurance plan, or a health maintenance organization plan established pursuant to this section at the time of the death of the deceased officer, employee, or retiree. “Surviving spouse” also means any widow or widower who is receiving or eligible to receive a monthly state warrant from a state retirement system as the beneficiary of a state officer, full-time state employee, or retiree who died prior to July 1, 1979. For the purposes of this section, any such widow or widower shall cease to be a surviving spouse upon his or her remarriage.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“TRICARE supplemental insurance plan” means the Department of Defense Health Insurance Program for eligible members of the uniformed services authorized by 10 U.S.C. s. 1097.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATE GROUP INSURANCE PROGRAM.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of State Group Insurance is created within the Department of Management Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to offer a comprehensive package of health insurance and retirement benefits and a personnel system for state employees which are provided in a cost-efficient and prudent manner, and to allow state employees the option to choose benefit plans which best suit their individual needs. Therefore, the state group insurance program is established which may include the state group health insurance plan or plans, health maintenance organization plans, group life insurance plans, TRICARE supplemental insurance plans, group accidental death and dismemberment plans, and group disability insurance plans. Furthermore, the department is additionally authorized to establish and provide as part of the state group insurance program any other group insurance plans or coverage choices that are consistent with the provisions of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision in this section to the contrary, it is the intent of the Legislature that the department shall be responsible for all aspects of the purchase of health care for state employees under the state group health insurance plan or plans, TRICARE supplemental insurance plans, and the health maintenance organization plans. Responsibilities shall include, but not be limited to, the development of requests for proposals or invitations to negotiate for state employee health services, the determination of health care benefits to be provided, and the negotiation of contracts for health care and health care administrative services. Prior to the negotiation of contracts for health care services, the Legislature intends that the department shall develop, with respect to state collective bargaining issues, the health benefits and terms to be included in the state group health insurance program. The department shall adopt rules necessary to perform its responsibilities pursuant to this section. It is the intent of the Legislature that the department shall be responsible for the contract management and day-to-day management of the state employee health insurance program, including, but not limited to, employee enrollment, premium collection, payment to health care providers, and other administrative functions related to the program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 287 and the authority of the department, for the purpose of protecting the health of, and providing medical services to, state employees participating in the state group insurance program, the department may contract to retain the services of professional administrators for the state group insurance program. The agency shall follow good purchasing practices of state procurement to the extent practicable under the circumstances.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each vendor in a major procurement, and any other vendor if the department deems it necessary to protect the state’s financial interests, shall, at the time of executing any contract with the department, post an appropriate bond with the department in an amount determined by the department to be adequate to protect the state’s interests but not higher than the full amount estimated to be paid annually to the vendor under the contract.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each major contract entered into by the department pursuant to this section shall contain a provision for payment of liquidated damages to the department for material noncompliance by a vendor with a contract provision. The department may require a liquidated damages provision in any contract if the department deems it necessary to protect the state’s financial interests.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 120.57(3) apply to the department’s contracting process, except:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A formal written protest of any decision, intended decision, or other action subject to protest shall be filed within 72 hours after receipt of notice of the decision, intended decision, or other action.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an alternative to any provision of s. 120.57(3), the department may proceed with the bid selection or contract award process if the director of the department sets forth, in writing, particular facts and circumstances which demonstrate the necessity of continuing the procurement process or the contract award process in order to avoid a substantial disruption to the provision of any scheduled insurance services.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services and the Division of State Group Insurance may not prohibit or limit any properly licensed insurer, health maintenance organization, prepaid limited health services organization, or insurance agent from competing for any insurance product or plan purchased, provided, or endorsed by the department or the division on the basis of the compensation arrangement used by the insurer or organization for its agents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided for in subparagraph (h)2., the state contribution toward the cost of any plan in the state group insurance program shall be uniform with respect to all state employees in a state collective bargaining unit participating in the same coverage tier in the same plan. This section does not prohibit the development of separate benefit plans for officers and employees exempt from the career service or the development of separate benefit plans for each collective bargaining unit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation by individuals in the program is available to all state officers, full-time state employees, and part-time state employees; and such participation in the program or any plan is voluntary. Participation in the program is also available to retired state officers and employees, as defined in paragraph (2)(g), who elect at the time of retirement to continue coverage under the program, but they may elect to continue all or only part of the coverage they had at the time of retirement. A surviving spouse may elect to continue coverage only under a state group health insurance plan, a TRICARE supplemental insurance plan, or a health maintenance organization plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person eligible to participate in the state group insurance program may be authorized by rules adopted by the department, in lieu of participating in the state group health insurance plan, to exercise an option to elect membership in a health maintenance organization plan which is under contract with the state in accordance with criteria established by this section and by said rules. The offer of optional membership in a health maintenance organization plan permitted by this paragraph may be limited or conditioned by rule as may be necessary to meet the requirements of state and federal laws.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall contract with health maintenance organizations seeking to participate in the state group insurance program through a request for proposal or other procurement process, as developed by the Department of Management Services and determined to be appropriate.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a schedule of minimum benefits for health maintenance organization coverage, and that schedule shall include: physician services; inpatient and outpatient hospital services; emergency medical services, including out-of-area emergency coverage; diagnostic laboratory and diagnostic and therapeutic radiologic services; mental health, alcohol, and chemical dependency treatment services meeting the minimum requirements of state and federal law; skilled nursing facilities and services; prescription drugs; age-based and gender-based wellness benefits; and other benefits as may be required by the department. Additional services may be provided subject to the contract between the department and the HMO. As used in this paragraph, the term “age-based and gender-based wellness benefits” includes aerobic exercise, education in alcohol and substance abuse prevention, blood cholesterol screening, health risk appraisals, blood pressure screening and education, nutrition education, program planning, safety belt education, smoking cessation, stress management, weight management, and women’s health education.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish uniform deductibles, copayments, coverage tiers, or coinsurance schedules for all participating HMO plans.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require detailed information from each health maintenance organization participating in the procurement process, including information pertaining to organizational status, experience in providing prepaid health benefits, accessibility of services, financial stability of the plan, quality of management services, accreditation status, quality of medical services, network access and adequacy, performance measurement, ability to meet the department’s reporting requirements, and the actuarial basis of the proposed rates and other data determined by the director to be necessary for the evaluation and selection of health maintenance organization plans and negotiation of appropriate rates for these plans. Upon receipt of proposals by health maintenance organization plans and the evaluation of those proposals, the department may enter into negotiations with all of the plans or a subset of the plans, as the department determines appropriate. Nothing shall preclude the department from negotiating regional or statewide contracts with health maintenance organization plans when this is cost-effective and when the department determines that the plan offers high value to enrollees.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may limit the number of HMOs that it contracts with in each service area based on the nature of the bids the department receives, the number of state employees in the service area, or any unique geographical characteristics of the service area. The department shall establish by rule service areas throughout the state.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons participating in the state group insurance program may be required to contribute towards a total state group health premium that may vary depending upon the plan and coverage tier selected by the enrollee and the level of state contribution authorized by the Legislature.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to negotiate and to contract with specialty psychiatric hospitals for mental health benefits, on a regional basis, for alcohol, drug abuse, and mental and nervous disorders. The department may establish, subject to the approval of the Legislature pursuant to subsection (5), any such regional plan upon completion of an actuarial study to determine any impact on plan benefits and premiums.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to contracting pursuant to subparagraph 2., the department may enter into contract with any HMO to participate in the state group insurance program which:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serves greater than 5,000 recipients on a prepaid basis under the Medicaid program;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not currently meet the 25-percent non-Medicare/non-Medicaid enrollment composition requirement established by the Department of Health excluding participants enrolled in the state group insurance program;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the minimum benefit package and copayments and deductibles contained in sub-subparagraphs 2.a. and b.;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is willing to participate in the state group insurance program at a cost of premiums that is not greater than 95 percent of the cost of HMO premiums accepted by the department in each service area; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the minimum surplus requirements of s. 641.225.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department is authorized to contract with HMOs that meet the requirements of sub-subparagraphs a.-d. prior to the open enrollment period for state employees. The department is not required to renew the contract with the HMOs as set forth in this paragraph more than twice. Thereafter, the HMOs shall be eligible to participate in the state group insurance program only through the request for proposal or invitation to negotiate process described in subparagraph 2.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All enrollees in a state group health insurance plan, a TRICARE supplemental insurance plan, or any health maintenance organization plan have the option of changing to any other health plan that is offered by the state within any open enrollment period designated by the department. Open enrollment shall be held at least once each calendar year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a contract between a treating provider and the state-contracted health maintenance organization is terminated for any reason other than for cause, each party shall allow any enrollee for whom treatment was active to continue coverage and care when medically necessary, through completion of treatment of a condition for which the enrollee was receiving care at the time of the termination, until the enrollee selects another treating provider, or until the next open enrollment period offered, whichever is longer, but no longer than 6 months after termination of the contract. Each party to the terminated contract shall allow an enrollee who has initiated a course of prenatal care, regardless of the trimester in which care was initiated, to continue care and coverage until completion of postpartum care. This does not prevent a provider from refusing to continue to provide care to an enrollee who is abusive, noncompliant, or in arrears in payments for services provided. For care continued under this subparagraph, the program and the provider shall continue to be bound by the terms of the terminated contract. Changes made within 30 days before termination of a contract are effective only if agreed to by both parties.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any HMO participating in the state group insurance program shall submit health care utilization and cost data to the department, in such form and in such manner as the department shall require, as a condition of participating in the program. The department shall enter into negotiations with its contracting HMOs to determine the nature and scope of the data submission and the final requirements, format, penalties associated with noncompliance, and timetables for submission. These determinations shall be adopted by rule.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish and direct, with respect to collective bargaining issues, a comprehensive package of insurance benefits that may include supplemental health and life coverage, dental care, long-term care, vision care, and other benefits it determines necessary to enable state employees to select from among benefit options that best suit their individual and family needs.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based upon a desired benefit package, the department shall issue a request for proposal or invitation to negotiate for health insurance providers interested in participating in the state group insurance program, and the department shall issue a request for proposal or invitation to negotiate for insurance providers interested in participating in the non-health-related components of the state group insurance program. Upon receipt of all proposals, the department may enter into contract negotiations with insurance providers submitting bids or negotiate a specially designed benefit package. Insurance providers offering or providing supplemental coverage as of May 30, 1991, which qualify for pretax benefit treatment pursuant to s. 125 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, with 5,500 or more state employees currently enrolled may be included by the department in the supplemental insurance benefit plan established by the department without participating in a request for proposal, submitting bids, negotiating contracts, or negotiating a specially designed benefit package. These contracts shall provide state employees with the most cost-effective and comprehensive coverage available; however, no state or agency funds shall be contributed toward the cost of any part of the premium of such supplemental benefit plans. With respect to dental coverage, the division shall include in any solicitation or contract for any state group dental program made after July 1, 2001, a comprehensive indemnity dental plan option which offers enrollees a completely unrestricted choice of dentists. If a dental plan is endorsed, or in some manner recognized as the preferred product, such plan shall include a comprehensive indemnity dental plan option which provides enrollees with a completely unrestricted choice of dentists.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the applicable provisions of s. 110.161, and s. 125 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the department shall enroll in the pretax benefit program those state employees who voluntarily elect coverage in any of the supplemental insurance benefit plans as provided by sub-subparagraph a.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing herein contained shall be construed to prohibit insurance providers from continuing to provide or offer supplemental benefit coverage to state employees as provided under existing agency plans.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The benefits of the insurance authorized by this section shall not be in lieu of any benefits payable under chapter 440, the Workers’ Compensation Law. The insurance authorized by this law shall not be deemed to constitute insurance to secure workers’ compensation benefits as required by chapter 440.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (f) requiring uniform contributions, and for the 2011-2012 fiscal year only, the state contribution toward the cost of any plan in the state group insurance plan is the difference between the overall premium and the employee contribution. This subsection expires June 30, 2012.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PAYMENT OF PREMIUMS; CONTRIBUTION BY STATE; LIMITATION ON ACTIONS TO PAY AND COLLECT PREMIUMS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (e) with respect to law enforcement officers, correctional and correctional probation officers, and firefighters, legislative authorization through the appropriations act is required for payment by a state agency of any part of the premium cost of participation in any group insurance plan. However, the state contribution for full-time employees or part-time permanent employees shall continue in the respective proportions for up to 6 months for any such officer or employee who has been granted an approved parental or medical leave of absence without pay.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a state officer or full-time state employee selects membership in a health maintenance organization as authorized by paragraph (3)(h), the officer or employee is entitled to a state contribution toward individual and dependent membership as provided by the Legislature through the appropriations act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During each policy or budget year, no state agency shall contribute a greater dollar amount of the premium cost for its officers or employees for any plan option under the state group insurance program than any other agency for similar officers and employees, nor shall any greater dollar amount of premium cost be made for employees in one state collective bargaining unit than for those in any other state collective bargaining unit. Nothing in this section prohibits the use of different levels of state contributions for positions exempt from career service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state contribution for a part-time permanent state employee who elects to participate in the program shall be prorated so that the amount of the cost contributed for the part-time permanent employee bears that relation to the amount of cost contributed for a similar full-time employee that the part-time employee’s normal workday bears to a full-time employee’s normal workday.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No state contribution for the cost of any part of the premium shall be made for retirees or surviving spouses for any type of coverage under the state group insurance program. However, any state agency that employs a full-time law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer who is killed or suffers catastrophic injury in the line of duty as provided in s. 112.19, or a full-time firefighter who is killed or suffers catastrophic injury in the line of duty as provided in s. 112.191, shall pay the entire premium of the state group health insurance plan selected for the employee’s surviving spouse until remarried, and for each dependent child of the employee, subject to the conditions and limitations set forth in s. 112.19 or s. 112.191, as applicable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the request of each state officer, full-time or part-time state employee, or retiree participating in the state group insurance program, and upon certification of the employing agency approved by the department, the Chief Financial Officer shall deduct from the salary or retirement warrant payable to each participant the amount so certified and shall handle such deductions in accordance with rules established by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No administrative or civil proceeding shall be commenced to collect an underpayment or refund an overpayment of premiums collected pursuant to this subsection unless such claim is filed with the department within 2 years after the alleged underpayment or overpayment was made. For purposes of this paragraph, a payroll deduction, salary reduction, or contribution by an agency is deemed to be made on the date the salary warrant is issued.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT POWERS AND DUTIES.<EmDash />The department is responsible for the administration of the state group insurance program. The department shall initiate and supervise the program as established by this section and shall adopt such rules as are necessary to perform its responsibilities. To implement this program, the department shall, with prior approval by the Legislature:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the benefits to be provided and the contributions to be required for the state group insurance program. Such determinations, whether for a contracted plan or a self-insurance plan pursuant to paragraph (c), do not constitute rules within the meaning of s. 120.52 or final orders within the meaning of s. 120.52. Any physician’s fee schedule used in the health and accident plan shall not be available for inspection or copying by medical providers or other persons not involved in the administration of the program. However, in the determination of the design of the program, the department shall consider existing and complementary benefits provided by the Florida Retirement System and the Social Security System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare, in cooperation with the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission, the specifications necessary to implement the program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract on a competitive proposal basis with an insurance carrier or carriers, or professional administrator, determined by the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission to be fully qualified, financially sound, and capable of meeting all servicing requirements. Alternatively, the department may self-insure any plan or plans contained in the state group insurance program subject to approval based on actuarial soundness by the Office of Insurance Regulation. The department may contract with an insurance company or professional administrator qualified and approved by the Office of Insurance Regulation to administer such plan. Before entering into any contract, the department shall advertise for competitive proposals, and such contract shall be let upon the consideration of the benefits provided in relationship to the cost of such benefits. In determining which entity to contract with, the department shall, at a minimum, consider: the entity’s previous experience and expertise in administering group insurance programs of the type it proposes to administer; the entity’s ability to specifically perform its contractual obligations in this state and other governmental jurisdictions; the entity’s anticipated administrative costs and claims experience; the entity’s capability to adequately provide service coverage and sufficient number of experienced and qualified personnel in the areas of claims processing, recordkeeping, and underwriting, as determined by the department; the entity’s accessibility to state employees and providers; the financial solvency of the entity, using accepted business sector measures of financial performance. The department may contract for medical services which will improve the health or reduce medical costs for employees who participate in the state group insurance plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a state group health insurance plan, be authorized to require copayments with respect to all providers under the plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have authority to establish a voluntary program for comprehensive health maintenance, which may include health educational components and health appraisals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any contract with an insurance carrier or carriers or professional administrator entered into by the department, require that the state and the enrollees be held harmless and indemnified for any financial loss caused by the failure of the insurance carrier or professional administrator to comply with the terms of the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any contract with an insurance carrier or carriers, or professional administrator entered into by the department, require that the carrier or professional administrator provide written notice to individual enrollees if any payment due to any health care provider of the enrollee remains unpaid beyond a period of time as specified in the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have authority to establish other voluntary programs to be funded on a pretax contribution basis or on a posttax contribution basis, as the department determines.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract with a single custodian to provide services necessary to implement and administer the health savings accounts authorized in subsection (12).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Final decisions concerning enrollment, the existence of coverage, or covered benefits under the state group insurance program shall not be delegated or deemed to have been delegated by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPOSIT OF PREMIUMS AND REFUNDS.<EmDash />Premium dollars collected and not required to pay the costs of the program, prior to being paid to the carrier insurance company, shall be invested, and the earnings from such investment shall be deposited in a trust fund to be designated in the State Treasury and utilized for increased benefits or reduced premiums for the participants or may be used to pay for the administration of the state group insurance program. Any refunds paid the state by the insurance carrier from premium dollar reserves held by the carrier and earned on such refunds shall be deposited in the trust fund and used for such purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTINUATION OF AGENCY INSURANCE PLANS.<EmDash />Nothing contained in this section shall require the discontinuation of any insurance plan provided by any state agency; however, no state or agency funds shall be contributed toward the cost of any part of the premium of such agency plans. Such agency plans shall not be deemed to be included in the state group insurance program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COVERAGE FOR LEGISLATIVE MEMBERS AND EMPLOYEES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature may provide coverage for its members and employees under all or any part of the state group insurance program; may provide coverage for its members and employees under a legislative group insurance program in lieu of all or any part of the state group insurance program; and, notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (4)(c), may assume the cost of any group insurance coverage provided to its members and employees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any legislative member who terminates his or her elected service after January 1, 1999, after having vested in the state retirement system, may purchase coverage in a state group health insurance plan at the same premium cost as that for retirees and surviving spouses. Such legislators may also elect coverage under the group term life insurance program prevailing for current members at the premium cost in effect for that plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PUBLIC RECORDS LAW; EXEMPTION.<EmDash />Patient medical records and medical claims records of state employees, former state employees, and their eligible covered dependents in the custody or control of the state group insurance program are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). Such records shall not be furnished to any person other than the affected state employee or former state employee or his or her legal representative, except upon written authorization of the employee or former state employee, but may be furnished in any civil or criminal action, unless otherwise prohibited by law, upon the issuance of a subpoena from a court of competent jurisdiction and proper notice to the state employee, former state employee, or his or her legal representative by the party seeking such records.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATEMENTS OF PURPOSE AND INTENT AND OTHER PROVISIONS REQUIRED FOR QUALIFICATION UNDER THE INTERNAL REVENUE CODE OF THE UNITED STATES.<EmDash />Any other provisions in this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provision in this chapter relating to a state group insurance program shall be construed and administered to the extent possible to qualify such program to be a qualified and nondiscriminatory employee benefit plan under existing or hereafter-enacted provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt any rule necessary to accomplish the purposes of this subsection not inconsistent with this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is declaratory of the legislative intent upon the original enactment of this section and is deemed to have been in effect since that date.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTICE BY HEALTH CARE PROVIDERS.<EmDash />Any health care provider that has entered into a contract with a carrier or professional administrator that has contracted with the department to administer the self-insurance program under this section shall provide written notification to the enrollee and the carrier or administrator at least 10 days before assigning or transferring the responsibility for collecting any payment or debt related to the plan to a collection agency or to any other third party.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEALTH SAVINGS ACCOUNTS.<EmDash />The department is authorized to establish health savings accounts for full-time and part-time state employees in association with a health insurance plan option authorized by the Legislature and conforming to the requirements and limitations of federal provisions relating to the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Reference Number="2"/>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member participating in this health insurance plan option is eligible to receive an employer contribution into the employee’s health savings account from the State Employees Health Insurance Trust Fund in an amount to be determined by the Legislature. A member is not eligible for an employer contribution upon termination of employment. For the 2012-2013 fiscal year, the state’s monthly contribution for employees having individual coverage shall be $41.66 and the monthly contribution for employees having family coverage shall be $83.33.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member participating in this health insurance plan option is eligible to deposit the member’s own funds into a health savings account.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The monthly premiums paid by the employer for a member participating in this health insurance plan option shall include an amount equal to the monthly employer contribution authorized by the Legislature for that fiscal year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health savings accounts shall be administered in accordance with the requirements and limitations of federal provisions relating to the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 79-190; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-186; s. 1, ch. 83-72; s. 1, ch. 84-3; s. 3, ch. 84-35; ss. 1, 2, ch. 86-27; s. 3, ch. 86-180; s. 1, ch. 87-156; s. 1, ch. 88-126; s. 6, ch. 88-290; s. 1, ch. 89-22; s. 1, ch 89-277; s. 3, ch. 90-196; s. 23, ch. 90-360; s. 76, ch. 91-45; s. 1, ch. 91-148; s. 1, ch. 91-264; s. 53, ch. 91-282; s. 6, ch. 91-431; s. 18, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 6, ch. 93-129; s. 2, ch. 93-149; s. 1, ch. 94-171; s. 29, ch. 95-146; s. 1400, ch. 95-147; s. 30, ch. 96-406; s. 10, ch. 96-410; s. 3, ch. 97-92; ss. 24, 38, ch. 98-46; s. 2, ch. 98-279; s. 37, ch. 99-2; s. 6, ch. 99-255; s. 4, ch. 99-264; s. 58, ch. 99-399; s. 11, ch. 2000-151; s. 4, ch. 2000-157; s. 2, ch. 2000-363; s. 1, ch. 2001-192; s. 17, ch. 2002-1; s. 2, ch. 2002-273; s. 889, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2003-91; s. 118, ch. 2003-261; s. 7, ch. 2004-347; s. 3, ch. 2005-97; s. 4, ch. 2005-100; s. 1, ch. 2005-175; s. 3, ch. 2006-18; s. 9, ch. 2006-269; s. 26, ch. 2007-73; s. 17, ch. 2008-153; s. 49, ch. 2009-82; ss. 55, 56, ch. 2010-153; ss. 59, 60, ch. 2011-47; s. 1, ch. 2011-68; s. 1, ch. 2012-27; s. 39, ch. 2012-119.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 39, ch. 2012-119, amended paragraph (12)(a) “[i]n order to implement specific appropriations for salaries and benefits in the 2012-2013 General Appropriations Act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>