<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.117" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Paid holidays.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following holidays shall be paid holidays observed by all state branches and agencies:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">New Year’s Day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Birthday of Martin Luther King, Jr., third Monday in January.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Memorial Day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Independence Day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Labor Day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Veterans’ Day, November 11.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thanksgiving Day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Friday after Thanksgiving.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Christmas Day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of these holidays falls on Saturday, the preceding Friday shall be observed as a holiday. If any of these holidays falls on Sunday, the following Monday shall be observed as a holiday.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor may declare, when appropriate, a state day of mourning in observance of the death of a person in recognition of service rendered to the state or nation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each full-time employee is entitled to one personal holiday each year. Each part-time employee is entitled to a personal holiday each year which shall be calculated proportionately to the personal holiday allowed to a full-time employee. Such personal holiday shall be credited to eligible employees on July 1 of each year to be taken prior to June 30 of the following year. Members of the teaching and research faculty of the State University System and administrative and professional positions exempted under s. 110.205(2)(d) are not eligible for this benefit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 79-190; s. 1, ch. 80-331; s. 1, ch. 88-63; s. 16, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 8, ch. 94-113; s. 5, ch. 96-399.</History></Section>