<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Responsibilities of departments and agencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each department or agency utilizing the services of volunteers shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take such actions as are necessary and appropriate to develop meaningful opportunities for volunteers involved in state-administered programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with the uniform rules adopted by the Department of Management Services governing the recruitment, screening, training, responsibility, use, and supervision of volunteers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take such actions as are necessary to ensure that volunteers understand their duties and responsibilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take such actions as are necessary and appropriate to ensure a receptive climate for citizen volunteers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the recognition of volunteers who have offered continuous and outstanding service to state-administered programs. Each department or agency using the services of volunteers is authorized to incur expenditures not to exceed $100 each plus applicable taxes for suitable framed certificates, plaques, or other tokens of recognition to honor, reward, or encourage volunteers for their service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize prior volunteer service as partial fulfillment of state employment requirements for training and experience pursuant to rules adopted by the Department of Management Services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 78-263; s. 24, ch. 79-190; s. 38, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 42, ch. 96-399; s. 13, ch. 99-399.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 112.903.</Text></Note></Section>