<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment policy of the state.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the purpose of this chapter to establish a system of personnel management. This system shall provide means to recruit, select, train, develop, and maintain an effective and responsible workforce and shall include policies and procedures for employee hiring and advancement, training and career development, position classification, salary administration, benefits, discipline, discharge, employee performance evaluations, affirmative action, and other related activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the policy of the state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all appointments, terminations, assignments, and maintenance of status, compensation, privileges, and other terms and conditions of employment in state government shall be made without regard to age, sex, race, color, religion, national origin, political affiliation, marital status, or disability, unless a specific requirement constitutes a bona fide occupational qualification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To support employees in balancing their personal needs and work responsibilities. This policy is designed to enhance the employee’s ability to blend the competing demands of work and personal life and produce a more skilled, accountable, and committed workforce for the system. Provisions may include, but need not be limited to, flexible work schedules, telework, part-time employment, and leaves of absence with or without pay.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as expressly provided by law, Florida residency is not required for any person as a condition precedent to employment; however, preference in hiring may be given to state residents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter contains the requirements for establishing and maintaining a system of personnel management on a merit basis. The system of personnel management shall be implemented so as to ensure that the state agencies participating in the system are eligible for federal funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter may not be construed either to infringe upon or to supersede the rights guaranteed public employees under chapter 447.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 79-190; s. 1, ch. 2012-215.</History></Section>