<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0110.502" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Scope of act; status of volunteers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every state department or state agency, through the head of the department or agency, secretary of the department, or executive director of the department, is authorized to recruit, train, and accept, without regard to requirements of the State Career Service System as set forth in part II of this chapter, the services of volunteers, including regular-service volunteers, occasional-service volunteers, or material donors, to assist in programs administered by the department or agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Volunteers recruited, trained, or accepted by any state department or agency shall not be subject to any provisions of law relating to state employment, to any collective bargaining agreement between the state and any employees’ association or union, or to any laws relating to hours of work, rates of compensation, leave time, and employee benefits, except those consistent with s. 110.504. However, all volunteers shall comply with applicable department or agency rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every department or agency utilizing the services of volunteers is hereby authorized to provide such incidental reimbursement or benefit consistent with the provisions of s. 110.504, including transportation costs, lodging, and subsistence, recognition, and other accommodations as the department or agency deems necessary to assist, recognize, reward, or encourage volunteers in performing their functions. No department or agency shall expend or authorize an expenditure therefor in excess of the amount provided for to the department or agency by appropriation in any fiscal year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons working with state agencies pursuant to this part shall be considered as unpaid independent volunteers and shall not be entitled to reemployment assistance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 78-263; s. 24, ch. 79-190; s. 48, ch. 96-399; s. 42, ch. 2012-30.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 112.902.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>