<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.131" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Other-personal-services employment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “agency” means any official, officer, commission, board, authority, council, committee, or department of the executive branch of state government and means any officer, court, commission, or other unit of the judicial branch of state government supported in whole or in part by appropriations made by the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency may employ any qualified individual in other-personal-services employment. For each other-personal-services employee, the agency shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain employee records identifying, at a minimum, the person employed, the hire date, the type of other-personal-services employment, and the number of hours worked.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the appropriate rate of pay and ensure that all payments are in compliance with the federal Fair Labor Standards Act and state law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review, determine, and document by June 30 of each year whether the continuation of each other-personal-services employment position is necessary to the mission of the agency. This review process does not apply to board members; consultants; seasonal employees; institutional clients employed as part of their rehabilitation; bona fide, degree-seeking students in accredited secondary or postsecondary educational programs; employees hired to deal with an emergency situation that affects the public health, safety, or welfare; or employees hired for a project that is identified by a specific appropriation or time-limited grant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless specifically provided by law, other-personal-services employees are not eligible for any form of paid leave, paid holidays, a paid personal day, participation in state group insurance or retirement benefits, or any other state employee benefit. Other-personal-services employees may be included in that part of an agency’s recognition and reward program that recognizes and rewards employees who submit innovative ideas that increase productivity, eliminate or reduce state expenditures, improve operations, or generate additional revenue or who meet or exceed the agency’s established criteria for a project or goal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning August 15, 2012, and each August 15 thereafter, each agency employing an individual in other-personal-services employment shall submit a report to the Executive Office of the Governor and to the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees containing the following information for the previous fiscal year ending June 30, 2012, and each June 30 thereafter:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total number of individuals serving in other-personal-services employment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of employment, average pay, and total number of hours worked for each individual serving in other-personal-services employment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 83-279; s. 1, ch. 84-87; s. 1, ch. 85-219; s. 5, ch. 86-180; s. 25, ch. 86-245; s. 23, ch. 86-290; s. 1, ch. 88-333; s. 25, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 664, ch. 95-147; s. 10, ch. 95-196; s. 16, ch. 95-280; s. 8, ch. 96-399; s. 9, ch. 97-237; s. 1, ch. 98-65; s. 5, ch. 99-399; s. 84, ch. 2000-318; s. 11, ch. 2001-43; s. 5, ch. 2007-217; s. 6, ch. 2012-215.</History></Section>