<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.1239" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State group health insurance program funding.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the state group health insurance program be managed, administered, operated, and funded in such a manner as to maximize the protection of state employee health insurance benefits. Inherent in this intent is the recognition that the health insurance liabilities attributable to the benefits offered state employees should be fairly, orderly, and equitably funded. Accordingly:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall determine the level of premiums necessary to fully fund the state group health insurance program for the next fiscal year. Such determination shall be made after each Self-Insurance Estimating Conference as provided in s. 216.136(9), but not later than December 1 and April 1 of each fiscal year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor, in the Governor’s recommended budget, shall provide premium rates necessary for full funding of the state group health insurance program, and the Legislature shall provide in the General Appropriations Act for a premium level necessary for full funding of the state group health insurance program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of funding, any additional appropriation amounts allocated to the state group health insurance program by the Legislature shall be considered as a state contribution and thus an increase in the state premiums.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 25, 38, ch. 98-46; ss. 25, 53, ch. 99-228; s. 63, ch. 2000-171; s. 47, ch. 2001-254; s. 45, ch. 2002-402; s. 48, ch. 2003-399; ss. 30, 76, ch. 2004-269; s. 2, ch. 2004-347; s. 5, ch. 2005-152.</History></Section>