<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Volunteer benefits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meals may be furnished without charge to regular-service volunteers serving state departments, provided the scheduled assignment extends over an established meal period, and to occasional-service volunteers at the discretion of the department head. No department shall expend or authorize any expenditure in excess of the amount provided for by appropriation in any fiscal year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lodging, if available, may be furnished temporarily, in case of a department emergency, at no charge to regular-service volunteers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation reimbursement may be furnished those volunteers whose presence is determined to be necessary to the department. Volunteers may utilize state vehicles in the performance of department-related duties. No department shall expend or authorize an expenditure in excess of the amount appropriated in any fiscal year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Volunteers shall be covered by state liability protection in accordance with the definition of a volunteer and the provisions of s. 768.28.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Volunteers shall be covered by workers’ compensation in accordance with chapter 440.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incidental recognition benefits or incidental nonmonetary awards may be furnished to volunteers serving in state departments to award, recognize, or encourage volunteers for their service. The awards may not cost in excess of $100 each plus applicable taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Volunteers, including volunteers receiving a stipend as provided by the Domestic Service Volunteer Act of 1973, as amended (Pub. L. No. 93-113), shall be covered by s. 768.1355, the Florida Volunteer Protection Act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 78-263; s. 24, ch. 79-190; s. 8, ch. 83-159; s. 49, ch. 96-399; s. 14, ch. 99-399.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 112.904.</Text></Note></Section>