<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.1245" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Savings sharing program; bonus payments; other awards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall adopt rules that prescribe procedures and promote a savings sharing program for an individual or group of employees who propose procedures or ideas that are adopted and that result in eliminating or reducing state expenditures, if such proposals are placed in effect and may be implemented under current statutory authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency head shall recommend employees individually or by group to be awarded an amount of money, which amount shall be directly related to the cost savings realized. Each proposed award and amount of money must be approved by the Legislative Budget Commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state agency, unless otherwise provided by law, may participate in the program. The Chief Justice shall have the authority to establish a savings sharing program for employees of the judicial branch within the parameters established in this section. The program shall apply to all employees within the Career Service, the Selected Exempt Service, and comparable employees within the judicial branch.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the judicial branch shall submit annually to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives information that outlines each agency’s level of participation in the savings sharing program. The information shall include, but is not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of proposals made.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of dollars and awards made to employees or groups for adopted proposals.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actual cost savings realized as a result of implementing employee or group proposals.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In June of each year, bonuses shall be paid to employees from funds authorized by the Legislature in an appropriation specifically for bonuses. Each agency shall develop a plan for awarding lump-sum bonuses, which plan shall be submitted no later than September 15 of each year and approved by the Office of Policy and Budget in the Executive Office of the Governor. Such plan shall include, at a minimum, but is not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that bonuses are subject to specific appropriation by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligibility criteria as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must have been employed prior to July 1 of that fiscal year and have been continuously employed through the date of distribution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must not have been on leave without pay consecutively for more than 6 months during the fiscal year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must have had no sustained disciplinary action during the period beginning July 1 through the date the bonus checks are distributed. Disciplinary actions include written reprimands, suspensions, dismissals, and involuntary or voluntary demotions that were associated with a disciplinary action.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must have demonstrated a commitment to the agency mission by reducing the burden on those served, continually improving the way business is conducted, producing results in the form of increased outputs, and working to improve processes.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must have demonstrated initiative in work and have exceeded normal job expectations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must have modeled the way for others by displaying agency values of fairness, cooperation, respect, commitment, honesty, excellence, and teamwork.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A periodic evaluation process of the employee’s performance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A process for peer input that is fair, respectful of employees, and affects the outcome of the bonus distribution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A division of the agency by work unit for purposes of peer input and bonus distribution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limitation on bonus distributions equal to 35 percent of the agency’s total authorized positions. This requirement may be waived by the Office of Policy and Budget in the Executive Office of the Governor upon a showing of exceptional circumstances.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each department head is authorized to incur expenditures to award suitable framed certificates, pins, and other tokens of recognition to retiring state employees whose service with the state has been satisfactory, in appreciation and recognition of such service. Such awards may not cost in excess of $100 each plus applicable taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each department head is authorized to incur expenditures to award suitable framed certificates, pins, or other tokens of recognition to state employees who demonstrate satisfactory service in the agency or to the state, in appreciation and recognition of such service. Such awards may not cost in excess of $100 each plus applicable taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each department head is authorized to incur expenditures not to exceed $100 each plus applicable taxes for suitable framed certificates, plaques, or other tokens of recognition to any appointed member of a state board or commission whose service to the state has been satisfactory, in appreciation and recognition of such service upon the expiration of such board or commission member’s final term in such position.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 83-72; s. 4, ch. 85-68; s. 1, ch. 87-68; s. 1, ch. 88-191; s. 85, ch. 92-142; s. 22, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 7, ch. 96-399; s. 4, ch. 99-399; s. 8, ch. 2001-43; s. 5, ch. 2003-138; s. 6, ch. 2005-152; s. 25, ch. 2007-73; s. 1, ch. 2009-20.</History></Section>