<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0110.233" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Political activities and unlawful acts prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall be appointed to, demoted, or dismissed from any position in the career service, or in any way favored or discriminated against with respect to employment in the career service, because of race, color, national origin, sex, handicap, religious creed, or political opinion or affiliation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall use or promise to use, directly or indirectly, any official authority or influence, whether possessed or anticipated, to secure or attempt to secure for any person an appointment or advantage in appointment to a position in the career service, or an increase in pay or other advantage in employment in any such position, for the purpose of influencing the vote or political action of any person or for any consideration; however, letters of inquiry, recommendations, and references by public employees or public officials shall not be considered political pressure unless any such letter contains a threat, intimidation, or irrelevant, derogatory, or false information. For the purposes of this section, the term “political pressure,” in addition to any appropriate meaning which may be ascribed thereto by lawful authority, includes the use of official authority or influence in any manner prohibited by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall, directly or indirectly, give, render, pay, offer, solicit, or accept any money, service, or other valuable consideration for or on account of any appointment, proposed appointment, promotion or proposed promotion to, or any advantage in, a position in the career service. The provisions of this subsection do not apply to a private employment agency licensed pursuant to the provisions of <Reference Number="1" />chapter 449 when the services of such private employment agency are requested by a state agency, board, department, or commission and neither the state nor any political subdivision pays the private employment agency for such services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an individual, each employee retains all rights and obligations of citizenship provided in the Constitution and laws of the state and the Constitution and laws of the United States. However, no employee in the career service shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold, or be a candidate for, public office while in the employment of the state or take any active part in a political campaign while on duty or within any period of time during which the employee is expected to perform services for which he or she receives compensation from the state. However, when authorized by his or her agency head and approved by the department as involving no interest which conflicts or activity which interferes with his or her state employment, an employee in the career service may be a candidate for or hold local public office. The department shall prepare and make available to all affected personnel who make such request a definite set of rules and procedures consistent with the provisions herein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the authority of his or her position to secure support for, or oppose, any candidate, party, or issue in a partisan election or affect the results thereof.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No state employee or official shall use any promise of reward or threat of loss to encourage or coerce any employee to support or contribute to any political issue, candidate, or party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt by rule procedures for Career Service System employees that require disclosure to the agency head of any application for or offer of employment, gift, contractual relationship, or financial interest with any individual, partnership, association, corporation, utility, or other organization, whether public or private, doing business with or subject to regulation by the agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 79-190; s. 2, ch. 80-207; s. 1, ch. 84-125; s. 5, ch. 89-277; s. 1, ch. 91-164; s. 21, ch. 91-431; s. 34, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 668, ch. 95-147; s. 23, ch. 2001-43.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions comprising chapter 449 were repealed by ch. 81-170.</Text></Note></Section>