<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0413.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Eligibility for vocational rehabilitation services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is eligible for vocational rehabilitation services if the person has a disability and requires vocational rehabilitation services to prepare for, enter, engage in, or retain gainful employment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determinations by other state or federal agencies regarding whether an individual satisfies one or more factors relating to the determination that an individual has a disability may be used. Individuals determined to have a disability pursuant to Title II or Title XVI of the Social Security Act shall be considered to have a physical or mental impairment that constitutes or results in a substantial impediment to employment and a significant disability.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual is presumed to benefit in terms of an employment outcome from vocational rehabilitation services under this part unless the division can demonstrate by clear and convincing evidence that the individual is incapable of benefiting from vocational rehabilitation services in terms of an employment outcome. Before making such a determination, the division must consider the individual’s abilities, capabilities, and capacity to perform in a work situation through the use of trial work experiences. Trial work experiences include supported employment, on-the-job training, or other work experiences using realistic work settings. Under limited circumstances, if an individual cannot take advantage of trial work experiences or if options for trial work experiences have been exhausted, the division shall conduct an extended evaluation, not to exceed 18 months. The evaluation must determine the eligibility of the individual and the nature and scope of needed vocational rehabilitation services. The extended evaluation must be reviewed once every 90 days to determine whether the individual is eligible for vocational rehabilitation services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall determine the eligibility of an individual for vocational rehabilitation services within a reasonable period of time, not to exceed 60 days after the individual has submitted an application to receive vocational rehabilitation services, unless unforeseen circumstances beyond the control of the division prevent the division from completing the determination within the prescribed time and the division and the individual agree that an extension of time is warranted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the division determines that an individual is eligible for vocational rehabilitation services, the division must complete an assessment for determining eligibility and vocational rehabilitation needs and ensure that an individualized plan for employment is prepared.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each individualized plan for employment must be jointly developed, agreed upon, and signed by the vocational rehabilitation counselor or coordinator and the eligible individual or, in an appropriate case, a parent, family member, guardian, advocate, or authorized representative, of the individual.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division must ensure that each individualized plan for employment is designed to achieve the specific employment outcome of the individual, consistent with the unique strengths, resources, priorities, concerns, abilities, and capabilities of the individual, and otherwise meets the content requirements for an individualized plan for employment as set out in federal law or regulation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each individualized plan for employment shall be reviewed annually, at which time the individual, or the individual’s parent, guardian, advocate, or authorized representative, shall be afforded an opportunity to review the plan and jointly redevelop and agree to its terms. Each plan shall be revised as needed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division must ensure that a determination of ineligibility made with respect to an individual before the initiation of an individualized plan for employment, based upon the review, and, to the extent necessary, upon the preliminary assessment, includes specification of the reasons for such a determination; the rights and remedies available to the individual, including, if appropriate, recourse to administrative remedies; and the availability of services provided by the client assistance program to the individual. If there is a determination of ineligibility, the division must refer the individual to other services that are part of the one-stop delivery system under s. 445.009 that address the individual’s training or employment-related needs or to local extended employment providers if the determination is based on a finding that the individual is incapable of achieving an employment outcome.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the division provides an eligible individual with vocational rehabilitation services in the form of vehicle modifications, the division shall consider all options available, including the purchase of a new, original equipment manufacturer vehicle that complies with the Americans with Disabilities Act for transportation vehicles. The division shall make the decision on vocational rehabilitation services based on the best interest of the eligible individual and cost-effectiveness.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the division is unable to provide services to all eligible individuals, the division shall establish an order of selection and serve those persons who have the most significant disabilities first.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 25364, 1959; s. 13, ch. 65-239; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 69-344; s. 311, ch. 77-147; s. 8, ch. 87-227; s. 16, ch. 94-324; s. 1, ch. 2009-60; s. 2, ch. 2010-70.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve">Former ss. 229.33, 229.0110.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>