<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0413.407" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assistive Technology Advisory Council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Assistive Technology Advisory Council, responsible for ensuring consumer involvement in the creation, application, and distribution of technology-related assistance to and for persons who have disabilities. The council shall fulfill its responsibilities through statewide policy development, both state and federal legislative initiatives, advocacy at both the state and federal level, planning of statewide resource allocations, policy-level management, reviews of both consumer responsiveness and the adequacy of program service delivery, and by performing the functions listed in this section.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall be composed of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals who have disabilities and who are assistive technology consumers or family members or guardians of those individuals.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives of consumer organizations concerned with assistive technology.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives of business and industry, including the insurance industry, concerned with assistive technology.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Division of Vocational Rehabilitation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Division of Blind Services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Florida Independent Living Council.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of Workforce Florida, Inc.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Department of Education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives of other state agencies that provide or coordinate services for persons with disabilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Total membership on the council shall not exceed 27 at any one time. A majority of the members shall be appointed in accordance with subparagraph 1.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall be appointed by the Commissioner of Education from a list of candidates proposed by the division director.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of council members shall be persons who have disabilities as defined in s. 413.20(7) who are also consumers of assistive technology or family members of such persons.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the council shall select two co-chairs from among the membership of the council.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One co-chair may be selected from the group described in paragraph (c) and one co-chair shall be selected from the other council members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No co-chair may be an elected member or an employee of a state agency or of any political subdivision of the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the council shall serve for a term of not more than 3 years, except that a member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which a predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No member of the council may serve more than two consecutive terms; however, any appointment under subparagraph 1., if for less than 18 months, shall not be considered a term for the purposes of this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member who has served two consecutive terms and has been retired from the council for at least 1 year may be reappointed to the council on the same basis as a new member.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vacancy occurring in the membership of the council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. A vacancy does not affect the power of the remaining members to execute the duties of the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the other functions specified in this section, the council shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act as the board of directors of a not-for-profit corporation created by the division. Through the corporation, the council shall provide direction to Florida’s Alliance for Assistive Services and Technology, a project sponsored by the department for the coordination and delivery of appropriate, cost-effective, state-of-the-art assistive technology services and devices.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint committees made up of members of the council to focus on specific issues within the council’s mandate. Committees may request and accept in-kind contributions of personnel from public or private entities to supply such staffing as the committees deem necessary to carry out their individual mandates. These committees shall include, but are not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An interagency committee composed of those members representing state agencies. The interagency committee shall work towards the development of cooperative agreements among government agencies and perform such other duties as the council deems appropriate. The interagency committee’s members shall assign staff from their respective agencies to the alliance, as an in-kind contribution for a specified period of time, to review federal and state legislation and agency policies and practices and to identify both facilitators of, and barriers to, accessibility and utilization of assistive technology services, devices, and funding sources.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A technology-awareness committee to guide the council’s public awareness, coordination, and collaboration activities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public policy and advocacy committee to review federal and state legislation and agency policies and practices and to identify facilitators of and barriers to access and utilization of assistive technology services, devices, and funding sources.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and approve all reports, recommendations, and proposed actions of committee staff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint the executive director of the alliance. The executive director shall be responsible for overall administration and day-to-day direction of the alliance, as well as supervision of all staff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually review and approve the strategic or business plan of the alliance, as submitted by the executive director.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit an annual comprehensive report of the activities of the council, the corporation, and the alliance to the division director.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform such other functions as the council determines to be appropriate which are comparable to functions performed by the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Convene at least four meetings each year in such places as it determines to be necessary to conduct council business and may conduct such forums or hearings as the council considers appropriate. The council shall make a report of each meeting which shall include a record of its discussions and recommendations, all of which reports shall be made available to the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with Pub. L. No. 108-364, the council shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigate financing options that will increase access to and funding for assistive technology devices and assistive technology services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop assistive technology demonstrations, reutilization programs, and loan programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide training and technical assistance in order to increase knowledge and awareness of the uses and benefits of assistive technology devices and assistive technology services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote public awareness activities designed to provide information relating to the benefits of assistive technology devices and assistive technology services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote coordination and collaboration among public and private entities that are responsible for policies, procedures, or funding for the provision of assistive technology devices and assistive technology services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 94-324; s. 1, ch. 2005-204; s. 8, ch. 2010-70.</History>
</Section>