<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0413.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retention of title to and disposal of equipment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to retain title to any property, tools, instruments, training supplies, equipment, or other items of value acquired for use of persons who have disabilities or personnel employed in the operation of the vocational rehabilitation program, and to repossess and transfer same for the use of other persons who have disabilities or personnel employed in the operation of the vocational rehabilitation program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to offer for sale any surplus items acquired in the operation of the program when they are no longer necessary or to exchange them for necessary items which may be used to greater advantage. When any such surplus equipment is sold or exchanged a receipt for same shall be taken from the purchaser showing the consideration given for such equipment and forwarded to the Chief Financial Officer, and any funds received by the division pursuant to any such transactions shall be deposited in the State Treasury in the appropriate federal or state rehabilitation funds and shall be available for expenditure for any purpose consistent with this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall have the exclusive right to develop rules relating to records and recordkeeping for division-owned property referenced in subsections (1) and (2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 25364, 1949; s. 13, ch. 65-239; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 312, ch. 77-147; s. 115, ch. 79-164; s. 9, ch. 87-227; s. 18, ch. 94-324; s. 454, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 229.35, 229.0112.</Text></Note></Section>