<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0413.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Products, purchase by state agencies and institutions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />When used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Accredited nonprofit workshop” means a Florida workshop which has been certified by either the Division of Blind Services, for workshops concerned with blind persons, or the Department of Children and Family Services, when other handicapped persons are concerned, and such “workshop” means a place where any article is manufactured or handwork is carried on and which is operated for the primary purpose of providing employment to severely handicapped individuals, including the blind, who cannot be readily absorbed in the competitive labor market.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Handicapped” means an individual so severely disabled physically, or mentally, as to be unable to enter private industry on a competitive basis, but who can be made employable through an accredited nonprofitmaking agency for the handicapped, and which individual is over the age of 16 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State institutions and agencies shall, where possible, purchase brooms, mops, rugs, rubber mats and other supplies (other than the products of prison labor) from sheltered Florida workshops operated by accredited nonprofit corporations, provided that such goods and supplies are of standard quality and price.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When convenience or emergency requires it, the Department of Children and Family Services may upon request of the purchasing officer of any institution or agency relieve her or him from the obligation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No state agency or institution shall purchase products or supplies purporting to be made by physically handicapped persons in workshops not certified under the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any purchasing officer who violates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 29663, 1955; s. 2, ch. 61-210; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 358, ch. 71-136; s. 6, ch. 77-259; s. 9, ch. 79-12; s. 175, ch. 79-400; s. 79, ch. 91-224; s. 52, ch. 97-103; s. 199, ch. 99-8.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 409.262.</Text></Note></Section>