<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0413.393" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State plan for independent living.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state plan for independent living shall be jointly developed and submitted by the Florida Independent Living Council and the division, and the plan must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include the existence of appropriate planning, financial support and coordination, and other assistance to appropriately address, on a statewide and comprehensive basis, needs in the state for the provision of state independent living services; the development and support of a statewide network of centers for independent living; and working relationships between programs providing independent living services and independent living centers and the vocational rehabilitation program established to provide services for persons who have disabilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify the objectives to be achieved under the plan, establish time periods for the achievement of the objectives, and explain how such objectives are consistent with and further the purpose of this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify that the state will provide independent living services under this part to persons who have significant disabilities and will provide the services in accordance with an independent living plan mutually agreed upon by an appropriate staff member of the service provider and the individual, unless the individual signs a waiver stating that such a plan is unnecessary.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe the extent and scope of independent living services to be provided under this part to meet such objectives. If the state makes arrangements, by grant or contract, for providing such services, such arrangements shall be described in the plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth a design for the establishment of a statewide network of centers for independent living that comply with the standards and assurances set forth in federal law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth the steps that will be taken to maximize the cooperation, coordination, and working relationships among the independent living rehabilitation service program, the Florida Independent Living Council, centers for independent living, the division, other agencies represented on such council, other councils that address the needs of specific disability populations and issues, and other public and private entities determined to be appropriate by the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe how services funded under this part will be coordinated with, and complement, other services in order to avoid unnecessary duplication with other federal and state funding for centers for independent living and independent living services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set forth steps to be taken regarding outreach to populations that are not served or that are underserved by programs under the act, including minority groups and urban and rural populations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide satisfactory assurances that all entities receiving financial assistance funds under this part will notify all individuals seeking or receiving services under this part about the availability of the client-assistance program, the purposes of the services provided under such program, and how to contact such program; take affirmative action to employ and advance in employment qualified persons who have disabilities on the same terms and conditions required with respect to the employment of such persons; adopt such fiscal control and fund-accounting procedures as may be necessary to ensure the proper disbursement of and accounting for funds paid to the state under this part and meet all the other requirements of federal law or regulation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a method for the periodic evaluation of the effectiveness of the state plan in meeting the objectives of the state plan, including evaluation of satisfaction by persons who have disabilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state plan for independent living shall provide for the review and revision of the plan, not less than once every 3 years, to ensure the existence of appropriate planning, financial support and coordination, and other assistance to appropriately address statewide, the needs in the state for independent living services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 94-324; s. 5, ch. 2010-70.</History>
</Section>