<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0413.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperative agreements with other governmental agencies relative to joint use of services and facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with any state agency or institution, county, county agency or institution, municipality, or municipal agency or institution for the purpose of enabling the division and cooperating governing bodies, agencies, and institutions to jointly use their services and facilities to enlarge and improve the opportunities for persons who have disabilities to achieve self-support or self-care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For such an agreement to be valid, it must be entered into by the governing bodies, agencies, or institutions involved and approved by the administrative officers or by the boards governing the counties, municipalities, agencies, or institutions. Such agreements shall provide only for those services by each political subdivision, agency, or institution which the political subdivision, agency, or institution is authorized by law to provide, provided that any political subdivision, agency, or institution shall be permitted to withdraw and terminate its part of an agreement at the end of any fiscal year by giving the other political subdivision, agency, or institution involved 30 days’ notice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to effectuate the provisions of this section, the Executive Office of the Governor is authorized and empowered within its discretion, when it finds it to be in the public interest to do so, to permit two or more agencies, institutions, or county or city governments, pursuant to their mutual, unanimous request, to pool funds or to transfer funds to the account of the division in order to carry out plans for rehabilitation which are lawful and which give promise of better achieving the rehabilitation of persons who have disabilities than would result through the separate efforts of the participants in the agreement. Funds pooled or transferred under this section may be made available for expenditures for rehabilitation by the agency designated in the agreement to disburse such funds. Funds expended pursuant to agreements authorized under this section may be utilized for the purpose of matching funds available under the terms of federal laws pertaining to the rehabilitation of persons who have disabilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of each agreement made pursuant to this section shall be filed with the Department of State within a period of 30 days following the consummation of such agreement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 63-246; s. 13, ch. 65-239; ss. 2, 3, ch. 67-371; ss. 10, 19, 31, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 69-344; s. 307, ch. 77-147; s. 137, ch. 79-190; s. 4, ch. 87-227; s. 10, ch. 94-324.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 229.302, 229.0106.</Text></Note></Section>