<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0413.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 413.032-413.037:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Blind” means an individual having central visual acuity of 20/200 or less in the better eye with correcting glasses or a disqualifying field defect in which the peripheral field has contracted to such an extent that the widest diameter or visual field subtends an angular distance no greater than 20 degrees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Other severely handicapped” and “severely handicapped individuals” mean an individual or class of individuals under a physical or mental disability other than blindness, which, according to criteria established by the department, after consultation with appropriate entities of the state and taking into account the views of nongovernmental entities representing the handicapped, constitutes a substantial handicap to employment and is of such a nature as to prevent the individual under such disability from currently engaging in normal competitive employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified nonprofit agency for the blind” means an agency:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organized under the laws of the United States or of this state, operated in the interest of blind individuals, the net income of which does not inure in whole or in part to the benefit of any shareholder or other individual;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which complies with any applicable occupational health and safety standard prescribed by the Secretary of Labor of the United States;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which, in the production of commodities and the provision of services, whether or not the commodities or services are procured under ss. 413.032-413.037, during the fiscal year employs blind individuals for not less than 75 percent of the person-hours of direct labor required for the production or provision of the commodities or services; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which meets the criteria for determining nonprofit status under the provisions of s. 196.195 and is registered and in good standing as a charitable organization with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services under the provisions of chapter 496.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified nonprofit agency for other severely handicapped” means an agency:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organized under the laws of the United States or of this state, operated in the interest of severely handicapped individuals who are not blind, the net income of which does not inure in whole or in part to the benefit of any shareholder or other individual;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which complies with any applicable occupational health and safety standard prescribed by the Secretary of Labor of the United States;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which, in the production of commodities and in the provision of services, whether or not the commodities or services are procured under ss. 413.032-413.037, during the fiscal year employs blind or other severely handicapped individuals for not less than 75 percent of the person-hours of direct labor required for the production or provision of the commodities or services; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which meets the criteria for determining nonprofit status under the provisions of s. 196.195 and is registered and in good standing as a charitable organization with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services under the provisions of chapter 496.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct labor” includes all work required for preparation, processing, and packing, but not supervision, administration, inspection, and shipping.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” includes any political subdivision of the state having its own purchasing agency, such as a county, municipality, school district, or other public body, that is supported in whole or in part by funds appropriated by the Legislature.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-236; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 1, 6, 7, ch. 81-11; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; ss. 3, 4, ch. 88-37; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 8, ch. 97-98; s. 53, ch. 97-103; s. 38, ch. 2002-207.</History></Section>