<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0413.208" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service providers; quality assurance; fitness for responsibilities; background screening.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service providers must register with the division. To qualify for registration, the division must ensure that the service provider maintains an internal system of quality assurance, has proven functional systems, and is subject to a due-diligence inquiry as to its fitness to undertake service responsibilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition of registration under this section, level 2 background screening pursuant to chapter 435 must be conducted by the division on each of the following persons:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator or a similarly titled person who is responsible for the day-to-day operation of the service provider.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial officer or similarly titled person who is responsible for the financial operation of the service provider.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person employed by, or otherwise engaged on the behalf of, a service provider who is expected to have direct, face-to-face contact with a vulnerable person as defined in s. 435.02 while providing services to the vulnerable person and having access to that person’s living areas, funds, personal property, or personal identification information as defined in s. 817.568.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director of the service provider.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Level 2 background screening pursuant to chapter 435 is not required for the following persons:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed physician, nurse, or other professional who is licensed by the Department of Health and who has undergone fingerprinting and background screening as part of such licensure if providing a service that is within the scope of her or his licensed practice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A relative of the vulnerable person receiving services. For purposes of this section, the term “relative” means an individual who is the father, mother, stepfather, stepmother, son, daughter, brother, sister, grandmother, grandfather, great-grandmother, great-grandfather, grandson, granddaughter, uncle, aunt, first cousin, nephew, niece, husband, wife, father-in-law, mother-in-law, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, brother-in-law, sister-in-law, stepson, stepdaughter, stepbrother, stepsister, half-brother, or half-sister of the vulnerable person.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service providers are responsible for initiating and completing the background screening as a condition of registration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every 5 years following the initial screening, each person subject to background screening under this section must submit to level 2 background rescreening as a condition of the service provider retaining such registration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Until the person’s background screening results are retained in the clearinghouse created under s. 435.12, the division may accept as satisfying the requirements of this section proof of compliance with level 2 screening standards submitted within the previous 5 years to meet any provider or professional licensure requirements of the Agency for Health Care Administration, the Department of Health, the Department of Elderly Affairs, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, or the Department of Children and Family Services, provided:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The screening standards and disqualifying offenses for the prior screening are equivalent to those specified in s. 435.04 and this section;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person subject to screening has not had a break in service from a position that requires level 2 screening for more than 90 days; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such proof is accompanied, under penalty of perjury, by an affidavit of compliance with the provisions of chapter 435 and this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the disqualifying offenses listed in s. 435.04, all persons subject to undergo background screening pursuant to this section must not have an arrest awaiting final disposition for, must not have been found guilty of, regardless of adjudication, or entered a plea of nolo contendere or guilty to, and must not have been adjudicated delinquent, and the record has not been expunged for, any offense prohibited under any of the following provisions or similar law of another jurisdiction:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 409.920, relating to Medicaid provider fraud.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 409.9201, relating to Medicaid fraud.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 741.28, relating to domestic violence.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 817.034, relating to fraudulent acts through mail, wire, radio, electromagnetic, photoelectronic, or photooptical systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 817.234, relating to false and fraudulent insurance claims.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 817.505, relating to patient brokering.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 817.568, relating to criminal use of personal identification information.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 817.60, relating to obtaining a credit card through fraudulent means.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 817.61, relating to fraudulent use of credit cards, if the offense was a felony.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 831.01, relating to forgery.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 831.02, relating to uttering forged instruments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 831.07, relating to forging bank bills, checks, drafts, or promissory notes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 831.09, relating to uttering forged bank bills, checks, drafts, or promissory notes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 831.31, relating to the sale, manufacture, delivery, or possession with the intent to sell, manufacture, or deliver any counterfeit controlled substance, if the offense was a felony.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may grant an exemption from disqualification from this section only as provided in s. 435.07.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost of the state and national criminal history records checks required by level 2 screening and their retention shall be borne by the service provider or the person being screened.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall deny, suspend, terminate, or revoke a registration, rate agreement, purchase order, referral, contract, or other agreement, or pursue other remedies in addition to or in lieu of denial, suspension, termination, or revocation, for failure to comply with this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the division has reasonable cause to believe that grounds for denial or termination of registration exist, it shall provide written notification to the person affected, identifying the specific record that indicates noncompliance with the standards established in this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a provider refuses to remove a person who is employed by, or otherwise engaged on behalf of, the provider and who is found to be not in compliance with the standards established in this section from contact with any vulnerable person, the service provider’s registration and contract shall be revoked.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2002-22; s. 6, ch. 2012-73.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 7, ch. 2012-73, provides that “[t]he background screening requirements of s. 413.208, Florida Statutes, as amended by this act do not apply to existing registrants with the Division of Vocational Rehabilitation within the Department of Education in effect before October 1, 2012. Such requirements apply to all registrants with the division that are renewed or entered into on or after October 1, 2012.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>