<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0413.341" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Applicant and eligible individual records; confidential and privileged.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All oral and written records, information, letters, and reports received, made, or maintained by the division relative to any applicant or eligible individual are privileged, confidential, and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). Any person who discloses or releases such records, information, or communications in violation of this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Such records may not be released except that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records may be released to the applicant or eligible individual or his or her representative upon receipt of a written waiver from the applicant or eligible individual. Medical, psychological, or other information that the division believes may be harmful to an applicant or eligible individual may not be released directly to him or her, but must be provided through his or her designated representative.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records may be released to an entity or individual officially engaged in an audit, a program evaluation, or research. Personally identifying information released under this paragraph remains privileged, confidential, and exempt under this section and may not be disclosed to third parties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records used in administering the program may be released as required to administer the program or as required by an agency or political subdivision of the state in the performance of its duties. Any agency or political subdivision to which records are released under this paragraph may not disclose the records to third parties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records may be released upon the order of an administrative law judge, a hearing officer, a judge of compensation claims, an agency head exercising quasi-judicial authority, or a judge of a court of competent jurisdiction following a finding in an in camera proceeding that the records are relevant to the inquiry before the court and should be released. The in camera proceeding and all records relating thereto are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever an applicant or eligible individual receiving services has declared any intention to harm other persons or property, such declaration may be disclosed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may also release personal information about an applicant or eligible individual receiving services in order to protect him or her or others when he or she poses a threat to his or her own safety or to the safety of others and shall, upon official request, release such information to law enforcement agencies investigating the commission of a crime.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records that come into the possession of the division and that are confidential by other provisions of law are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1), and may not be released by the division, except as provided in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-214; s. 17, ch. 90-330; s. 36, ch. 91-46; s. 57, ch. 91-220; s. 2, ch. 91-269; s. 19, ch. 94-324; s. 265, ch. 96-406; s. 196, ch. 96-410; s. 1030, ch. 97-103; s. 3, ch. 2010-70.</History>
</Section>