<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0413.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Products and services by blind persons; sale, exhibition regulated.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When appearing in the Florida Statutes “blind person” shall mean an individual having central visual acuity 20/200 or less in the better eye with correcting glasses, or a disqualifying field defect in which the peripheral field has contracted to such an extent that the widest diameter or visual field subtends an angular distance no greater than 20 degrees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of the Florida Statutes no representation shall be made that a product or service is “blind-made” unless the manufacturer employs blind persons to an extent constituting not less than 75 percent of the total hours worked by personnel engaged in the direct labor of production of manufactured blind-made products, or services. Direct labor production shall mean all work required for the preparation, processing and packing but not including supervision, administration, inspection and shipping, or the production of the materials from which the finished product is manufactured.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person or organization shall sell, distribute, or exhibit any product or service which purports or is advertised to be “blind-made,” unless the Division of Blind Services shall certify that such product or service complies with the provisions of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, including the officers, owners, or members of any corporation or organization that violates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 28029, 1953; s. 2, ch. 61-210; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 357, ch. 71-136; s. 291, ch. 77-147; s. 5, ch. 77-259; s. 78, ch. 91-224.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 413.09, 409.261.</Text></Note></Section>