<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0413.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Interference with or injury to a service animal; penalties; restitution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who, with reckless disregard, interferes with, or permits a dog that he or she owns or is in the immediate control of to interfere with, the use of a service animal by obstructing, intimidating, or otherwise jeopardizing the safety of the service animal or its user commits a misdemeanor of the second degree for the first offense and a misdemeanor of the first degree for each subsequent offense, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who, with reckless disregard, injures or kills, or permits a dog that he or she owns or is in the immediate control of to injure or kill, a service animal commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who intentionally injures or kills, or permits a dog that he or she owns or is in the immediate control of to injure or kill, a service animal commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is convicted of a violation of this section, in addition to any other penalty, must make full restitution for all damages that arise out of or are related to the offense, including incidental and consequential damages incurred by the service animal’s user.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restitution includes the value of the service animal; replacement and training or retraining expenses for the service animal and the user; veterinary and other medical and boarding expenses for the service animal; medical expenses for the user; and lost wages or income incurred by the user during any period that the user is without the services of the service animal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2002-176; s. 2, ch. 2005-63.</History></Section>