<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0159.704" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Designation by Board of Governors of the State University System; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall prepare and submit to the Board of Governors of the State University System a petition requesting that the authority be designated a research and development authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition shall contain, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resolution of the governing board of the county constituting the authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A concept of operation of the proposed research and development park consistent with s. 159.27(7) and the purposes of ss. 159.701-159.7095.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of affiliation with one or more state-based, accredited, public or private institutions of higher learning with research and development capabilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of availability of a site suitable for the projected scope of operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of the economic feasibility of the proposed research and development park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plan for funding the development of the proposed research and development park, including a minimum financial commitment by the authority of $50,000 in liquid assets for development purposes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of the petition and designation as a research and development authority by the Board of Governors of the State University System, the authority shall be empowered to transact any business and exercise any power authorized by ss. 159.701-159.7095 for the purposes set out in such sections.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 79-101; s. 4, ch. 85-313; s. 5, ch. 88-409; s. 18, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>