<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0159.604" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of housing finance authorities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county in this state may create by ordinance a separate public body corporate and politic, to be known as the “Housing Finance Authority” of the county for which it is created, to carry out only the powers granted in this act. A housing finance authority shall not transact any business or exercise any powers under this act until the governing body of the county for which such housing finance authority is created passes a resolution declaring the need for a housing finance authority to function to alleviate a shortage of housing and capital for investment in housing in its area of operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any suit, action, or proceeding involving the validity or enforcement of or relating to any contract of a housing finance authority, the housing finance authority shall be conclusively deemed to have been established and authorized to transact business and exercise its powers under this act upon proof of the adoption of an ordinance by the appropriate governing body declaring the need for the housing finance authority. The ordinance shall be sufficient if it declares the need for such a housing finance authority and finds that there is a shortage of housing and capital for investment in housing within its area of operation. A copy of the ordinance certified by the clerk of the circuit court shall be admissible in evidence in any suit, action, or proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county for which the housing finance authority is created may, at its sole discretion, and at any time, alter or change the structure, organization, programs, or activities of any housing finance authority, including the power to terminate such authority, subject to any limitation on the impairment of contracts entered into by such authority and subject to the limitations or requirements of this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 78-89.</History></Section>