<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0159.47" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of the authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority is authorized and empowered:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have perpetual succession as a body politic and corporate and to adopt bylaws for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt an official seal and alter the same at pleasure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To maintain an office at such place or places in the county as it may designate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and be sued in its own name and to plead and be impleaded;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter into contracts for any of the purposes enumerated in ss. 159.44-159.53 and in the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To issue revenue bonds or other debt obligations repayable solely from revenues derived from the sale, operation, or leasing of projects or other payments received under financing agreements with respect thereto, subject to the approval or disapproval of the commission pursuant to s. 125.01(1)(z).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To exercise all the powers in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of revenue bonds to finance the cost of projects conferred on counties, municipalities, special districts, and other local governmental bodies by the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act. All of the privileges, benefits, powers, and terms of that act shall be fully applicable to authorities created pursuant to s. 159.45. Industrial development revenue bonds may be authorized, issued, and sold by authorities in compliance with the criteria and requirements set forth in the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act. The bonds of each issue shall be dated; bear interest at such rate or rates, including variable rates; mature at such time or times; be redeemable prior to maturity at such price or prices; be in such denominations; contain such recitals; and be sold for such price or prices and in such manner as provided in the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act. Projects may be acquired, constructed, leased, operated, or sold in the manner provided in the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act, and the items of cost as enumerated therein may be included as project costs. The repayment of bonds issued by the authorities may be secured by trust agreements or security agreements as set forth in that act; and fees, rents, and charges for the use of any project or any part of any project may be collected and fixed by the authority in the manner provided in that act. All moneys received pursuant to the provisions of ss. 159.44-159.53 shall constitute trust funds as provided in the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act. The remedies provided by the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act shall also be applicable to bonds issued pursuant to ss. 159.44-159.53, and bonds of the authority may be refunded in the manner provided therein and shall be eligible for investment as provided in that act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire by lease, purchase, or option real and personal property for use as sites for the location of projects as defined in the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act. Authorities shall have the power to prepare sites for industrial use, including industrial parks to be used in connection with one or more projects, and may construct thereon access roads, drainage facilities, utilities, and other improvements necessary for ultimate use by industrial projects. The acquisition, development, and financing of such sites may be in the manner provided in ss. 159.44-159.53 and the Florida Industrial Development Financing Act. Authorities may also use such current funds as are available to acquire and prepare property as sites for industrial development purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To secure the issuance and repayment of industrial development bonds by a lease, mortgage, or other security instrument encumbering only the capital improvements which are financed by the authority in any case in which an addition to a project is financed or in which less than the entire project is financed or refinanced by industrial development bonds, subject to the approval or disapproval of the commission pursuant to s. 125.01(1)(z). The lease, mortgage, or other security instrument may include a security interest in both the land and personal property or may include a lease, mortgage, or other security instrument sufficient for the purpose encumbering only the personal property, including machinery and equipment, which is being financed. In financing projects, authorities may enter into financing agreements of such types as they may approve with such security instruments or trust agreements as the authority shall deem adequate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide, arrange, and make expenditures for transportation, lodging, meals, and other reasonable and necessary items and services for such necessary persons as determined by the chair of the authority, in connection with the performance of promotional and other duties of the authority. However, entertainment expenses shall be authorized only when meeting with business prospects, as defined in paragraph (l), potential prospects, purchasers of Florida exports, potential purchasers of Florida exports, and foreign governmental dignitaries. All travel and entertainment-related expenditures in excess of $10 made pursuant to this section shall be substantiated by paid bills therefor. Complete and detailed justification for all travel and entertainment-related expenditures made pursuant to this section shall be shown on the travel expense voucher or attached thereto. Transportation and other incidental expenses, other than those provided in s. 112.061, shall only be authorized for members and employees of the authority, other authorized persons, and business prospects when traveling pursuant to paragraph (l). All other transportation and incidental expenses pursuant to this section shall be as provided in s. 112.061. Operational or promotional advances, as defined in s. 288.35(4), obtained pursuant to this section, shall not be commingled with any other funds. Any unused operational, promotional, or other funds advanced pursuant to this section shall be refunded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay by advancement or reimbursement, or a combination thereof, the costs of per diem of members or employees of the authority and other authorized persons, for foreign travel at the current rates as specified in the federal publication “Standardized Regulations (Government Civilians, Foreign Areas),” and incidental expenses as provided in s. 112.061. The provisions of this paragraph shall apply for any member or employee of the authority traveling in foreign countries for the purpose of promoting economic or industrial development of the county, if such travel expenses are approved and certified by the agency head from whose funds the traveler is paid. As used in this paragraph, the term “authorized person” has the same meaning as provided in s. 112.061(2)(e). With the exception of provisions concerning rates of payment for per diem, the provisions of s. 112.061 are applicable to the travel described in this subsection. As used in this paragraph, “foreign travel” means all travel outside the United States. Persons traveling in foreign countries pursuant to this section shall not be entitled to reimbursements or advancements pursuant to s. 112.061(6)(a)2.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay by advancement or reimbursement, or a combination thereof, the actual reasonable and necessary costs of meals, lodging, and incidental expenses of members and employees of the authority and other authorized persons when meeting with a business prospect of the state, purchaser of Florida exports, or foreign governmental dignitaries. Furthermore, when actually traveling with a business prospect or purchaser of Florida exports or foreign governmental dignitaries, the actual cost of transportation is allowable. As used in this paragraph, “business prospect” means any person or representative of a firm actively considering the location of a business within the county. With the exception of the provisions concerning rates of payment, the provisions of s. 112.061 are applicable to the travel described in this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraphs (j), (k), and (l) of subsection (1) are applicable to any county agency which was created by special act for the purpose of attracting industry; and the chair, members, or employees of such agency shall be considered to be the chair, members, or employees of an authority under this section for purposes of those paragraphs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 70-229; ss. 5, 6, ch. 80-209; s. 15, ch. 80-287; s. 23, ch. 83-271; s. 887, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>