<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0159.605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Members; employees; duties and compensation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each housing finance authority shall be composed of not less than five members appointed by the governing body of the county for which the housing finance authority is created, one of whom shall be designated chair. Not less than a majority of the members shall be knowledgeable in one of the following fields: labor, finance, or commerce. The terms of the members shall be 4 years each, except that the terms of the initial members shall be as follows: Two members shall serve a term of 1 year; one member shall serve a term of 2 years; one member shall serve a term of 3 years; and the remainder shall serve a term of 4 years. A member of the housing finance authority shall hold office until his or her successor has been appointed and has qualified. Each vacancy shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term. A certificate of the appointment or reappointment of any member of the housing finance authority shall be filed with the clerk of the circuit court of the county, and the certificate shall be conclusive evidence of the due and proper appointment of the member. A member shall receive no compensation for his or her services, but shall be entitled to necessary expenses, including travel expenses, incurred in the discharge of duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers of each housing finance authority granted by this act shall be vested in the members of the housing finance authority in office from time to time. A majority of the members constitutes a quorum, and action may be taken by the housing finance authority upon a vote of a majority of the members present.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A housing finance authority may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ such agents and employees, permanent or temporary, as it requires and shall determine the qualifications, duties, and compensation of those agents and employees.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegate to an agent or employee such powers or duties as it considers proper.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ its own legal counsel.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create or assist in creating corporations that qualify as not-for-profit corporations under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, and under the laws of this state, and that are engaged in acquiring, constructing, reconstructing, or rehabilitating qualifying housing developments.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Until the members of the housing finance authority are appointed, the governing body of the county for which the housing finance authority is created and the chair of the housing finance authority shall have full authority to carry out the powers of a housing finance authority under this act; however, the governing body shall not delegate its authority to the chair under this provision. Except as provided in this section, no member of the housing finance authority may be an officer or employee of the county for which the housing finance authority is created.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-89; s. 2, ch. 86-214; s. 1, ch. 93-221; s. 889, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>