<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0159.285" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional county powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county shall have full power and authority to issue revenue bonds for the purpose of financing and providing funds to pay the cost of pollution-control facilities or devices, or to provide facilities for the furnishing of water or sewerage or solid-waste disposal incorporated as a part of any project whether or not the site or sites of the project are located wholly or in part outside the boundaries of the county issuing the revenue bonds. However, the ultimate owner or user of the project shall maintain the project or the owner’s or user’s principal place of business within the boundaries of the county issuing the revenue bonds, and the revenue bonds shall comply with the requirements of s. 10(c), Art. VII of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition precedent to issuing revenue bonds for the purpose of financing and providing funds to pay the cost of pollution-control facilities or devices or to provide facilities for the furnishing of water or sewerage or solid-waste disposal incorporated in a project located outside the boundaries of the county as authorized by subsection (1), the board of county commissioners or industrial development authority shall determine that the proposed facilities or devices are reasonably designed and intended to eliminate, mitigate, abate, control, or prevent air or water pollution or to provide facilities for the furnishing of water or sewerage or solid-waste disposal within the meaning of the rules and regulations of the Internal Revenue Service and that the ultimate owner or user of the project involved is financially responsible and fully capable and willing to fulfill its obligations under the contractual arrangements or lease with the county governing the project, including the obligation to pay rent or contract installments in the amounts and at the times required, to operate, repair, and maintain, at its own expense, the project leased or owned, and to serve the purposes of this part and such other responsibilities as may be imposed under the lease or contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county issuing revenue bonds pursuant to subsection (1) for the purpose of financing and providing funds for a project located wholly or in part outside the boundaries of the county issuing the revenue bonds may, in its discretion, request the board of county commissioners or the industrial development authority for the county or counties in which the site or sites of the project are located wholly or in part to make the determination required by s. 159.29 of the county issuing the bonds. The determination by such county or counties in which the project is located wholly or in part that the criteria and requirements of s. 159.29 are met shall be final and conclusive and shall constitute satisfaction of the requirements of s. 159.29.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 75-126; s. 1, ch. 77-269; s. 1, ch. 78-120.</History></Section>