<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0159.809" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recapture of unused amounts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On June 1 of each year, any portion of each allocation made pursuant to s. 159.804(4) for which the division has not issued a written confirmation shall be added to the Florida First Business allocation pool.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On July 1 of each year, any portion of each allocation made pursuant to s. 159.804(2) for which the division has not issued a written confirmation shall be added to the Florida First Business allocation pool. On July 1 of each year, any portion of each allocation made pursuant to s. 159.804(3) for which the division has not issued a written confirmation or has not received an issuance report shall be added to the Florida First Business allocation pool. On and after July 2 of each year, any portion of such allocations for which a written confirmation has been issued and which confirmation expires or is relinquished by the agency receiving the allocation, shall be added to the state allocation pool.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On October 1 of each year, any portion of the allocation made to the Florida First Business allocation pool pursuant to s. 159.804(5), subsection (1), or subsection (2), which is eligible for carryforward pursuant to s. 146(f) of the Code but which has not been certified for carryforward by the Department of Economic Opportunity, shall be returned to the Florida First Business allocation pool.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On November 16 of each year, any portion of the allocation, made pursuant to s. 159.804(1), s. 159.804(5), or subsection (1), subsection (2), or subsection (3), other than as provided in s. 159.8083, for which an issuance report for bonds utilizing such an allocation has not been received by the division prior to that date shall be added to the state allocation pool.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 85-282; s. 7, ch. 87-222; s. 8, ch. 92-127; s. 12, ch. 95-416; s. 6, ch. 96-210; s. 6, ch. 2000-353; s. 55, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>