<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0159.803" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“County” means the geographic boundaries of each county as established by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private activity bond” or “bond” means any bond which requires an allocation pursuant to s. 146 of the Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the director of the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration or his or her designee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the State of Florida, any unit of local government, industrial development authority, or other entity in this state authorized to issue private activity bonds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Priority project” means a solid waste disposal facility or a sewage facility, as such terms are defined in s. 142 of the Code, or a water facility, as defined in s. 142 of the Code, which is operated by a member-owned, not-for-profit utility, or any project which is to be located in an area which is an enterprise zone designated pursuant to s. 290.0065.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Issued” or “issuance” has the same meaning as in the Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Code” means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, and the regulations and rulings issued thereunder.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Housing bonds” means bonds issued pursuant to s. 142(d) of the Code to finance qualified residential units or mortgage revenue bonds issued pursuant to s. 143 of the Code which require an allocation under s. 146 of the Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturing facility” means a facility described in s. 144(a)(12)(C) of the Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Florida First Business project” means any project which is certified by the Department of Economic Opportunity as eligible to receive an allocation from the Florida First Business allocation pool established pursuant to s. 159.8083. The Department of Economic Opportunity may certify those projects meeting the criteria set forth in s. 288.106(4)(b) or any project providing a substantial economic benefit to this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgage credit certificate” means those certificates issued pursuant to s. 25 of the Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 85-282; s. 8, ch. 86-181; s. 2, ch. 87-222; s. 1, ch. 92-127; s. 147, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 60, ch. 94-136; s. 1436, ch. 95-147; s. 6, ch. 95-416; s. 2, ch. 96-210; s. 7, ch. 96-320; s. 39, ch. 2000-210; s. 7, ch. 2004-381; s. 2, ch. 2010-136; s. 52, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>