<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0159.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative findings and purposes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agriculture, tourism, urban development, historic preservation, education, and health care industries, among others, are vital to the economy of the state and to the welfare of the people and need to be enhanced and expanded to improve the competitive position of the state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a need to enhance other economic activity in the state by attracting manufacturing development, business enterprise management, and other activities conducive to economic promotion in order to provide a stronger, more balanced, and stable economy in the state, while providing through pollution control and otherwise for the health and safety of the people;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to improve the prosperity and welfare of the state and its inhabitants; to improve education, living conditions, and health care; to promote the preservation of historic structures; to promote the rehabilitation of enterprise zones; to promote improved transportation; to promote effective and efficient pollution control throughout the state; to promote the advancement of education and science and research in and the economic development of the state; and to increase purchasing power and opportunities for gainful employment, it is necessary and in the public interest to facilitate the financing of the projects provided for in this part and to facilitate and encourage the planning and development of these projects without regard to the boundaries between counties, municipalities, special districts, and other local governmental bodies or agencies in order to more effectively and efficiently serve the interests of the greatest number of people in the widest area practicable; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes to be achieved by such projects and the financing of them in compliance with the criteria and requirements of this part are predominantly the public purposes stated in this section, and such purposes implement the governmental purposes under the State Constitution of providing for the health, safety, and welfare of the people, including implementing the purpose of s. 10(c), Art. VII of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 69-104; s. 1, ch. 75-126; s. 2, ch. 79-101; s. 1, ch. 80-287; s. 7, ch. 82-119; s. 18, ch. 83-271; s. 1, ch. 84-308; s. 3, ch. 85-282.</History></Section>