<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0159.8083"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida First Business allocation pool.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida First Business allocation pool is hereby established. The Florida First Business allocation pool shall be available solely to provide written confirmation for private activity bonds to finance Florida First Business projects certified by the Department of Economic Opportunity as eligible to receive a written confirmation. Allocations from such pool shall be awarded statewide pursuant to procedures specified in s. 159.805, except that the provisions of s. 159.805(2), (3), and (6) do not apply. Florida First Business projects that are eligible for a carryforward do not lose their allocation pursuant to s. 159.809(3) on October 1, or pursuant to s. 159.809(4) on November 16, if they have applied for and have been granted a carryforward by the division pursuant to s. 159.81(1). In issuing written confirmations of allocations for Florida First Business projects, the division shall use the Florida First Business allocation pool. If allocation is not available from the Florida First Business allocation pool, the division shall issue written confirmations of allocations for Florida First Business projects pursuant to s. 159.806 or s. 159.807, in such order. For the purpose of determining priority within a regional allocation pool or the state allocation pool, notices of intent to issue bonds for Florida First Business projects to be issued from a regional allocation pool or the state allocation pool shall be considered to have been received by the division at the time it is determined by the division that the Florida First Business allocation pool is unavailable to issue confirmation for such Florida First Business project. If the total amount requested in notices of intent to issue private activity bonds for Florida First Business projects exceeds the total amount of the Florida First Business allocation pool, the director shall forward all timely notices of intent to issue, which are received by the division for such projects, to the Department of Economic Opportunity, which shall render a decision as to which notices of intent to issue are to receive written confirmations.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 95-416; s. 9, ch. 96-320; s. 8, ch. 2000-353; s. 54, ch. 2011-142; s. 43, ch. 2012-116.</History></Section>