<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0159.612" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A housing finance authority may issue revenue bonds from time to time in the discretion of the housing finance authority for the purposes of this act. A housing finance authority may also issue refunding bonds for the purpose of paying, retiring, or refunding any bonds previously issued by such housing finance authority. A housing finance authority may also issue refunding bonds for the purpose of paying, retiring, or refunding any bonds previously issued by another housing finance authority if such other housing finance authority consents to the issuance of such refunding bonds. A housing finance authority may issue such types of bonds as it may determine; provided that the principal and interest on such bonds are payable solely and only from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The repayment of any loans made by the housing finance authority pursuant to the provisions of s. 159.608 or purchased by the housing finance authority pursuant to s. 159.608; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of any housing loans or commitments to purchase housing loans which are purchased pursuant to s. 159.608.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bonds issued pursuant to the provisions of this act shall be secured by a mortgage or other security device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no event shall any bonds issued pursuant to the provisions of this act be payable from the general revenues of the housing finance authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the members of a housing finance authority nor any person executing the bonds shall be liable personally on the bonds by reason of the issuance thereof. The bonds issued pursuant to the provisions hereof, and the bonds shall so state on their face, shall not be a debt of the county or the state, or any political subdivision thereof; and neither the county, nor any state or political subdivision thereof, shall be liable thereon; nor in any event shall such bonds or obligations be payable out of any funds or properties other than those of the housing finance authority.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 78-89; s. 1, ch. 99-178.</History></Section>