<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; ss. 943.085-943.255.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following words and phrases as used in ss. 943.085-943.255 are defined as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law enforcement officer” means any person who is elected, appointed, or employed full time by any municipality or the state or any political subdivision thereof; who is vested with authority to bear arms and make arrests; and whose primary responsibility is the prevention and detection of crime or the enforcement of the penal, criminal, traffic, or highway laws of the state. This definition includes all certified supervisory and command personnel whose duties include, in whole or in part, the supervision, training, guidance, and management responsibilities of full-time law enforcement officers, part-time law enforcement officers, or auxiliary law enforcement officers but does not include support personnel employed by the employing agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Correctional officer” means any person who is appointed or employed full time by the state or any political subdivision thereof, or by any private entity which has contracted with the state or county, and whose primary responsibility is the supervision, protection, care, custody, and control, or investigation, of inmates within a correctional institution; however, the term “correctional officer” does not include any secretarial, clerical, or professionally trained personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Correctional probation officer” means a person who is employed full time by the state whose primary responsibility is the supervised custody, surveillance, and control of assigned inmates, probationers, parolees, or community controllees within institutions of the Department of Corrections or within the community. The term includes supervisory personnel whose duties include, in whole or in part, the supervision, training, and guidance of correctional probation officers, but excludes management and administrative personnel above, but not including, the probation and parole regional administrator level.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employing agency” means any agency or unit of government or any municipality or the state or any political subdivision thereof, or any agent thereof, which has constitutional or statutory authority to employ or appoint persons as officers. The term also includes any private entity which has contracted with the state or county for the operation and maintenance of a nonjuvenile detention facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commission” means the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Part-time law enforcement officer” means any person employed or appointed less than full time, as defined by an employing agency, with or without compensation, who is vested with authority to bear arms and make arrests and whose primary responsibility is the prevention and detection of crime or the enforcement of the penal, criminal, traffic, or highway laws of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Part-time correctional officer” means any person who is employed or appointed less than full time, as defined by the employing or appointing agency, with or without compensation, whose responsibilities include the supervision, protection, care, custody, and control of inmates within a correctional institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Auxiliary law enforcement officer” means any person employed or appointed, with or without compensation, who aids or assists a full-time or part-time law enforcement officer and who, while under the direct supervision of a full-time or part-time law enforcement officer, has the authority to arrest and perform law enforcement functions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Auxiliary correctional officer” means any person employed or appointed, with or without compensation, who aids or assists a full-time or part-time correctional officer and who, while under the supervision of a full-time or part-time correctional officer, has the same authority as a full-time or part-time correctional officer for the purpose of providing supervision, protection, care, custody, and control of inmates within a correctional institution or a county or municipal detention facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private criminal justice training school” means any private school, corporation, or institution, for profit or not for profit, devoted wholly or in part to instruction, by correspondence or otherwise, in criminal justice services, administration, training, and education, which awards any type of certificate, diploma, degree, or recognition for attendance, graduation, study, or participation to students, enrollees, or participants. This definition applies to all such schools operating wholly or in part within the state, including those chartered, incorporated, or formed outside the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Support personnel” means any person employed or appointed by an employing agency who is not an officer or, as specified by the commission, other professional employee in the criminal justice system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Program” means the Criminal Justice Professionalism Program of the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Head of the department” means the Governor and Cabinet, as provided for in ss. 20.201 and 20.03(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Officer” means any person employed or appointed as a full-time, part-time, or auxiliary law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public criminal justice training school” means any academy operated by an employing agency that is certified by the commission to conduct criminal justice training courses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Criminal justice training school” means any private or public criminal justice training school certified by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Training center director” means a full-time salaried employee of a criminal justice training school who is responsible for the scheduling and general management of criminal justice courses and supervision and evaluation of criminal justice instructors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Auxiliary correctional probation officer” means any person employed or appointed, with or without compensation, who aids or assists a full-time or part-time correctional probation officer and who, while under the supervision of a full-time or part-time correctional probation officer, has the same authority as a full-time or part-time correctional probation officer for the purpose of providing supervision of offenders in the community.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Part-time correctional probation officer” means a person who is employed less than full time by the state whose primary responsibility is the supervised custody, surveillance, and control of assigned inmates, probationers, parolees, or community controllees within institutions of the Department of Corrections or in the community.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Diverse population” means members of a cultural group with common origins, customs, and styles of living. This definition includes both ethnic and religious minorities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Criminal justice executive” includes executives of law enforcement, correctional, and correctional probation agencies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 74-386; s. 4, ch. 78-323; s. 2, ch. 80-71; ss. 4, 24, 25, ch. 81-24; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 1, ch. 83-259; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 1, ch. 84-156; s. 3, ch. 84-258; ss. 6, 40, ch. 86-183; s. 5, ch. 86-187; ss. 5, 6, ch. 87-186; s. 39, ch. 89-526; s. 47, ch. 91-110; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 12, ch. 95-283; s. 1, ch. 97-225; s. 16, ch. 98-94; s. 1042, ch. 2002-387; s. 2, ch. 2007-45.</History></Section>