<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0943.0313" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Domestic Security Oversight Council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that there exists a need to provide executive direction and leadership with respect to terrorism prevention, preparation, protection, response, and recovery efforts by state and local agencies in this state. In recognition of this need, the Domestic Security Oversight Council is hereby created. The council shall serve as an advisory council pursuant to s. 20.03(7) to provide guidance to the state’s regional domestic security task forces and other domestic security working groups and to make recommendations to the Governor and the Legislature regarding the expenditure of funds and allocation of resources related to counter-terrorism and domestic security efforts.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEMBERSHIP.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Domestic Security Oversight Council shall consist of the following voting members:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Division of Emergency Management.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Agriculture.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adjutant general of the Florida National Guard.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state chief information officer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each sheriff or chief of police who serves as a co-chair of a regional domestic security task force pursuant to s. 943.0312(1)(b).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each of the department’s special agents in charge who serve as a co-chair of a regional domestic security task force.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two representatives of the Florida Fire Chiefs Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the Florida Police Chiefs Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the Florida Prosecuting Attorneys Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair of the Statewide Domestic Security Intelligence Committee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="16">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the Florida Hospital Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="17">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the Emergency Medical Services Advisory Council.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="18">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the Florida Emergency Preparedness Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="19">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One representative of the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the members designated in paragraph (a), the council may invite other ex officio, nonvoting members to attend and participate in council meetings. Those nonvoting members may include, but need not be limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Health Care Administration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Environmental Protection.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Division of Law Enforcement within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Commission on Human Relations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the United States Coast Guard.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A United States Attorney from a federal judicial circuit within this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A special agent in charge from an office of the Federal Bureau of Investigation within this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ORGANIZATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the council serves a legitimate state, county, and municipal purpose and that service on the council is consistent with a member’s principal service in public office or employment. Membership on the council does not disqualify a member from holding any other public office or being employed by a public entity, except that a member of the Legislature may not serve on the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement shall serve as chair of the council, and the director of the Division of Emergency Management shall serve as vice chair of the council. In the absence of the chair, the vice chair shall serve as chair. In the absence of the vice chair, the chair may name any member of the council to perform the duties of the chair if such substitution does not extend beyond a defined meeting, duty, or period of time.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any absent voting member of the council may be represented by a designee empowered to act on any issue before the council to the same extent that the designating member is empowered. If a co-chair of a regional domestic security task force is absent from a council meeting, the co-chair shall appoint a subcommittee chair of that task force as the designee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall establish bylaws for its general governance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of the council serving by reason of the office or employment held by the member shall cease to serve on the council at such time as he or she ceases to hold the office or employment which was the basis for appointment to the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives from agencies or organizations other than those designated by title shall be chosen by the entity. Except for those individuals designated by title, council members shall be certified annually to the chair by the organization they represent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council or their designees shall serve without compensation but are entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses pursuant to s. 112.061.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide the council with the staff support necessary to assist in the performance of its duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEETINGS.<EmDash />The council must meet at least semiannually. Additional meetings may be held as necessary. A majority of the members of the council constitutes a quorum.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall establish an executive committee consisting of the following members:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Division of Emergency Management.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Agriculture.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement shall serve as the chair of the executive committee, and the director of the Division of Emergency Management shall serve as the vice chair of the executive committee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive committee shall approve all matters brought before the council prior to consideration. When expedited action of the council is deemed necessary by the chair or vice chair, the executive committee may act on behalf of the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DUTIES OF THE COUNCIL.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Domestic Security Oversight Council shall serve as an advisory council to the Governor, the Legislature, and the Chief of Domestic Security. The council shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the development, maintenance, and operation of a comprehensive multidisciplinary domestic security strategy that will guide the state’s prevention, preparedness, protection, response, and recovery efforts against terrorist attacks and make appropriate recommendations to ensure the implementation of that strategy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the development of integrated funding plans to support specific projects, goals, and objectives necessary to the state’s domestic security strategy and make appropriate recommendations to implement those plans.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and recommend approval of prioritized recommendations from regional domestic security task forces and state working groups on the use of available funding to ensure the use of such funds in a manner that best promotes the goals of statewide, regional, and local domestic security through coordinated planning and implementation strategies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and recommend approval of statewide policies and operational protocols that support the domestic security efforts of the regional domestic security task forces and state agencies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the overall statewide effectiveness of domestic security and counter-terrorism efforts in order to provide suggestions to improve or enhance those efforts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the efforts of any agency or entity involved in state or local domestic security and counter-terrorism efforts that requests assistance or that appears to need such review in order to provide suggestions to improve or enhance those efforts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review efforts within the state to better secure state and local infrastructure against terrorist attack and make recommendations to enhance the effectiveness of such efforts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and recommend legislative initiatives related to the state’s domestic security and provide endorsement or recommendations to enhance the effectiveness of such efforts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review statewide or multiagency mobilizations and responses to major domestic security incidents and recommend suggestions for training, improvement of response efforts, or improvement of coordination or for other strategies that may be derived as necessary from such reviews.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct any additional review or inquiry or make recommendations to the Governor and Legislature in support of other initiatives, as may be necessary, to fulfill the function of general oversight of the state’s domestic security and counter-terrorism efforts and to promote increased security.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote and preserve intergovernmental cooperation and consensus among state and local agencies, the Federal Government, private entities, other states, and other nations, as appropriate, under the guidance of the Governor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Domestic Security Oversight Council shall make an annual funding recommendation to the Governor and Legislature which shall prioritize funding requests based on allocations from all available sources for implementing the state’s domestic security strategy. This recommendation must include the prioritized recommendations of each of the regional domestic security task forces and the various working groups that participate in the prioritization process for funding allocations. The recommendation must reflect the consideration of strategic priorities and allocations that best serve the state’s overall domestic security needs. The recommendation shall be transmitted to the Governor and the Legislature by December 31 of each year. If additional funds become available, or reallocation of funding is required beyond current spending authorizations, the council may make recommendations to the Governor for consideration by the Legislative Budget Commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORTS.<EmDash />The council shall report annually on its activities, on or before December 31 of each calendar year, to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the chairs of the committees having principal jurisdiction over domestic security in the Senate and the House of Representatives.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AGENCY DESIGNATION.<EmDash />For purposes of this section, the Domestic Security Oversight Council shall be considered a criminal justice agency within the definition of s. 119.011(4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2005-165; s. 13, ch. 2007-105; s. 111, ch. 2008-6; s. 444, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>