<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.2567" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Operation and administration accounts; annual budget.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each directing agency or school is authorized to create an account in the name of its regional assessment center within the restricted current fund at the directing school or directing agency, which account within the restricted current fund must be used exclusively for the operation and administration of the center in the county’s region. Moneys deposited into the account within the restricted current fund shall consist of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicant fees and user fees, as established by the center’s advisory board for use of the services of the center by prospective employees and participating criminal justice agencies in each region.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such donations and grants as the center may receive.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">No funds may be transferred from the general current fund, the auxiliary fund, or any other restricted current fund for the operation of any center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each directing school or directing agency shall prepare an annual budget for the operation and administration of its center. The budget for any fiscal year shall be submitted to the advisory board of the center for its consideration and approval no later than 60 days prior to the end of the previous fiscal year. The total expenditures for any fiscal year may not exceed the funds available from the account within the restricted current fund described in subsection (1), and no program for the center may be approved by the advisory board unless all funds for the program are available from the account within the restricted current fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 91-205.</History></Section>