<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Option to become state-operated laboratory; operational control.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those laboratories specified in s. 943.35 may submit to the Department of Law Enforcement a request to become state-operated laboratories. Such request shall include an offer to convey to the state the laboratory facility, including the physical plant, fixtures, equipment, and property on which such facility is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement shall evaluate the request and make a determination based on the crime laboratory needs of the state. If the department concurs with the request, a plan for the transfer of the laboratory shall be jointly developed between representatives of the department and the chief of such laboratory or his or her designated representative. Such transfer plan shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision to allow any employee of such laboratory to maintain his or her position, or a position with comparable duties, with no decrease in pay for a reasonable transition period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision specifying the duration of the transition period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision to ensure that there shall be no reduction in the level of services provided by the laboratory during the transition period. Implementation of the transfer plan is conditioned upon the approval of the Governor through inclusion of the expenses entailed in such transfer in his or her budget recommendations to the Legislature and the Legislature approving such recommendation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At such time as the state assumes the full financial responsibility for the operation of the laboratory, the Department of Law Enforcement will assume operational control, subject to the provisions of the transfer plan. The laboratory facility, including the physical plant, fixtures, equipment, and property on which such facility is located, shall be conveyed to the state upon assumption of full financial responsibility by the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 9, ch. 74-362; s. 2, ch. 78-347; s. 1641, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>