<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.133" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Responsibilities of employing agency, commission, and program with respect to compliance with employment qualifications and the conduct of background investigations; injunctive relief.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employing agency is fully responsible for the collection, verification, and maintenance of documentation establishing that an applicant complies with the requirements of ss. 943.13 and 943.131, and any rules adopted pursuant to ss. 943.13 and 943.131.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the employment or appointment of any officer, the chief law enforcement or correctional officer administrator or probation and parole regional administrator of the employing agency, or his or her designee, is required to execute and maintain a registration affidavit-of-compliance form adopted by the commission, attesting to compliance by the employing agency with subsection (1). The affidavit shall be executed under oath and constitutes an official statement within the purview of s. 837.06. The affidavit shall include conspicuous language that intentional false execution of the affidavit constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree. The information contained in the registration affidavit-of-compliance form must be submitted, or electronically transmitted, to the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt rules that establish procedures for conducting background investigations. The rules must specify a form for employing agencies to use to document the findings of the background investigation. Before employing or appointing any officer, the employing agency must conduct a thorough background investigation in accordance with the rules. The background information should include information setting forth the facts and reasons for any of the applicant’s previous separations from private or public employment or appointment, as the applicant understands them. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “separation from employment or appointment” includes any firing, termination, resignation, retirement, or voluntary or involuntary extended leave of absence from any salaried or nonsalaried position. The employing agency must maintain the original background investigation form, which must be signed by the administrator of the employing agency or his or her designee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the employing agency is a private entity under contract to the county or the state pursuant to s. 944.105, s. 951.062, or chapter 957, the contracting agency shall be responsible for meeting the requirements of subsections (1), (2), and (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may inspect and copy the documentation of an employing agency to ensure compliance with subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an employing agency employs or appoints an officer in violation of this section or of s. 943.13, s. 943.131, or s. 943.135, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto, the Department of Legal Affairs, at the request of the chair of the commission, shall apply to the circuit court in the county of the employing agency for injunctive relief prohibiting the employment or appointment of the person contrary to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employing agency must annually submit information to the commission, as specified by rule, relating to all certified officers employed by or appointed to the employing agency so that the commission may update its records for all certified officers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 84-258; ss. 8, 43, ch. 86-183; s. 2, ch. 86-286; ss. 5, 6, ch. 87-186; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 92-131; s. 9, ch. 93-252; s. 2, ch. 95-408; s. 1631, ch. 97-102; s. 4, ch. 97-225; s. 17, ch. 98-94.</History></Section>