<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public safety system information technology resources; guiding principles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following guiding principles adopted by the Criminal and Juvenile Justice Information Systems Council are hereby adopted as guiding principles for the management of public safety system information technology resources:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperative planning by public safety system entities is a prerequisite for the effective development of systems to enable sharing of data.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The planning process, as well as coordination of development efforts, should identify and include all principals from the outset.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public safety system entities should be committed to maximizing information sharing and moving away from proprietary positions taken relative to data they capture and maintain.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public safety system entities should maximize public access to data and, in so doing, should specifically implement guidelines and practices that address security, privacy, and confidentiality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public safety system entities should strive for electronic sharing of information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice by public safety system entities of charging each other for data should, insofar as possible, be eliminated. Further, when the capture of data for mutual benefit can be accomplished, the costs for the development, capture, and network for access to that data should be shared.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The redundant capture of data should, insofar as possible, be eliminated. Redundant capture of data should be discouraged unless there is a specific business need for it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public safety systems should adhere to information exchange standards approved by the council.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council should adopt where possible applicable national standards for data exchange.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 96-388; s. 9, ch. 2008-249.</History></Section>