<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.0437" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Commercial social networking websites.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this section, the term “commercial social networking website” means a commercially operated Internet website that allows users to create web pages or profiles that provide information about themselves and are available publicly or to other users and that offers a mechanism for communication with other users, such as a forum, chat room, electronic mail, or instant messenger.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may provide information relating to electronic mail addresses and instant message names maintained as part of the sexual offender registry to commercial social networking websites or third parties designated by commercial social networking websites. The commercial social networking website may use this information for the purpose of comparing registered users and screening potential users of the commercial social networking website against the list of electronic mail addresses and instant message names provided by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed to impose any civil liability on a commercial social networking website for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action voluntarily taken in good faith to remove or disable any profile of a registered user associated with an electronic mail address or instant message name contained in the sexual offender registry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action taken to restrict access by such registered user to the commercial social networking website.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 2007-143.</History></Section>