<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.0312" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Regional domestic security task forces.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that there is a need to develop and implement a statewide strategy to address prevention, preparation, protection, response, and recovery efforts by federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies, emergency management agencies, fire and rescue departments, first-responder personnel and others in dealing with potential or actual terrorist acts within or affecting this state.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist the department and the Chief of Domestic Security in performing their roles and duties in this regard, the department shall establish a regional domestic security task force in each of the department’s operational regions. The task forces shall serve in an advisory capacity to the department and the Chief of Domestic Security and shall provide support to the department in its performance of functions pertaining to domestic security.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to annual appropriation, the department shall provide dedicated employees to support the function of each regional domestic security task force.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each task force shall be co-chaired by the department’s special agent in charge of the operational region in which the task force is located and by a local sheriff or chief of police from within the operational region.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each task force membership may also include representatives of state and local law enforcement agencies, fire and rescue departments, or first-responder personnel; representatives of emergency management agencies and health, medical, and hospital agencies; representatives of local emergency planning committees; and other persons as deemed appropriate and necessary by the task force co-chairs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The co-chairs of each task force may appoint subcommittees and subcommittee chairs as necessary in order to address issues related to the various disciplines represented on the task force, except that subcommittee chairs for emergency management shall be appointed with the approval of the director of the Division of Emergency Management. A subcommittee chair shall serve at the pleasure of the co-chairs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with the state’s domestic security strategic goals and objectives, each task force shall coordinate efforts to counter terrorism, as defined by s. 775.30, among local, state, and federal resources to ensure that such efforts are not fragmented or unnecessarily duplicated; coordinate training for local and state personnel to counter terrorism as defined by s. 775.30; coordinate the collection and dissemination of investigative and intelligence information; and facilitate responses to terrorist incidents within or affecting each region. With the approval of the Chief of Domestic Security, the task forces may incorporate other objectives reasonably related to the goals of enhancing the state’s domestic security and ability to detect, prevent, and respond to acts of terrorism within or affecting this state. Each task force shall take into account the variety of conditions and resources present within its region.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief of Domestic Security, in conjunction with the Division of Emergency Management, the regional domestic security task forces, and the various state entities responsible for establishing training standards applicable to state law enforcement officers and fire, emergency, and first-responder personnel shall identify appropriate equipment and training needs, curricula, and materials related to the effective response to suspected or actual acts of terrorism or incidents involving real or hoax weapons of mass destruction as defined in s. 790.166. Recommendations for funding for purchases of equipment, delivery of training, implementation of, or revision to basic or continued training required for state licensure or certification, or other related responses shall be made by the Chief of Domestic Security to the Domestic Security Oversight Council, the Executive Office of the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives as necessary to ensure that the needs of this state with regard to the preparing, equipping, training, and exercising of response personnel are identified and addressed. In making such recommendations, the Chief of Domestic Security and the Division of Emergency Management shall identify all funding sources that may be available to fund such efforts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each regional domestic security task force, working in conjunction with the department, the Office of the Attorney General, and other public or private entities, shall work to ensure that hate-driven acts against ethnic groups that may have been targeted as a result of acts of terrorism in or affecting this state are appropriately investigated and responded to.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of each regional domestic security task force may not receive any pay other than their salaries normally received from their employers, but are entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses in accordance with s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to annual appropriation, the department shall provide staff and administrative support for the regional domestic security task forces.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2001-365; s. 4, ch. 2005-165.</History></Section>