<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0943.0582" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prearrest, postarrest, or teen court diversion program expunction.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any law dealing generally with the preservation and destruction of public records, the department may provide, by rule adopted pursuant to chapter 120, for the expunction of any nonjudicial record of the arrest of a minor who has successfully completed a prearrest or postarrest diversion program for minors as authorized by s. 985.125.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “expunction” has the same meaning ascribed in and effect as s. 943.0585, except that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 943.0585(4)(a) do not apply, except that the criminal history record of a person whose record is expunged pursuant to this section shall be made available only to criminal justice agencies for the purpose of determining eligibility for prearrest, postarrest, or teen court diversion programs; when the record is sought as part of a criminal investigation; or when the subject of the record is a candidate for employment with a criminal justice agency. For all other purposes, a person whose record is expunged under this section may lawfully deny or fail to acknowledge the arrest and the charge covered by the expunged record.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records maintained by local criminal justice agencies in the county in which the arrest occurred that are eligible for expunction pursuant to this section shall be sealed as the term is used in s. 943.059.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “nonviolent misdemeanor” includes simple assault or battery when prearrest or postarrest diversion expunction is approved in writing by the state attorney for the county in which the arrest occurred.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall expunge the nonjudicial arrest record of a minor who has successfully completed a prearrest or postarrest diversion program if that minor:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits an application for prearrest or postarrest diversion expunction, on a form prescribed by the department, signed by the minor’s parent or legal guardian, or by the minor if he or she has reached the age of majority at the time of applying.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits the application for prearrest or postarrest diversion expunction no later than 6 months after completion of the diversion program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits to the department, with the application, an official written statement from the state attorney for the county in which the arrest occurred certifying that he or she has successfully completed that county’s prearrest or postarrest diversion program and that participation in the program is strictly limited to minors arrested for a nonviolent misdemeanor who have not otherwise been charged with or found to have committed any criminal offense or comparable ordinance violation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participated in a prearrest or postarrest diversion program that expressly authorizes or permits such expunction to occur.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participated in a prearrest or postarrest diversion program based on an arrest for a nonviolent misdemeanor that would not qualify as an act of domestic violence as that term is defined in s. 741.28.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has never, prior to filing the application for expunction, been charged with or been found to have committed any criminal offense or comparable ordinance violation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to charge a $75 processing fee for each request received for prearrest or postarrest diversion program expunction, for placement in the Department of Law Enforcement Operating Trust Fund, unless such fee is waived by the executive director.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section operates retroactively to permit the expunction of any nonjudicial record of the arrest of a minor who has successfully completed a prearrest or postarrest diversion program on or after July 1, 2000; however, in the case of a minor whose completion of the program occurred before the effective date of this section, the application for prearrest or postarrest diversion expunction must be submitted within 6 months after the effective date of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expunction or sealing granted under this section does not prevent the minor who receives such relief from petitioning for the expunction or sealing of a later criminal history record as provided for in ss. 943.0585 and 943.059, if the minor is otherwise eligible under those sections.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2001-125; s. 10, ch. 2001-127; s. 66, ch. 2004-267; s. 117, ch. 2006-120; s. 35, ch. 2010-117.</History>
</Section>