<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0943.131" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary employment or appointment; minimum basic recruit training exemption.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employing agency may temporarily employ or appoint a person who complies with the qualifications for employment in s. 943.13(1)-(8), but has not fulfilled the requirements of s. 943.13(9) and (10), if a critical need exists to employ or appoint the person and such person is or will be enrolled in the next approved basic recruit training program available in the geographic area or that no assigned state training program for state officers is available within a reasonable time. The employing agency must maintain documentation which demonstrates that a critical need exists to employ a person pursuant to this section. Prior to the employment or appointment of any person other than a correctional probation officer under this subsection, the person shall comply with the firearms provisions established pursuant to s. 943.17(1)(a). Any person temporarily employed or appointed as an officer under this subsection must attend the first training program offered in the geographic area, or the first assigned state training program for a state officer, subsequent to his or her employment or appointment. A person temporarily employed or appointed as an officer under this subsection must begin basic recruit training within 180 consecutive days after employment. Such person must fulfill the requirements of s. 943.13(9) within 18 months after beginning basic recruit training and must fulfill the certification examination requirements of s. 943.13(10) within 180 consecutive days after completing basic recruit training. A person hired after he or she has commenced basic recruit training or after completion of basic recruit training must fulfill the certification examination requirements of s. 943.13(10) within 180 consecutive days after completion of basic recruit training or the commencement of employment, whichever occurs later.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no case may the person be temporarily employed or appointed for more than 30 months. A person shall not be eligible to transfer to another employer while employed pursuant to this subsection. However, a person who is temporarily employed or appointed and is attending the first training program offered in the geographic area, or has been assigned to a state training program, may continue to be temporarily employed or appointed until the person:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails or withdraws from a basic recruit training program within the time limits specified in this subsection;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails to achieve an acceptable score on the officer certification examination within 180 consecutive days after the successful completion of the basic recruit training program within the time limits specified in this subsection; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is separated from employment or appointment by the employing agency within the time limits specified in this subsection.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person temporarily employed or appointed under the provisions of this subsection may perform the duties of an officer unless he or she is adequately supervised by another officer of the same discipline. The supervising officer must be in full compliance with the provisions of s. 943.13 and must be employed or appointed by the employing agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons employed under this subsection are subject to the provisions of s. 943.1395.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who have had a certification administered pursuant to s. 943.1395 revoked by the commission or have voluntarily relinquished such certification shall be ineligible for employment pursuant to this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an applicant seeks an exemption from completing a commission-approved basic recruit training program, the employing agency or criminal justice selection center must verify that the applicant has successfully completed a comparable basic recruit training program for the discipline in which the applicant is seeking certification in another state or for the Federal Government or a previous Florida basic recruit training program. Further, the employing agency or criminal justice selection center must verify that the applicant has served as a full-time sworn officer in another state or for the Federal Government for at least 1 year provided there is no more than an 8-year break in employment or was a previously certified Florida officer provided there is no more than an 8-year break in employment, as measured from the separation date of the most recent qualifying employment to the time a complete application is submitted for an exemption under this section. When the employing agency or criminal justice selection center obtains written documentation regarding the applicant’s criminal justice experience, the documentation must be submitted to the commission. The commission shall adopt rules that establish criteria and procedures to determine if the applicant is exempt from completing the commission-approved basic recruit training program and, upon making a determination, shall notify the employing agency or criminal justice selection center. An applicant who is exempt from completing the commission-approved basic recruit training program must demonstrate proficiency in the high-liability areas, as defined by commission rule, and must complete the requirements of s. 943.13(10) within 1 year after receiving an exemption. If the proficiencies and requirements of s. 943.13(10) are not met within the 1 year, the applicant must seek an additional exemption pursuant to the requirements of this subsection. Except as provided in subsection (1), before the employing agency may employ or appoint the applicant as an officer, the applicant must meet the minimum qualifications described in s. 943.13(1)-(8), and must fulfill the requirements of s. 943.13(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 84-258; s. 72, ch. 85-62; s. 7, ch. 85-224; s. 42, ch. 86-183; s. 2, ch. 86-286; ss. 5, 6, ch. 87-186; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 7, ch. 93-252; s. 1630, ch. 97-102; s. 3, ch. 97-225; s. 5, ch. 2000-226; s. 3, ch. 2002-205; s. 3, ch. 2003-278; s. 5, ch. 2010-62.</History>
</Section>