<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.134" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Release of employee information by employers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employing agency” has the same meaning ascribed in s. 943.10.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employment information” includes, but is not limited to, written information relating to job applications, performance evaluations, attendance records, disciplinary matters, reasons for termination, eligibility for rehire, and other information relevant to an officer’s performance, except information that any other state or federal law prohibits disclosing or information that is subject to a legally recognized privilege the employer is otherwise entitled to invoke.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer, or an agent thereof, is conducting a background investigation of an applicant for temporary or permanent employment or appointment as a full-time, part-time, or auxiliary law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer with an employing agency, the applicant’s current or former employer, or the employer’s agent, shall provide to the officer or his or her agent conducting the background investigation employment information concerning the applicant. The investigating officer or his or her agent must present to the employer from whom the information is being sought credentials demonstrating the investigating officer’s employment with the employing agency and an authorization form for release of information which is designed and approved by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authorization form for release of information must:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be either the original authorization or a copy or facsimile of the original authorization;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have been executed by the applicant no more than 1 year before the request;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain a statement that the authorization has been specifically furnished to the employing agency presenting the authorization; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bear the authorized signature of the applicant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not require an employer to maintain employment information other than that kept in the ordinary course of business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an employer refuses to disclose information to an employing agency in accordance with this section, the employing agency has grounds for a civil action for injunctive relief requiring disclosure by the employer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employer who discloses employment information under this section is immune from civil liability for such disclosure or its consequences as provided in s. 768.095.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employer may charge a reasonable fee to cover the actual costs incurred by the employer in copying and furnishing documents to an employing agency as required by this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-94.</History></Section>