<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal and Juvenile Justice Information Systems Council.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Criminal and Juvenile Justice Information Systems Council within the department.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall be composed of 15 members, consisting of the Attorney General or a designated assistant; the executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement or a designated assistant; the secretary of the Department of Corrections or a designated assistant; the chair of the Parole Commission or a designated assistant; the Secretary of Juvenile Justice or a designated assistant; the executive director of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles or a designated assistant; the Secretary of Children and Family Services or a designated assistant; the State Courts Administrator or a designated assistant; 1 public defender appointed by the Florida Public Defender Association, Inc.; 1 state attorney appointed by the Florida Prosecuting Attorneys Association, Inc.; and 5 members, to be appointed by the Governor, consisting of 2 sheriffs, 2 police chiefs, and 1 clerk of the circuit court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members appointed by the Governor shall be appointed for terms of 4 years. No appointive member shall serve beyond the time he or she ceases to hold the office or employment by reason of which the member was eligible for appointment to the council. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring because of death, resignation, or ineligibility for membership shall serve only for the unexpired term of his or her predecessor or until a successor is appointed and qualifies. Any member who, without cause, fails to attend two consecutive meetings may be removed by the Governor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall annually elect its chair and other officers. The council shall meet semiannually or at the call of its chair, at the request of a majority of its membership, at the request of the department, or at such times as may be prescribed by its rules. A majority of the members of the council constitutes a quorum, and action by a majority of the council shall be official.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Membership on the council shall not disqualify a member from holding any other public office or being employed by a public entity except that no member of the Legislature shall serve on the council. The Legislature finds that the council serves a state, county, and municipal purpose and that service on the council is consistent with a member’s principal service in a public office or employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses as provided by s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 74-386; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 4, ch. 78-323; s. 2, ch. 78-347; s. 12, ch. 80-409; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 81-10; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 4, ch. 85-224; ss. 4, 6, 7, ch. 87-177; s. 1, ch. 88-52; s. 50, ch. 88-122; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 95-161; s. 32, ch. 95-267; s. 3, ch. 96-388; s. 1849, ch. 97-102; s. 7, ch. 2008-249.</History></Section>