<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.052" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition reporting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Criminal Justice Information Program shall, by rule, establish procedures and a format for each criminal justice agency to monitor its records and submit reports, as provided by this section, to the program. The disposition report shall be developed by the program and shall include the offender-based transaction system number.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each law enforcement officer or booking officer shall include on the arrest fingerprint card the offender-based transaction system number.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each clerk of the court shall submit the uniform dispositions to the program or in a manner acceptable to the program. The report shall be submitted at least once a month and, when acceptable by the program, may be submitted in an automated format. The disposition report is mandatory for dispositions relating to adult offenders only. Beginning July 1, 2008, a disposition report for each disposition relating to a minor offender is mandatory.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall submit information to the program relating to the receipt or discharge of any person who is sentenced to a state correctional institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Juvenile Justice shall submit information to the program relating to the receipt or discharge of any minor who is found to have committed an offense that would be a felony if committed by an adult, or is found to have committed a misdemeanor specified in s. 943.051(3), and is committed to the custody of the Department of Juvenile Justice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 80-409; s. 3, ch. 85-224; s. 3, ch. 86-187; s. 3, ch. 87-177; s. 91, ch. 94-209; s. 8, ch. 98-94; s. 6, ch. 2006-176.</History></Section>