<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.1755" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Criminal Justice Executive Institute.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that there exists a need to provide quality training for criminal justice executives in this state. In recognition of this need, the Florida Criminal Justice Executive Institute is hereby created, to be administered for the purpose of providing such training as is deemed necessary to prepare the state’s present and future criminal justice executives to deal with the complex issues facing the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature further finds that there exists a need to improve relationships between law enforcement agencies and the diverse populations they serve. To this end the Florida Criminal Justice Executive Institute shall conduct research projects, utilizing the resources of community colleges and universities, for the purpose of improving law enforcement interaction and intervention in communities of diverse populations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The institute is established within the Department of Law Enforcement and affiliated with the State University System. The Board of Governors of the State University System shall, in cooperation with the Department of Law Enforcement, determine the specific placement of the institute within the system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The institute shall cooperate with the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission, and shall be guided and directed by a policy board composed of the following members:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons shall serve on the policy board:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Corrections.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education or an employee of the Department of Education designated by the Commissioner.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Juvenile Justice.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons shall be nominated by the entities referred to in this paragraph and shall become members of the board upon approval of the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission. Members appointed under this paragraph shall serve 2-year terms:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three chiefs of municipal police departments nominated by the Florida Police Chiefs Association.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three sheriffs nominated by the Florida Sheriffs Association.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county jail administrator nominated by the Florida Sheriffs Association and the Florida Association of Counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative nominated by the State Law Enforcement Chiefs Association.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy board shall establish administrative procedures and operational guidelines necessary to ensure that criminal justice executive training needs are identified and met through the delivery of quality instruction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the policy board are entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses pursuant to s. 112.061 to the extent such expenses are associated with meetings or training activities, appropriate to the Department of Law Enforcement, and deemed necessary by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Six members constitute a quorum of the board.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-157; ss. 9, 13, ch. 91-74; s. 31, ch. 91-201; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 4, ch. 95-161; s. 9, ch. 97-225; s. 63, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>