<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.146" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Securing of copyrights by the department and sale of department work products.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “product” includes any and all inventions, methodologies, techniques, and creations that may be properly protected by patent, copyright, or trademark. The term specifically includes, but is not limited to, job task analyses; all curricula developed for basic or postbasic training in the disciplines of law enforcement, corrections, and correctional probation; support materials, including, but not limited to, associated instructor or student guides, textbooks, computer software, and video, electronic, and digital materials; and all other materials, regardless of form, developed by or on behalf of the commission to support the delivery of the basic recruit or postbasic training in the disciplines of law enforcement, corrections, and correctional probation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the Department of Law Enforcement is authorized, in its own name, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform all things necessary to secure copyrights on any legitimately acquired work product and to enforce its rights therein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">License, lease, assign, or otherwise give written consent to any person, firm, or corporation for the publication, manufacture, or use of any product protected by copyright, whether on a royalty basis or for such other consideration as the department may deem proper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take any action necessary, including legal action to enforce its rights under any agreement and to protect its property rights from improper or unlawful use or infringement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce the collection of any payments or other obligations due to the department for the publication or use of any product by any other party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell any product, except where otherwise provided by public records laws, which the department may create or cause to be created, whether or not the product is protected by a copyright of the department, and to execute all instruments necessary to consummate any such sale.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do all other acts necessary and proper for the execution of powers and duties conferred upon the department under this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall notify the Department of State in writing whenever property rights by copyright are secured or exploited by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proceeds from the sale of products or the right to publish or use a product shall be deposited in the Grants and Donations Trust Fund of the department and may be appropriated to finance activities of the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 98-251.</History></Section>