<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.2563" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advisory board organization; center oversight.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each advisory board shall elect a chair from among its members. Other offices may be created as each board finds necessary or appropriate, and any such offices shall be filled by election from the membership of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each advisory board shall meet at least once during each calendar quarter, at such other times as the board may determine, and at any time upon the call of the chair. Each board shall recommend the adoption of rules for the transaction of its business. Based upon such recommendation, the center shall adopt procedural and substantive rules for its operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A quorum of each advisory board shall consist of a simple majority, and no official action of the board other than declaring a recess or rescheduling a meeting may be taken unless a quorum is present. A majority vote of the members present and voting is necessary for an advisory board to act on any matter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each center shall submit to its advisory board for approval the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for testing, examination, and background investigation for criminal justice personnel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amounts of any applicant fees charged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amounts of any user fees charged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual budget for the center, including any fixed capital expenditures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number, types, and salaries of employees employed by the center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other criteria or requirements for proper administration of the center.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 91-205; s. 1639, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>