<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0943.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers, duties, and functions of the commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules for the administration of ss. 943.085-943.255 pursuant to chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be responsible for the execution, administration, implementation, and evaluation of its powers, duties, and functions under ss. 943.085-943.255, including any rules promulgated or policies established hereunder.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certify, and revoke the certification of, officers, instructors, including agency in-service training instructors, and criminal justice training schools.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish uniform minimum employment standards for the various criminal justice disciplines.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish uniform minimum training standards for the training of officers in the various criminal justice disciplines.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consult and cooperate with municipalities or the state or any political subdivision of the state and with universities, colleges, community colleges, and other educational institutions concerning the development of criminal justice training schools and programs or courses of instruction, including, but not necessarily limited to, education and training in the areas of criminal justice administration and all allied and supporting disciplines.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct official inquiries or require criminal justice training schools to conduct official inquiries of criminal justice training instructors who are certified by the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish minimum curricular requirements for criminal justice training schools.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make, publish, or encourage studies on any aspect of criminal justice education and training or recruitment, including the development of defensible and job-related psychological, selection, and performance evaluation tests.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the approval of the head of the department, make and enter into such contracts and agreements with other agencies, organizations, associations, corporations, individuals, or federal agencies as the commission determines are necessary, expedient, or incidental to the performance of its duties or the execution of its powers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to each commission member and, upon request, to any sheriff, chief of police, state law enforcement or correctional agency chief administrator, or training center director or to any other concerned citizen minutes of commission meetings and notices and agendas of commission meetings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a central repository of records for the proper administration of its duties, powers, and functions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue final orders which include findings of fact and conclusions of law and which constitute final agency action for the purpose of chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce compliance with provisions of this chapter through injunctive relief and civil fines.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make recommendations concerning any matter within the purview of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules for the certification, maintenance, and discipline of officers who engage in those specialized areas found to present a high risk of harm to the officer or the public at large and which would in turn increase the potential liability of an employing agency. The commission shall adopt rules requiring the demonstration of proficiency in firearms for all law enforcement officers. The commission shall by rule include the frequency of demonstration of proficiency with firearms and the consequences for officers failing to demonstrate proficiency with firearms.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implement, administer, maintain, and revise a job-related officer certification examination for each criminal justice discipline. The commission shall, by rule, establish procedures for the administration of the officer certification examinations. Further, the commission shall establish standards for acceptable performance for each officer certification examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 74-386; s. 2, ch. 76-270; s. 2, ch. 78-291; s. 4, ch. 78-323; s. 298, ch. 79-400; s. 4, ch. 80-71; ss. 6, 24, 25, ch. 81-24; s. 1, ch. 82-46; ss. 15, 18, ch. 82-149; s. 3, ch. 83-259; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 2, ch. 84-156; s. 5, ch. 84-258; s. 6, ch. 85-224; s. 6, ch. 86-187; ss. 5, 6, ch. 87-186; s. 1, ch. 88-51; s. 48, ch. 91-110; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-252; s. 53, ch. 95-196; s. 1, ch. 2002-205; s. 1, ch. 2003-278; s. 4, ch. 2010-62.</History>
</Section>