<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0943.0435" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sexual offenders required to register with the department; penalty.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual offender” means a person who meets the criteria in sub-subparagraph a., sub-subparagraph b., sub-subparagraph c., or sub-subparagraph d., as follows:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been convicted of committing, or attempting, soliciting, or conspiring to commit, any of the criminal offenses proscribed in the following statutes in this state or similar offenses in another jurisdiction: s. 787.01, s. 787.02, or s. 787.025(2)(c), where the victim is a minor and the defendant is not the victim’s parent or guardian; s. 787.06(3)(b), (d), (f), (g), or (h); s. 794.011, excluding s. 794.011(10); s. 794.05; s. 796.03; s. 796.035; s. 800.04; s. 810.145(8); s. 825.1025; s. 827.071; s. 847.0133; s. 847.0135, excluding s. 847.0135(6); s. 847.0137; s. 847.0138; s. 847.0145; or s. 985.701(1); or any similar offense committed in this state which has been redesignated from a former statute number to one of those listed in this sub-sub-subparagraph; and</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been released on or after October 1, 1997, from the sanction imposed for any conviction of an offense described in sub-sub-subparagraph (I). For purposes of sub-sub-subparagraph (I), a sanction imposed in this state or in any other jurisdiction includes, but is not limited to, a fine, probation, community control, parole, conditional release, control release, or incarceration in a state prison, federal prison, private correctional facility, or local detention facility;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishes or maintains a residence in this state and who has not been designated as a sexual predator by a court of this state but who has been designated as a sexual predator, as a sexually violent predator, or by another sexual offender designation in another state or jurisdiction and was, as a result of such designation, subjected to registration or community or public notification, or both, or would be if the person were a resident of that state or jurisdiction, without regard to whether the person otherwise meets the criteria for registration as a sexual offender;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishes or maintains a residence in this state who is in the custody or control of, or under the supervision of, any other state or jurisdiction as a result of a conviction for committing, or attempting, soliciting, or conspiring to commit, any of the criminal offenses proscribed in the following statutes or similar offense in another jurisdiction: s. 787.01, s. 787.02, or s. 787.025(2)(c), where the victim is a minor and the defendant is not the victim’s parent or guardian; s. 787.06(3)(b), (d), (f), (g), or (h); s. 794.011, excluding s. 794.011(10); s. 794.05; s. 796.03; s. 796.035; s. 800.04; s. 810.145(8); s. 825.1025; s. 827.071; s. 847.0133; s. 847.0135, excluding s. 847.0135(6); s. 847.0137; s. 847.0138; s. 847.0145; or s. 985.701(1); or any similar offense committed in this state which has been redesignated from a former statute number to one of those listed in this sub-subparagraph; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or after July 1, 2007, has been adjudicated delinquent for committing, or attempting, soliciting, or conspiring to commit, any of the criminal offenses proscribed in the following statutes in this state or similar offenses in another jurisdiction when the juvenile was 14 years of age or older at the time of the offense:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 794.011, excluding s. 794.011(10);</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(4)(b) where the victim is under 12 years of age or where the court finds sexual activity by the use of force or coercion;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(5)(c)1. where the court finds molestation involving unclothed genitals; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(5)(d) where the court finds the use of force or coercion and unclothed genitals.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all qualifying offenses listed in sub-subparagraph (1)(a)1.d., the court shall make a written finding of the age of the offender at the time of the offense.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For each violation of a qualifying offense listed in this subsection, the court shall make a written finding of the age of the victim at the time of the offense. For a violation of s. 800.04(4), the court shall additionally make a written finding indicating that the offense did or did not involve sexual activity and indicating that the offense did or did not involve force or coercion. For a violation of s. 800.04(5), the court shall additionally make a written finding that the offense did or did not involve unclothed genitals or genital area and that the offense did or did not involve the use of force or coercion.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Convicted” means that there has been a determination of guilt as a result of a trial or the entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld, and includes an adjudication of delinquency of a juvenile as specified in this section. Conviction of a similar offense includes, but is not limited to, a conviction by a federal or military tribunal, including courts-martial conducted by the Armed Forces of the United States, and includes a conviction or entry of a plea of guilty or nolo contendere resulting in a sanction in any state of the United States or other jurisdiction. A sanction includes, but is not limited to, a fine, probation, community control, parole, conditional release, control release, or incarceration in a state prison, federal prison, private correctional facility, or local detention facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permanent residence,” “temporary residence,” and “transient residence” have the same meaning ascribed in s. 775.21.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Institution of higher education” means a career center, community college, college, state university, or independent postsecondary institution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Change in enrollment or employment status” means the commencement or termination of enrollment or employment or a change in location of enrollment or employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electronic mail address” has the same meaning as provided in s. 668.602.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Instant message name” means an identifier that allows a person to communicate in real time with another person using the Internet.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report in person at the sheriff’s office:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the county in which the offender establishes or maintains a permanent, temporary, or transient residence within 48 hours after:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing permanent, temporary, or transient residence in this state; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being released from the custody, control, or supervision of the Department of Corrections or from the custody of a private correctional facility; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the county where he or she was convicted within 48 hours after being convicted for a qualifying offense for registration under this section if the offender is not in the custody or control of, or under the supervision of, the Department of Corrections, or is not in the custody of a private correctional facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any change in the information required to be provided pursuant to paragraph (b), including, but not limited to, any change in the sexual offender’s permanent, temporary, or transient residence, name, any electronic mail address and any instant message name required to be provided pursuant to paragraph (4)(d), after the sexual offender reports in person at the sheriff’s office, shall be accomplished in the manner provided in subsections (4), (7), and (8).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide his or her name; date of birth; social security number; race; sex; height; weight; hair and eye color; tattoos or other identifying marks; occupation and place of employment; address of permanent or legal residence or address of any current temporary residence, within the state or out of state, including a rural route address and a post office box; if no permanent or temporary address, any transient residence within the state, address, location or description, and dates of any current or known future temporary residence within the state or out of state; home telephone number and any cellular telephone number; any electronic mail address and any instant message name required to be provided pursuant to paragraph (4)(d); date and place of each conviction; and a brief description of the crime or crimes committed by the offender. A post office box shall not be provided in lieu of a physical residential address.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the sexual offender’s place of residence is a motor vehicle, trailer, mobile home, or manufactured home, as defined in chapter 320, the sexual offender shall also provide to the department through the sheriff’s office written notice of the vehicle identification number; the license tag number; the registration number; and a description, including color scheme, of the motor vehicle, trailer, mobile home, or manufactured home. If the sexual offender’s place of residence is a vessel, live-aboard vessel, or houseboat, as defined in chapter 327, the sexual offender shall also provide to the department written notice of the hull identification number; the manufacturer’s serial number; the name of the vessel, live-aboard vessel, or houseboat; the registration number; and a description, including color scheme, of the vessel, live-aboard vessel, or houseboat.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the sexual offender is enrolled, employed, or carrying on a vocation at an institution of higher education in this state, the sexual offender shall also provide to the department through the sheriff’s office the name, address, and county of each institution, including each campus attended, and the sexual offender’s enrollment or employment status. Each change in enrollment or employment status shall be reported in person at the sheriff’s office, within 48 hours after any change in status. The sheriff shall promptly notify each institution of the sexual offender’s presence and any change in the sexual offender’s enrollment or employment status.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">When a sexual offender reports at the sheriff’s office, the sheriff shall take a photograph and a set of fingerprints of the offender and forward the photographs and fingerprints to the department, along with the information provided by the sexual offender. The sheriff shall promptly provide to the department the information received from the sexual offender.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 48 hours after the report required under subsection (2), a sexual offender shall report in person at a driver’s license office of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, unless a driver’s license or identification card that complies with the requirements of s. 322.141(3) was previously secured or updated under s. 944.607. At the driver’s license office the sexual offender shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If otherwise qualified, secure a Florida driver’s license, renew a Florida driver’s license, or secure an identification card. The sexual offender shall identify himself or herself as a sexual offender who is required to comply with this section and shall provide proof that the sexual offender reported as required in subsection (2). The sexual offender shall provide any of the information specified in subsection (2), if requested. The sexual offender shall submit to the taking of a photograph for use in issuing a driver’s license, renewed license, or identification card, and for use by the department in maintaining current records of sexual offenders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the costs assessed by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for issuing or renewing a driver’s license or identification card as required by this section. The driver’s license or identification card issued must be in compliance with s. 322.141(3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, upon request, any additional information necessary to confirm the identity of the sexual offender, including a set of fingerprints.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each time a sexual offender’s driver’s license or identification card is subject to renewal, and, without regard to the status of the offender’s driver’s license or identification card, within 48 hours after any change in the offender’s permanent, temporary, or transient residence or change in the offender’s name by reason of marriage or other legal process, the offender shall report in person to a driver’s license office, and shall be subject to the requirements specified in subsection (3). The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall forward to the department all photographs and information provided by sexual offenders. Notwithstanding the restrictions set forth in s. 322.142, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles is authorized to release a reproduction of a color-photograph or digital-image license to the Department of Law Enforcement for purposes of public notification of sexual offenders as provided in this section and ss. 943.043 and 944.606.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender who vacates a permanent, temporary, or transient residence and fails to establish or maintain another permanent, temporary, or transient residence shall, within 48 hours after vacating the permanent, temporary, or transient residence, report in person to the sheriff’s office of the county in which he or she is located. The sexual offender shall specify the date upon which he or she intends to or did vacate such residence. The sexual offender must provide or update all of the registration information required under paragraph (2)(b). The sexual offender must provide an address for the residence or other place that he or she is or will be located during the time in which he or she fails to establish or maintain a permanent or temporary residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender who remains at a permanent, temporary, or transient residence after reporting his or her intent to vacate such residence shall, within 48 hours after the date upon which the offender indicated he or she would or did vacate such residence, report in person to the agency to which he or she reported pursuant to paragraph (b) for the purpose of reporting his or her address at such residence. When the sheriff receives the report, the sheriff shall promptly convey the information to the department. An offender who makes a report as required under paragraph (b) but fails to make a report as required under this paragraph commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender must register any electronic mail address or instant message name with the department prior to using such electronic mail address or instant message name on or after October 1, 2007. The department shall establish an online system through which sexual offenders may securely access and update all electronic mail address and instant message name information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a sexual offender who is also a sexual predator, as defined in s. 775.21. A sexual predator must register as required under s. 775.21.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County and local law enforcement agencies, in conjunction with the department, shall verify the addresses of sexual offenders who are not under the care, custody, control, or supervision of the Department of Corrections in a manner that is consistent with the provisions of the federal Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 and any other federal standards applicable to such verification or required to be met as a condition for the receipt of federal funds by the state. Local law enforcement agencies shall report to the department any failure by a sexual offender to comply with registration requirements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender who intends to establish a permanent, temporary, or transient residence in another state or jurisdiction other than the State of Florida shall report in person to the sheriff of the county of current residence within 48 hours before the date he or she intends to leave this state to establish residence in another state or jurisdiction. The notification must include the address, municipality, county, and state of intended residence. The sheriff shall promptly provide to the department the information received from the sexual offender. The department shall notify the statewide law enforcement agency, or a comparable agency, in the intended state or jurisdiction of residence of the sexual offender’s intended residence. The failure of a sexual offender to provide his or her intended place of residence is punishable as provided in subsection (9).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender who indicates his or her intent to establish a permanent, temporary, or transient residence in another state or jurisdiction other than the State of Florida and later decides to remain in this state shall, within 48 hours after the date upon which the sexual offender indicated he or she would leave this state, report in person to the sheriff to which the sexual offender reported the intended change of permanent, temporary, or transient residence, and report his or her intent to remain in this state. The sheriff shall promptly report this information to the department. A sexual offender who reports his or her intent to establish a permanent, temporary, or transient residence in another state or jurisdiction but who remains in this state without reporting to the sheriff in the manner required by this subsection commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender who does not comply with the requirements of this section commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender who commits any act or omission in violation of this section may be prosecuted for the act or omission in the county in which the act or omission was committed, the county of the last registered address of the sexual offender, or the county in which the conviction occurred for the offense or offenses that meet the criteria for designating a person as a sexual offender.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An arrest on charges of failure to register when the offender has been provided and advised of his or her statutory obligations to register under subsection (2), the service of an information or a complaint for a violation of this section, or an arraignment on charges for a violation of this section constitutes actual notice of the duty to register. A sexual offender’s failure to immediately register as required by this section following such arrest, service, or arraignment constitutes grounds for a subsequent charge of failure to register. A sexual offender charged with the crime of failure to register who asserts, or intends to assert, a lack of notice of the duty to register as a defense to a charge of failure to register shall immediately register as required by this section. A sexual offender who is charged with a subsequent failure to register may not assert the defense of a lack of notice of the duty to register.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration following such arrest, service, or arraignment is not a defense and does not relieve the sexual offender of criminal liability for the failure to register.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Corrections, the Department of Juvenile Justice, any law enforcement agency in this state, and the personnel of those departments; an elected or appointed official, public employee, or school administrator; or an employee, agency, or any individual or entity acting at the request or upon the direction of any law enforcement agency is immune from civil liability for damages for good faith compliance with the requirements of this section or for the release of information under this section, and shall be presumed to have acted in good faith in compiling, recording, reporting, or releasing the information. The presumption of good faith is not overcome if a technical or clerical error is made by the department, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Corrections, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the personnel of those departments, or any individual or entity acting at the request or upon the direction of any of those departments in compiling or providing information, or if information is incomplete or incorrect because a sexual offender fails to report or falsely reports his or her current place of permanent, temporary, or transient residence.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 943.04354, a sexual offender must maintain registration with the department for the duration of his or her life, unless the sexual offender has received a full pardon or has had a conviction set aside in a postconviction proceeding for any offense that meets the criteria for classifying the person as a sexual offender for purposes of registration. However, a sexual offender:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been lawfully released from confinement, supervision, or sanction, whichever is later, for at least 25 years and has not been arrested for any felony or misdemeanor offense since release, provided that the sexual offender’s requirement to register was not based upon an adult conviction:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a violation of s. 787.01 or s. 787.02;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a violation of s. 794.011, excluding s. 794.011(10);</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a violation of s. 800.04(4)(b) where the court finds the offense involved a victim under 12 years of age or sexual activity by the use of force or coercion;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a violation of s. 800.04(5)(b);</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a violation of s. 800.04(5)c.2. where the court finds the offense involved unclothed genitals or genital area;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any attempt or conspiracy to commit any such offense; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a violation of similar law of another jurisdiction,</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">may petition the criminal division of the circuit court of the circuit in which the sexual offender resides for the purpose of removing the requirement for registration as a sexual offender.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may grant or deny relief if the offender demonstrates to the court that he or she has not been arrested for any crime since release; the requested relief complies with the provisions of the federal Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 and any other federal standards applicable to the removal of registration requirements for a sexual offender or required to be met as a condition for the receipt of federal funds by the state; and the court is otherwise satisfied that the offender is not a current or potential threat to public safety. The state attorney in the circuit in which the petition is filed must be given notice of the petition at least 3 weeks before the hearing on the matter. The state attorney may present evidence in opposition to the requested relief or may otherwise demonstrate the reasons why the petition should be denied. If the court denies the petition, the court may set a future date at which the sexual offender may again petition the court for relief, subject to the standards for relief provided in this subsection.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall remove an offender from classification as a sexual offender for purposes of registration if the offender provides to the department a certified copy of the court’s written findings or order that indicates that the offender is no longer required to comply with the requirements for registration as a sexual offender.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As defined in sub-subparagraph (1)(a)1.b. must maintain registration with the department for the duration of his or her life until the person provides the department with an order issued by the court that designated the person as a sexual predator, as a sexually violent predator, or by another sexual offender designation in the state or jurisdiction in which the order was issued which states that such designation has been removed or demonstrates to the department that such designation, if not imposed by a court, has been removed by operation of law or court order in the state or jurisdiction in which the designation was made, and provided such person no longer meets the criteria for registration as a sexual offender under the laws of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that sexual offenders, especially those who have committed offenses against minors, often pose a high risk of engaging in sexual offenses even after being released from incarceration or commitment and that protection of the public from sexual offenders is a paramount government interest. Sexual offenders have a reduced expectation of privacy because of the public’s interest in public safety and in the effective operation of government. Releasing information concerning sexual offenders to law enforcement agencies and to persons who request such information, and the release of such information to the public by a law enforcement agency or public agency, will further the governmental interests of public safety. The designation of a person as a sexual offender is not a sentence or a punishment but is simply the status of the offender which is the result of a conviction for having committed certain crimes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has reason to believe that a sexual offender is not complying, or has not complied, with the requirements of this section and who, with the intent to assist the sexual offender in eluding a law enforcement agency that is seeking to find the sexual offender to question the sexual offender about, or to arrest the sexual offender for, his or her noncompliance with the requirements of this section:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withholds information from, or does not notify, the law enforcement agency about the sexual offender’s noncompliance with the requirements of this section, and, if known, the whereabouts of the sexual offender;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Harbors, or attempts to harbor, or assists another person in harboring or attempting to harbor, the sexual offender; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conceals or attempts to conceal, or assists another person in concealing or attempting to conceal, the sexual offender; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides information to the law enforcement agency regarding the sexual offender that the person knows to be false information,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sexual offender must report in person each year during the month of the sexual offender’s birthday and during the sixth month following the sexual offender’s birth month to the sheriff’s office in the county in which he or she resides or is otherwise located to reregister.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, a sexual offender who is required to register as a result of a conviction for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 787.01 or s. 787.02 where the victim is a minor and the offender is not the victim’s parent or guardian;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 794.011, excluding s. 794.011(10);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(4)(b) where the court finds the offense involved a victim under 12 years of age or sexual activity by the use of force or coercion;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(5)(b);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(5)(c)1. where the court finds molestation involving unclothed genitals or genital area;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(5)c.2. where the court finds molestation involving unclothed genitals or genital area;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 800.04(5)(d) where the court finds the use of force or coercion and unclothed genitals or genital area;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any attempt or conspiracy to commit such offense; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of a similar law of another jurisdiction,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">must reregister each year during the month of the sexual offender’s birthday and every third month thereafter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff’s office may determine the appropriate times and days for reporting by the sexual offender, which shall be consistent with the reporting requirements of this subsection. Reregistration shall include any changes to the following information:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name; social security number; age; race; sex; date of birth; height; weight; hair and eye color; address of any permanent residence and address of any current temporary residence, within the state or out of state, including a rural route address and a post office box; if no permanent or temporary address, any transient residence within the state; address, location or description, and dates of any current or known future temporary residence within the state or out of state; any electronic mail address and any instant message name required to be provided pursuant to paragraph (4)(d); home telephone number and any cellular telephone number; date and place of any employment; vehicle make, model, color, and license tag number; fingerprints; and photograph. A post office box shall not be provided in lieu of a physical residential address.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the sexual offender is enrolled, employed, or carrying on a vocation at an institution of higher education in this state, the sexual offender shall also provide to the department the name, address, and county of each institution, including each campus attended, and the sexual offender’s enrollment or employment status.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the sexual offender’s place of residence is a motor vehicle, trailer, mobile home, or manufactured home, as defined in chapter 320, the sexual offender shall also provide the vehicle identification number; the license tag number; the registration number; and a description, including color scheme, of the motor vehicle, trailer, mobile home, or manufactured home. If the sexual offender’s place of residence is a vessel, live-aboard vessel, or houseboat, as defined in chapter 327, the sexual offender shall also provide the hull identification number; the manufacturer’s serial number; the name of the vessel, live-aboard vessel, or houseboat; the registration number; and a description, including color scheme, of the vessel, live-aboard vessel or houseboat.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any sexual offender who fails to report in person as required at the sheriff’s office, or who fails to respond to any address verification correspondence from the department within 3 weeks of the date of the correspondence or who fails to report electronic mail addresses or instant message names, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff’s office shall, within 2 working days, electronically submit and update all information provided by the sexual offender to the department in a manner prescribed by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 97-299; s. 7, ch. 98-81; s. 114, ch. 99-3; s. 3, ch. 2000-207; s. 3, ch. 2000-246; s. 3, ch. 2002-58; s. 2, ch. 2004-371; s. 9, ch. 2005-28; s. 3, ch. 2006-200; s. 4, ch. 2006-299; s. 159, ch. 2007-5; s. 10, ch. 2007-143; s. 4, ch. 2007-207; s. 2, ch. 2007-209; s. 3, ch. 2009-194; s. 4, ch. 2010-92; s. 4, ch. 2012-19; s. 11, ch. 2012-97.</History>
</Section>