<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.2565" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Centralized information centers on prospective employment candidates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each center shall develop, establish, and maintain a centralized information center on prospective candidates for criminal justice positions in the region served. Each center shall provide and undertake standardized screening, testing, examination, and background investigation of applicants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the request of any participating criminal justice agency in the region served, the center shall provide a list of qualified applicants for employment and report all information gathered during the testing, screening, and investigation of each applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each center may make recommendations concerning uniform standards for the recruitment and testing of criminal justice personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each center shall comply with local, state, and federal regulations for the hiring and promotion of minorities and women.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each center may enter into contracts and agreements to carry out its purposes. Any such contracts require approval by the advisory board and the directing school or directing agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those centers operating under a directing school shall not generate full-time equivalent students for the directing school as a part of the directing school’s enrollment. Classes which are part of the regular program of the college to train law enforcement and correctional officers are not affected by this prohibition.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 91-205.</History></Section>