<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.054" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exchange of federal criminal history records and information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal history information derived from any United States Department of Justice criminal justice information system is available:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To criminal justice agencies for criminal justice purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to applicable federal laws and regulations for use in connection with licensing or local or state employment or for such other uses only as authorized by federal or state laws which have been approved by the United States Attorney General or the Attorney General’s designee. When no active prosecution of the charge is known to be pending, arrest data more than 1 year old is not disseminated unless accompanied by information relating to the disposition of that arrest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For issuance of press releases and publicity designed to effect the apprehension of wanted persons in connection with serious or significant offenses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exchange of federal criminal history information is subject to cancellation if dissemination is made outside the receiving departments or related agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A criminal justice agency may refer to federal criminal history records and disclose to the public factual information concerning the status of an investigation; the apprehension, arrest, release, or prosecution of an individual; the adjudication of charges; or the correctional status of an individual when such disclosure is reasonably contemporaneous with the event to which the information relates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions of this section are required by the Federal Government as a condition of utilizing the United States Department of Justice criminal history record information systems.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 80-409; s. 2, ch. 94-126; s. 441, ch. 96-406; s. 1846, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>