<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal Justice Investigations and Forensic Science Program; creation; investigative, forensic, and related authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Criminal Justice Investigations and Forensic Science Program within the Department of Law Enforcement. The program shall be supervised by personnel who shall be employed by the department upon the recommendation of the executive director. Such personnel shall supervise, direct, coordinate, and administer activities of the program which are assigned by the executive director.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In carrying out the investigative services of the Criminal Justice Investigations and Forensic Science Program and under appropriate rules and regulations adopted by the department, upon written order of the Governor, or by direction of the Legislature acting by a concurrent resolution, and at the direction of the executive director, the department may investigate violations of any of the criminal laws of the state, and shall have authority to bear arms, make arrests and apply for, serve and execute search warrants, arrest warrants, capias, and other process of the court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigations may also be conducted in connection with the faithful execution and effective enforcement of the laws of the state with reference to organized crime, vice, racketeering, rioting, inciting to riot, and insurrection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may also engage in such other investigative activities as will aid local law enforcement officers in preventing or solving crimes and controlling criminal activity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All investigators employed by the department shall be considered law enforcement officers for all purposes. The executive director shall have the authority to designate the person occupying any appropriate position within the department as a law enforcement officer, if such person is qualified under the department’s personnel regulations relating to agents and is certified pursuant to s. 943.1395(1), and all persons thus employed by the department shall be considered law enforcement officers for all purposes and shall be entitled to the privileges, protection, and benefits of ss. 112.19, 121.051, 122.34, and 870.05.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever it shall appear to the department that there is cause for the prosecution of a crime, the department shall refer the evidence of such crime to the officials authorized to conduct the prosecution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to establish regional violent crime investigation coordinating teams composed of persons including, but not limited to, forensic investigators and law enforcement officers from both state and local criminal justice agencies. The functions of a regional violent crime investigation coordinating team include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Responding to violent crimes in a timely and comprehensive manner, utilizing analytic, forensic, investigative, and technical expertise and equipment to provide key support to local law enforcement agencies undertaking difficult violent crime investigations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitating communication and coordination among state and local criminal justice agencies, including facilitating and coordinating the use of state law enforcement resources for concentrated task force efforts in violent crime investigations constituting emergency situations within the region.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the request of a sheriff, a police chief, or other appropriate law enforcement administrator, the executive director may deploy a regional violent crime investigation team to assist a law enforcement agency in a violent crime investigation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In carrying out the services of the Criminal Justice Investigations and Forensic Science Program and under appropriate rules and regulations adopted by the department, the department may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and recommend cooperative policies for coordinating the law enforcement work of all state, county, and municipal agencies that are responsible for law enforcement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist local law enforcement agencies by providing consultation, research, and planning assistance, training, and field technical services and engage in other activities to aid local law enforcement officers in preventing and solving crimes and controlling criminal activity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide forensic services to state, local, and other law enforcement agencies and criminal justice agencies and adopt policies, procedures, and standards for operating state-operated crime laboratories.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 74-386; s. 5, ch. 76-247; s. 1, ch. 77-127; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 2, ch. 78-347; s. 34, ch. 79-8; s. 1, ch. 86-187; s. 2, ch. 89-3; s. 2, ch. 93-204; s. 2, ch. 94-215; s. 4, ch. 98-94; s. 9, ch. 2005-100.</History></Section>