<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0943.042" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Violent Crime Investigative Emergency and Drug Control Strategy Implementation Account.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created a Violent Crime Investigative Emergency and Drug Control Strategy Implementation Account within the Department of Law Enforcement Operating Trust Fund. The account shall be used to provide emergency supplemental funds to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and local law enforcement agencies that are involved in complex and lengthy violent crime investigations, or matching funding to multiagency or statewide drug control or illicit money laundering investigative efforts or task force efforts that significantly contribute to achieving the state’s goal of reducing drug-related crime, that represent a significant illicit money laundering investigative effort, or that otherwise significantly support statewide strategies developed by the Statewide Drug Policy Advisory Council established under s. 397.333;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and local law enforcement agencies that are involved in violent crime investigations which constitute a significant emergency within the state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Counties that demonstrate a significant hardship or an inability to cover extraordinary expenses associated with a violent crime trial.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In consultation with the Florida Violent Crime and Drug Control Council, the department must maintain rules which, at minimum, address the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for determining what constitutes a complex and lengthy violent crime investigation for the purpose of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for determining those violent crime investigations which constitute a significant emergency within the state for the purpose of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for determining the circumstances under which counties may receive emergency supplemental funds for extraordinary expenses associated with a violent crime trial under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guidelines which establish a $100,000 maximum limit on the amount that may be disbursed on a single investigation and a $200,000 maximum limit on funds that may be provided to a single agency during the agency’s fiscal year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for law enforcement agencies to use when applying for funds, including certification by the head of the agency that a request complies with the requirements established by the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual evaluation and audit of the trust fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With regard to the funding of drug control or illicit money laundering investigative efforts or task force efforts, the department shall adopt rules which, at a minimum, address the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for determining what constitutes a multiagency or statewide drug control or illicit money laundering investigative effort or task force effort eligible to seek funding under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for determining whether a multiagency or statewide investigation or task force effort significantly contributes to achieving the state’s goals and strategies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations upon the amount that may be disbursed yearly to a single multiagency or statewide drug control or illicit money laundering investigation or task force effort.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures to utilize when applying for funds, including a required designation of the amount of matching funds being provided by the task force or participating agencies and a signed commitment by the head of each agency seeking funds that funds so designated will be utilized as represented if council funding is provided.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements to expend funds provided by the council in the manner authorized by the council, and a method of accounting for the receipt, use, and disbursement of any funds expended in drug control or illicit money laundering investigative efforts or task force efforts funded in part under the authority of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for reporting by recipient agencies on the performance and accomplishments secured by the investigative or task force efforts, including a requirement that the reports demonstrate how the state’s drug control goals and strategies have been promoted by the efforts, and how other investigative goals have been met, including arrests made by such efforts, results of prosecutions based on such arrests, impact upon organized criminal enterprise structures by reason of such efforts, property or currency seizures made, illicit money laundering operations disrupted or otherwise impacted, forfeiture of assets by reason of such efforts, and anticipated or actual utilization of assets received by reason of a forfeiture based in whole or in part upon an investigation funded in whole or in part by council funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as permitted in this section, a disbursement from the Violent Crime Investigative Emergency and Drug Control Strategy Implementation Account shall not be used to supplant existing appropriations of state and local law enforcement agencies and counties or to otherwise fund expenditures that are ordinary or reasonably predictable for the operation of a state or local law enforcement agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The moneys placed in the account shall consist of appropriations from the Legislature or moneys received from any other public or private source. Any local law enforcement agency that acquires funds pursuant to the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act or any other forfeiture action is authorized to donate a portion of such funds to the account.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a finding by a majority of the members of the council, any unexcused failure by recipient agencies or task forces to utilize funds in the manner authorized by this section and the Florida Violent Crime and Drug Control Council, or to timely provide required accounting records, reports, or other information requested by the council or by the department related to funding requested or provided, shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Constitute a basis for a demand by the council for the immediate return of all or any portion of funds previously provided to the recipient by the council; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Result in termination or limitation of any pending funding by the council under this section,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and may, upon specific direction of a majority of the council, result in disqualification of the involved agencies or task forces from consideration for additional or future funding for investigative efforts as described in this section for a period of not more than 2 years following the council’s action. The council, through the department, is authorized to pursue any collection remedies necessary if a recipient agency fails to return funds as demanded.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-204; s. 3, ch. 94-215; s. 2, ch. 97-302; s. 3, ch. 2001-127; s. 10, ch. 2011-51.</History>
</Section>