<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.132" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Implementation of federal Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2004.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall by rule establish the manner in which Title 18, 44 U.S.C. ss. 926B and 926C, the federal Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2004, relating to the carrying of concealed firearms by qualified law enforcement officers and qualified retired law enforcement officers, as defined in the act, shall be implemented in the state. In order to facilitate the implementation within the state of Title 18, 44 U.S.C. ss. 926B and 926C, the commission shall develop and authorize a uniform firearms proficiency verification card to be issued to persons who achieve a passing score on the firing range testing component as utilized in the minimum firearms proficiency course applicable to active law enforcement officers, indicating the person’s name and the date upon which he or she achieved the passing score. Each such card shall be issued only by firearms instructors certified by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities operating firing ranges on which firearms instructors certified by the commission administer the firing range testing component as utilized in the minimum firearms proficiency course applicable to active law enforcement officers may open the firing range under terms and conditions established by the operating entity to other persons for purposes of allowing such persons to demonstrate their ability to achieve a passing score on the firing range testing component as utilized in the minimum firearms proficiency course. All costs associated with the demonstration by any such person that he or she meets the requirements of the firing range testing component as utilized in the minimum firearms proficiency course shall be at the expense of the person being tested.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-111.</History></Section>