<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.056" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Access to, review and challenge of, criminal history records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of verification of the accuracy and completeness of a criminal history record, the Department of Law Enforcement shall provide, in the manner prescribed by rule, such record for review upon verification, by fingerprints, of the identity of the requesting person. If a minor, or the parent or legal guardian of a minor, requests a copy of the minor’s criminal history record, the Department of Law Enforcement shall provide such copy for review upon verification, by fingerprints, of the identity of the minor. The providing of such record shall not require the payment of any fees, except those provided for by federal regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal justice agencies subject to chapter 120 shall be subject to hearings regarding those portions of criminal history records for which the agency served as originator. When it is determined what the record should contain in order to be complete and accurate, the Criminal Justice Information Program shall be advised and shall conform state and federal records to the corrected criminal history record information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal justice agencies not subject to chapter 120 shall be subject to administrative proceedings for challenges to criminal history record information in accordance with rules established by the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, an individual whose record has been corrected shall be given the names of all known noncriminal justice agencies to which the data has been given. The correcting agency shall notify all known criminal justice recipients of the corrected information, and those agencies shall modify their records to conform to the corrected record.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 9, ch. 80-409; s. 3, ch. 94-126; s. 93, ch. 94-209; s. 12, ch. 98-94.</History></Section>