<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Officers’ minimum qualifications for employment or appointment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or after October 1, 1984, any person employed or appointed as a full-time, part-time, or auxiliary law enforcement officer or correctional officer; on or after October 1, 1986, any person employed as a full-time, part-time, or auxiliary correctional probation officer; and on or after October 1, 1986, any person employed as a full-time, part-time, or auxiliary correctional officer by a private entity under contract to the Department of Corrections, to a county commission, or to the Department of Management Services shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 19 years of age.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a citizen of the United States, notwithstanding any law of the state to the contrary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a high school graduate or its “equivalent” as the commission has defined the term by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not have been convicted of any felony or of a misdemeanor involving perjury or a false statement, or have received a dishonorable discharge from any of the Armed Forces of the United States. Any person who, after July 1, 1981, pleads guilty or nolo contendere to or is found guilty of any felony or of a misdemeanor involving perjury or a false statement is not eligible for employment or appointment as an officer, notwithstanding suspension of sentence or withholding of adjudication. Notwithstanding this subsection, any person who has pled nolo contendere to a misdemeanor involving a false statement, prior to December 1, 1985, and has had such record sealed or expunged shall not be deemed ineligible for employment or appointment as an officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have documentation of his or her processed fingerprints on file with the employing agency or, if a private correctional officer, have documentation of his or her processed fingerprints on file with the Department of Corrections or the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission. If administrative delays are caused by the department or the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the person has complied with subsections (1)-(4) and (6)-(9), he or she may be employed or appointed for a period not to exceed 1 calendar year from the date he or she was employed or appointed or until return of the processed fingerprints documenting noncompliance with subsections (1)-(4) or subsection (7), whichever occurs first. Beginning January 15, 2007, the department shall retain and enter into the statewide automated fingerprint identification system authorized by s. 943.05 all fingerprints submitted to the department as required by this section. Thereafter, the fingerprints shall be available for all purposes and uses authorized for arrest fingerprint cards entered in the statewide automated fingerprint identification system pursuant to s. 943.051. The department shall search all arrest fingerprint cards received pursuant to s. 943.051 against the fingerprints retained in the statewide automated fingerprint identification system pursuant to this section and report to the employing agency any arrest records that are identified with the retained employee’s fingerprints. By January 1, 2008, a person who must meet minimum qualifications as provided in this section and whose fingerprints are not retained by the department pursuant to this section must be refingerprinted. These fingerprints must be forwarded to the department for processing and retention.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have passed a physical examination by a licensed physician, physician assistant, or certified advanced registered nurse practitioner, based on specifications established by the commission. In order to be eligible for the presumption set forth in s. 112.18 while employed with an employing agency, a law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer must have successfully passed the physical examination required by this subsection upon entering into service as a law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer with the employing agency, which examination must have failed to reveal any evidence of tuberculosis, heart disease, or hypertension. A law enforcement officer, correctional officer, or correctional probation officer may not use a physical examination from a former employing agency for purposes of claiming the presumption set forth in s. 112.18 against the current employing agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a good moral character as determined by a background investigation under procedures established by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute and submit to the employing agency or, if a private correctional officer, submit to the appropriate governmental entity an affidavit-of-applicant form, adopted by the commission, attesting to his or her compliance with subsections (1)-(7). The affidavit shall be executed under oath and constitutes an official statement within the purview of s. 837.06. The affidavit shall include conspicuous language that the intentional false execution of the affidavit constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree. The affidavit shall be retained by the employing agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complete a commission-approved basic recruit training program for the applicable criminal justice discipline, unless exempt under this subsection. An applicant who has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed a comparable basic recruit training program for the applicable criminal justice discipline in another state or for the Federal Government; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Served as a full-time sworn officer in another state or for the Federal Government for at least 1 year provided there is no more than an 8-year break in employment, as measured from the separation date of the most recent qualifying employment to the time a complete application is submitted for an exemption under this section,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is exempt in accordance with s. 943.131(2) from completing the commission-approved basic recruit training program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Achieve an acceptable score on the officer certification examination for the applicable criminal justice discipline.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with the continuing training or education requirements of s. 943.135.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 74-386; s. 1, ch. 76-277; s. 4, ch. 78-323; s. 5, ch. 80-71; ss. 7, 24, 25, ch. 81-24; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 6, ch. 84-258; ss. 7, 41, ch. 86-183; s. 7, ch. 86-187; ss. 1, 5, 6, ch. 87-186; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 92-131; s. 5, ch. 93-252; s. 1, ch. 95-408; s. 1629, ch. 97-102; s. 2, ch. 97-225; s. 2, ch. 2002-205; s. 2, ch. 2003-278; s. 1, ch. 2004-78; s. 4, ch. 2004-248; s. 12, ch. 2006-176; s. 1, ch. 2007-27.</History></Section>