<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0943.04353" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Triennial study of sexual predator and sexual offender registration and notification procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall, every 3 years, perform a study of the effectiveness of Florida’s sexual predator and sexual offender registration process and community and public notification provisions. As part of determining the effectiveness of the registration process, OPPAGA shall examine the current practices of: the Department of Corrections, county probation offices, clerk of courts, court administrators, county jails and booking facilities, Department of Children and Family Services, judges, state attorneys’ offices, Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, Department of Law Enforcement, and local law enforcement agencies as they relate to: sharing of offender information regarding registered sexual predators and sexual offenders for purposes of fulfilling the requirements set forth in the registration laws; ensuring the most accurate, current, and comprehensive information is provided in a timely manner to the registry; ensuring the effective supervision and subsequent monitoring of sexual predators and offenders; and ensuring informed decisions are made at each point of the criminal justice and registration process. In addition to determining the effectiveness of the registration process, the report shall focus on the question of whether the notification provisions in statute are sufficient to apprise communities of the presence of sexual predators and sexual offenders. The report shall examine how local law enforcement agencies collect and disseminate information in an effort to notify the public and communities of the presence of sexual predators and offenders. If the report finds deficiencies in the registration process, the notification provisions, or both, the report shall provide options for correcting those deficiencies and shall include the projected cost of implementing those options. In conducting the study, the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall consult with the Florida Council Against Sexual Violence and the Florida Association for the Treatment of Sexual Abusers in addition to other interested entities that may offer experiences and perspectives unique to this area of research. The report shall be submitted to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 1, 2006.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 2005-28; s. 114, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>