<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0961.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Compensation for wrongful incarceration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this act and subject to the limitations and procedures prescribed in this section, a person who is found to be entitled to compensation under the provisions of this act is entitled to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monetary compensation for wrongful incarceration, which shall be calculated at a rate of $50,000 for each year of wrongful incarceration, prorated as necessary to account for a portion of a year. For persons found to be wrongfully incarcerated after December 31, 2008, the Chief Financial Officer may adjust the annual rate of compensation for inflation using the change in the December-to-December “Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers” of the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A waiver of tuition and fees for up to 120 hours of instruction at any career center established under s. 1001.44, any community college as defined in s. 1000.21(3), or any state university as defined in s. 1000.21(6), if the wrongfully incarcerated person meets and maintains the regular admission requirements of such career center, community college, or state university; remains registered at such educational institution; and makes satisfactory academic progress as defined by the educational institution in which the claimant is enrolled;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of any fine, penalty, or court costs imposed and paid by the wrongfully incarcerated person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of any reasonable attorney’s fees and expenses incurred and paid by the wrongfully incarcerated person in connection with all criminal proceedings and appeals regarding the wrongful conviction, to be calculated by the department based upon the supporting documentation submitted as specified in s. 961.05; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in s. 943.0585, immediate administrative expunction of the person’s criminal record resulting from his or her wrongful arrest, wrongful conviction, and wrongful incarceration. The Department of Legal Affairs and the Department of Law Enforcement shall, upon a determination that a claimant is entitled to compensation, immediately take all action necessary to administratively expunge the claimant’s criminal record arising from his or her wrongful arrest, wrongful conviction, and wrongful incarceration. All fees for this process shall be waived.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The total compensation awarded under paragraphs (a), (c), and (d) may not exceed $2 million. No further award for attorney’s fees, lobbying fees, costs, or other similar expenses shall be made by the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In calculating monetary compensation under paragraph (1)(a), a wrongfully incarcerated person who is placed on parole or community supervision while serving the sentence resulting from the wrongful conviction and who commits anything less than a felony law violation that results in revocation of the parole or community supervision is eligible for compensation for the total number of years incarcerated. A wrongfully incarcerated person who commits a felony law violation that results in revocation of the parole or community supervision is ineligible for any compensation under subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 calendar days after issuing notice to the claimant that his or her claim satisfies all of the requirements under this act, the department shall notify the Chief Financial Officer to draw a warrant from the General Revenue Fund or another source designated by the Legislature in law for the purchase of an annuity for the claimant based on the total amount determined by the department under this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall purchase an annuity on behalf of the claimant for a term of not less than 10 years. The terms of the annuity shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide that the annuity may not be sold, discounted, or used as security for a loan or mortgage by the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain beneficiary provisions for the continued disbursement of the annuity in the event of the death of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the Chief Financial Officer draws the warrant for the purchase of the annuity, the claimant must sign a release and waiver on behalf of the claimant and his or her heirs, successors, and assigns, forever releasing the state or any agency, instrumentality, or any political subdivision thereof, or any other entity subject to the provisions of s. 768.28, from all present or future claims that the claimant or his or her heirs, successors, or assigns may have against such entities arising out of the facts in connection with the wrongful conviction for which compensation is being sought under the act. The release and waiver must be provided to the department prior to the issuance of the warrant by the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A wrongfully incarcerated person may not submit an application for compensation under this act if the person has a lawsuit pending against the state or any agency, instrumentality, or any political subdivision thereof, or any other entity subject to the provisions of s. 768.28, in state or federal court requesting compensation arising out of the facts in connection with the claimant’s conviction and incarceration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A wrongfully incarcerated person may not submit an application for compensation under this act if the person is the subject of a claim bill pending for claims arising out of the facts in connection with the claimant’s conviction and incarceration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once an application is filed under this act, a wrongfully incarcerated person may not pursue recovery under a claim bill until the final disposition of the application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any amount awarded under this act is intended to provide the sole compensation for any and all present and future claims arising out of the facts in connection with the claimant’s conviction and incarceration. Upon notification by the department that an application meets the requirements of this act, a wrongfully incarcerated person may not recover under a claim bill.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any compensation awarded under a claim bill shall be the sole redress for claims arising out of the facts in connection with the claimant’s conviction and incarceration and, upon any award of compensation to a wrongfully incarcerated person under a claim bill, the person may not receive compensation under this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any payment made under this act does not constitute a waiver of any defense of sovereign immunity or an increase in the limits of liability on behalf of the state or any person subject to the provisions of s. 768.28 or other law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2008-39.</History></Section>