<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0336.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Counties; contracts for construction of roads; procedure; contractor’s bond.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioners shall let the work on roads out on contract, in accordance with s. 336.41(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such contracts shall be let to the lowest responsible bidder, after publication of notice for bids containing specifications furnished by the commissioners in a newspaper published in the county where such contract is made, at least once each week for 2 consecutive weeks prior to the making of such contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon accepting a satisfactory bid, the commissioners shall enter into a contract with the party whose bid has been accepted. Such contract shall contain the specifications of the work to be done or material furnished, the time limit in which the construction is to be completed or material delivered, the time and amounts in which payments are to be made upon the contract, and a penalty to be paid by the contractor for the failure to comply with the terms of such contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The successful bidder shall enter into a good and sufficient bond with the commissioners for the faithful execution of the contract; the amount of the bond to be fixed by the commissioners, and the sufficiency of said bond to be likewise approved by the commissioners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioners may reject any or all bids and require new bids to be made.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 102, ch. 29965, 1955; s. 12, ch. 77-165; s. 24, ch. 90-279; s. 79, ch. 2002-20; s. 33, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>