<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0336.0255" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Distribution of additional local option tax.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 336.025, for calendar year 1993, the tax authorized in s. 336.025(1)(b) shall be imposed to November 1, 1993, to be effective January 1, 1994. Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 336.025: the county may, prior to September 1, 1993, establish by interlocal agreement with one or more of the municipalities located therein, representing a majority of the population of the incorporated area within the county, a distribution formula for dividing the entire proceeds of the local option gas tax among the county government and all eligible municipalities within the county and the proceeds of the tax shall be distributed among the county government and eligible municipalities based on the interlocal agreement. If no interlocal agreement is reached prior to September 1, 1993, the proceeds of the tax imposed prior to November 1, 1993, shall be distributed among the county government and eligible municipalities based on the transportation expenditures of each for the immediately preceding 5 fiscal years, as a proportion of the total of such expenditures for the county and all municipalities within the county. After the initial imposition of a tax imposed prior to November 1, 1993, and distributed based on historical transportation expenditures, the proportions shall be recalculated every 10 years based on the transportation expenditures of the immediately preceding 5 years. However, such recalculation shall under no circumstances materially or adversely affect the rights of holders of outstanding bonds, which are backed by taxes authorized in this section, and the amounts distributed to the county government and each municipality shall not be reduced below the amount necessary for the payment of principal and interest and reserves for principal and interest as required under the covenants of any bond resolution outstanding on the date of the recalculation.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 41, ch. 93-206.</History></Section>