<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0336.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County transportation trust fund; controls and administrative remedies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county shall establish and maintain a transportation trust fund for all transportation-related revenues and expenditures. All funds received by a county for transportation shall be deposited into this fund. No expenditures other than transportation expenditures authorized by law shall be made from such fund. Each county shall use a uniform accounts classification system approved by the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General shall conduct an audit of each such special trust fund at such intervals of time as practicable and in accordance with s. 11.45, to assure that the surplus of the constitutional gas tax distributed to each county is being expended in accordance with law. If, as a result of an audit, the Auditor General determines that a county has violated the constitutional or statutory requirements for expenditure of transportation funds, he or she shall immediately notify the county. The county shall have an opportunity to respond to the auditor’s report within 30 days after the date of written notification to the county. If the Auditor General refuses to modify or repeal his or her findings, the county may have such findings reviewed pursuant to the provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act, chapter 120. If the findings of the Auditor General are upheld after exhaustion of all administrative and legal remedies of the county, no further surplus constitutional gas tax funds in excess of funds for committed projects shall be distributed to the violating county until the county corrects the matters cited by the Auditor General and such corrections have been certified by the Auditor General as having been completed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 77-165; s. 40, ch. 83-3; s. 63, ch. 84-309; s. 493, ch. 95-148; s. 372, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 339.083.</Text></Note></Section>