<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0336.68" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special road and bridge district boundaries; property owner rights and options.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of real property located within both the boundaries of a community development district created under chapter 190 and within the boundaries of a special road and bridge district created by the alternative method of establishing special road and bridge districts previously authorized under <Reference Number="1" />ss. 336.61-336.67 shall have the option to select the community development district to be the provider of the road and drainage improvements to the property of the owner. Having made the selection, the property owner shall further have the right to withdraw the property from the boundaries of the special road and bridge district under the procedures set forth in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for withdrawal, the subject property shall not have received improvements or benefits from the special road and bridge district; there shall be no outstanding bonded indebtedness of the special road and bridge district for which the property is subject to ad valorem tax levies; and the withdrawal of the property shall not create an enclave bounded on all sides by the other property within the boundaries of the district when the property owner withdraws the property from the boundaries of the district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election by a property owner to withdraw property from the boundaries of a district as described in this section shall be accomplished by filing a certificate in the official records of the county in which the property is located. The certificate shall identify the name and mailing address of the owner, the legal description of the property, the name of the district from which the property is being withdrawn, and the general location of the property within district. The certificate shall further state that the property has not received benefits from the district from which the property is to be withdrawn; that there is no bonded indebtedness owed by the district; and that the property being withdrawn will not become an enclave within the district boundaries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property owner shall provide copies of the recorded certificate to the governing body of the district from which the property is being withdrawn within 10 days after the date that the certificate is recorded. If the district does not record an objection to the withdrawal of the property in the public records within 30 days after the recording of the certificate identifying the criteria in this section that have not been met, the withdrawal shall be final and the property shall be permanently withdrawn from the boundaries of the district.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-220; s. 52, ch. 2007-5.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by ss. 125-132, ch. 84-309.</Text></Note></Section>