<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0336.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Closing and abandonment of roads; authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioners, with respect to property under their control may in their own discretion, and of their own motion, or upon the request of any agency of the state, or of the federal government, or upon petition of any person or persons, are hereby authorized and empowered to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vacate, abandon, discontinue and close any existing public or private street, alleyway, road, highway, or other place used for travel, or any portion thereof, other than a state or federal highway, and to renounce and disclaim any right of the county and the public in and to any land in connection therewith;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Renounce and disclaim any right of the county and the public in and to any land, or interest therein, acquired by purchase, gift, devise, dedication or prescription for street, alleyway, road or highway purposes, other than lands acquired for state and federal highway; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Renounce and disclaim any right of the county and the public in and to land, other than land constituting, or acquired for, a state or federal highway, delineated on any recorded map or plat as a street, alleyway, road or highway.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioners, upon such motion, request, or petition, may adopt a resolution declaring that at a definite time and place a public hearing will be held to consider the advisability of exercising the authority granted in this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 49, ch. 29965, 1955.</History></Section>