<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0481.303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Landscape Architecture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registered landscape architect” means a person who holds a license to practice landscape architecture in this state under the authority of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate of registration” means a license issued by the department to a natural person to engage in the practice of landscape architecture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate of authorization” means a license issued by the department to a corporation or partnership to engage in the practice of landscape architecture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Landscape architecture” means professional services, including, but not limited to, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consultation, investigation, research, planning, design, preparation of drawings, specifications, contract documents and reports, responsible construction supervision, or landscape management in connection with the planning and development of land and incidental water areas, including the use of Florida-friendly landscaping as defined in s. 373.185, where, and to the extent that, the dominant purpose of such services or creative works is the preservation, conservation, enhancement, or determination of proper land uses, natural land features, ground cover and plantings, or naturalistic and aesthetic values;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The determination of settings, grounds, and approaches for and the siting of buildings and structures, outdoor areas, or other improvements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The setting of grades, shaping and contouring of land and water forms, determination of drainage, and provision for storm drainage and irrigation systems where such systems are necessary to the purposes outlined herein; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The design of such tangible objects and features as are necessary to the purpose outlined herein.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Landscape design” means consultation for and preparation of planting plans drawn for compensation, including specifications and installation details for plant materials, soil amendments, mulches, edging, gravel, and other similar materials. Such plans may include only recommendations for the conceptual placement of tangible objects for landscape design projects. Construction documents, details, and specifications for tangible objects and irrigation systems shall be designed or approved by licensed professionals as required by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 18, ch. 79-407; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 18, 19, ch. 88-347; s. 8, ch. 91-41; s. 8, ch. 91-68; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 173, ch. 94-218; s. 1, ch. 98-245; s. 27, ch. 2009-243.</History></Section>