<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0481.209" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examinations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person desiring to be licensed as a registered architect by initial examination shall apply to the department, complete the application form, and remit a nonrefundable application fee. The department shall license any applicant who the board certifies:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed the licensure examination prescribed by board rule; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of a school or college of architecture with a program accredited by the National Architectural Accreditation Board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person desiring to be licensed as a registered interior designer shall apply to the department for licensure. The department shall administer the licensure examination for interior designers to each applicant who has completed the application form and remitted the application and examination fees specified in s. 481.207 and who the board certifies:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate from an interior design program of 5 years or more and has completed 1 year of diversified interior design experience;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate from an interior design program of 4 years or more and has completed 2 years of diversified interior design experience;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed at least 3 years in an interior design curriculum and has completed 3 years of diversified interior design experience; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate from an interior design program of at least 2 years and has completed 4 years of diversified interior design experience.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Subsequent to October 1, 2000, for the purpose of having the educational qualification required under this subsection accepted by the board, the applicant must complete his or her education at a program, school, or college of interior design whose curriculum has been approved by the board as of the time of completion. Subsequent to October 1, 2003, all of the required amount of educational credits shall have been obtained in a program, school, or college of interior design whose curriculum has been approved by the board, as of the time each educational credit is gained. The board shall adopt rules providing for the review and approval of programs, schools, and colleges of interior design and courses of interior design study based on a review and inspection by the board of the curriculum of programs, schools, and colleges of interior design in the United States, including those programs, schools, and colleges accredited by the Foundation for Interior Design Education Research. The board shall adopt rules providing for the review and approval of diversified interior design experience required by this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 19, ch. 79-273; s. 357, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 7, 23, 24, ch. 88-383; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 300, ch. 94-119; s. 4, ch. 95-389; s. 5, ch. 96-309; s. 18, ch. 2000-332; s. 3, ch. 2001-269; s. 26, ch. 2012-61.</History>
</Section>