<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0481.2251" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings against registered interior designers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the disciplinary actions specified in subsection (2) may be taken:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to obtain, obtaining, or renewing, by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentation, or through an error of the board, a license to practice interior design;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice interior design revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another jurisdiction for any act which would constitute a violation of this part or of chapter 455;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the provision of interior design services or to the ability to provide interior design services. A plea of nolo contendere shall create a rebuttable presumption of guilt to the underlying criminal charges. However, the board shall allow the person being disciplined to present any evidence relevant to the underlying charges and the circumstances surrounding her or his plea;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">False, deceptive, or misleading advertising;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the board any person who the licensee knows is in violation of this part or the rules of the board;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, or advising any unlicensed person to use the title “interior designer” contrary to this part or to a rule of the board;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a registered interior designer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, or willfully impeding or obstructing such filing or inducing another person to do so. Such reports or records shall include only those which are signed in the capacity as a registered interior designer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making deceptive, untrue, or fraudulent representations in the provision of interior design services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accepting and performing professional responsibilities which the licensee knows or has reason to know that she or he is not competent or licensed to perform;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this part, any rule of the board, or a lawful order of the board previously entered in a disciplinary hearing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conspiring with another licensee or with any other person to commit an act, or committing an act, which would tend to coerce, intimidate, or preclude another licensee from lawfully advertising her or his services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acceptance of compensation or any consideration by an interior designer from someone other than the client without full disclosure of the compensation or consideration amount or value to the client prior to the engagement for services, in violation of s. 481.2131(2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rendering or offering to render architectural services; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing an act of fraud or deceit, or of negligence, incompetency, or misconduct, in the practice of interior design, including, but not limited to, allowing the preparation of any interior design studies, plans, or other instruments of service in an office that does not have a full-time Florida-registered interior designer assigned to such office or failing to exercise responsible supervisory control over services or projects, as required by board rule.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board finds any person guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order taking the following action or imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to approve an application for licensure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to renew an existing license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each violation or separate offense and a fine of up to $5,000 for matters pertaining to a material violation of the Florida Building Code as reported by a local jurisdiction; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 17, 24, ch. 88-383; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 306, ch. 94-119; s. 419, ch. 97-103; s. 131, ch. 98-166; s. 16, ch. 98-287; s. 122, ch. 2000-141; s. 191, ch. 2000-160; s. 35, ch. 2001-186; s. 4, ch. 2001-372; s. 4, ch. 2005-124.</History></Section>