<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0481.311" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall license any applicant who the board certifies is qualified to practice landscape architecture and who has paid the initial licensure fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall certify for licensure any applicant who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Passes the examination required by s. 481.309; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfies the experience requirement of s. 481.310.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall certify as qualified for a license by endorsement an applicant who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualifies to take the examination as set forth in s. 481.309; and has passed a national, regional, state, or territorial licensing examination which is substantially equivalent to the examination required by s. 481.309; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid license to practice landscape architecture issued by another state or territory of the United States, if the criteria for issuance of such license were substantially identical to the licensure criteria which existed in this state at the time the license was issued.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall certify as qualified for a certificate of authorization any applicant corporation or partnership who satisfies the requirements of s. 481.319.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may refuse to certify any applicant who is under investigation in any jurisdiction for any act which would constitute a violation of this act or of chapter 455, until the investigation is complete and disciplinary proceedings have been terminated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may refuse to certify any applicant who has violated any of the provisions of s. 481.325.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 18, ch. 79-407; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 8, 18, 19, ch. 88-347; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 242, ch. 94-119; s. 133, ch. 98-166; s. 193, ch. 2000-160.</History></Section>