<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0481.219" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification of partnerships, limited liability companies, and corporations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of or the offer to practice architecture or interior design by licensees through a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership offering architectural or interior design services to the public, or by a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership offering architectural or interior design services to the public through licensees under this part as agents, employees, officers, or partners, is permitted, subject to the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, a certificate of authorization shall be required for a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, or person practicing under a fictitious name, offering architectural services to the public jointly or separately. However, when an individual is practicing architecture in her or his own name, she or he shall not be required to be certified under this section. Certification under this subsection to offer architectural services shall include all the rights and privileges of certification under subsection (3) to offer interior design services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, a certificate of authorization shall be required for a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, or person operating under a fictitious name, offering interior design services to the public jointly or separately. However, when an individual is practicing interior design in her or his own name, she or he shall not be required to be certified under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All final construction documents and instruments of service which include drawings, specifications, plans, reports, or other papers or documents involving the practice of architecture which are prepared or approved for the use of the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership and filed for public record within the state shall bear the signature and seal of the licensee who prepared or approved them and the date on which they were sealed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All drawings, specifications, plans, reports, or other papers or documents prepared or approved for the use of the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership by an interior designer in her or his professional capacity and filed for public record within the state shall bear the signature and seal of the licensee who prepared or approved them and the date on which they were sealed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a certificate of authorization to any applicant who the board certifies as qualified for a certificate of authorization and who has paid the fee set in s. 481.207.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall certify an applicant as qualified for a certificate of authorization to offer architectural or interior design services, provided that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more of the principal officers of the corporation or limited liability company, or one or more partners of the partnership, and all personnel of the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership who act in its behalf in this state as architects, are registered as provided by this part; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more of the principal officers of the corporation or one or more partners of the partnership, and all personnel of the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership who act in its behalf in this state as interior designers, are registered as provided by this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing a procedure for the biennial renewal of certificates of authorization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall renew a certificate of authorization upon receipt of the renewal application and biennial renewal fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each partnership, limited liability company, and corporation certified under this section shall notify the department within 30 days of any change in the information contained in the application upon which the certification is based. Any registered architect or interior designer who qualifies the corporation, limited liability company, or partnership as provided in subsection (7) shall be responsible for ensuring responsible supervising control of projects of the entity and upon termination of her or his employment with a partnership, limited liability company, or corporation certified under this section shall notify the department of the termination within 30 days.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No corporation, limited liability company, or partnership shall be relieved of responsibility for the conduct or acts of its agents, employees, or officers by reason of its compliance with this section. However, the architect who signs and seals the construction documents and instruments of service shall be liable for the professional services performed, and the interior designer who signs and seals the interior design drawings, plans, or specifications shall be liable for the professional services performed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary action against a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership shall be administered in the same manner and on the same grounds as disciplinary action against a registered architect or interior designer, respectively.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to mean that a certificate of registration to practice architecture or interior design shall be held by a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership. Nothing in this section prohibits corporations, limited liability companies, and partnerships from joining together to offer architectural, engineering, interior design, surveying and mapping, and landscape architectural services, or any combination of such services, to the public, provided that each corporation, limited liability company, or partnership otherwise meets the requirements of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corporations, limited liability companies, or partnerships holding a valid certificate of authorization to practice architecture shall be permitted to use in their title the term “interior designer” or “registered interior designer.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 19, ch. 79-273; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 13, 23, 24, ch. 88-383; s. 6, ch. 89-66; s. 10, ch. 89-162; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 119, 304, ch. 94-119; s. 7, ch. 95-389; s. 415, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 2005-124.</History></Section>