<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0481.225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings against registered architects.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the disciplinary actions in subsection (3) may be taken:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of s. 455.227(1), s. 481.221, or s. 481.223, or any rule of the board or department lawfully adopted pursuant to this part or chapter 455.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to obtain or procure a license to practice architecture by bribery or fraudulent misrepresentations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice architecture revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country, for any act that would constitute a violation of this part or of chapter 455.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of architecture or the ability to practice architecture.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record that the licensee knows to be false, willfully failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports or records include only those that are prepared in the capacity of a registered architect.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner that is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing an act of fraud or deceit, or of negligence, incompetency, or misconduct, in the practice of architecture, including, but not limited to, allowing the preparation of any architectural studies, plans, or other instruments of service in an office that does not have a full-time Florida-registered architect assigned to such office or failing to ensure the responsible supervising control of services or projects, as required by board rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing on a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, or advising any unlicensed person to practice architecture contrary to this part or to a rule of the department or the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a registered architect.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to influence or overrule the professional judgment of an architect by an act that, if carried out, would constitute negligence contrary to the exercise of professional judgment in accordance with professionally accepted standards of practice or would threaten the public health, safety, or welfare.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing building code inspection services under s. 553.791, without satisfying the insurance requirements of that section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall specify, by rule, what acts or omissions constitute a violation of subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board finds any registered architect guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of an application for licensure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each count or separate offense and a fine of up to $5,000 for matters pertaining to a material violation of the Florida Building Code as reported by a local jurisdiction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the registered architect on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the board may specify, including requiring the registered architect to attend continuing education courses or to work under the supervision of another registered architect.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restriction of the authorized scope of practice by the registered architect.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall reissue the license of a disciplined registered architect upon certification by the board that he or she has complied with all of the terms and conditions set forth in the final order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 19, ch. 79-273; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 16, 23, 24, ch. 88-383; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 235, 308, ch. 94-119; s. 418, ch. 97-103; s. 130, ch. 98-166; s. 15, ch. 98-287; s. 121, ch. 2000-141; s. 190, ch. 2000-160; s. 35, ch. 2001-186; s. 4, ch. 2001-372; s. 3, ch. 2005-30; s. 3, ch. 2005-124; s. 5, ch. 2005-147; s. 60, ch. 2009-195; s. 51, ch. 2010-106.</History>
</Section>