<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0481.319" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corporate and partnership practice of landscape architecture; certificate of authorization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of or offer to practice landscape architecture by registered landscape architects registered under this part through a corporation or partnership offering landscape architectural services to the public, or through a corporation or partnership offering landscape architectural services to the public through individual registered landscape architects as agents, employees, officers, or partners, is permitted, subject to the provisions of this section, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more of the principal officers of the corporation, or partners of the partnership, and all personnel of the corporation or partnership who act in its behalf as landscape architects in this state are registered landscape architects;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more of the officers, one or more of the directors, one or more of the owners of the corporation, or one or more of the partners of the partnership is a registered landscape architect; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation or partnership has been issued a certificate of authorization by the board as provided herein.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All documents involving the practice of landscape architecture which are prepared for the use of the corporation or partnership shall bear the signature and seal of a registered landscape architect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant corporation shall file with the department the names and addresses of all officers and board members of the corporation, including the principal officer or officers, duly registered to practice landscape architecture in this state and, also, of all individuals duly registered to practice landscape architecture in this state who shall be in responsible charge of the practice of landscape architecture by the corporation in this state. An applicant partnership shall file with the department the names and addresses of all partners of the partnership, including the partner or partners duly registered to practice landscape architecture in this state and, also, of an individual or individuals duly registered to practice landscape architecture in this state who shall be in responsible charge of the practice of landscape architecture by said partnership in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each partnership and corporation licensed under this part shall notify the department within 1 month of any change in the information contained in the application upon which the license is based. Any landscape architect who terminates his or her employment with a partnership or corporation licensed under this part shall notify the department of the termination within 1 month.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary action against a corporation or partnership shall be administered in the same manner and on the same grounds as disciplinary action against a registered landscape architect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fact that registered landscape architects practice landscape architecture through a corporation or partnership as provided in this section shall not relieve any landscape architect from personal liability for his or her professional acts.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 6, 18, ch. 79-407; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 11, 18, 19, ch. 88-347; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 422, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>