<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.233" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Release of balloons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the release into the atmosphere of large numbers of balloons inflated with lighter-than-air gases poses a danger and nuisance to the environment, particularly to wildlife and marine animals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, firm, or corporation to intentionally release, organize the release, or intentionally cause to be released within a 24-hour period 10 or more balloons inflated with a gas that is lighter than air except for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Balloons released by a person on behalf of a governmental agency or pursuant to a governmental contract for scientific or meteorological purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hot air balloons that are recovered after launching;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Balloons released indoors; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Balloons that are either biodegradable or photodegradable, as determined by rule of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, and which are closed by a hand-tied knot in the stem of the balloon without string, ribbon, or other attachments. In the event that any balloons are released pursuant to the exemption established in this paragraph, the party responsible for the release shall make available to any law enforcement officer evidence of the biodegradability or photodegradability of said balloons in the form of a certificate executed by the manufacturer. Failure to provide said evidence shall be prima facie evidence of a violation of this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subsection (2) is guilty of a noncriminal infraction, punishable by a fine of $250.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may petition the circuit court to enjoin the release of 10 or more balloons if that person is a citizen of the county in which the balloons are to be released.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 89-113; s. 186, ch. 99-245; s. 53, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.995.</Text></Note></Section>