<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.3751" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Taking and possession of alligators; trapping licenses; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall take or possess any alligator or the eggs thereof without having first obtained from the commission a trapping license and paid the fee provided in this section. Such license shall be dated when issued and remain valid for 12 months after the date of issuance and shall authorize the person to whom it is issued to take or possess alligators and their eggs, and to sell, possess, and process alligators and their hides and meat, in accordance with law and commission rules. Such license shall not be transferable and shall not be valid unless it bears on its face in indelible ink the name of the person to whom it is issued. Such license shall be in the personal possession of the licensee while such person is taking alligators or their eggs or is selling, possessing, or processing alligators or their eggs, hides, or meat. The failure of the licensee to exhibit such license to the commission or its wildlife officers, when such person is found taking alligators or their eggs or is found selling, possessing, or processing alligators or their eggs, hides, or meat, shall be a violation of law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to assure the optimal utilization of the estimated available alligator resource and to ensure adequate control of the alligator management and harvest program, the commission may by rule limit the number of participants engaged in the taking of alligators or their eggs from the wild.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person who has been convicted of any violation of s. 379.3015 or s. 379.409 or the rules of the commission relating to the illegal taking of crocodilian species shall be eligible for issuance of a license for a period of 5 years subsequent to such conviction. In the event such violation involves the unauthorized taking of an endangered crocodilian species, no license shall be issued for 10 years subsequent to the conviction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license and issuance fee, and the activity authorized thereby, shall be as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual fee for issuance of a resident alligator trapping license, which permits a resident of the state to take alligators occurring in the wild other than alligator hatchlings, to possess and process alligators taken under authority of such alligator trapping license or otherwise legally acquired, and to possess, process, and sell their hides and meat, shall be $250.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual fee for issuance of a nonresident alligator trapping license, which permits a person other than a resident of the state to take alligators occurring in the wild other than alligator hatchlings, to possess and process alligators taken under authority of such alligator trapping license, and to possess, process, and sell their hides and meat, shall be $1,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual fee for issuance of an alligator trapping agent’s license, which permits a person to act as an agent of any person who has been issued a resident or nonresident alligator trapping license as provided in paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) and to take alligators occurring in the wild other than alligator hatchlings, to possess and process alligators taken under authority of such agency relationship, and to possess, process, and sell their hides and meat, shall be $50.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual fee for issuance of an alligator farming license, which permits a person to operate a facility for captive propagation of alligators, to possess alligators for captive propagation, to take alligator hatchlings and alligator eggs occurring in the wild, to rear such alligators, alligator hatchlings, and alligator eggs in captivity, to process alligators taken or possessed under authority of such alligator farming license or otherwise legally acquired, and to possess, process, and sell their hides and meat, shall be $250.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual fee for issuance of an alligator farming agent’s license, which permits a person to act as an agent of any person who has been issued an alligator farming license as provided in paragraph (d) and to take alligator hatchlings and alligator eggs occurring in the wild, to possess and process alligators taken under authority of such agency relationship, and to possess, process, and sell their hides and meat, shall be $50.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual fee for issuance of an alligator processor’s license, which permits a person to buy and process alligators lawfully taken by alligator trapping licenseholders and taken or possessed by alligator farming licenseholders and to sell alligator meat, hides, and other parts, shall be $250.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this section, “process” shall mean the possession and skinning or butchering of an alligator by someone other than the holder of the alligator trapping license, alligator trapping agent’s license, alligator farming license, or alligator farming agent’s license who has authorized the taking and possession of such alligator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall take any alligator egg occurring in the wild or possess any such egg unless such person has obtained, or is a licensed agent of another person who has obtained, an alligator egg collection permit. The alligator egg collection permit shall be required in addition to the alligator farming license provided in paragraph (2)(d). The commission is authorized to assess a fee for issuance of the alligator egg collection permit of up to $5 per egg authorized to be taken or possessed pursuant to such permit. Irrespective of whether a fee is assessed, $1 per egg collected and retained, excluding eggs collected on private wetland management areas, shall be transferred from the alligator management program to the General Inspection Trust Fund, to be administered by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services for the purpose of providing marketing and education services with respect to alligator products produced in this state, notwithstanding other provisions in this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt criteria by rule to establish appropriate qualifications for alligator collectors who may receive permits pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 87-199; s. 18, ch. 98-333; s. 15, ch. 2000-364; s. 7, ch. 2003-151; s. 162, ch. 2008-247; s. 38, ch. 2009-86.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.6673.</Text></Note></Section>