<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.3002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">J. W. Corbett and Cecil M. Webb Wildlife Management Areas.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission of this state is neither authorized nor empowered to do the following as to the J. W. Corbett Wildlife Management Area in Palm Beach County or the Cecil M. Webb Wildlife Management Area without the approval of the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund that such action is in the best interest of orderly and economical development of said area, viz.:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To trade, barter, lease, or exchange lands therein for lands of greater acreage contiguous to said wildlife management areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To grant easements for construction and maintenance of roads, railroads, canals, ditches, dikes, and utilities, including but not limited to telephone, telegraph, oil, gas, electric power, water, and sewers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To convey or release all rights in and to the phosphate, minerals, metals, and petroleum that is or may be in, on or under any lands traded, bartered, leased, or exchanged pursuant to paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund and the State Board of Education and all and every board, state department or state agency of the state having any title, right and interest in or to the land including oil and mineral rights in the lands to be traded, bartered, leased or exchanged within the J. W. Corbett Wildlife Management Area in Palm Beach County, is authorized and empowered to convey this interest of whatsoever nature to the record owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys received from the sale of lands within either wildlife management area, less reasonable expenses incident to the sale, shall be used by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission to acquire acreage contiguous to the wildlife management area or lands of equal wildlife value. The sale shall be made directly to the state, notwithstanding the procedures of s. 270.08 to the contrary.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 31410, 1956; ss. 27, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-60; s. 1, ch. 75-304; s. 159, ch. 99-13; s. 117, ch. 99-245; s. 95, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.023.</Text></Note></Section>