<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Panther Research and Management Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission the Florida Panther Research and Management Trust Fund to be used exclusively for the purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Money from the fund shall be spent only for the following purposes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To manage and protect existing Florida panther populations by increasing panther food sources where food is a limiting factor, determining conflicts between public use and panther survival, maintaining sufficient genetic variability in existing populations, and undertaking management and enforcement activities that protect panther habitat.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To educate the public concerning the value of the panther and the necessity for panther management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To reestablish Florida panthers into areas of suitable habitat, where feasible, by assessing the necessity of a captive breeding program for purposes of reintroduction of the panthers into the suitable habitat; selecting potential sites for reintroduction and investigating associated human sociological aspects; and assessing the potential for panther habitat acquisition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote and market the Florida panther license plate authorized under s. 320.08058.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission is authorized to receive donations for deposit into the Florida Panther Research and Management Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 83-173; s. 26, ch. 97-153; s. 1, ch. 97-259; s. 3, ch. 98-333; s. 16, ch. 99-4; s. 149, ch. 99-245; s. 5, ch. 2005-158; s. 18, ch. 2007-223; s. 15, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.672.</Text></Note></Section>