<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.2225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Everglades recreational sites; definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />It is the intent of the Legislature to provide for the development and management of recreational sites in the water conservation areas of the Florida Everglades when such development:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Can be accomplished without endangering the water quality and quantity of supply and where environmental impact will be minimal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is located on the exterior fringes of the Everglades to discourage extensive uncontrolled use of the interior regions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is located where convenient access is possible for the millions of Floridians living in urban areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offers recreational potential for nature trails, bird study, picnic areas, boating, fishing, hunting, and target shooting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is located where proper management and law enforcement can be provided.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commission” means the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Indian reservations” means lands as designated by chapter 285.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Development of recreational sites” means any improvements to existing facilities or sites and also such new selection and improvements as are needed for the various recreational activities as herein provided.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECREATIONAL SITES.<EmDash />The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission is directed to develop, manage, and enforce laws on certain recreational sites in the water conservation areas of the Everglades from funds to be appropriated by the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No recreational site will be developed on any Indian reservations as created by chapter 285 without first obtaining written approval for such development from the Indians of the particular reservation lands affected.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, ch. 73-249; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 4, ch. 78-323; s. 25, ch. 83-85; s. 27, ch. 83-218; s. 15, ch. 95-146; s. 22, ch. 99-5; s. 118, ch. 99-245; s. 31, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.025.</Text></Note></Section>