<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0379.3761" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exhibition or sale of wildlife; fees; classifications.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to provide humane treatment and sanitary surroundings for wild animals kept in captivity, no person, party, firm, association, or corporation shall have, or be in possession of, in captivity for the purpose of public display with or without charge or for public sale any wildlife, specifically birds, mammals, amphibians, and reptiles, whether native to Florida or not, without having first secured a permit from the commission authorizing such person, party, firm, association, or corporation to have in its possession in captivity the species and number of wildlife specified within such permit; however, this section does not apply to any wildlife not protected by law and the rules of the commission. No person, party, firm, association, or corporation may sell any wild animal life designated by commission rule as a conditional or prohibited species, Class I or Class II wildlife, reptile of concern, or venomous reptile in this state, including a sale with delivery made in this state, regardless of the origin of the sale or the location of the initial transaction, unless authorized by the commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees to be paid for the issuance of permits required by subsection (1) shall be as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For not more than 25 Class I or Class II individual specimens in the aggregate of all species, the sum of $150 per annum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For over 25 Class I or Class II individual specimens in the aggregate of all species, the sum of $250 per annum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any number of Class III individual specimens in the aggregate of all species, the sum of $50 per annum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The fees prescribed by this subsection shall be submitted to the commission with the application for permit required by subsection (1) and shall be deposited in the State Game Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a permit shall be required to include in her or his application a statement showing the place, number, and species of wildlife to be held in captivity by the applicant and shall be required upon request by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission to show when, where, and in what manner she or he came into possession of any wildlife acquired subsequent to the effective date of this act. The source of acquisition of such wildlife shall not be divulged by the commission except in connection with a violation of this section or a regulation of the commission in which information as to source of wildlife is required as evidence in the prosecution of such violation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section relative to licensing for exhibition do not apply to any municipal, county, state, or other publicly owned wildlife exhibit or any traveling zoo, circus, or exhibit licensed under chapter 205. </Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to the possession, control, care, and maintenance of ostriches, emus, rheas, and bison domesticated and confined for commercial farming purposes, except those kept and maintained on hunting preserves or game farms or primarily for exhibition purposes in zoos, carnivals, circuses, and other such establishments where such species are kept primarily for display to the public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section is punishable as provided in s. 379.4015.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-290; s. 84, ch. 79-164; s. 2, ch. 93-223; s. 590, ch. 95-148; s. 173, ch. 99-245; s. 33, ch. 2002-46; s. 9, ch. 2003-151; s. 2, ch. 2005-210; s. 164, ch. 2008-247; s. 39, ch. 2009-86; s. 4, ch. 2010-185.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.921(1)-(3), (7), (8).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>