<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.212" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fish and Wildlife Habitat Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission the Fish and Wildlife Habitat Program for the purpose of acquiring, assisting other agencies or local governments in acquiring, or managing lands important to the conservation of fish and wildlife.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission or its designee shall manage such lands for the primary purpose of maintaining and enhancing their habitat value for fish and wildlife. Other uses may be allowed that are not contrary to this purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where acquisition pursuant to this section will result in state ownership of land, title shall be vested in the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund as required in chapter 253. Land acquisition pursuant to this section shall be voluntary, negotiated acquisition and, where title is to be vested in the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, is subject to the acquisition procedures of s. 253.025.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquisition costs shall include purchase prices and costs and fees associated with title work, surveys, and appraisals required to complete an acquisition.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys which may be deposited into the Land Acquisition Trust Fund for the purposes of this section may include, but not be limited to, donations, grants, development-of-regional-impact wildlife mitigation contributions, or legislative appropriations. Preservation 2000 acquisition moneys and Conservation and Recreation Lands management moneys shall not be deposited into this fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 90-136; s. 10, ch. 90-217; s. 2, ch. 90-227; s. 20, ch. 94-240; s. 17, ch. 94-265; s. 124, ch. 99-245; s. 21, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.074.</Text></Note></Section>