<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.2525" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Noncultured shellfish harvesting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROTECTION OF SHELLFISH AQUACULTURE PRODUCTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission shall assist in protecting shellfish aquaculture products produced on leased or granted reefs in the hands of lessees or grantees from the state. Harvesting shellfish is prohibited within a distance of 25 feet outside lawfully marked lease boundaries or within setback and access corridors within specifically designated high-density aquaculture lease areas and aquaculture use zones.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in cooperation with the commission, shall provide the Legislature with recommendations as needed for the development and the proper protection of the rights of the state and private holders therein with respect to the oyster and clam business.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REMOVING OYSTERS, CLAMS, OR MUSSELS FROM NATURAL REEFS; LICENSES, ETC., PENALTY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to use a dredge or any means or implement other than hand tongs in removing oysters from the natural or artificial state reefs. This restriction shall apply to all areas of Apalachicola Bay for all shellfish harvesting, excluding private grounds leased or granted by the state prior to July 1, 1989, if the lease or grant specifically authorizes the use of implements other than hand tongs for harvesting. Except in Apalachicola Bay, upon the payment of $25 annually, for each vessel or boat using a dredge or machinery in the gathering of clams or mussels, a special activity license may be issued by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission pursuant to s. 379.361 for such use to such person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of any mechanical harvesting device other than ordinary hand tongs for taking shellfish for any purpose from public shellfish beds in Apalachicola Bay shall be unlawful.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The possession of any mechanical harvesting device on the waters of Apalachicola Bay from 5 p.m. until sunrise shall be unlawful.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each vessel used for the transport or deployment of a dredge or scrape shall prominently display the lease or grant number or numbers, in numerals which are at least 12 inches high and 6 inches wide, in such a manner that the lease or grant number or numbers are readily identifiable from both the air and the water.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Oysters may be harvested from natural or public grounds by common hand tongs or by hand, by scuba diving, free diving, leaning from vessels, or wading. In the Apalachicola Bay, this provision shall apply to all shellfish.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The commission shall apply other statutes, rules, or conditions necessary to protect the environment and natural resources from improper transport, deployment, and operation of a dredge or scrape. Any violation of this subsection or of any other statutes, rules, or conditions referenced in the special activity license shall be considered a violation of the license and shall result in revocation of the license and forfeiture of the bond submitted to the commission as a prerequisite to the issuance of this license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE RETURNS AS TO OYSTERS OR CLAMS HANDLED.<EmDash />Each packer, canner, corporation, firm, commission person, or dealer in fish shall, on the first day of each month, make a return under oath to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, as to the number of oysters, clams, and shellfish purchased, caught, or handled during the preceding month. Whoever is found guilty of making any false affidavit to any such report is guilty of perjury and punished as provided by law, and any person who fails to make such report shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $500 or by imprisonment in the county jail not exceeding 6 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SEIZURE OF VESSELS AND CARGOES VIOLATING OYSTER AND CLAM LAWS, ETC.<EmDash />Vessels, with their cargoes, violating the provisions of the laws relating to oysters and clams may be seized by anyone duly and lawfully authorized to make arrests under this section or by any sheriff or the sheriff’s deputies, and taken into custody, and when not arrested by the sheriff or the sheriff’s deputies, delivered to the sheriff of the county in which the seizure is made, and shall be liable to forfeiture, on appropriate proceedings being instituted by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, before the courts of that county. In such case the cargo shall at once be disposed of by the sheriff, for account of whom it may concern. Should the master or any of the crew of said vessel be found guilty of using dredges or other instruments in fishing oysters on natural reefs contrary to law, or fishing on the natural oyster or clam reefs out of season, or unlawfully taking oysters or clams belonging to a lessee, such vessel shall be declared forfeited by the court, and ordered sold and the proceeds of the sale shall be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the General Revenue Fund; any person guilty of such violations shall not be permitted to have any license provided for in this chapter within a period of 1 year from the date of conviction. Pending proceedings such vessel may be released upon the owner furnishing bond, with good and solvent security in double the value of the vessel, conditioned upon its being returned in good condition to the sheriff to abide the judgment of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DREDGING OF DEAD SHELLS PROHIBITED.<EmDash />The dredging of dead shell deposits is prohibited in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REQUIREMENTS FOR OYSTER VESSELS.<EmDash />All vessels used for the harvesting, gathering, or transporting of noncultured oysters for commercial use shall be constructed and maintained to prevent contamination or deterioration of oysters. To this end, all such vessels shall be provided with false bottoms and bulkheads fore and aft to prevent oysters from coming in contact with any bilge water. No dogs or other animals shall be allowed at any time on vessels used to harvest or transport oysters. A violation of any provision of this subsection shall result in at least the revocation of the violator’s license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 28145, 1953; s. 1, ch. 57-256; s. 1, ch. 57-163; s. 1, ch. 59-346; s. 1, ch. 59-490; s. 1, ch. 61-99; s. 2, ch. 61-58; s. 3, ch. 61-22; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 61-100; s. 19, ch. 63-512; ss. 1, 2, ch. 63-120; s. 1, ch. 63-396; s. 3, ch. 65-140; s. 1, ch. 65-436; s. 1, ch. 67-234; ss. 19, 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 298, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 71-244; s. 1, ch. 71-245; s. 1, ch. 71-246; s. 129, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 72-204; s. 1, ch. 72-236; s. 102, ch. 73-333; s. 1, ch. 75-120; s. 1, ch. 76-106; s. 1, ch. 77-92; s. 111, ch. 77-104; s. 52, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-197; s. 1, ch. 77-206; s. 23, ch. 78-95; s. 1, ch. 78-96; s. 33, ch. 79-65; s. 1, ch. 79-111; ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-52; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 1, ch. 82-408; s. 6, ch. 83-134; s. 27, ch. 83-216; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 2, ch. 84-121; s. 15, ch. 84-254; ss. 14, 17, ch. 85-234; s. 5, ch. 86-219; ss. 16, 19, ch. 86-240; ss. 7, 12, ch. 89-98; s. 3, ch. 89-116; ss. 19, 26, 42, ch. 89-175; s. 16, ch. 91-78; ss. 4, 5, ch. 91-187; ss. 5, 6, ch. 91-254; s. 5, ch. 91-286; s. 234, ch. 94-356; s. 92, ch. 95-143; s. 997, ch. 95-148; s. 37, ch. 96-321; s. 13, ch. 98-333; s. 64, ch. 99-8; s. 60, ch. 99-245; s. 12, ch. 2000-364; s. 381, ch. 2003-261; s. 13, ch. 2004-264; s. 89, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 6, ch. 83-134, as amended by s. 2, ch. 84-121; by s. 5, ch. 86-219; and by s. 19, ch. 86-240, repealed then-existing subsections (14)-(16) and (38), effective July 1, 1984, and further provided that if the Governor and Cabinet had not adopted appropriate rules by July 1, 1984, they would remain in force until such rules were effective. Section 9, ch. 83-134, provided that, prior to the adoption of rules amending, readopting, or repealing those provisions set forth in s. 6, the Marine Fisheries Commission would hold a public hearing thereon, and no such amendment, readoption, or repeal would be acted upon until it had been determined, based upon appropriate findings of fact, that such action would not adversely affect the resource. The Marine Fisheries Commission was transferred to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission by s. 3, ch. 99-245.</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 370.16.</Text></Note></Section>