<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0379.304" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exhibition or sale of wildlife.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
	<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits issued pursuant to s. 379.3761 and places where wildlife is kept or held in captivity shall be subject to inspection by officers of the commission at all times. The commission shall have the power to release or confiscate any specimens of any wildlife, specifically birds, mammals, amphibians, or reptiles, whether native to the state or not, when it is found that conditions under which they are being confined are unsanitary, or unsafe to the public in any manner, or that the species of wildlife are being maltreated, mistreated, or neglected or kept in any manner contrary to the provisions of chapter 828, any such permit to the contrary notwithstanding. Before any such wildlife is confiscated or released under the authority of this section, the owner thereof shall have been advised in writing of the existence of such unsatisfactory conditions; the owner shall have been given 30 days in which to correct such conditions; the owner shall have failed to correct such conditions; the owner shall have had an opportunity for a proceeding pursuant to chapter 120; and the commission shall have ordered such confiscation or release after careful consideration of all evidence in the particular case in question. The final order of the commission shall constitute final agency action.</Text>
</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In instances where wildlife is seized or taken into custody by the commission, said owner or possessor of such wildlife shall be responsible for payment of all expenses relative to the capture, transport, boarding, veterinary care, or other costs associated with or incurred due to seizure or custody of wildlife. Such expenses shall be paid by said owner or possessor upon any conviction or finding of guilt of a criminal or noncriminal violation, regardless of adjudication or plea entered, of any provision of chapter 828 or this chapter, or rule of the commission or if such violation is disposed of under s. 921.187. Failure to pay such expense may be grounds for revocation or denial of permits to such individual to possess wildlife.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any animal on exhibit of a type capable of contracting or transmitting rabies shall be immunized against rabies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is authorized to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is punishable as provided by s. 379.4015.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-290; s. 16, ch. 78-95; s. 32, ch. 83-218; s. 8, ch. 91-134; s. 5, ch. 98-333; s. 173, ch. 99-245; s. 33, ch. 2002-46; s. 9, ch. 2003-151; s. 107, ch. 2008-247; s. 33, ch. 2009-86; s. 11, ch. 2010-185.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.921(4)-(6), (9), (10).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>