<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.2253" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Compact; implementing legislation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FORM.<EmDash />The Governor of this state is hereby authorized and directed to execute a compact on behalf of the State of Florida with any one or more of the States of Maine, New Hampshire, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, Connecticut, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Georgia, and with such other states as may enter into the compact, legally joining therein in the form substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ATLANTIC STATES MARINE FISHERIES<NewLine />COMPACT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The contracting states solemnly agree:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE I</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The purpose of this compact is to promote the better utilization of the fisheries, marine, shell, and anadromous, of the Atlantic seaboard by the development of a joint program for the promotion and protection of such fisheries, and by the prevention of the physical waste of the fisheries from any cause. It is not the purpose of this compact to authorize the states joining herein to limit the production of fish or fish products for the purpose of establishing or fixing the price thereof, or creating and perpetuating a monopoly.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE II</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">This agreement shall become operative immediately as to those states executing it whenever any two or more of the States of Maine, New Hampshire, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, Connecticut, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia and Florida have executed it in the form that is in accordance with the laws of the executing state and the Congress has given its consent. Any state contiguous with any of the aforementioned states and riparian upon waters frequented by anadromous fish, flowing into waters under the jurisdiction of any of the aforementioned states, may become a party hereto as hereinafter provided.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE III</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Each state joining herein shall appoint three representatives to a commission hereby constituted and designated as the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission. One shall be the executive officer of the administrative agency of such state charged with the conservation of the fisheries resources to which this compact pertains or, if there be more than one officer or agency, the official of that state named by the governor thereof. The second shall be a member of the legislature of such state designated by such legislature or, in the absence of such designation, such legislator shall be designated by the governor thereof, provided that if it is constitutionally impossible to appoint a legislator as a commissioner from such state, the second member shall be appointed in such manner as is established by law. The third shall be a citizen who shall have a knowledge of and interest in the marine fisheries problem to be appointed by the governor. This commission shall be a body corporate with the powers and duties set forth herein.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE IV</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The duty of the said commission shall be to make inquiry and ascertain from time to time such methods, practices, circumstances and conditions as may be disclosed for bringing about the conservation and the prevention of the depletion and physical waste of the fisheries, marine, shell and anadromous, of the Atlantic seaboard. The commission shall have power to recommend the coordination of the exercise of the police powers of the several states within their respective jurisdictions to promote the preservation of those fisheries and their protection against overfishing, waste, depletion or any abuse whatsoever and to assure a continuing yield from the fisheries resources of the aforementioned states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">To that end the commission shall draft and, after consultation with the advisory committee hereinafter authorized, recommend to the governors and legislatures of the various signatory states legislation dealing with the conservation of the marine, shell and anadromous fisheries of the Atlantic seaboard. The commission shall, more than one month prior to any regular meeting of the legislature in any signatory state, present to the governor of the state its recommendations relating to enactments to be made by the legislature of that state in furthering the intents and purposes of this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The commission shall consult with and advise the pertinent administrative agencies in the states party hereto with regard to problems connected with the fisheries and recommend the adoption of such regulations as it deems advisable.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The commission shall have power to recommend to the states party hereto the stocking of the waters of such states with fish and fish eggs or joint stocking by some or all of the states party hereto and when two or more of the states shall jointly stock waters the commission shall act as the coordinating agency for such stocking.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE V</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The commission shall elect from its number a chair and a vice chair and shall appoint and at its pleasure remove or discharge such officers and employees as may be required to carry the provisions of this compact into effect and shall fix and determine their duties, qualifications and compensation. Said commission shall adopt rules and regulations for the conduct of its business. It may establish and maintain one or more offices for the transaction of its business and may meet at any time or place but must meet at least once a year.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VI</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">No action shall be taken by the commission in regard to its general affairs except by the affirmative vote of a majority of the whole number of compacting states present at any meeting. No recommendation shall be made by the commission in regard to any species of fish except by the affirmative vote of a majority of the compacting states which have an interest in such species. The commission shall define what shall be an interest.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The Fish and Wildlife Service of the Department of the Interior of the Government of the United States shall act as the primary research agency of the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission cooperating with the research agencies in each state for that purpose. Representatives of the said Fish and Wildlife Service shall attend the meetings of the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">An advisory committee to be representative of the commercial fishers and the saltwater anglers and such other interests of each state as the commission deems advisable shall be established by the commission as soon as practicable for the purpose of advising the commission upon such recommendations as it may desire to make.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VIII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">When any state other than those named specifically in Article II of this compact shall become a party thereto for the purpose of conserving its anadromous fish in accordance with the provisions of Article II the participation of such state in the action of the commission shall be limited to such species of anadromous fish.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE IX</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Nothing in this compact shall be construed to limit the powers of any signatory state or to repeal or prevent the enactment of any legislation or the enforcement of any requirement by any signatory state imposing additional conditions to conserve its fisheries.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE X</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Continued absence of representation or of any representative on the commission from any state party hereto shall be brought to the attention of the governor thereof.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE XI</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The states party hereto agree to make annual appropriations to the support of the commission in proportion to the primary market value of the products of their fisheries, exclusive of cod and haddock, as recorded in the most recent published reports of the Fish and Wildlife Service of the United States Department of the Interior, provided no state shall contribute less than $200 per annum and the annual contribution of each state above the minimum shall be figured to the nearest $100.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">The compacting states agree to appropriate initially the annual amounts scheduled below, which amounts are calculated in the manner set forth herein, on the basis of the catch record of 1938. Subsequent budgets shall be recommended by a majority of the commission and the cost thereof allocated equitably among the states in accordance with their respective interests and submitted to the compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">Schedule of Initial Annual<NewLine />State Contributions</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Maine<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$700</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">New Hampshire<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />200</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Massachusetts<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />2,300</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Rhode Island<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />300</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Connecticut<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />400</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">New York<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />1,300</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">New Jersey<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />800</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Delaware<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />200</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Maryland<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />700</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Virginia<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />1,300</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">North Carolina<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />600</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">South Carolina<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />200</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Georgia<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />200</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Florida<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />1,500</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE XII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">This compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each compacting state until renounced by it. Renunciation of this compact must be preceded by sending 6 months’ notice in writing of intention to withdraw from the compact to the other states party hereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMMISSIONERS; APPOINTMENT AND REMOVAL.<EmDash />In pursuance of Article III of said compact there shall be three members (hereinafter called commissioners) of the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission (hereinafter called commission) from this state. The first commissioner from this state shall be the Executive Director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, ex officio, and the term of any such ex officio commissioner shall terminate at the time he or she ceases to hold said office of Executive Director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, and his or her successor as commissioner shall be his or her successor as executive director. The second commissioner from this state shall be a legislator appointed on a rotating basis by the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House of Representatives, beginning with the appointment of a member of the Senate, and the term of any such commissioner shall terminate at the time he or she ceases to hold said legislative office. The Governor (subject to confirmation by the Senate), shall appoint a citizen as a third commissioner who shall have a knowledge of, and interest in, the marine fisheries problem. The term of said commissioner shall be 3 years and the commissioner shall hold office until a successor shall be appointed and qualified. Vacancies occurring in the office of such commissioner from any reason or cause shall be filled by appointment by the Governor (subject to confirmation by the Senate), for the unexpired term. The Executive Director of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission as ex officio commissioner may delegate, from time to time, to any deputy or other subordinate in his or her department or office, the power to be present and participate, including voting, as his or her representative or substitute at any meeting of or hearing by or other proceeding of the commission. The terms of each of the initial three members shall begin at the date of the appointment of the appointive commissioner, provided the said compact shall then have gone into effect in accordance with Article II of the compact; otherwise, they shall begin upon the date upon which said compact shall become effective in accordance with said Article II. Any commissioner may be removed from office by the Governor upon charges and after a hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS OF COMMISSION AND COMMISSIONERS.<EmDash />There is hereby granted to the commission and the commissioners thereof all the powers provided for in the said compact and all the powers necessary or incidental to the carrying out of said compact in every particular. All officers of the State of Florida are hereby authorized and directed to do all things falling within their respective provinces and jurisdiction necessary or incidental to the carrying out of said compact in every particular; it being hereby declared to be the policy of the State of Florida to perform and carry out the said compact and to accomplish the purposes thereof. All officers, bureaus, departments and persons of and in the state government or administration of the State of Florida are hereby authorized and directed at convenient times and upon request of the said commission to furnish the said commission with information and data possessed by them or any of them and to aid said commission by loan of personnel or other means lying within their legal rights respectively.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS OF COMMISSION SUPPLEMENTAL.<EmDash />Any powers herein granted to the commission shall be regarded as in aid of and supplemental to and in no case a limitation upon any of the powers vested in said commission by other laws of the State of Florida or by the laws of the States of Maine, New Hampshire, Massachusetts, Connecticut, Rhode Island, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia and Florida or by the Congress or the terms of said compact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCOUNTS TO BE KEPT BY COMMISSION; EXAMINATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and disbursements and shall report to the Governor and the Legislature of the State of Florida on or before the 10th day of December in each year, setting forth in detail the transactions conducted by it during the 12 months preceding December 1 of that year and shall make recommendations for any legislative action deemed by it advisable, including amendments to the statutes of the State of Florida which may be necessary to carry out the intent and purposes of the compact between the signatory states.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Financial Services is authorized and empowered from time to time to examine the accounts and books of the commission, including its receipts, disbursements and such other items referring to its financial standing as such department deems proper and to report the results of such examination to the governor of such state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPROPRIATION FOR EXPENSES OF COMMISSION.<EmDash />The sum of $600, annually, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the State Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the expenses of the commission created by the compact authorized by this law. The moneys hereby appropriated shall be paid out of the State Treasury on the audit and warrant of the Chief Financial Officer upon vouchers certified by the chair of the commission in the manner prescribed by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 28145, 1953; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 130, ch. 71-377; s. 9, ch. 77-85; s. 238, ch. 94-356; s. 998, ch. 95-148; s. 253, ch. 99-245; s. 3, ch. 2001-272; s. 382, ch. 2003-261; s. 36, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 370.19.</Text></Note></Section>