<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0379.353" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recreational licenses and permits; exemptions from fees and requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hunting, freshwater fishing, and saltwater fishing licenses and permits shall be issued without fee to any resident who is certified or determined:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be totally and permanently disabled for purposes of workers’ compensation under chapter 440 as verified by an order of a judge of compensation claims or written confirmation by the carrier providing workers’ compensation benefits, or to be totally and permanently disabled by the Railroad Retirement Board, by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor, or by any branch of the United States Armed Forces, or who holds a valid identification card issued under the provisions of s. 295.17, upon proof of same. Any license issued under this paragraph after January 1, 1997, expires after 5 years and must be reissued, upon request, every 5 years thereafter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be disabled by the United States Social Security Administration, upon proof of same. Any license issued under this paragraph after October 1, 1999, expires after 2 years and must be reissued, upon proof of certification of disability, every 2 years thereafter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A disability license issued after July 1, 1997, and before July 1, 2000, retains the rights vested thereunder until the license has expired.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hunting, freshwater fishing, or saltwater fishing license or permit is not required for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any child under 16 years of age, except as otherwise provided in this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person hunting or freshwater fishing on her or his homestead property, or on the homestead property of the person’s spouse or minor child; or any minor child hunting or freshwater fishing on the homestead property of her or his parent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident who is a member of the United States Armed Forces and not stationed in this state, when home on leave for 30 days or less, upon submission of orders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident fishing for recreational purposes only, within her or his county of residence with live or natural bait, using poles or lines not equipped with a fishing line retrieval mechanism. This exemption does not apply to residents fishing in a legally established fish management area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person freshwater fishing in a fish pond of 20 acres or less that is located entirely within the private property of the fish pond owner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person freshwater fishing in a fish pond that is licensed in accordance with s. 379.356.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person fishing who has been accepted as a client for developmental disabilities services by the Department of Children and Family Services, provided the department furnishes proof thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
	<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident saltwater fishing from land or from a structure fixed to the land who has been determined eligible by the Department of Children and Family Services for the food assistance program, temporary cash assistance, or the Medicaid programs. A benefit issuance or program identification card issued by the Department of Children and Family Services or the Florida Medicaid program of the Agency for Health Care Administration shall serve as proof of program eligibility. The client must have in his or her possession the ID card and positive proof of identification when fishing.</Text>
</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person saltwater fishing from a vessel licensed pursuant to s. 379.354(7).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person saltwater fishing from a vessel the operator of which is licensed pursuant to s. 379.354(7).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person saltwater fishing who holds a valid saltwater products license issued under s. 379.361(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person saltwater fishing for recreational purposes from a pier licensed under s. 379.354.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident fishing for mullet in fresh water who has a valid Florida freshwater fishing license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident 65 years of age or older who has in her or his possession proof of age and residency. A no-cost license under this paragraph may be obtained from any tax collector’s office upon proof of age and residency and must be in the possession of the resident during hunting, freshwater fishing, and saltwater fishing activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any employee of the commission who takes freshwater fish, saltwater fish, or game as part of employment with the commission, or any other person authorized by commission permit to take freshwater fish, saltwater fish, or game for scientific or educational purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident recreationally freshwater fishing who holds a valid commercial fishing license issued under s. 379.363(1)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2002-46; s. 14, ch. 2006-304; s. 16, ch. 2007-223; s. 138, ch. 2008-247; s. 41, ch. 2009-21; s. 3, ch. 2009-65; s. 7, ch. 2010-209.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.562.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>