<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.2201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Deposit of license fees; allocation of federal funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in ss. 379.203 and 379.207, all saltwater license and permit fees collected pursuant to s. 379.354 shall be deposited into the Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund, to be used as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not more than 7.5 percent of the total fees collected shall be used for administration of the licensing program and for information and education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than 30 percent of the total fees collected shall be used for law enforcement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than 32.5 percent of the total fees collected shall be used for marine research and management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than 30 percent of the total fees collected, for fishery enhancement, including, but not limited to, fishery statistics development, artificial reefs, and fish hatcheries.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds from recreational saltwater fishing license fees paid by fishers shall only be appropriated to the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds available from the Wallop-Breaux Aquatic Resources Trust Fund shall be distributed by the commission between freshwater fisheries management and research and marine fisheries management and research in proportion to the numbers of resident fresh and saltwater anglers as determined by the most current data on license sales. Unless otherwise provided by federal law, the commission, at a minimum, shall provide the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than 5 percent or more than 10 percent of the funds allocated to the commission shall be expended for an aquatic resources education program; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not less than 10 percent of the funds allocated to the commission shall be expended for acquisition, development, renovation, or improvement of boating facilities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 89-270; s. 6, ch. 90-243; s. 13, ch. 91-78; s. 212, ch. 94-356; s. 985, ch. 95-148; s. 5, ch. 96-300; s. 25, ch. 96-321; s. 4, ch. 98-203; s. 42, ch. 99-245; s. 17, ch. 2002-46; s. 10, ch. 2004-264; s. 1, ch. 2007-337; s. 22, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 370.0608; s. 372.5701.</Text></Note></Section>