<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.2293" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Airport activities within the scope of a federally approved wildlife hazard management plan or a federal or state permit or other authorization for depredation or harassment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that the ability of airports to manage wildlife hazards in a manner consistent with state and federal law is necessary to prevent jeopardy to human life or aircraft safety. It is the intent of the Legislature that actions taken by airports within the scope of authorizations to manage wildlife for such purposes not be subject to penalties, restrictions, liabilities, or sanctions and that such authorizations not be superseded by actions of other state or local agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An airport authority or other entity owning or operating an airport, as defined in s. 330.27(2), is not subject to any administrative or civil penalty, restriction, or other sanction with respect to any authorized action taken in a non-negligent manner for the purpose of protecting human life or aircraft safety from wildlife hazards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, an “authorized action taken for the purpose of protecting human life or aircraft safety from wildlife hazards” is an action authorized by or within the scope of any of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The airport’s wildlife hazard management plan, as approved by the Federal Aviation Administration.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A depredation permit issued by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A standing order of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rule 68A-9.010(4) or rule 68A-27.002, Florida Administrative Code, or a permit authorizing the harassment of wildlife issued by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “authorized action taken for the purpose of protecting human life or aircraft safety from wildlife hazards” does not include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dredging or filling of wetlands or other surface waters or alteration of a stormwater management system, unless authorized by and performed in compliance with a permit issued under part IV of chapter 373 or an emergency order under chapter 373. However, such a permit or emergency order is not required prior to the activity when the airport authority or other entity described in subsection (2) determines that an emergency condition exists which requires immediate action to protect human life and the airport authority or other entity described in subsection (2) obtains the appropriate permit under part IV of chapter 373 within 1 year after conducting the emergency action.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trespass on lands or unauthorized interference with an easement not owned or leased by the airport authority or other entity referred to in subsection (2).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an authorized action taken for the purpose of protecting human life or aircraft safety from wildlife hazards as defined in subsection (3) conflicts or appears to conflict with a development permit, land development regulation, local comprehensive plan, or other environmental or land-use law, rule, restriction, or requirement, the authorization described in subsection (3) shall prevail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to applying to the airport authority or other owner or operator of the airport, the immunities conferred by this section also apply to any officer, employee, contractor, or employee of a contractor of the airport authority or other owner or operator of the airport, or any member of the airport’s governing body, to the extent that the actions of the officer, employee, contractor, contractor’s employee, or member are authorized by or within the scope of one or more of the legal authorities described in subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section is intended to provide immunity from liability with respect to intentional or negligent torts, and nothing in this section is intended to affect the waiver of sovereign immunity under s. 768.28.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2009-167.</History></Section>