<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Illegal molestation of or theft from freshwater fishing gear.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, or corporation that willfully molests any authorized and lawfully permitted freshwater fishing gear belonging to another without the express written consent of the owner commits a Level Four violation under s. 379.401. Any written consent must be available for immediate inspection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, or corporation that willfully removes the contents of any authorized and lawfully permitted freshwater fishing gear belonging to another without the express written consent of the owner commits a Level Four violation under s. 379.401. Any written consent must be available for immediate inspection.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A person, firm, or corporation that receives a citation for a violation of this subsection is prohibited, immediately upon receipt of such citation and until adjudicated or convicted of a felony under this subsection, from transferring any endorsements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, or corporation convicted pursuant to subsection (1) of removing the contents of freshwater fishing gear without the express written consent of the owner shall permanently lose all of his or her freshwater and saltwater fishing privileges, including his or her recreational and commercial licenses and endorsements, and shall be assessed an administrative penalty of not more than $5,000. The endorsements of such person, firm, or corporation are not transferable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “freshwater fishing gear” means haul seines, slat baskets, wire traps, hoop nets, or pound nets, and includes the lines or buoys attached thereto.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2002-264; s. 29, ch. 2006-304; s. 173, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.99022.</Text></Note></Section>