<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.223" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Citizen support organizations; use of state property; audit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission may authorize the establishment of citizen support organizations to provide assistance, funding, and promotional support for the programs of the commission. For purposes of this section, the term “citizen support organization” means an organization which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a corporation not for profit incorporated pursuant to the provisions of chapter 617 and approved by the Department of State.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is organized and operated to conduct programs and activities; raise funds; request and receive grants, gifts, and bequests of money; acquire, receive, hold, invest, and administer in its own name securities, funds, or real or personal property; and make expenditures for the benefit of the commission or an individual program unit of the commission; except that such organization may not receive funds from the commission or the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute by grant, gift, or contract unless specifically authorized by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission has determined acts in a manner that is consistent with the goals of the commission and the best interests of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is approved in writing by the commission to operate for the benefit of the commission. Such approval must be stated in a letter of agreement from the executive director of the commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission may permit a citizen support organization to use commission property, facilities, and personnel free of charge. A citizen support organization may use commission property, facilities, and personnel if such use is consistent with the approved purpose of that citizen support organization and if such use does not unreasonably interfere with the general public’s use of commission property, facilities, and personnel for established purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may prescribe conditions upon the use by a citizen support organization of commission property, facilities, or personnel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may not permit the use of any property, facilities, or personnel of the state by a citizen support organization that does not provide equal membership and employment opportunities to all persons regardless of race, color, national origin, religion, sex, or age.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each citizen support organization shall provide for an annual financial audit in accordance with s. 215.981. The identity of a donor or prospective donor to a citizen support organization who desires to remain anonymous and all information identifying such donor or prospective donor are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. Such anonymity shall be maintained in the auditor’s report.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-84; s. 111, ch. 90-360; s. 1, ch. 95-127; s. 172, ch. 96-406; s. 114, ch. 99-245; s. 107, ch. 2001-266; s. 7, ch. 2004-264; s. 32, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.0215.</Text></Note></Section>