<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.2257" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperative agreements with U. S. Forest Service; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission is authorized and empowered:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter into cooperative agreements with the United States Forest Service for the development of game, bird, fish, reptile, or fur-bearing animal management and demonstration projects on and in the Osceola National Forest in Columbia and Baker Counties, and in the Ocala National Forest in Marion, Lake, and Putnam Counties and in the Apalachicola National Forest in Liberty County. Provided, however, that no such cooperative agreements shall become effective in any county concerned until confirmed by the board of county commissioners of such county expressed through appropriate resolution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with the United States Forest Service, to make, adopt, promulgate, amend, and repeal rules and regulations, consistent with law, for the further or better control of hunting, fishing, and control of wildlife in the above National Forests or parts thereof; to shorten seasons and reduce bag limits, or shorten or close seasons on any species of game, bird, fish, reptile, or fur-bearing animal within the limits prescribed by the Florida law, in the above enumerated National Forests or parts thereof, when it shall find after investigation that such action is necessary to assure the maintenance of an adequate supply of wildlife.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fix a charge not to exceed $5, for persons 18 years of age and over, and not to exceed $2 for persons under the age of 18 years, over and above the license fee for hunting now required by law. This additional fee is to apply only on areas covered by above cooperative agreements. The proceeds from this additional license fee shall be used in the development, propagation of wildlife, and protection of the areas covered by the cooperative agreements as the commission and the United States Forest Service may deem proper. Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the commission to change any penalty prescribed by law or to change the amount of general license fees or the general authority conferred by licenses prescribed by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of chapter 120, notice of the making, adoption, and promulgation of the above rules and regulations shall be given by posting said notices, or copies of the rules and regulations, in the offices of the county judges and in the post offices within the area to be affected and within 10 miles thereof. In addition to the posting of said notices, as aforesaid, copies of said notices or of said rules and regulations shall also be published in newspapers published at the county seats of Baker, Columbia, Marion, Lake, Putnam, and Liberty Counties, or so many thereof as have newspapers, once not more than 35 nor less than 28 days and once not more than 21 nor less than 14 days prior to the opening of the state hunting season in said areas. Any person violating any rules or regulations promulgated by the commission to cover these areas under cooperative agreements between the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission and the United States Forest Service, none of which shall be in conflict with the laws of Florida, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-4, 7, 8, ch. 17939, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 1977(117), 8135(9-a); s. 1, ch. 23090, 1945; s. 315, ch. 71-136; s. 16, ch. 78-95; s. 158, ch. 99-245; s. 40, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.74.</Text></Note></Section>