<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0379.3762" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Personal possession of wildlife.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person or persons to possess any wildlife as defined in this act, whether native to Florida or not, until she or he has obtained a permit as provided by this section from the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The classifications of types of wildlife and fees to be paid for permits for the personal possession of wildlife shall be as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Class I</Font><EmDash />Wildlife which, because of its nature, habits, or status, shall not be possessed as a personal pet.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Class II</Font><EmDash />Wildlife considered to present a real or potential threat to human safety, the sum of $140 per annum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Class III</Font><EmDash />All other wildlife not included in Class I or Class II, for which a no-cost permit must be obtained from the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, corporation, or association exhibiting or selling wildlife and being duly permitted as provided by s. 379.304 shall be exempt from the fee requirement to receive a permit under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to the possession, control, care, and maintenance of ostriches, emus, rheas, and bison domesticated and confined for commercial farming purposes, except those kept and maintained on hunting preserves or game farms or primarily for exhibition purposes in zoos, carnivals, circuses, and other such establishments where such species are kept primarily for display to the public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section is punishable as provided in s. 379.4015.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-309; s. 9, ch. 91-134; s. 3, ch. 93-223; s. 591, ch. 95-148; s. 174, ch. 99-245; s. 34, ch. 2002-46; s. 10, ch. 2003-151; s. 3, ch. 2005-210; s. 165, ch. 2008-247; s. 40, ch. 2009-86; s. 14, ch. 2010-185.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.922(1), (2), (5)-(7).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>