<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of commission grant programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission is authorized to establish grant programs that are consistent with statutory authority and legislative appropriations. The commission is further authorized to receive funds from any legal source for purposes of matching state dollars or for passing through the agency as grants to other entities whether or not matching funds or in-kind matches are required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any grant program established by the commission, the commission shall adopt rules, pursuant to the requirements of chapter 120, for each grant program which shall include, but are not limited to: the method or methods of payment; the supporting documents required before payment will be made; when matching funds or in-kind matches are allowed; what moneys, services, or other sources and amounts of matching funds or in-kind matches will be eligible for use for matching the grant by the commission; who is eligible to participate in the program; and other provisions that the commission finds necessary to achieve program objectives and an accounting for state funds in accordance with law and generally accepted accounting principles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is authorized to preaudit or postaudit account books and other documentation of a grant recipient to assure that grant funds have been used in accordance with the terms of the grant and state rules and statutes. When such audit reveals that moneys have not been spent in accordance with grant requirements, the commission may withhold moneys or recover moneys previously paid. A grant recipient will be allowed a maximum of 60 days to submit any additional pertinent documentation to offset the amount identified as being due the commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-225; s. 198, ch. 94-356; s. 237, ch. 99-245; s. 10, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 370.023.</Text></Note></Section>