<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0379.208" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund; purposes.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission shall serve as a broad-based depository for funds from various marine-related and boating-related activities and shall be administered by the commission for the purposes of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for marine research.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for fishery enhancement, including, but not limited to, fishery statistics development, artificial reefs, and fish hatcheries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for marine law enforcement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for administration of licensing programs for recreational fishing, saltwater products sales, and related information and education activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for the operations of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for titling and registration of vessels.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for marine turtle protection, research, and recovery activities from revenues that are specifically credited to the trust fund for these purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding activities for rehabilitation of oyster harvesting areas from which special oyster surcharge fees are collected, including relaying and transplanting live oysters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for boating research, boating-related programs and activities, and for law enforcement on state waters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding for the stone crab trap reduction program under s. 379.365, the blue crab effort management program under s. 379.366, the spiny lobster trap certificate program under s. 379.3671, and the trap retrieval program under s. 379.2424.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund shall receive the proceeds from:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All license fees collected pursuant to ss. 379.361 and 379.362.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds collected from the registration of vessels and other fees pursuant to s. 328.72.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fees collected under ss. 379.2424, 379.355, 379.357, 379.365, 379.366, and 379.3671.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fines and penalties under ss. 379.365, 379.366, 379.3671, and 379.407.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other revenues as provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds provided to the Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund from vessel registration fees pursuant to s. 328.76 may be used for the following purposes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To reimburse the cost of activities authorized pursuant to the Fish and Wildlife Service of the United States Department of the Interior. The facilities must be involved in the actual rescue and full-time acute care veterinarian-based rehabilitation of manatees. The cost of activities includes, but is not limited to, costs associated with expansion, capital outlay, repair, maintenance, and operation related to the rescue, treatment, stabilization, maintenance, release, and monitoring of manatees. Moneys distributed through the contractual agreement to each facility for manatee rehabilitation must be proportionate to the number of manatees under acute care rehabilitation; the number of maintenance days medically necessary in the facility; and the number released during the previous fiscal year. The commission may set a cap on the total amount reimbursed per manatee per year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For training on the care, treatment, and rehabilitation of marine mammals at the Whitney Laboratory and the College of Veterinary Medicine at the University of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For program administration costs of the agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds transferred to the Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund from the Fuel Tax Collection Trust Fund pursuant to s. 206.606 shall be used for the following purposes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide additional water-related law enforcement positions within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission primarily for the purpose of enforcing laws designed to protect manatee populations. Law enforcement positions funded under this provision shall be assigned to counties having the highest incidence of manatee deaths and injuries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the placement of uniform waterway markers on state waters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide funding for construction and maintenance of publicly owned boat ramps, piers, and docks, directly and through grants to counties and municipalities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To implement and administer programs related to boating safety and education, manatee technical avoidance technology, and economic development initiatives to promote boating in the state, including competitive grants programs as provided in s. 327.47.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For other activities of the Boating and Waterways Section such as coordinating the submission of state comments on boating-related events.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Funds not used in one fiscal year must be carried over for use in subsequent years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 96-321; s. 59, ch. 99-245; s. 34, ch. 99-289; s. 35, ch. 2000-197; s. 2, ch. 2001-62; s. 51, ch. 2002-1; s. 4, ch. 2002-46; s. 4, ch. 2003-156; s. 3, ch. 2004-264; s. 5, ch. 2007-223; s. 10, ch. 2008-114; s. 18, ch. 2008-247; s. 2, ch. 2012-95.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 370.0603.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>