<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.246" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tortugas shrimp beds; gifted and loan property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission is authorized to take title in the name of the state to any vessel or vessels suitable for use in carrying out the inspection and patrol of the Tortugas Bed which may be offered as a gift to the state by any person, firm, corporation, or association in the shrimp industry for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section. In the event such title is taken to such vessel or vessels, the commission is authorized to operate and keep said vessel or vessels in proper repair.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission is further authorized to accept the temporary loan of any vessel or vessels, suitable for use in carrying out the provisions of this section, for periods not exceeding 1 year. However, the state shall not assume any liability to the owner or owners of said vessels for any damage done by said vessels to other vessels, persons, or property. In the operation of said loaned vessels, upkeep and repair shall consist only of minor repairs and routine maintenance. The owner or owners shall carry full marine insurance coverage on said loaned vessel or vessels for the duration of the period during which said vessels are operated by the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, ch. 57-358; s. 1, ch. 61-470; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 62, ch. 69-353; s. 1, ch. 70-163; s. 296, ch. 71-136; s. 2, ch. 72-54; s. 1, ch. 74-1; s. 23, ch. 78-95; s. 32, ch. 79-65; s. 8, ch. 83-134; s. 2, ch. 84-121; s. 1, ch. 85-163; ss. 13, 17, ch. 85-234; s. 13, ch. 86-240; s. 22, ch. 98-227; s. 248, ch. 99-245; s. 78, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 8, ch. 83-134, as amended by s. 2, ch. 84-121, and by s. 1, ch. 85-163, repealed the then-existing section, effective July 1, 1986, and further provided that if the Governor and Cabinet had not adopted appropriate rules by July 1, 1986, it would remain in force until such rules were effective. Section 9, ch. 83-134, provided that, prior to the adoption of rules amending, readopting, or repealing those provisions set forth in s. 8, the Marine Fisheries Commission would hold a public hearing thereon, and no such amendment, readoption, or repeal would be acted upon until it had been determined, based upon appropriate findings of fact, that such action would not adversely affect the resource. The Marine Fisheries Commission was transferred to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission by s. 3, ch. 99-245.</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 370.151.</Text></Note></Section>