<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0379.3511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment of subagents for the sale of hunting, fishing, and trapping licenses and permits.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subagents shall serve at the pleasure of the commission. The commission may establish, by rule, procedures for the selection and appointment of subagents. The following are requirements for subagents so appointed:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may require each subagent to post an appropriate bond as determined by the commission, using an insurance company acceptable to the commission. In lieu of the bond, the commission may purchase blanket bonds covering all or selected subagents or may allow a subagent to post other security as required by the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subagent may sell licenses and permits as authorized by the commission at specific locations within the county and in states as will best serve the public interest and convenience in obtaining licenses and permits. The commission may prohibit subagents from selling certain licenses or permits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to handle licenses or permits for a fee or compensation of any kind unless he or she has been appointed as a subagent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully violates any of the provisions of this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
	<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subagent may charge and receive as his or her compensation 50 cents for each license or permit sold. This charge is in addition to the sum required by law to be collected for the sale and issuance of each license or permit. This charge does not apply to the shoreline fishing license; however, for each shoreline fishing license issued, the subagent may retain 50 cents from other license proceeds otherwise due the commission.</Text>
</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subagent shall submit payment for and report the sale of licenses and permits to the commission as prescribed by the commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission or any other law enforcement agency may carry out any investigation necessary to secure information required to carry out and enforce this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All social security numbers that are provided pursuant to ss. 379.352 and 379.354 and are contained in records of any subagent appointed under this section are confidential as provided in those sections.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, ch. 59-494; s. 1, ch. 65-509; s. 310, ch. 71-136; s. 106, ch. 71-355; s. 103, ch. 73-333; s. 1, ch. 80-369; s. 3, ch. 82-188; s. 31, ch. 83-218; s. 9, ch. 85-235; s. 14, ch. 90-243; s. 578, ch. 95-148; s. 17, ch. 96-300; s. 17, ch. 98-397; s. 138, ch. 99-245; s. 38, ch. 2000-362; ss. 25, 26, ch. 2002-46; s. 135, ch. 2008-247; s. 1, ch. 2010-146.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 372.574.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>