<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0379.245" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Spiny lobster reports by dealers during closed season required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 3 days after the commencement of the closed season for the taking of spiny lobster, each and every seafood dealer, either retail or wholesale, intending to possess whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat during closed season shall submit to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, on forms provided by the commission, a sworn report of the quantity, in pounds, of whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, and spiny lobster meat in the dealer’s name or possession as of the date the season closed. This report shall state the location and number of pounds of whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, and spiny lobster meat. The commission shall not accept any reports not delivered or postmarked by midnight of the 3rd calendar day after the commencement of the closed season, and any stocks of spiny lobster reported therein are declared a nuisance and may be seized by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to submit a report as described in subsection (1) or reporting a greater or lesser amount of whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat than is actually in the dealer’s possession or name is a major violation of this chapter, punishable as provided in s. 379.407(1), s. 379.414, or both. The commission shall seize the entire supply of unreported or falsely reported whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat, and shall carry the same before the court for disposal. The dealer shall post a cash bond in the amount of the fair value of the entire quantity of unreported or falsely reported spiny lobster as determined by the judge. After posting the cash bond, the dealer shall have 24 hours to transport said products outside the limits of Florida for sale as provided by s. 379.337. Otherwise, the product shall be declared a nuisance and disposed of by the commission according to law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All dealers having reported stocks of spiny lobster may sell or offer to sell such stocks of spiny lobster; however, such dealers shall submit an additional report on the last day of each month during the duration of the closed season. Reports shall be made on forms supplied by the commission. Each dealer shall state on this report the number of pounds brought forward from the previous report period, the number of pounds sold during the report period, the number of pounds, if any, acquired from a licensed wholesale dealer during the report period, and the number of pounds remaining on hand. In every case, the amount of spiny lobster sold plus the amount reported on hand shall equal the amount acquired plus the amount reported remaining on hand in the last submitted report. Copies of records or invoices documenting the number of pounds acquired during the closed season must be maintained by the wholesale or retail dealer and shall be kept available for inspection by the commission for a period not less than 3 years from the date of the recorded transaction. Reports postmarked later than midnight on the 3rd calendar day of each month during the duration of the closed season will not be accepted by the commission. Dealers for which late supplementary reports are not accepted by the commission must show just cause why their entire stock of whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat should not be seized by the commission. Whenever a dealer fails to timely submit the monthly supplementary report as described in this subsection, the dealer may be subject to the following civil penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a first violation, the commission shall assess a civil penalty of $500.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second violation within the same spiny lobster closed season, the commission shall assess a civil penalty of $1,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a third violation within the same spiny lobster closed season, the commission shall assess a civil penalty of $2,500 and may seize said dealer’s entire stock of whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat and carry the same before the court for disposal. The dealer shall post a cash bond in the amount of the fair value of the entire remaining quantity of spiny lobster as determined by the judge. After posting the cash bond, a dealer shall have 24 hours to transport said products outside the limits of Florida for sale as provided by s. 379.337. Otherwise, the product shall be declared a nuisance and disposed of by the commission according to law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All seafood dealers shall at all times during the closed season make their stocks of whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat available for inspection by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each wholesale and retail dealer in whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat shall keep throughout the period of the spiny lobster closed season copies of the bill of sale or invoice covering each transaction involving whole spiny lobster, spiny lobster tails, or spiny lobster meat. Such invoices and bills shall be kept available at all times for inspection by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission may adopt rules incorporating by reference such forms as are necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 41, ch. 97-160; s. 23, ch. 97-164; s. 13, ch. 98-203; s. 8, ch. 98-227; s. 108, ch. 99-245; s. 16, ch. 2000-197; s. 11, ch. 2007-223; s. 77, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 370.1405.</Text></Note></Section>