<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0633.082" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection of fire control systems, fire hydrants, and fire protection systems.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal shall have the right to inspect any fire control system during and after construction to determine that such system meets the standards set forth in the laws and rules of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fire hydrants and fire protection systems installed in public and private properties, except one-family or two-family dwellings, shall be inspected following procedures established in the nationally recognized inspection, testing, and maintenance standards publications NFPA-24 and NFPA-25 as set forth in the edition adopted by the State Fire Marshal. Quarterly, annual, 3-year, and 5-year inspections consistent with the contractual provisions with the owner shall be conducted by the certificateholder or permittees employed by the certificateholder pursuant to s. 633.521, except that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public fire hydrants owned by a governmental entity shall be inspected following procedures established in the inspection, testing, and maintenance standards adopted by the State Fire Marshal or equivalent standards such as those contained in the latest edition of the American Water Works Association’s Manual M17, “Installation, Field Testing, and Maintenance of Fire Hydrants.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County, municipal, and special district utilities may perform fire hydrant inspections required by this section using designated employees. Such designated employees need not be certified under this chapter. However, counties, municipalities, or special districts that use designated employees are responsible for ensuring that the designated employees are qualified to perform such inspections.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inspecting contractor shall provide to the building owner or hydrant owner and the local authority having jurisdiction a copy of the applicable inspection report established under this chapter. The maintenance of fire hydrant and fire protection systems as well as corrective actions on deficient systems is the responsibility of the owner of the system or hydrant. Equipment requiring periodic testing or operation to ensure its maintenance shall be tested or operated as specified in the Fire Prevention Code, Life Safety Code, National Fire Protection Association standards, or as directed by the agency having jurisdiction, provided that such agency shall not require a sprinkler system not required by the Fire Prevention Code, Life Safety Code, or National Fire Protection Association standards to be removed regardless of its condition. This section does not prohibit governmental entities from inspecting and enforcing firesafety codes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least once each year, each fire hydrant shall be opened fully and the water allowed to flow until all foreign materials have cleared the hydrant. The flow shall be maintained for not less than 1 minute.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a fire hydrant is made nonfunctional by the closing of a water supply valve, the valve must immediately be tagged with a red tag that is boldly marked “nonfunctional” and the local fire authority notified that the hydrant is nonfunctional.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 78-141; s. 25, ch. 2005-147; s. 9, ch. 2006-65; s. 2, ch. 2010-173; s. 53, ch. 2010-176.</History>
</Section>