<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.083" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sale or use of certain types of fire extinguishers prohibited; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to have for use any of the following types of fire extinguishers:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carbon tetrachloride;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chlorobromomethane;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dibromodifluoromethane (commonly known as Halon 1202);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dichlorodifluoromethane;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Azeotropic chloromethane;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">1,2 dibromo-2-chloro-1, 1,2 trifluoroethane;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">1,2 dibromo-2, 2-difluoroethane;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Methyl bromide;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ethylene dibromide;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hydrogen bromide;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Methylene bromide;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bromodifluoromethane;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other toxic or poisonous vaporizing liquid fire extinguishers using extinguishing agents determined by the State Fire Marshal to be unacceptably harmful; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inverting water fire extinguishers.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to offer for sale, sell, or give in this state any of the types of fire extinguishers listed in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, directly or through an agent, to sell, offer for sale, or give in this state any make, type, or model of fire extinguisher, either new or used, unless such make, type, or model of extinguisher has first been tested and is currently approved or listed by Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., Factory Mutual Laboratories, Inc., or another testing laboratory recognized by the State Fire Marshal as nationally recognized in accordance with procedures adopted by rule, taking into account the laboratory’s facilities, procedures, use of nationally recognized standards, and any other criteria reasonably calculated to reach an informed determination, and unless such extinguisher carries an Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., or manufacturer’s serial number. Such serial number shall be permanently stamped on the manufacturer’s identification and instruction plate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates any of the provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 70-417; s. 658, ch. 71-136; s. 2, ch. 78-141; s. 5, ch. 84-243; s. 18, ch. 89-233.</History></Section>