<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalty for violation of law, rule, or order to cease and desist or for failure to comply with corrective order.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this law, any order or rule of the State Fire Marshal, or any order to cease and desist or to correct conditions issued under this chapter commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, to intentionally or willfully:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Render a fire extinguisher or preengineered system required by statute or by rule inoperative except during such time as the extinguisher or preengineered system is being serviced, hydrotested, tested, repaired, or recharged, except pursuant to court order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obliterate the serial number on a fire extinguisher for purposes of falsifying service records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly service, recharge, repair, hydrotest, test, or inspect a fire extinguisher or preengineered system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the license or permit number of another person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold a permit and allow another person to use said permit number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use, or permit the use of, any license by any individual or organization other than the one to whom the license is issued.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pyrotechnic display” means a special effect created through the use of a pyrotechnic material or pyrotechnic device.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pyrotechnic device” means any device containing pyrotechnic materials and capable of producing a special effect.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pyrotechnic material” means a chemical mixture used to produce visible or audible effects by combustion, deflagration, or detonation when such chemical mixture consists predominantly of solids capable of producing a controlled, self-sustaining, and self-contained exothermic chemical reaction that results in heat, gas, sound, light, or a combination of such effects, without requiring external oxygen.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who initiates a pyrotechnic display within any structure commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, unless:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The structure has a fire protection system installed in compliance with s. 633.065.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of the structure has authorized in writing the pyrotechnic display.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local jurisdiction requires a permit for the use of a pyrotechnic display in an occupied structure, such permit has been obtained and all conditions of the permit complied with or, if the local jurisdiction does not require a permit for the use of a pyrotechnic display in an occupied structure, the person initiating the display has complied with National Fire Protection Association, Inc., Standard 1126, 2001 Edition, Standard for the Use of Pyrotechnics before a Proximate Audience.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall not be construed to preclude prosecution for a more general offense resulting from the same criminal transaction or episode. This subsection does not apply to the manufacture, distribution, sale at wholesale or retail, or seasonal sale of products regulated under chapter 791 if the products are not used in an occupied structure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 21847, 1943; s. 11, ch. 65-216; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 659, ch. 71-136; s. 7A, ch. 71-141; s. 3, ch. 78-141; s. 13, ch. 87-287; s. 22, ch. 89-233; s. 157, ch. 91-224; s. 6, ch. 98-170; s. 57, ch. 98-419; s. 3, ch. 2005-117.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 633.16.</Text></Note></Section>