<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.541" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contracting without certificate prohibited; violations; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any organization or individual to engage in the business of layout, fabrication, installation, inspection, alteration, repair, or service of a fire protection system, other than a preengineered system, act in the capacity of a fire protection contractor, or advertise itself as being a fire protection contractor without having been duly certified and holding a valid and existing certificate, except as hereinafter provided. The holder of a certificate used to qualify an organization must be a full-time employee of the qualified organization or business. A certificateholder who is employed by more than one fire protection contractor during the same period of time is deemed not to be a full-time employee of either contractor. The State Fire Marshal shall revoke, for a period of time determined by the State Fire Marshal, the certificate of a certificateholder who allows the use of the certificate to qualify a company of which the certificateholder is not a full-time employee. A contractor who maintains more than one place of business must employ a certificateholder at each location. Nothing in this subsection prohibits an employee acting on behalf of governmental entities from inspecting and enforcing firesafety codes, provided such employee is certified under s. 633.081.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fire protection contractor certified under this chapter may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into a written or oral agreement to authorize, or otherwise knowingly allow, a contractor who is not certified under this chapter to engage in the business of, or act in the capacity of, a fire protection contractor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply for or obtain a construction permit for fire protection work unless the fire protection contractor or the business organization qualified by the fire protection contractor has contracted to conduct the work specified in the application for the permit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this act or commits any of the acts constituting cause for disciplinary action as herein set forth is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the penalties provided in subsection (3), a fire protection contractor certified under this chapter who violates any provision of this section or who commits any act constituting cause for disciplinary action is subject to suspension or revocation of the certificate and administrative fines pursuant to s. 633.547.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 75-240; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 8, ch. 78-141; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-128; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 21, ch. 95-379.</History></Section>