<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.702" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts regarding alarm system contractors or certified unlimited electrical contractors; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person, directly or through an agent, to sell, offer for sale, or give any make, type, or model of fire alarm system, either new or used, unless such make, type, or model has been tested and is currently approved or listed by a nationally recognized testing laboratory.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for any fire alarm system contractor or certified unlimited electrical contractor to intentionally or willfully:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Render inoperative any fire alarm system which is required by the State Fire Marshal’s rules, except when the system is being serviced, tested, repaired, inspected, or improved.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly install, service, test, repair, improve, or inspect a fire alarm system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly combining or conspiring with any person by allowing one’s certificate to be used by any uncertified person with intent to evade the provisions of this act. When a licensee allows his or her license to be used by one or more companies without having any active participation in the operation or management of said companies, such act constitutes prima facie evidence of any intent to evade the provisions of this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for any person to intentionally or willfully install, service, test, repair, improve, or inspect a fire alarm system unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is the holder of a valid and current active license as a certified unlimited electrical contractor, as defined in part II of chapter 489;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is the holder of a valid and current active license as a licensed fire alarm contractor, as defined in part II of chapter 489;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is authorized to act as a fire alarm system agent pursuant to s. 489.5185; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person is exempt pursuant to s. 489.503.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 14, ch. 87-254; s. 71, ch. 91-110; s. 159, ch. 91-224; s. 450, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 2005-116; s. 31, ch. 2005-147.</History></Section>