<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Fire Safety Board; membership.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Fire Safety Board is created consisting of seven members who are citizens and residents of this state. One shall be the State Fire Marshal, or her or his designated appointee who shall be an administrative employee of the marshal; one shall be an administrative officer from a building department representing an incorporated municipality or a county; one shall be an administrative officer from a fire department representing an incorporated municipality or a county; two shall be contractors licensed pursuant to s. 633.521; and two shall be persons who hold valid licenses under s. 633.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for appointment, each contractor shall personally hold a current certificate of competency and a current license issued by the State Fire Marshal, together with an unexpired occupational license to operate as a contractor issued by an incorporated municipality or a county; be actively engaged in such business and have been so engaged for a period of not less than 5 consecutive years before the date of her or his appointment; and be a citizen and resident of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for appointment, each fire equipment dealer shall personally hold a current Class A, B, or C and Class D fire equipment dealer license issued by the State Fire Marshal, together with an unexpired occupational license to operate as a fire equipment dealer issued by an incorporated municipality or a county; shall be actively engaged in such business and have been so engaged for a period of not less than 5 consecutive years before the date of appointment; and shall be a citizen and resident of this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal’s term on the board, or that of her or his designated administrative employee, shall coincide with the State Fire Marshal’s term of office. Of the other six members of the board, one member shall be appointed for a term of 1 year, one member for a term of 2 years, two members for terms of 3 years, and two members for terms of 4 years. All terms expire on June 30 of the last year of the term. Effective July 1, 1997, as the term of each member expires, the State Fire Marshal shall appoint a member to fill the vacancy for a term of 4 years. The State Fire Marshal may remove any appointed member for cause. A vacancy in the membership of the board for any cause shall be filled by appointment by the State Fire Marshal for the balance of the unexpired term.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 6, 7, ch. 75-240; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 81-264; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 13, ch. 84-243; ss. 1, 3, ch. 87-181; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 16, ch. 93-276; s. 1, ch. 97-19; s. 440, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 97-124.</History></Section>