<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of State Fire Marshal; powers, duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish uniform minimum standards for the employment and training of firefighters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish minimum curriculum requirements for schools operated by or for any employing agency for the specific purpose of training firefighter recruits or firefighters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve institutions, instructors, and facilities for school operation by or for any employing agency for the specific purpose of training firefighters and firefighter recruits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify, by rule, standards for the approval, denial of approval, probation, and revocation of approval of institutions, instructors, and facilities for training firefighters and firefighter recruits; including a rule that an instructor must complete 40 hours of continuing education every 3 years in order to maintain the approval of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue certificates of competency to persons who, by reason of experience and completion of basic inservice training, advanced education, or specialized training, are especially qualified for particular aspects or classes of firefighter duties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish minimum training qualifications for persons serving as firesafety coordinators for their respective departments of state government and certify all persons who satisfy such qualifications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a uniform lesson plan to be followed by firesafety instructors in the training of state employees in firesafety and emergency evacuation procedures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have complete jurisdiction over, and complete management and control of, the Florida State Fire College and be invested with full power and authority to make all rules and regulations necessary for the governance of said institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a superintendent of the Florida State Fire College and such other instructors, experimental helpers, and laborers as may be necessary and remove the same as in its judgment and discretion may be best, fix their compensation, and provide for their payment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have full management, possession, and control of the lands, buildings, structures, and property belonging to the Florida State Fire College.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the courses of study and curriculum of the Florida State Fire College.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make rules and regulations for the admission of trainees to the Florida State Fire College.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Visit and inspect the Florida State Fire College and every department thereof and provide for the proper keeping of accounts and records thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make and prepare all necessary budgets of expenditures for the enlargement, proper furnishing, maintenance, support, and conduct of the Florida State Fire College.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Select and purchase all property, furniture, fixtures, and paraphernalia necessary for the Florida State Fire College.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Build, construct, change, enlarge, repair, and maintain any and all buildings or structures of the Florida State Fire College that may at any time be necessary for said institution and purchase and acquire all lands and property necessary for same, of every nature and description whatsoever.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Care for and maintain the Florida State Fire College and do and perform every other matter or thing requisite to the proper management, maintenance, support, and control of said institution, necessary or requisite to carry out fully the purpose of this act and for raising it to, and maintaining it at, the proper efficiency and standard as required in and by the provisions of ss. 633.43-633.49.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division, subject to the limitations and restrictions elsewhere herein imposed, may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules and regulations for the administration of ss. 633.30-633.49 pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt a seal and alter the same at its pleasure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue and be sued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire any real or personal property by purchase, gift, or donation, and have water rights.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise the right of eminent domain to acquire any property and lands necessary to the establishment, operation, and expansion of the Florida State Fire College.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make contracts and execute necessary or convenient instruments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undertake by contract or contracts, or by its own agent and employees, and otherwise than by contract, any project or projects, and operate and maintain such projects.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept grants of money, materials, or property of any kind from a federal agency, private agency, county, city, town, corporation, partnership, or individual upon such terms and conditions as the grantor may impose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform all acts and do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers granted herein and the purposes of ss. 633.30-633.49.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The title to all property referred to in ss. 633.43-633.49, however acquired, shall be vested in the department and shall only be transferred and conveyed by it.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 9, ch. 25097, 1949; ss. 18, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 9, ch. 75-151; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 3, ch. 82-189; s. 27, ch. 89-233; s. 8, ch. 90-359; s. 12, ch. 99-205; s. 26, ch. 2000-157; s. 1406, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 163.534.</Text></Note></Section>