<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.162" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fire suppression system contractors; disciplinary action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The violation of any provision of this chapter or any rule adopted and promulgated pursuant hereto or the failure or refusal to comply with any notice or order to correct a violation or any cease and desist order by any person who possesses a license or permit issued pursuant to s. 633.061 is cause for denial, nonrenewal, revocation, or suspension of such license or permit by the State Fire Marshal after such officer has determined that the person is guilty of such violation. An order of suspension shall state the period of time of such suspension, which period may not be in excess of 2 years from the date of such order. An order of revocation may be entered for a period not exceeding 5 years. Such orders shall effect suspension or revocation of all licenses or permits then held by the person, and during such period of time no license or permit shall be issued to such person. During the suspension or revocation of any license or permit, the former licensee or permittee shall not engage in or attempt or profess to engage in any transaction or business for which a license or permit is required under this chapter or directly or indirectly own, control, or be employed in any manner by any firm, business, or corporation for which a license or permit under this chapter is required. If, during the period between the beginning of proceedings and the entry of an order of suspension or revocation by the State Fire Marshal, a new license or permit has been issued to the person so charged, the order of suspension or revocation shall operate to suspend or revoke such new license or permit held by such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not, so long as the revocation or suspension remains in effect, grant any new license or permit for the establishment of any new firm, business, or corporation of any person or qualifier that has or will have the same or similar management, ownership, control, employees, permittees, or licensees, or will use a same or similar name as a previously revoked or suspended firm, business, corporation, person, or qualifier.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal may deny, nonrenew, suspend, or revoke the license or permit of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, or corporation the license of which under this chapter has been suspended or revoked;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any firm or corporation if an officer, qualifier, director, stockholder, owner, or person interested directly or indirectly in the firm or corporation has had his or her license or permit under this chapter suspended or revoked; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is or has been an officer, qualifier, director, stockholder, or owner of a firm or corporation, or who was interested directly or indirectly in a firm or corporation, the license or permit of which has been suspended or revoked under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it is cause for denial, nonrenewal, revocation, or suspension of a license or permit by the State Fire Marshal if she or he determines that the licensee or permittee has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rendered inoperative a fire extinguisher or preengineered system required by statute or by rule, except during such time as the extinguisher or preengineered system is being inspected, serviced, repaired, hydrotested, or recharged, or except pursuant to court order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Falsified any record required to be maintained by this chapter or rules adopted pursuant hereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly serviced, recharged, repaired, hydrotested, tested, or inspected a fire extinguisher or preengineered system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While holding a permit or license, allowed another person to use the permit number or license number, or used a license number or permit number other than her or his valid license number or permit number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to provide proof of insurance to the State Fire Marshal or failed to maintain in force the insurance coverage required by s. 633.061.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to obtain, retain, or maintain one or more of the qualifications for a license or permit as specified in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Made a material misstatement, misrepresentation, or committed a fraud in obtaining or attempting to obtain a license or permit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to notify the State Fire Marshal, in writing, within 30 days after a change of residence, principal business address, or name.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, the department shall not issue a new license or permit if it finds that the circumstance or circumstances for which the license or permit was previously revoked or suspended still exist or are likely to recur.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 71-141; s. 21, ch. 78-95; s. 8, ch. 84-243; s. 12, ch. 87-287; s. 20, ch. 89-233; s. 7, ch. 93-276; s. 430, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 98-170; s. 56, ch. 98-419; s. 1399, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>