<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.809" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Firefighter employers whose firefighter employees have a high frequency of work-related injuries.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall develop a means by which the division may identify individual firefighter employers whose firefighter employees have a high frequency or severity of work-related injuries. The division shall carry out safety inspections of the facilities and operations of those firefighter employers in order to assist them in reducing the frequency and severity of work-related injuries. The division shall develop safety and health programs for those firefighter employers. Insurers shall distribute such safety and health programs to the firefighter employers so identified by the division. Those firefighter employers identified by the division as having a high frequency or severity of work-related injuries shall implement a safety and health program developed by the division. The division shall carry out safety inspections of those firefighter employers so identified to ensure compliance with the safety and health program and to assist such firefighter employers in reducing the number of work-related injuries. The division may not assess penalties as a result of such inspections, except as provided by s. 633.813. Copies of any report made as the result of such an inspection shall be provided to the firefighter employer and its insurer. Firefighter employers may submit their own safety and health programs to the division for approval in lieu of using the safety and health program developed by the division. The division shall promptly review the program submitted and approve or disapprove the program within 60 days or such program shall be deemed approved. Upon approval by the division, the program shall be implemented by the firefighter employer. If the program is not approved or if a program is not submitted, the firefighter employer shall implement the program developed by the division. The division shall adopt rules setting forth the criteria for safety and health programs, as such rules relate to this section.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2002-404.</History></Section>