<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Uniform firesafety standards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature hereby determines that to protect the public health, safety, and welfare it is necessary to provide for firesafety standards governing the construction and utilization of certain buildings and structures. The Legislature further determines that certain buildings or structures, due to their specialized use or to the special characteristics of the person utilizing or occupying these buildings or structures, should be subject to firesafety standards reflecting these special needs as may be appropriate.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish uniform firesafety standards that apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All new, existing, and proposed state-owned and state-leased buildings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All new, existing, and proposed hospitals, nursing homes, assisted living facilities, adult family-care homes, correctional facilities, public schools, transient public lodging establishments, public food service establishments, elevators, migrant labor camps, mobile home parks, lodging parks, recreational vehicle parks, recreational camps, residential and nonresidential child care facilities, facilities for the developmentally disabled, motion picture and television special effects productions, tunnels, and self-service gasoline stations, of which standards the State Fire Marshal is the final administrative interpreting authority.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In the event there is a dispute between the owners of the buildings specified in paragraph (b) and a local authority requiring a more stringent uniform firesafety standard for sprinkler systems, the State Fire Marshal shall be the final administrative interpreting authority and the State Fire Marshal’s interpretation regarding the uniform firesafety standards shall be considered final agency action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to the uniform firesafety standards, the department shall develop uniform statewide standards which are reasonably prudent with respect to protecting life, safety, and property and which take into consideration the characteristics of the people utilizing the subject buildings and structures and other hazards associated with the subject buildings and structures throughout the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local authority may not require more stringent uniform firesafety standards with respect to buildings or structures subject to such standards except as provided in paragraph (c). A local authority may, on a case-by-case basis, in order to meet special situations arising from historic, geographic, or unusual conditions, with respect to a building or structure which is subject to the uniform firesafety standards, authorize equivalent alternative standards for such building or structure; however, the alternative requirements shall not result in a level of protection to life, safety, or property less stringent than the applicable uniform firesafety standards. All such local authorities shall enforce, within their firesafety jurisdiction, the uniform firesafety standards for those buildings specified in paragraph (1)(b) and the minimum firesafety standards adopted pursuant to s. 394.879.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local authority may require more stringent uniform firesafety standards for sprinkler systems in buildings specified in paragraph (b), for which the construction contract is let after January 1, 1994, if the following conditions are met:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local authority has adopted, by ordinance, a fire service facilities and operation plan that outlines goals and objectives for related equipment, personnel, and capital improvement needs of the local authority for the next 5 years.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local authority has adopted, by ordinance, a provision requiring proportionate reductions in, or rebate or waivers of, impact or other fees or assessments levied on buildings that are built or modified in compliance with the more stringent sprinkler standards.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local authority has adopted, by ordinance, a plan that requires buildings specified in paragraph (b) to be equipped with an automatic sprinkler system installed in compliance with the provisions prescribed in standards as established by the National Fire Protection Association and adopted by the State Fire Marshal.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In the event there is a dispute between the owners of the buildings specified in paragraph (b) and a local authority requiring a more stringent uniform firesafety standard for sprinkler systems, the State Fire Marshal shall be the final administrative interpreting authority and the State Fire Marshal’s interpretation regarding the uniform firesafety standards shall be considered final agency action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In establishing the uniform firesafety standards and the minimum firesafety standards, as required by s. 394.879, the department shall consider types of construction materials and their flame spread and smoke characteristics, occupancy levels, means of egress, special hazard protection, smoke barriers, interior finish, and fire protection systems or equipment and occupancy features necessary to minimize danger to life from fire, smoke, fumes, or panic. In considering these factors, the department shall develop minimum standards which are reasonably prudent with respect to protecting life, safety, and property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, each nursing home licensed under part II of chapter 400 shall be protected throughout by an approved, supervised automatic sprinkler system in accordance with s. 9 of National Fire Protection Association, Inc., Life Safety Code, no later than December 31, 2010. A nursing home licensee shall submit complete sprinkler construction documents to the Agency for Health Care Administration for review by December 31, 2008, and the licensee must gain final approval to start construction from the agency by June 30, 2009. The agency shall grant a 6-month extension to a nursing home licensee if the completion and submission of the sprinkler construction documents are contingent upon the approval of the application for the loan guarantee program authorized under s. 633.0245. In such case, the agency may extend the deadline for final approval to begin construction beyond June 30, 2009, but the deadline may not be extended beyond December 31, 2009.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may grant up to two 1-year extensions of the time limits for compliance in subparagraph (a)2. if the division determines that the nursing home has been prevented from complying for reasons beyond its control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to adopt any rule necessary for the implementation and enforcement of this subsection. The division shall enforce this subsection in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, and any nursing home licensed under part II of chapter 400 that is in violation of this subsection may be subject to administrative sanctions by the division pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adjustments shall be made to the provider Medicaid rate to allow reimbursement over a 5-year period for Medicaid’s portion of the costs incurred to meet the requirements of this subsection. Funding for this adjustment shall come from existing nursing home appropriations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 87-287; s. 2, ch. 90-359; s. 29, ch. 93-150; s. 2, ch. 93-276; s. 44, ch. 95-210; s. 7, ch. 95-379; s. 4, ch. 99-179; s. 3, ch. 2002-287; s. 1392, ch. 2003-261; s. 2, ch. 2005-234; s. 2, ch. 2008-192.</History></Section>