<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fire and Emergency Incident Information Reporting Program; duties; fire reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fire and Emergency Incident Information Reporting Program is created within the Division of State Fire Marshal. The program shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and maintain an electronic communication system capable of transmitting fire and emergency incident information to and between fire protection agencies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate a Fire and Emergency Incident Information Reporting System that shall be responsible for:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receiving fire and emergency incident information from fire protection agencies.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preparing and disseminating annual reports to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, fire protection agencies, and, upon request, the public. Each report shall include, but not be limited to, the information listed in the National Fire Incident Reporting System.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, providing other states and federal agencies with fire and emergency incident data of this state.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules to effectively and efficiently implement, administer, manage, maintain, and use the Fire and Emergency Incident Information Reporting Program. The rules shall be considered minimum requirements and shall not preclude a fire protection agency from implementing its own requirements which shall not conflict with the rules of the Division of State Fire Marshal.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By rule, establish procedures and a format for each fire protection agency to voluntarily monitor its records and submit reports to the program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish an electronic information database which is accessible and searchable by fire protection agencies.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of State Fire Marshal shall consult with the Florida Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and the State Surgeon General of the Department of Health to coordinate data, ensure accuracy of the data, and limit duplication of efforts in data collection, analysis, and reporting.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fire and Emergency Incident Information System Technical Advisory Panel is created within the Division of State Fire Marshal. The panel shall advise, review, and recommend to the State Fire Marshal with respect to the requirements of this section. The membership of the panel shall consist of the following 15 members:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The current 13 members of the Firefighters Employment, Standards, and Training Council as established in s. 633.31.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member from the Florida Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, appointed by the director of the Florida Forest Service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member from the Department of Health, appointed by the State Surgeon General.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this section, the term “fire protection agency” shall be defined by rule by the Division of State Fire Marshal.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-117; s. 75, ch. 2012-7; s. 112, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>