<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standard service tag required on all fire extinguishers and preengineered systems; serial number required on all portable fire extinguishers; standard inspection tags required on all fire protection systems.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal shall adopt by rule specifications as to the size, shape, color, and information and data contained thereon of service tags to be attached to all fire extinguishers and preengineered systems required by statute or by rule, whether they be portable, stationary, or on wheels when they are placed in service, installed, serviced, repaired, tested, recharged, or inspected. Fire extinguishers may be tagged only after meeting all standards as set forth by this chapter, the standards of the National Fire Protection Association, and manufacturer’s specifications. Preengineered systems may be tagged only after a system has been inspected, serviced, installed, repaired, tested, recharged, and hydrotested in compliance with this chapter, the standards of the National Fire Protection Association, and the manufacturer’s specifications, and after a report, as specified by rule, has been completed in detail, indicating any and all deficiencies or deviations from the manufacturer’s specifications and the standards of the National Fire Protection Association. A copy of the inspection report shall be provided to the owner at the time of inspection, and, if a system is found to be in violation of this chapter, the manufacturer’s specifications, or the standards of the National Fire Protection Association, a copy shall be forwarded to the state or local authority having jurisdiction within 30 days from the date of service. It shall be unlawful to place in service, service, test, repair, inspect, install, hydrotest, or recharge any fire extinguisher or preengineered system without attaching one of these tags completed in detail, including the actual month work was performed, or to use a tag not meeting the specifications set forth by the State Fire Marshal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All portable fire extinguishers required by statute or by rule shall be listed by Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., or approved by Factory Mutual Laboratories, Inc., or listed by a nationally recognized testing laboratory in accordance with procedures adopted pursuant to s. 633.083(2), and carry an Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., or manufacturer’s serial number. These listings, approvals, and serial numbers may be stamped on the manufacturer’s identification and instructions plate or on a separate Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., or Factory Mutual Laboratories, Inc., plate soldered or attached to the extinguisher shell in some permanent manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal shall adopt by rule specifications as to the size, shape, color, information, and data contained thereon of inspection tags to be attached to all types of fire protection systems and information required on an inspection report of such an inspection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 65-216; s. 4, ch. 67-78; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 71-141; s. 17, ch. 89-233; s. 38, ch. 95-211; s. 2, ch. 97-124; s. 4, ch. 98-170; s. 55, ch. 98-419; s. 24, ch. 2005-147.</History></Section>