<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State Fire Marshal to keep records of fires; reports of agents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal shall keep in her or his office a record of all fires occurring in this state upon which she or he had caused an investigation to be made and all facts concerning the same. These records, obtained or prepared by the State Fire Marshal pursuant to her or his investigation, include documents, papers, letters, maps, diagrams, tapes, photographs, films, sound recordings, and evidence. These records are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until the investigation is completed or ceases to be active. For purposes of this section, an investigation is considered “active” while such investigation is being conducted by the department with a reasonable, good faith belief that it may lead to the filing of administrative, civil, or criminal proceedings. An investigation does not cease to be active if the department is proceeding with reasonable dispatch, and there is a good faith belief that action may be initiated by the department or other administrative or law enforcement agency. Further, these documents, papers, letters, maps, diagrams, tapes, photographs, films, sound recordings, and evidence relative to the subject of an investigation shall not be subject to subpoena until the investigation is completed or ceases to be active, unless the State Fire Marshal consents. These records shall be made daily from the reports furnished the State Fire Marshal by her or his agents or others. Whenever the State Fire Marshal releases an investigative report, any person requesting a copy of the report shall pay in advance, and the State Fire Marshal shall collect in advance, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 624.501(19)(a) and (b), a fee of $10 for the copy of the report, which fee shall be deposited into the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund. The State Fire Marshal may release the report without charge to any state attorney or to any law enforcement agency or fire department assisting in the investigation.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 20671, 1941; s. 9, ch. 65-216; s. 4, ch. 67-78; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 70-299; s. 1, ch. 78-149; s. 2, ch. 85-323; s. 202, ch. 90-363; s. 1, ch. 93-112; s. 6, ch. 93-276; s. 13, ch. 95-379; s. 391, ch. 96-406; s. 1742, ch. 97-102; s. 99, ch. 2002-1; s. 1397, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 633.09.</Text></Note></Section>