<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0633.72" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Fire Code Advisory Council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the department the Florida Fire Code Advisory Council with 11 members appointed by the State Fire Marshal. The council shall advise and recommend to the State Fire Marshal changes to and interpretation of the uniform firesafety standards adopted under s. 633.022, the Florida Fire Prevention Code, and those portions of the Florida Fire Prevention Code that have the effect of conflicting with building construction standards that are adopted pursuant to ss. 633.0215 and 633.022. The members of the council shall represent the following groups and professions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be the State Fire Marshal, or his or her designated appointee who shall be an administrative employee of the marshal;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be an administrative officer from a fire department representing a municipality or a county selected from a list of persons submitted by the Florida Fire Chiefs Association;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be an architect licensed in the state selected from a list of persons submitted by the Florida Association/American Institute of Architects;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be an engineer with fire protection design experience registered to practice in the state selected from a list of persons submitted by the Florida Engineering Society;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be an administrative officer from a building department of a county or municipality selected from a list of persons submitted by the Building Officials Association of Florida;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be a contractor licensed in the state selected from a list submitted by the Florida Home Builders Association;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be a Florida certified firefighter selected from a list submitted by the Florida Professional Firefighters’ Association;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be a Florida certified municipal fire inspector selected from a list submitted by the Florida Fire Marshal’s Association;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be selected from a list submitted by the Department of Education;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be selected from a list submitted by the Chancellor of the State University System; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be representative of the general public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal and the Florida Building Commission shall coordinate efforts to provide consistency between the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code and the Life Safety Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council and Florida Building Commission shall cooperate through joint representation and coordination of codes and standards to resolve conflicts in their development, updating, and interpretation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each appointee shall serve a 4-year term. No member shall serve more than two consecutive terms. No member of the council shall be paid a salary as such member, but each shall receive travel and expense reimbursement as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 17, 18, ch. 87-287; s. 24, ch. 88-149; ss. 4, 5, ch. 91-429; s. 451, ch. 97-102; s. 61, ch. 98-287; s. 50, ch. 99-3; s. 106, ch. 2000-141; s. 58, ch. 2010-176.</History>
</Section>