<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Violations; orders to cease and desist, correct hazardous conditions, preclude occupancy, or vacate; enforcement; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is determined by the department that a violation specified in this subsection exists, the State Fire Marshal or her or his deputy may issue and deliver to the person committing the violation an order to cease and desist from such violation, to correct any hazardous condition, to preclude occupancy of the affected building or structure, or to vacate the premises of the affected building or structure. Such violations are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as set forth in paragraph (b), a violation of any provision of this chapter, of any rule adopted pursuant thereto, of any applicable uniform firesafety standard adopted pursuant to s. 633.022 which is not adequately addressed by any alternative requirements adopted on a local level, or of any minimum firesafety standard adopted pursuant to s. 394.879.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A substantial violation of an applicable minimum firesafety standard adopted pursuant to s. 633.025 which is not reasonably addressed by any alternative requirement imposed at the local level, or an unreasonable interpretation of an applicable minimum firesafety standard, and which violation or interpretation clearly constitutes a danger to lifesafety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A building or structure which is in a dilapidated condition and as a result thereof creates a danger to life, safety, or property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A building or structure which contains explosive matter or flammable liquids or gases constituting a danger to life, safety, or property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the conduct of a firesafety inspection authorized by ss. 633.081 and 633.085, it is determined that a violation described in this section exists which poses an immediate danger to the public health, safety, or welfare, the State Fire Marshal may issue an order to vacate the building in question, which order shall be immediately effective and shall be an immediate final order under s. 120.569(2)(n). With respect to a facility under the jurisdiction of a district school board or community college board of trustees, the order to vacate shall be issued jointly by the district superintendent or college president and the State Fire Marshal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal may seek an injunction in the circuit court of the county in which the building is located to enforce an order issued pursuant to this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates or fails to comply with any order under subsection (1) or subsection (2) is guilty of a misdemeanor, punishable as provided in s. 633.171.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 65-216; s. 4, ch. 67-78; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 71-141; s. 21, ch. 78-95; s. 7, ch. 84-243; s. 11, ch. 87-287; s. 14, ch. 95-379; s. 276, ch. 96-410; s. 1743, ch. 97-102; s. 49, ch. 99-3; s. 1398, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>