<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.551" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County and municipal powers; effect of ch. 75-240.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this act limits the power of a municipality or county to regulate the quality and character of work performed by contractors through a system of permits, fees, and inspections which are designed to secure compliance with, and aid in the implementation of, state and local building laws or to enforce other local laws for the protection of the public health and safety.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this act limits the power of a municipality or county to adopt any system of permits requiring submission to and approval by the municipality or county of plans and specifications for work to be performed by contractors before commencement of the work, except that no municipality or county shall require a fire protection system contractor’s shop drawings to be sealed by a professional engineer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any official authorized to issue building or other related permits shall ascertain that the applicant contractor is duly certified before issuing the permit. The evidence shall consist only of the exhibition to him or her of current evidence of certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal shall inform each county and municipal building department, prior to November 1 of each year, of the names of the certified contractors and the type of certificate held.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 75-240; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 8, ch. 78-141; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-128; s. 34, ch. 89-233; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 449, ch. 97-102; s. 3, ch. 98-35.</History></Section>