<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.808" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigate and prescribe by rule what safety devices, safeguards, or other means of protection must be adopted for the prevention of accidents in every firefighter employee place of employment or at any fire scene; determine what suitable devices, safeguards, or other means of protection for the prevention of occupational diseases must be adopted or followed in any or all such firefighter places of employment or at any fire scene; and adopt reasonable rules for the prevention of accidents, the safety, protection, and security of firefighter employees engaged in interior firefighting, and the prevention of occupational diseases.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ascertain, fix, and order such reasonable standards and rules for the construction, repair, and maintenance of firefighter employee places of employment as shall render them safe. Such rules and standards shall be adopted in accordance with chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist firefighter employers in the development and implementation of firefighter employee safety training programs by contracting with professional safety organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules prescribing recordkeeping responsibilities for firefighter employers, which may include maintaining a log and summary of occupational injuries, diseases, and illnesses, for producing on request a notice of injury and firefighter employee accident investigation records, and prescribing a retention schedule for such records.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2002-404.</History></Section>