<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.547" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary action; fire protection system contractors; grounds for denial, nonrenewal, suspension, or revocation of certificate or permit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal shall investigate the alleged illegal action of any fire protection system contractor or permittee certified under this chapter and hold hearings pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute cause for disciplinary action:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of this chapter or of any rule adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of the applicable building codes or laws of this state or any municipality or county thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diversion of funds or property received for prosecution or completion of a specified construction project or operation when, as a result of the diversion, the contractor is, or will be, unable to fulfill the terms of her or his obligation or contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary action by any municipality or county, which action shall be reviewed by the State Fire Marshal before taking any disciplinary action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to supervise the installation of the fire protection system covered by the building permit signed by the contractor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rendering a fire protection system, standpipe system, or underground water supply main connecting to the system inoperative except when the fire protection system, standpipe system, or underground water supply main is being inspected, serviced, tested, or repaired, or except pursuant to court order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly servicing, repairing, testing, or inspecting a fire protection, standpipe system, or underground water supply main connecting to the system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to provide proof of insurance to the State Fire Marshal or failing to maintain in force the insurance coverage required by s. 633.521.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to obtain, retain, or maintain one or more of the qualifications for a certificate as specified in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a material misstatement, misrepresentation, or committing a fraud in obtaining or attempting to obtain a certificate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to notify the State Fire Marshal, in writing, within 30 days after a change of residence address, principal business address, or name.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal is authorized to take the following disciplinary action:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">She or he may suspend the certificateholder for a period not to exceed 2 years from all operations as a contractor during the period fixed by the State Fire Marshal, but she or he may permit the certificateholder to complete any contracts then incomplete.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">She or he may revoke a certificate for a period not to exceed 5 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the suspension or revocation of the certificate, the former certificateholder shall not engage in or attempt to profess to engage in any transaction or business for which a certificate is required under this chapter or directly or indirectly own, control, or be employed in any manner by any firm or corporation for which a certificate under this chapter is required. The department shall not, so long as the revocation or suspension remains in effect, grant any new certificate for the establishment of any new firm, business, or corporation of any person that has or will have the same or similar management, ownership, control, or employees or that will use a same or similar name as a previously revoked or suspended firm, business, or corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal may deny, suspend, or revoke the certificate of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, or corporation the certificate of which under this chapter has been suspended or revoked.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any firm or corporation if an officer, director, stockholder, owner, or person interested directly or indirectly has had his or her certificate under this chapter suspended or revoked.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is or has been an officer, director, stockholder, or owner of a firm or corporation, or who was interested directly or indirectly in a corporation, the certificate of which has been suspended or revoked under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lapse or suspension of a certificate by operation of law or by order of the State Fire Marshal or a court or its voluntary surrender by a certificateholder does not deprive the State Fire Marshal of jurisdiction to investigate or act in disciplinary proceedings against the certificateholder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a petition in bankruptcy, either voluntary or involuntary, or the making of a composition of creditors or the appointment of a receiver for the business of the certificateholder may be considered by the State Fire Marshal as just cause for suspension of a certificate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 75-240; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 8, ch. 78-141; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 19, ch. 84-243; ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-128; s. 33, ch. 89-233; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 20, ch. 93-276; s. 448, ch. 97-102; s. 7, ch. 98-170; s. 58, ch. 98-419; s. 30, ch. 2005-147.</History></Section>