<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigation of fraudulent insurance claims and crimes; immunity of insurance companies supplying information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal or an agent appointed pursuant to s. 633.02, any law enforcement officer as defined in s. 111.065, any law enforcement officer of a federal agency, or any fire department official who is engaged in the investigation of a fire loss may request any insurance company or its agent, adjuster, employee, or attorney, investigating a claim under an insurance policy or contract with respect to a fire to release any information whatsoever in the possession of the insurance company or its agent, adjuster, employee, or attorney relative to a loss from that fire. The insurance company shall release the available information to and cooperate with any official authorized to request such information pursuant to this section. The information shall include, but shall not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurance policy relevant to a loss under investigation and any application for such a policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any policy premium payment records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The records, reports, and all material pertaining to any previous claims made by the insured with the reporting company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material relating to the investigation of the loss, including statements of any person, proof of loss, and other relevant evidence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Memoranda, notes, and correspondence relating to the investigation of the loss in the possession of the insurance company or its agents, adjusters, employees, or attorneys.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an insurance company has reason to suspect that a fire loss to its insured’s real or personal property was caused by incendiary means, the company shall notify the State Fire Marshal and shall furnish her or him with all material acquired by the company during the course of its investigation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of fraud, bad faith, or malice, no representative of an insurance company or of the National Insurance Crime Bureau employed to adjust or investigate losses caused by fire shall be liable for damages in a civil action for furnishing information concerning fires suspected to be other than accidental to investigators employed by other insurance companies or the National Insurance Crime Bureau.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No insurance company or person who furnishes information on its behalf shall be liable for damages in a civil action or subject to criminal prosecution for any oral or written statement made or any other action taken that is necessary and required by the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At such time as the release of the investigative records is required by law, the official or agency in possession of such records shall provide written notice to the insurance company providing the information and to all parties, at least 10 days prior to releasing such records. Official, departmental, or agency personnel may discuss such matters with other official, departmental, or agency personnel, and any insurance company complying with this section, and may share such information, if such discussion is necessary to enable the orderly and efficient conduct of the investigation. These discussions are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 286.011.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actions of an insurance company or of its agents, employees, adjusters, or attorneys, in complying with the statutory obligation of this section shall in no way be construed by a court as a waiver or abandonment of any privilege or confidentiality of attorney work product, attorney-client communication, or such other privilege or immunity as is provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any official described in subsection (1) may be required to testify as to any information in her or his possession regarding an insurance loss in any civil action in which any person seeks recovery under a policy against an insurance company for an insurance loss, subject to the provisions of subsection (6).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may intentionally refuse to release any information requested pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully violates the provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 78-149; s. 1, ch. 83-96; s. 3, ch. 88-222; s. 158, ch. 91-224; s. 2, ch. 93-112; s. 15, ch. 95-379; s. 392, ch. 96-406; s. 1744, ch. 97-102; s. 3, ch. 97-124.</History></Section>