<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for installation, inspection, and maintenance of fire suppression equipment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements for installation of fire extinguishers and preengineered systems are as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fire equipment dealers shall be licensed under s. 633.061.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Equipment supplied shall be listed by a nationally recognized testing laboratory, such as Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., or Factory Mutual Laboratories, Inc. Equipment supplied for new installations or alterations of existing systems must be currently listed as described in this section. The State Fire Marshal shall adopt by rule procedures for determining whether a laboratory is nationally recognized, taking into account the laboratory’s facilities, procedures, use of nationally recognized standards, and any other criteria reasonably calculated to reach an informed determination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Equipment shall be installed in accordance with the applicable standards of the National Fire Protection Association and the manufacturer’s drawings and specifications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each piece of equipment supplied shall be guaranteed for a period of 1 year against defects in material or operation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fire equipment dealer shall furnish the consumer with: the manufacturer’s descriptive literature, including the specifications and maintenance requirements as approved by the nationally recognized testing laboratory; the operating instructions for all equipment installed; the mechanical drawings and specifications for proper installation and use of equipment; and a diagram of the final installation, if applicable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Equipment shall be inspected, serviced, and maintained in accordance with the manufacturer’s maintenance procedures and with the applicable National Fire Protection Association standards.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 75-240; s. 2, ch. 80-342; s. 3, ch. 84-243; s. 16, ch. 89-233; s. 4, ch. 91-189; s. 3, ch. 98-170; s. 54, ch. 98-419.</History></Section>