<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0633.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Firefighters Employment, Standards, and Training Council.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the department a Firefighters Employment, Standards, and Training Council of 13 members. Two members shall be fire chiefs appointed by the Florida Fire Chiefs Association, two members shall be firefighters who are not officers, appointed by the Florida Professional Firefighters Association, two members shall be firefighter officers who are not fire chiefs, appointed by the State Fire Marshal, one member appointed by the Florida League of Cities, one member appointed by the Florida Association of Counties, one member appointed by the Florida Association of Special Districts, one member appointed by the Florida Fire Marshal’s Association, and one member appointed by the State Fire Marshal, and one member shall be a director or instructor of a state-certified firefighting training facility appointed by the State Fire Marshal. To be eligible for appointment as a fire chief member, firefighter officer member, firefighter member, or a director or instructor of a state-certified firefighting facility, a person shall have had at least 4 years’ experience in the firefighting profession. The remaining member, who shall be appointed by the State Fire Marshal, shall not be a member or representative of the firefighting profession or of any local government. Members shall serve only as long as they continue to meet the criteria under which they were appointed, or unless a member has failed to appear at three consecutive and properly noticed meetings unless excused by the chair.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members shall be appointed for 4-year terms and in no event shall a member serve more than two consecutive terms. Any vacancy shall be filled in the manner of the original appointment for the remaining time of the term.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal, in making her or his appointments, shall take into consideration representation by geography, population, and other relevant factors, in order that the membership on the council will be apportioned to give representation to the state at large rather than to a particular area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Membership on the council shall not disqualify a member from holding any other public office or being employed by a public entity, except that no member of the Legislature shall serve on the council.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 70-110; ss. 1, 3, ch. 75-151; s. 3, ch. 77-107; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 1, 3, 4, ch. 81-70; s. 1, ch. 82-46; ss. 1, 2, ch. 87-180; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 10, ch. 93-276; s. 433, ch. 97-102; s. 16, ch. 2002-404; s. 1401, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 163.471.</Text></Note></Section>