<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition and appraisal of property seized under this chapter.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every peace officer, other than the sheriff, seizing property pursuant to the provisions of ss. 849.36-849.46 shall forthwith make return of the seizure thereof and deliver the said property to the sheriff of the county wherein the same was seized. The said return to the sheriff shall describe the property seized and give in detail the facts and circumstances under which the same was seized and state in full the reason why the seizing officer knew, or was led to believe, that the said property was being used for or in connection with a violation of the statutes and laws of this state prohibiting lotteries and gambling in this state. The said return shall contain the names of all persons, firms and corporations known to the seizing officer to be interested in the seized property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When property is seized by the sheriff pursuant to this chapter, or when property seized by another is delivered to the sheriff as aforesaid, the sheriff shall forthwith fix the approximate value thereof and make return thereof to the clerk of the circuit court as hereinafter provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The return of the sheriff aforesaid shall contain a schedule of the property seized describing the same in reasonable detail and give in detail the facts and circumstances under which it was seized and state in full the reason why the seizing officer knew or was led to believe that the property was being used for or in connection with a violation of the statutes and laws of this state prohibiting lotteries or gambling in this state; and a statement of the names of all persons, firms and corporations known to the sheriff to be interested in the seized property; and in cases where the said property was seized by another the sheriff shall attach to his or her said return, as an exhibit thereto, the return of the seizing officer to him or her.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff shall hold the said property seized pending its disposal by the court as hereinafter provided.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 29712, 1955; s. 1380, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>