<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Machines or devices which come within provisions of law defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any machine or device is a slot machine or device within the provisions of this chapter if it is one that is adapted for use in such a way that, as a result of the insertion of any piece of money, coin, or other object, such machine or device is caused to operate or may be operated and if the user, by reason of any element of chance or of any other outcome of such operation unpredictable by him or her, may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive or become entitled to receive any piece of money, credit, allowance, or thing of value, or any check, slug, token, or memorandum, whether of value or otherwise, which may be exchanged for any money, credit, allowance, or thing of value or which may be given in trade; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secure additional chances or rights to use such machine, apparatus, or device, even though it may, in addition to any element of chance or unpredictable outcome of such operation, also sell, deliver, or present some merchandise, indication of weight, entertainment, or other thing of value.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed, interpreted, or applied to the possession of a reverse vending machine. As used in this section, a reverse vending machine is a machine into which empty beverage containers are deposited for recycling and which provides a payment of money, merchandise, vouchers, or other incentives. At a frequency less than upon the deposit of each beverage container, a reverse vending machine may pay out a random incentive bonus greater than that guaranteed payment in the form of money, merchandise, vouchers, or other incentives. The deposit of any empty beverage container into a reverse vending machine does not constitute consideration nor shall a reverse vending machine be deemed to be a slot machine within this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 18143, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(405-b); s. 1, ch. 67-203; s. 1, ch. 77-275; s. 2, ch. 84-247; s. 3, ch. 89-176; s. 1368, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>