<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Printing lottery tickets, etc., prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law, it is unlawful for any person, in any house, office, shop or building in this state to write, typewrite, print, or publish any lottery ticket or advertisement, circular, bill, poster, pamphlet, list or schedule, announcement or notice, of lottery prizes or drawings or any other matter or thing in any way connected with any lottery drawing, scheme or device, or to set up any type or plate for any such purpose, to be used or distributed in this state, or to be sent out of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law, it is unlawful for the owner or lessee of any such house, shop or building knowingly to permit the printing, typewriting, writing or publishing therein of any lottery ticket or advertisement, circular, bill, poster, pamphlet, list, schedule, announcement or notice of lottery prizes or drawings, or any other matter or thing in any way connected with any lottery drawing, scheme or device, or knowingly to permit therein the setting up of any type or plate for any such purpose to be used or distributed in this state, or to be sent out of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this chapter shall make unlawful the printing or production of any advertisement or any lottery ticket for a lottery conducted in any other state or nation where such lottery is not prohibited by the laws of such state or nation, or the sale of such materials by the manufacturer thereof to any person or entity conducting or participating in the conduct of such a lottery in any other state or nation. This section does not authorize any advertisement within Florida relating to lotteries of any other state or nation, or the sale or resale within Florida of such lottery tickets, chances, or shares to individuals, or any other acts otherwise in violation of any laws of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of this section shall be a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 4373, 1895; GS 3583; RGS 5510; CGL 7668; s. 1066, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 96-320.</History></Section>