<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.231" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gambling devices; manufacture, sale, purchase or possession unlawful.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except in instances when the following described implements or apparatus are being held or transported by authorized persons for the purpose of destruction, as hereinafter provided, and except in instances when the following described instruments or apparatus are being held, sold, transported, or manufactured by persons who have registered with the United States Government pursuant to the provisions of Title 15 of the United States Code, ss. 1171 et seq., as amended, so long as the described implements or apparatus are not displayed to the general public, sold for use in Florida, or held or manufactured in contravention of the requirements of 15 U.S.C. ss. 1171 et seq., it shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture, sell, transport, offer for sale, purchase, own, or have in his or her possession any roulette wheel or table, faro layout, crap table or layout, chemin de fer table or layout, chuck-a-luck wheel, bird cage such as used for gambling, bolita balls, chips with house markings, or any other device, implement, apparatus, or paraphernalia ordinarily or commonly used or designed to be used in the operation of gambling houses or establishments, excepting ordinary dice and playing cards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalties provided for the violation of this section, any occupational license held by a person found guilty of violating this section shall be suspended for a period not to exceed 5 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section and s. 849.05 do not apply to a vessel of foreign registry or a vessel operated under the authority of a country except the United States, while docked in this state or transiting in the territorial waters of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 29665, 1955; s. 9, ch. 74-385; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 2, ch. 87-255; s. 1372, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>