<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.0935" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Charitable, nonprofit organizations; drawings by chance; required disclosures; unlawful acts and practices; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Drawing by chance” or “drawing” means an enterprise in which, from the entries submitted by the public to the organization conducting the drawing, one or more entries are selected by chance to win a prize. The term “drawing” does not include those enterprises, commonly known as “matching,” “instant winner,” or “preselected sweepstakes,” which involve the distribution of winning numbers, previously designated as such, to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Organization” means an organization which is exempt from federal income taxation pursuant to 26 U.S.C. s. 501(c)(3), (4), (7), (8), (10), or (19), and which has a current determination letter from the Internal Revenue Service, and its bona fide members or officers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 849.09 shall not be construed to prohibit an organization qualified under 26 U.S.C. s. 501(c)(3), (4), (7), (8), (10), or (19) from conducting drawings by chance pursuant to the authority granted by this section, provided the organization has complied with all applicable provisions of chapter 496.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All brochures, advertisements, notices, tickets, or entry blanks used in connection with a drawing by chance shall conspicuously disclose:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules governing the conduct and operation of the drawing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name of the organization and its principal place of business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The source of the funds used to award cash prizes or to purchase prizes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date, hour, and place where the winner will be chosen and the prizes will be awarded, unless the brochures, advertisements, notices, tickets, or entry blanks are not offered to the public more than 3 days prior to the drawing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That no purchase or contribution is necessary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any organization which, pursuant to the authority granted by this section, promotes, operates, or conducts a drawing by chance:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To design, engage in, promote, or conduct any drawing in which the winner is predetermined by means of matching, instant win, or preselected sweepstakes or otherwise or in which the selection of the winners is in any way rigged;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require an entry fee, donation, substantial consideration, payment, proof of purchase, or contribution as a condition of entering the drawing or of being selected to win a prize. However, this provision shall not prohibit an organization from suggesting a minimum donation or from including a statement of such suggested minimum donation on any printed material utilized in connection with the fundraising event or drawing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To condition the drawing on a minimum number of tickets having been disbursed to contributors or on a minimum amount of contributions having been received;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To arbitrarily remove, disqualify, disallow, or reject any entry or to discriminate in any manner between entrants who gave contributions to the organization and those who did not give such contributions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fail to promptly notify, at the address set forth on the entry blank, any person, whose entry is selected to win, of the fact that he or she won;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fail to award all prizes offered;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To print, publish, or circulate literature or advertising material used in connection with the drawing which is false, deceptive, or misleading;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To cancel a drawing; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To condition the acquisition or giveaway of any prize upon the receipt of voluntary donations or contributions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization conducting the drawing may limit the number of tickets distributed to each drawing entrant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a deceptive and unfair trade practice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any organization which engages in any act or practice in violation of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. However, any organization or other person who sells or offers for sale in this state a ticket or entry blank for a raffle or other drawing by chance, without complying with the requirements of paragraph (3)(d), is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable by fine only as provided in s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to the state lottery operated pursuant to chapter 24.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-181; ss. 1, 2, ch. 88-115; s. 216, ch. 91-224; s. 1, ch. 96-253; s. 1825, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 97-108.</History></Section>