<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amusement games or machines; when chapter inapplicable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be taken or construed as applicable to an arcade amusement center having amusement games or machines which operate by means of the insertion of a coin and which by application of skill may entitle the person playing or operating the game or machine to receive points or coupons which may be exchanged for merchandise only, excluding cash and alcoholic beverages, provided the cost value of the merchandise or prize awarded in exchange for such points or coupons does not exceed 75 cents on any game played.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be taken or construed as applicable to any retail dealer who operates as a truck stop, as defined in <Reference Number="2" />chapter 336 and which operates a minimum of 6 functional diesel fuel pumps, having amusement games or machines which operate by means of the insertion of a coin or other currency and which by application of skill may entitle the person playing or operating the game or machine to receive points or coupons which may be exchanged for merchandise limited to noncash prizes, toys, novelties, and Florida Lottery products, excluding alcoholic beverages, provided the cost value of the merchandise or prize awarded in exchange for such points or coupons does not exceed 75 cents on any game played. This subparagraph applies only to games and machines which are operated for the entertainment of the general public and tourists as bona fide amusement games or machines. This subsection shall not apply, however, to any game or device defined as a gambling device in <Reference Number="3" />24 U.S.C. s. 1171, which requires identification of each device by permanently affixing seriatim numbering and name, trade name, and date of manufacture under s. 1173, and registration with the United States Attorney General, unless excluded from applicability of the chapter under s. 1178. This subsection shall not be construed to authorize video poker games or any other game or machine that may be construed as a gambling device under Florida law.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this subsection shall be taken or construed as applicable to a coin-operated game or device designed and manufactured only for bona fide amusement purposes which game or device may by application of skill entitle the player to replay the game or device at no additional cost, if the game or device: can accumulate and react to no more than 15 free replays; can be discharged of accumulated free replays only by reactivating the game or device for one additional play for such accumulated free replay; can make no permanent record, directly or indirectly, of free replays; and is not classified by the United States as a gambling device in <Reference Number="3" />24 U.S.C. s. 1171, which requires identification of each device by permanently affixing seriatim numbering and name, trade name, and date of manufacture under s. 1173, and registration with the United States Attorney General, unless excluded from applicability of the chapter under s. 1178. This subsection shall not be construed to authorize video poker games, or any other game or machine that may be construed as a gambling device under Florida law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “arcade amusement center” as used in this section means a place of business having at least 50 coin-operated amusement games or machines on premises which are operated for the entertainment of the general public and tourists as a bona fide amusement facility.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 84-247; s. 159, ch. 96-320; ss. 69, 79, ch. 96-323.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 159, ch. 96-320, and s. 79, ch. 96-323. For a description of multiple provisions in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Subparagraph (1)(a)2. and paragraph (1)(b) were also amended by s. 69, ch. 96-323, and that version reads:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. Nothing contained in this chapter shall be taken or construed as applicable to any retail dealer who operates as a truck stop, as defined in <Reference Number="2" />chapter 336, having amusement games or machines which operate by means of the insertion of a coin or other currency and which by application of skill may entitle the person playing or operating the game or machine to receive points or coupons which may be exchanged for merchandise limited to noncash prizes, toys, novelties, and Florida Lottery products, excluding alcoholic beverages, provided the cost value of the merchandise or prize awarded in exchange for such points or coupons does not exceed 75 cents on any game played. This subparagraph applies only to games and machines which are operated for the entertainment of the general public and tourists as bona fide amusement games or machines. This subsection shall not apply, however, to any game or device classified by the United States as requiring a federal gaming stamp under applicable provisions of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Nothing in this subsection shall be taken or construed as applicable to a coin-operated game or device designed and manufactured only for bona fide amusement purposes which game or device may by application of skill entitle the player to replay the game or device at no additional cost, if the game or device: can accumulate and react to no more than 15 free replays; can be discharged of accumulated free replays only by reactivating the game or device for one additional play for such accumulated free replay; can make no permanent record, directly or indirectly, of free replays; and is not classified by the United States as requiring a federal gambling tax stamp under applicable provisions of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material referencing truck stops in ch. 336 was in s. 336.021(1)(c)3.; it was deleted by s. 15, ch. 97-54.</Text></Note><Note Reference="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Title 24 of the United States Code relates to hospitals and asylums; chapter 24 of Title 15 of the United States Code relates to transportation of gambling devices.</Text></Note></Section>