<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Manufacture, sale, possession, etc., of coin-operated devices prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To manufacture, own, store, keep, possess, sell, rent, lease, let on shares, lend or give away, transport, or expose for sale or lease, or to offer to sell, rent, lease, let on shares, lend or give away, or permit the operation of, or for any person to permit to be placed, maintained, or used or kept in any room, space, or building owned, leased or occupied by the person or under the person’s management or control, any slot machine or device or any part thereof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make or to permit to be made with any person any agreement with reference to any slot machine or device, pursuant to which the user thereof, as a result of any element of chance or other outcome unpredictable to him or her, may become entitled to receive any money, credit, allowance, or thing of value or additional chance or right to use such machine or device, or to receive any check, slug, token or memorandum entitling the holder to receive any money, credit, allowance or thing of value.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to section 2 of that chapter of the Congress of the United States entitled “An act to prohibit transportation of gaming devices in interstate and foreign commerce,” approved January 2, 1951, being ch. 1194, 64 Stat. 1134, and also designated as 15 U.S.C. ss. 1171-1177, the State of Florida, acting by and through the duly elected and qualified members of its Legislature, does hereby in this section, and in accordance with and in compliance with the provisions of section 2 of such chapter of Congress, declare and proclaim that any county of the State of Florida within which slot machine gaming is authorized pursuant to chapter 551 is exempt from the provisions of section 2 of that chapter of the Congress of the United States entitled “An act to prohibit transportation of gaming devices in interstate and foreign commerce,” designated as 15 U.S.C. ss. 1171-1177, approved January 2, 1951. All shipments of gaming devices, including slot machines, into any county of this state within which slot machine gaming is authorized pursuant to chapter 551 and the registering, recording, and labeling of which have been duly performed by the manufacturer or distributor thereof in accordance with sections 3 and 4 of that chapter of the Congress of the United States entitled “An act to prohibit transportation of gaming devices in interstate and foreign commerce,” approved January 2, 1951, being ch. 1194, 64 Stat. 1134, and also designated as 15 U.S.C. ss. 1171-1177, shall be deemed legal shipments thereof into this state provided the destination of such shipments is an eligible facility as defined in s. 551.102 or the facility of a slot machine manufacturer or slot machine distributor as provided in s. 551.109(2)(a).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 18143, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(405-a); s. 1367, ch. 97-102; s. 2, ch. 2005-362; s. 156, ch. 2007-5; s. 11, ch. 2007-252.</History></Section>