<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0849.0931" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bingo authorized; conditions for conduct; permitted uses of proceeds; limitations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bingo game” means and refers to the activity, commonly known as “bingo,” in which participants pay a sum of money for the use of one or more bingo cards. When the game commences, numbers are drawn by chance, one by one, and announced. The players cover or mark those numbers on the bingo cards which they have purchased until a player receives a given order of numbers in sequence that has been preannounced for that particular game. This player calls out “bingo” and is declared the winner of a predetermined prize. More than one game may be played upon a bingo card, and numbers called for one game may be used for a succeeding game or games.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bingo card” means and refers to the flat piece of paper or thin pasteboard employed by players engaged in the game of bingo. The bingo card shall have not fewer than 24 playing numbers printed on it. These playing numbers shall range from 1 through 75, inclusive. More than one set of bingo numbers may be printed on any single piece of paper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization” means an organization which has qualified for exemption from federal income tax as an exempt organization under the provisions of s. 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 or s. 528 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended; which is engaged in charitable, civic, community, benevolent, religious, or scholastic works or other similar activities; and which has been in existence and active for a period of 3 years or more.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deal” means a separate set or package of not more than 4,000 instant bingo tickets in which the predetermined minimum prize payout is at least 65 percent of the total receipts from the sale of the entire deal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Flare” means the board or placard that accompanies each deal of instant bingo tickets and that has printed on or affixed to it the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The game name.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer’s name or distinctive logo.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The form number.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ticket count.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prize structure, including the number of symbols or number combinations for winning instant bingo tickets by denomination, with their respective winning symbols or number combinations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost per play.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The game serial number.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Instant bingo” means a form of bingo that is played at the same location as bingo, using tickets by which a player wins a prize by opening and removing a cover from the ticket to reveal a set of numbers, letters, objects, or patterns, some of which have been designated in advance as prize winners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Objects” means a set of 75 balls or other precision shapes that are imprinted with letters and numbers in such a way that numbers 1 through 15 are marked with the letter “B,” numbers 16 through 30 are marked with the letter “I,” numbers 31 through 45 are marked with the letter “N,” numbers 46 through 60 are marked with the letter “G,” and numbers 61 through 75 are marked with the letter “O.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rack” means the container in which the objects are placed after being drawn and announced.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Receptacle” means the container from which the objects are drawn or ejected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Session” means a designated set of games played in a day or part of a day.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">None of the provisions of this chapter shall be construed to prohibit or prevent charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organizations engaged in charitable, civic, community, benevolent, religious, or scholastic works or other similar endeavors, which organizations have been in existence and active for a period of 3 years or more, from conducting bingo games or instant bingo, provided the entire proceeds derived from the conduct of such games, less actual business expenses for articles designed for and essential to the operation, conduct, and playing of bingo or instant bingo, are donated by such organizations to the endeavors mentioned above. In no case may the net proceeds from the conduct of such games be used for any other purpose whatsoever. The proceeds derived from the conduct of bingo games or instant bingo shall not be considered solicitation of public donations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the express intent of the Legislature that no charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization serve as a sponsor of a bingo game or instant bingo conducted by another, but such organization may only be directly involved in the conduct of such a game as provided in this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an organization is not engaged in efforts of the type set out above, its right to conduct bingo games hereunder is conditioned upon the return of all the proceeds from such games to the players in the form of prizes. If at the conclusion of play on any day during which a bingo game is allowed to be played under this section there remain proceeds which have not been paid out as prizes, the organization conducting the game shall at the next scheduled day of play conduct bingo games without any charge to the players and shall continue to do so until the proceeds carried over from the previous days played have been exhausted. This provision in no way extends the limitation on the number of prize or jackpot games allowed in one day as provided for in subsection (5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of a condominium association, a cooperative association, a homeowners’ association as defined in s. 720.301, a mobile home owners’ association, a group of residents of a mobile home park as defined in chapter 723, or a group of residents of a mobile home park or recreational vehicle park as defined in chapter 513 to conduct bingo is conditioned upon the return of the net proceeds from such games to players in the form of prizes after having deducted the actual business expenses for such games for articles designed for and essential to the operation, conduct, and playing of bingo. Any net proceeds remaining after paying prizes may be donated by the association to a charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization which is exempt from federal income tax under the provisions of s. 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code to be used in such recipient organization’s charitable, civic, community, benevolent, religious, or scholastic works or similar activities or, in the alternative, such remaining proceeds shall be used as specified in subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for instant bingo prizes, which are limited to the amounts displayed on the ticket or on the game flare, a jackpot shall not exceed the value of $250 in actual money or its equivalent, and there shall be no more than three jackpots in any one session of bingo.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for instant bingo, which is not limited by this subsection, the number of days per week during which organizations authorized under this section may conduct bingo shall not exceed two.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for instant bingo prizes, which are limited to the amounts displayed on the ticket or on the game flare, there shall be no more than three jackpots on any one day of play. All other game prizes shall not exceed $50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person involved in the conduct of any bingo game or instant bingo must be a resident of the community where the organization is located and a bona fide member of the organization sponsoring such game and may not be compensated in any way for operation of such game. When bingo games or instant bingo is conducted by a charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization, the organization conducting the games must designate up to three members of that organization to be in charge of the games, one of whom shall be present during the entire session at which the games are conducted. The organization conducting the games is responsible for posting a notice, which notice states the name of the organization and the designated member or members, in a conspicuous place on the premises at which the session is held or instant bingo is played. A caller in a bingo game may not be a participant in that bingo game.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization involved in the conduct of a bingo game or instant bingo must be located in the county, or within a 15-mile radius of, where the bingo game or instant bingo is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No one under 18 years of age shall be allowed to play any bingo game or instant bingo or be involved in the conduct of a bingo game or instant bingo in any way.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any organization conducting bingo open to the public may refuse entry to any person who is objectionable or undesirable to the sponsoring organization, but such refusal of entry shall not be on the basis of race, creed, color, religion, sex, national origin, marital status, or physical handicap.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bingo games or instant bingo may be held only on the following premises:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property owned by the charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property owned by the charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization that will benefit by the proceeds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property leased for a period of not less than 1 year by a charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organization, providing the lease or rental agreement does not provide for the payment of a percentage of the proceeds generated at such premises to the lessor or any other party and providing the rental rate for such premises does not exceed the rental rates charged for similar premises in the same locale.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property owned by a municipality or a county when the governing authority has, by appropriate ordinance or resolution, specifically authorized the use of such property for the conduct of such games.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to bingo games conducted by a condominium association, a cooperative association, a homeowners’ association as defined in s. 720.301, a mobile home owners’ association, a group of residents of a mobile home park as defined in chapter 723, or a group of residents of a mobile home park or recreational vehicle park as defined in chapter 513, property owned by the association, property owned by the residents of the mobile home park or recreational vehicle park, or property which is a common area located within the condominium, mobile home park, or recreational vehicle park.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each bingo game shall be conducted in accordance with the following rules:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The objects, whether drawn or ejected, shall be essentially equal as to size, shape, weight, and balance and as to all other characteristics that may control their selection from the receptacle. The caller shall cancel any game if, during the course of a game, the mechanism used in the drawing or ejection of objects becomes jammed in such a manner as to interfere with the accurate determination of the next number to be announced or if the caller determines that more than one object is labeled with the same number or that there is a number to be drawn without a corresponding object. Any player in a game canceled pursuant to this paragraph shall be permitted to play the next game free of charge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to commencement of any bingo session, the member in charge shall cause a verification to be made of all objects to be placed in the receptacle and shall inspect the objects in the presence of a disinterested person to ensure that all objects are present and that there are no duplications or omissions of numbers on the objects. Any player shall be entitled to call for a verification of numbers before, during, and after a session.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The card or sheet on which the game is played shall be part of a deck, group, or series, no two of which may be alike in any given game.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All numbers shall be visibly displayed after being drawn and before being placed in the rack.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bona fide bingo shall consist of a predesignated arrangement of numbers on a card or sheet that correspond with the numbers on the objects drawn from the receptacle and announced. Errors in numbers announced or misplaced in the rack may not be recognized as a bingo.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a caller has started to vocally announce a number, the caller shall complete the call. If any player has obtained a bingo on a previous number, such player will share the prize with the player who gained bingo on the last number called.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Numbers on the winning cards or sheets shall be announced and verified in the presence of another player. Any player shall be entitled at the time the winner is determined to call for a verification of numbers drawn. The verification shall be in the presence of the member designated to be in charge of the occasion or, if such person is also the caller, in the presence of an officer of the licensee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determining a winner, the caller shall ask, “Are there any other winners?” If no one replies, the caller shall declare the game closed. No other player is entitled to share the prize unless she or he has declared a bingo prior to this announcement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seats may not be held or reserved by an organization or person involved in the conduct of any bingo game for players not present, nor may any cards be set aside, held, or reserved from one session to another for any player.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instant bingo tickets must be sold at the price printed on the ticket or on the game flare by the manufacturer, not to exceed $1. Discounts may not be given for the purchase of multiple tickets, nor may tickets be given away free of charge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each deal of instant bingo tickets must be accompanied by a flare, and the flare must be posted before the sale of any tickets in that deal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each instant bingo ticket in a deal must bear the same serial number, and there may not be more than one serial number in each deal. Serial numbers printed on a deal of instant bingo tickets may not be repeated by the manufacturer on the same form for a period of 3 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The serial number for each deal must be clearly and legibly placed on the outside of each deal’s package, box, or other container.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instant bingo tickets manufactured, sold, or distributed in this state must comply with the applicable standards on pull-tabs of the North American Gaming Regulators Association, as amended.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided under paragraph (e), an instant bingo ticket manufactured, sold, or distributed in this state must:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be manufactured so that it is not possible to identify whether it is a winning or losing instant bingo ticket until it has been opened by the player as intended.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be manufactured using at least a two-ply paper stock construction so that the instant bingo ticket is opaque.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have the form number, the deal’s serial number, and the name or logo of the manufacturer conspicuously printed on the face or cover of the instant bingo ticket.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a form of winner protection that allows the organization to verify, after the instant bingo ticket has been played, that the winning instant bingo ticket presented for payment is an authentic winning instant bingo ticket for the deal in play. The manufacturer shall provide a written description of the winner protection with each deal of instant bingo tickets.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manufacturer and distributor that sells or distributes instant bingo tickets in this state to charitable, nonprofit, or veterans’ organizations shall prepare an invoice that contains the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Date of sale.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Form number and serial number of each deal sold.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of instant bingo tickets in each deal sold.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name of distributor or organization to whom each deal is sold.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Price of each deal sold.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All information contained on an invoice must be maintained by the distributor or manufacturer for 3 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The invoice, or a true and accurate copy thereof, must be on the premises where any deal of instant bingo tickets is stored or in play.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any organization or other person who willfully and knowingly violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. For a second or subsequent offense, the organization or other person commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 92-280; s. 1, ch. 93-160; s. 1, ch. 94-326; s. 1363, ch. 97-102; s. 13, ch. 99-382; ss. 59, 70, ch. 2000-258; ss. 27, 28, ch. 2001-64; s. 2, ch. 2007-228.</History></Section>