<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0175.121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Revenue and Division of Retirement to keep accounts of deposits; disbursements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality or special fire control district having a chapter or local law plan established pursuant to this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall keep a separate account of all moneys collected for each municipality and each special fire control district under the provisions of this chapter. All moneys so collected must be transferred to the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund and shall be separately accounted for by the division. The moneys budgeted as necessary to pay the expenses of the division for the daily oversight and monitoring of the firefighters’ pension plans under this chapter and for the oversight and actuarial reviews conducted under part VII of chapter 112 are annually appropriated from the interest and investment income earned on the moneys collected for each municipality or special fire control district and deposited in the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund. Interest and investment income remaining thereafter in the trust fund which is unexpended and otherwise unallocated by law shall revert to the General Revenue Fund on June 30 of each year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall, on or before July 1 of each year, and at such other times as authorized by the division, draw his or her warrants on the full net amount of money then on deposit in the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund pursuant to this chapter, specifying the municipalities and special fire control districts to which the moneys must be paid and the net amount collected for and to be paid to each municipality or special fire control district, respectively, subject to the limitation on disbursement under s. 175.122. The sum payable to each municipality or special fire control district is appropriated annually out of the Police and Firefighters’ Premium Tax Trust Fund. The warrants of the Chief Financial Officer shall be payable to the respective municipalities and special fire control districts entitled to receive them and shall be remitted annually by the division to the respective municipalities and special fire control districts. In lieu thereof, the municipality or special fire control district may provide authorization to the division for the direct payment of the premium tax to the board of trustees. In order for a municipality or special fire control district and its pension fund to participate in the distribution of premium tax moneys under this chapter, all the provisions shall be complied with annually, including state acceptance pursuant to part VII of chapter 112.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys not distributed to municipalities and special fire control districts under this section as a result of the limitation on disbursement contained in s. 175.122, or as a result of any municipality or special fire control district not having qualified in any given year, or portion thereof, shall be transferred to the Firefighters’ Supplemental Compensation Trust Fund administered by the Department of Revenue, as provided in s. 633.382.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys transferred under paragraph (a) but not needed to support the supplemental compensation program in a given year shall be redistributed pro rata to those participating municipalities and special fire control districts that transfer any portion of their funds to support the supplemental compensation program in that year. Such additional moneys shall be used to cover or offset costs of the retirement plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist the Department of Revenue, the division shall identify those municipalities and special fire control districts that are eligible for redistribution as provided in s. 633.382(4)(c)2., by listing the municipalities and special fire control districts from which funds were transferred under paragraph (a) and specifying the amount transferred by each.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-249; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 74-294; s. 3, ch. 85-61; s. 7, ch. 86-41; s. 21, ch. 93-193; s. 11, ch. 94-259; s. 1449, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 95-250; s. 10, ch. 99-1; s. 162, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>