<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0175.371" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer to another state retirement system; benefits payable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, special fire control district, chapter plan, local law municipality, local law special fire control district, or local law plan under this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any firefighter who has a vested right to benefits under a pension plan created pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and who elects to participate in another state retirement system may not receive a benefit under the provisions of the latter retirement system for any year’s service for which benefits are paid under the provisions of the pension plan created pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When every active participant in any pension plan created pursuant to this chapter elects to transfer to another state retirement system, the pension plan created pursuant to this chapter shall be terminated and the assets distributed in accordance with s. 175.361. If some participants in a pension plan created pursuant to this chapter elect to transfer to another state retirement system and other participants elect to remain in the existing plan created pursuant to this chapter, the plan created pursuant to this chapter shall continue to receive state premium tax moneys until fully funded. If the plan is fully funded at a particular valuation date and not fully funded at a later valuation date, the plan shall resume receipt of state premium tax moneys until the plan is once again fully funded. “Fully funded” means that the present value of all benefits, accrued and projected, is less than the available assets and the present value of future member contributions and future plan sponsor contributions on an actuarial entry age cost funding basis. Effective May 31, 1998, for plans discussed herein, the plan shall remain in effect until the final benefit payment has been made to the last participant or beneficiary and shall then be terminated in accordance with s. 175.361.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 86-41; s. 37, ch. 99-1; s. 5, ch. 2002-66.</History></Section>