<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0175.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certified copy of ordinance or resolution filed; insurance companies’ annual report of premiums; duplicate files; book of accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality, special fire control district, chapter plan, local law municipality, local law special fire control district, or local law plan under this chapter, whenever any municipality passes an ordinance or whenever any special fire control district passes a resolution establishing a chapter plan or local law plan assessing and imposing the taxes authorized in s. 175.101, a certified copy of such ordinance or resolution shall be deposited with the division. Thereafter every insurance company, association, corporation, or other insurer carrying on the business of property insurance on real or personal property, on or before the succeeding March 1 after date of the passage of the ordinance or resolution, shall report fully in writing and under oath to the division and the Department of Revenue a just and true account of all premiums by such insurer received for property insurance policies covering or insuring any real or personal property located within the corporate limits of each such municipality or special fire control district during the period of time elapsing between the date of the passage of the ordinance or resolution and the end of the calendar year. The report shall include the code designation as prescribed by the division for each piece of insured property, real or personal, located within the corporate limits of each municipality and within the legally defined boundaries of each special fire control district. The aforesaid insurer shall annually thereafter, on March 1, file with the Department of Revenue a similar report covering the preceding year’s premium receipts, and every such insurer at the same time of making such reports shall pay to the Department of Revenue the amount of the tax hereinbefore mentioned. Every insurer engaged in carrying on such insurance business in the state shall keep accurate books of accounts of all such business done by it within the corporate limits of each such municipality and within the legally defined boundaries of each such special fire control district, and in such manner as to be able to comply with the provisions of this chapter. Based on the insurers’ reports of premium receipts, the division shall prepare a consolidated premium report and shall furnish to any municipality or special fire control district requesting the same a copy of the relevant section of that report.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-249; ss. 12, 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 75-240; s. 20, ch. 93-193; s. 1, ch. 95-250; s. 9, ch. 99-1; s. 6, ch. 2000-355.</History></Section>