<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0051.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Summary procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedure in this section applies only to those actions specified by statute or rule. Rules of procedure apply to this section except when this section or the statute or rule prescribing this section provides a different procedure. If there is a difference between the time period prescribed in a rule and in this section, this section governs.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PLEADINGS.<EmDash />Plaintiff’s initial pleading shall contain the matters required by the statute or rule prescribing this section or, if none is so required, shall state a cause of action. All defenses of law or fact shall be contained in defendant’s answer which shall be filed within 5 days after service of process. If the answer incorporates a counterclaim, plaintiff shall include all defenses of law or fact in his or her answer to the counterclaim and shall serve it within 5 days after service of the counterclaim. No other pleadings are permitted. All defensive motions, including motions to quash, shall be heard by the court prior to trial.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCOVERY.<EmDash />Depositions on oral examination may be taken by any party at any time. Other discovery and admissions may be had only on order of court setting the time for compliance. No discovery postpones the time for trial except for good cause shown or by stipulation of the parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">JURY.<EmDash />If a jury trial is authorized by law, any party may demand it in any pleading or by a separate paper served not later than 5 days after the action comes to issue. When a jury is in attendance at the close of pleading or the time of demand for jury trial, the action may be tried immediately; otherwise, the court shall order a special venire to be summoned immediately. If a special venire be summoned, the party demanding the jury shall deposit sufficient money with the clerk to pay the jury fees which shall be taxed as costs if he or she prevails.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NEW TRIAL.<EmDash />Motion for new trial shall be filed and served within 5 days after verdict, if a jury trial was had, or after entry of judgment, if trial was by the court. A reserved motion for directed verdict shall be renewed within the period for moving for a new trial.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPEAL.<EmDash />Notice of appeal shall be filed and served within 30 days from the rendition of the judgment appealed from.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 67-254; s. 23, ch. 73-333; s. 5, ch. 87-405; s. 292, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>