<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0491.0112" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sexual misconduct by a psychotherapist; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any psychotherapist who commits sexual misconduct with a client, or former client when the professional relationship was terminated primarily for the purpose of engaging in sexual contact, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083; however, a second or subsequent offense is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any psychotherapist who violates subsection (1) by means of therapeutic deception commits a felony of the second degree punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The giving of consent by the client to any such act shall not be a defense to these offenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “psychotherapist” means any person licensed pursuant to chapter 458, chapter 459, part I of chapter 464, chapter 490, or chapter 491, or any other person who provides or purports to provide treatment, diagnosis, assessment, evaluation, or counseling of mental or emotional illness, symptom, or condition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Therapeutic deception” means a representation to the client that sexual contact by the psychotherapist is consistent with or part of the treatment of the client.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual misconduct” means the oral, anal, or vaginal penetration of another by, or contact with, the sexual organ of another or the anal or vaginal penetration of another by any object.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Client” means a person to whom the services of a psychotherapist are provided.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-70; s. 13, ch. 91-201; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 137, ch. 2000-318.</History></Section>