<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0491.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Clinical Social Work, Marriage and Family Therapy, and Mental Health Counseling.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the department the Board of Clinical Social Work, Marriage and Family Therapy, and Mental Health Counseling composed of nine members appointed by the Governor and confirmed by the Senate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Six members of the board shall be persons licensed under this chapter as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members shall be licensed practicing clinical social workers.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members shall be licensed practicing marriage and family therapists.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members shall be licensed practicing mental health counselors.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members shall be citizens of the state who are not and have never been licensed in a mental health-related profession and who are in no way connected with the practice of any such profession.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than January 1, 1988, the Governor shall appoint nine members of the board as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members for terms of 2 years each.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members for terms of 3 years each.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members for terms of 4 years each.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As the terms of the initial members expire, the Governor shall appoint successors for terms of 4 years; and those members shall serve until their successors are appointed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement and enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All applicable provisions of chapter 456 relating to activities of regulatory boards shall apply to the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall maintain its official headquarters in the City of Tallahassee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 19, ch. 87-252; ss. 19, 20, ch. 90-263; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 193, ch. 94-218; s. 152, ch. 98-166; s. 163, ch. 98-200; s. 212, ch. 2000-160.</History></Section>