<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0491.0149" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Display of license; use of professional title on promotional materials.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person licensed under this chapter as a clinical social worker, marriage and family therapist, or mental health counselor, or certified as a master social worker shall conspicuously display the valid license issued by the department or a true copy thereof at each location at which the licensee practices his or her profession.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed clinical social worker shall include the words “licensed clinical social worker” or the letters “LCSW” on all promotional materials, including cards, brochures, stationery, advertisements, and signs, naming the licensee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed marriage and family therapist shall include the words “licensed marriage and family therapist” or the letters “LMFT” on all promotional materials, including cards, brochures, stationery, advertisements, and signs, naming the licensee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed mental health counselor shall include the words “licensed mental health counselor” or the letters “LMHC” on all promotional materials, including cards, brochures, stationery, advertisements, and signs, naming the licensee.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person registered under this chapter as a clinical social worker intern, marriage and family therapist intern, or mental health counselor intern shall conspicuously display the valid registration issued by the department or a true copy thereof at each location at which the registered intern is completing the experience requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered clinical social worker intern shall include the words “registered clinical social worker intern,” a registered marriage and family therapist intern shall include the words “registered marriage and family therapist intern,” and a registered mental health counselor intern shall include the words “registered mental health counselor intern” on all promotional materials, including cards, brochures, stationery, advertisements, and signs, naming the registered intern.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person provisionally licensed under this chapter as a provisional clinical social worker licensee, provisional marriage and family therapist licensee, or provisional mental health counselor licensee shall conspicuously display the valid provisional license issued by the department or a true copy thereof at each location at which the provisional licensee is providing services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provisional clinical social worker licensee shall include the words “provisional clinical social worker licensee,” a provisional marriage and family therapist licensee shall include the words “provisional marriage and family therapist licensee,” and a provisional mental health counselor licensee shall include the words “provisional mental health counselor licensee” on all promotional materials, including cards, brochures, stationery, advertisements, and signs, naming the provisional licensee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 20, ch. 90-263; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 516, ch. 97-103; s. 19, ch. 97-198; s. 211, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>