<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0491.0045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Intern registration; requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 1998, an individual who intends to practice in Florida to satisfy the postgraduate or post-master’s level experience requirements, as specified in s. 491.005(1)(c), (3)(c), or (4)(c), must register as an intern in the profession for which he or she is seeking licensure prior to commencing the post-master’s experience requirement or an individual who intends to satisfy part of the required graduate-level practicum, internship, or field experience, outside the academic arena for any profession, must register as an intern in the profession for which he or she is seeking licensure prior to commencing the practicum, internship, or field experience.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall register as a clinical social worker intern, marriage and family therapist intern, or mental health counselor intern each applicant who the board certifies has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the application form and remitted a nonrefundable application fee not to exceed $200, as set by board rule;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the education requirements as specified in s. 491.005(1)(c), (3)(c), or (4)(c) for the profession for which he or she is applying for licensure, if needed; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted an acceptable supervision plan, as determined by the board, for meeting the practicum, internship, or field work required for licensure that was not satisfied in his or her graduate program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identified a qualified supervisor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual registered under this section must remain under supervision until he or she is in receipt of a license or a letter from the department stating that he or she is licensed to practice the profession for which he or she applied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who has applied for intern registration on or before December 31, 2001, and has satisfied the education requirements of s. 491.005 that are in effect through December 31, 2000, will have met the educational requirements for licensure for the profession for which he or she has applied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals who have commenced the experience requirement as specified in s. 491.005(1)(c), (3)(c), or (4)(c) but failed to register as required by subsection (1) shall register with the department before January 1, 2000. Individuals who fail to comply with this subsection shall not be granted a license, and any time spent by the individual completing the experience requirement prior to registering as an intern shall not count toward completion of such requirement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 97-198; s. 202, ch. 97-264; s. 165, ch. 99-397.</History></Section>