<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0473.309" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Practice requirements for partnerships, corporations, and limited liability companies; business entities practicing public accounting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership may not engage in the practice of public accounting, as defined in s. 473.302(8)(a), unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a form of partnership recognized by Florida law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Partners owning at least 51 percent of the financial interest and voting rights of the partnership are certified public accountants in some state. However, each partner who is a certified public accountant in another state and is domiciled in this state must be a certified public accountant of this state and hold an active license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least one general partner is a certified public accountant of this state and holds an active license or, in the case of a firm that must have a license pursuant to s. 473.3101(1)(a)2., at least one general partner is a certified public accountant in some state and meets the requirements of s. 473.3141(1)(a) or (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All partners who are not certified public accountants in any state are engaged in the business of the partnership as their principal occupation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is in compliance with rules adopted by the board pertaining to minimum capitalization, letters of credit, and adequate public liability insurance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is currently licensed as required by s. 473.3101.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation may not engage in the practice of public accounting, as defined in s. 473.302(8)(a), unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a corporation duly organized in this or some other state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shareholders of the corporation owning at least 51 percent of the financial interest and voting rights of the corporation are certified public accountants in some state and are principally engaged in the business of the corporation. However, each shareholder who is a certified public accountant in another state and is domiciled in this state must be a certified public accountant of this state and hold an active license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal officer of the corporation is a certified public accountant in some state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least one shareholder of the corporation is a certified public accountant and holds an active license in this state or, in the case of a firm that must have a license pursuant to s. 473.3101(1)(a)2., at least one shareholder is a certified public accountant in some state and meets the requirements of s. 473.3141(1)(a) or (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All shareholders who are not certified public accountants in any state are engaged in the business of the corporation as their principal occupation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is in compliance with rules adopted by the board pertaining to minimum capitalization, letters of credit, and adequate public liability insurance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is currently licensed as required by s. 473.3101.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited liability company may not engage in the practice of public accounting, as defined in s. 473.302(8)(a), unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a limited liability company duly organized in this or some other state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the limited liability company owning at least 51 percent of the financial interest and voting rights of the company are certified public accountants in some state. However, each member who is a certified public accountant in some state and is domiciled in this state must be a certified public accountant of this state and hold an active license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least one member of the limited liability company is a certified public accountant and holds an active license in this state or, in the case of a firm that must have a license pursuant to s. 473.3101(1)(a)2., at least one member is a certified public accountant in some state and meets the requirements of s. 473.3141(1)(a) or (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All members who are not certified public accountants in any state are engaged in the business of the company as their principal occupation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is in compliance with rules adopted by the board pertaining to minimum capitalization, letters of credit, and adequate public liability insurance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is currently licensed as required by s. 473.3101.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or any other firm is engaged in the practice of public accounting if its employees are engaged in the practice of public accounting. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a licensed audit firm may own all or part of another licensed audit firm.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 25, ch. 79-202; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 11, ch. 85-9; s. 22, ch. 89-374; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 16, ch. 93-110; s. 1, ch. 93-284; s. 1, ch. 97-35; s. 5, ch. 98-340; s. 2, ch. 2000-114; s. 8, ch. 2009-54.</History></Section>