<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0473.322" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice public accounting unless the person is a certified public accountant or a public accountant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assume or use the titles or designations “certified public accountant” or “public accountant” or the abbreviation “C.P.A.” or any other title, designation, words, letters, abbreviations, sign, card, or device tending to indicate that the person holds a license to practice public accounting under this chapter or the laws of any other state, territory, or foreign jurisdiction, unless the person holds an active license under this chapter or has the practice privileges pursuant to s. 473.3141;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform or offer to perform any services described in s. 473.302(8)(a) unless such person holds an active license under this chapter and is a licensed audit firm, provides such services through a licensed audit firm, or complies with ss. 473.3101 and 473.3141. This paragraph does not prohibit the performance by persons other than certified public accountants of other services involving the use of accounting skills, including the preparation of tax returns and the preparation of financial statements without expression of opinion thereon;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as her or his own the license of another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give false or forged evidence to the board or a member thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a public accounting license that has been suspended, revoked, or placed on inactive or delinquent status;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ unlicensed persons to practice public accounting; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conceal information relative to violations of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 20, 25, ch. 79-202; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 11, ch. 85-9; s. 104, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 222, ch. 94-119; s. 2, ch. 94-151; s. 2, ch. 96-261; s. 1116, ch. 97-103; s. 12, ch. 98-340; s. 3, ch. 2000-114; s. 21, ch. 2009-54.</History></Section>