<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0473.305" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, may establish fees to be paid for applications, examination, reexamination, licensing and renewal, reinstatement, and recordmaking and recordkeeping. The fee for the examination shall be established at an amount that covers the costs for the procurement or development, administration, grading, and review of the examination. The fee for the examination is refundable if the applicant is found to be ineligible to sit for the examination. The fee for initial application is nonrefundable, and the combined fees for application and examination may not exceed $250 plus the actual per applicant cost to the department for purchase of the examination from the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants or a similar national organization. The biennial renewal fee may not exceed $250. The board may also establish, by rule, a reactivation <Reference Number="1" />fee, and a delinquency fee not to exceed $50 for continuing professional education reporting forms. The board shall establish fees which are adequate to ensure the continued operation of the board and to fund the proportionate expenses incurred by the department which are allocated to the regulation of public accountants. Fees shall be based on department estimates of the revenue required to implement this chapter and the provisions of law with respect to the regulation of certified public accountants.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 25, ch. 79-202; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 10, 11, ch. 85-9; s. 1, ch. 87-221; s. 22, ch. 88-205; s. 48, ch. 89-162; s. 20, ch. 89-374; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 2009-54; s. 2, ch. 2009-69; s. 13, ch. 2009-195.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The comma following the word “fee” was retained in the amendment to the section by s. 2, ch. 2009-69, but stricken in the amendments by s. 6, ch. 2009-54, and s. 13, ch. 2009-195.</Text></Note></Section>