<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0473.3101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure of sole proprietors, partnerships, corporations, limited liability companies, and other legal entities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each sole proprietor, partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or any other firm seeking to engage in the practice of public accounting, as defined in s. 473.302(8)(a), in this state must file an application for licensure with the department and supply the information the board requires. An application must be made upon the affidavit of a sole proprietor, general partner, shareholder, or member who is a certified public accountant.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following must hold a license issued under this section:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any firm with an office in this state which uses the title “CPA,” “CPA firm,” or any other title, designation, words, letters, abbreviations, or device tending to indicate that the firm practices public accounting.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any firm that does not have an office in this state but performs the services described in s. 473.3141(4) for a client having its home office in this state. The board shall define by rule what constitutes an office.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A firm that is not subject to the requirements of subparagraph (a)2. may perform other professional services while using the title “CPA,” “CPA firm,” or any other title, designation, words, letters, abbreviations, or device tending to indicate that the firm practices public accounting in this state without a license issued under this section only if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It performs such services through an individual with practice privileges granted under s. 473.3141; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It can lawfully do so in the state where the individual with practice privileges has his or her principal place of business.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall determine whether the sole proprietor, partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or any other firm meets the requirements for practice and, pending that determination, may certify to the department the partnership, corporation, or limited liability company for provisional licensure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each license must be renewed every 2 years. Each sole proprietor, partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or any other firm licensed under this section must notify the department within 1 month after any change in the information contained in the application on which its license is based.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 25, ch. 79-202; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 11, ch. 85-9; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 17, ch. 93-110; s. 2, ch. 93-284; s. 6, ch. 98-340; s. 9, ch. 2009-54.</History></Section>