<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0473.306" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examinations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person desiring to be licensed as a Florida certified public accountant shall apply to the department to take the licensure examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant is entitled to take the licensure examination to practice in this state as a certified public accountant if the applicant has completed 120 semester hours or 160 quarter hours from an accredited college or university with a concentration in accounting and business courses as specified by the board by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have the authority to establish the standards for determining and shall determine:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What constitutes a passing grade for each subject or part of the licensure examination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which educational institutions, in addition to the universities in the State University System of Florida, shall be deemed to be accredited colleges or universities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What courses and number of hours constitute a major in accounting; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What courses and number of hours constitute additional accounting courses acceptable under s. 473.308(3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may adopt an alternative licensure examination for persons who have been licensed to practice public accountancy or its equivalent in a foreign country so long as the International Qualifications Appraisal Board of the National Association of State Boards of Accountancy has ratified an agreement with that country for reciprocal licensure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of maintaining the proper educational qualifications for licensure under this chapter, the board may appoint an Educational Advisory Committee, which shall be composed of one member of the board, two persons in public practice who are licensed under this chapter, and four academicians on faculties of universities in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 25, ch. 79-202; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 10, 11, ch. 85-9; s. 2, ch. 87-221; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 125, ch. 94-119; s. 3, ch. 98-340; s. 9, ch. 2000-332; s. 1, ch. 2008-81.</History></Section>