<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0014.20195" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suicide Prevention Coordinating Council; creation; membership; duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Statewide Office for Suicide Prevention a Suicide Prevention Coordinating Council. The council shall develop strategies for preventing suicide.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCOPE OF ACTIVITY.<EmDash />The Suicide Prevention Coordinating Council is a coordinating council as defined in s. 20.03 and shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the Statewide Office for Suicide Prevention regarding the development of a statewide plan for suicide prevention, with the guiding principle being that suicide is a preventable problem. The statewide plan must:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Align and provide direction for statewide suicide prevention initiatives.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish partnerships with state and private agencies for the purpose of promoting public awareness of suicide prevention.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Address specific populations in this state who are at risk for suicide.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify ways to improve access to crisis services for individuals in acute situations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify resources to support the implementation of the statewide plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assemble an ad hoc advisory committee comprised of members from outside the council, if necessary, in order for the council to receive advice and assistance in carrying out its responsibilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make findings and recommendations regarding suicide prevention programs and activities. The council shall prepare an annual report and present it to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 1, 2008, and each year thereafter. The annual report must describe the status of existing and planned initiatives identified in the statewide plan for suicide prevention and any recommendations arising therefrom.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEMBERSHIP.<EmDash />The Suicide Prevention Coordinating Council shall consist of 27 voting members and one nonvoting member.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirteen members shall be appointed by the director of the Statewide Office for Suicide Prevention and shall represent the following organizations:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Association of School Psychologists.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Sheriffs Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Suicide Prevention Action Network USA.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Initiative of Suicide Prevention.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Suicide Prevention Coalition.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The American Foundation of Suicide Prevention.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida School Board Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The National Council for Suicide Prevention.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state chapter of AARP.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Alcohol and Drug Abuse Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Council for Community Mental Health.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Counseling Association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NAMI Florida.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following state officials or their designees shall serve on the coordinating council:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Elderly Affairs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Health Care Administration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Juvenile Justice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Corrections.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Veterans’ Affairs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Children and Family Services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall appoint four additional members to the coordinating council. The appointees must have expertise that is critical to the prevention of suicide or represent an organization that is not already represented on the coordinating council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the members appointed by the director of the Statewide Office for Suicide Prevention, seven members shall be appointed to initial terms of 3 years, and seven members shall be appointed to initial terms of 4 years. For the members appointed by the Governor, two members shall be appointed to initial terms of 4 years, and two members shall be appointed to initial terms of 3 years. Thereafter, such members shall be appointed to terms of 4 years. Any vacancy on the coordinating council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment, and any member who is appointed to fill a vacancy occurring because of death, resignation, or ineligibility for membership shall serve only for the unexpired term of the member’s predecessor. A member is eligible for reappointment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Statewide Office for Suicide Prevention shall be a nonvoting member of the coordinating council and shall act as chair.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the coordinating council shall serve without compensation. Any member of the coordinating council who is a public employee is entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEETINGS.<EmDash />The coordinating council shall meet at least quarterly or upon the call of the chair. The council meetings may be held via teleconference or other electronic means.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2007-46; s. 1, ch. 2008-6; s. 2, ch. 2010-159; s. 1, ch. 2010-204; s. 2, ch. 2011-51; s. 37, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>