<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0014.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Commission on the Status of Women.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established in the Office of the Attorney General the Florida Commission on the Status of Women, consisting of 22 members. The Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, the Attorney General, and the Governor shall each appoint four members, and the Chief Financial Officer and the Commissioner of Agriculture shall each appoint three members, for a term of 4 years. The members appointed shall include persons who represent rural and urban interests and the ethnic and cultural diversity of the state’s population. No member shall serve more than 8 consecutive years on the commission. A vacancy shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall meet once in the first, second, and fourth quarters of each year and upon the call of the chairperson or two other officers. Annually, at the meeting in the first quarter, officers consisting of a chairperson, vice chairperson, secretary, and treasurer shall be elected. Each officer shall serve until a successor is elected and qualified. No officer shall serve more than two consecutive terms in the same office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses in accordance with s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the commission to study the changing and developing roles of women in American society. The study shall include, but not be limited to, the following areas:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The socioeconomic factors that influence the status of women.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of individual potential.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The encouragement of women to utilize their capabilities and assume leadership roles.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coordination of efforts of numerous women’s organizations interested in the welfare of women.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification and recognition of contributions made by women to the community, state, and nation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The implementation of paragraphs (a)-(e) where working conditions, financial security, and legal status of both sexes are improved.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may apply for and accept funds, grants, gifts, and services from the state, the government of the United States or any of its agencies, or any other public or private source for the purpose of defraying clerical and administrative costs as may be necessary in carrying out its duties under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning January 1, 1993, the commission shall report annually on January 1 to the Governor, the Attorney General, the Cabinet, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, and the minority leaders of the House and Senate on the study carried out under the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 91-77; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 4, ch. 2003-6.</History></Section>