<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0014.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State-Federal relations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is the intent of the Legislature to establish mechanisms through which the legislative and executive branches of state government can work together in a cooperative alliance, to strengthen the state’s relationship with our Congressional Delegation and with federal executive branch agencies, to improve our position in relation to federal legislative initiatives which have a fiscal impact or substantive policy impact on the state, and to establish and maintain a viable network and communications structure to facilitate the transmittal of essential information between state and federal officials, and to take all necessary steps to maximize the receipt of various federal funds by the State of Florida. Florida’s Congressional Delegation is, in this regard, the most important linkage in representing Florida’s interests in the nation’s capital. Therefore, the mechanisms and resources created herein, for the furtherance of the state’s intergovernmental efforts, shall include the Congressional Delegation and be available to meet its needs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREATION OF THE OFFICE OF STATE-FEDERAL RELATIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created, within the Executive Office of the Governor, the Office of State-Federal Relations for the State of Florida, hereinafter referred to as the “office,” to be located in Washington, D.C. The office shall represent both the legislative and executive branches of state government. The Legislature shall have direct access to the staff of the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duties of the office shall be determined by the Governor, in consultation with the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide legislative and administrative liaison between state and federal officials and agencies and with Congress.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide grants assistance and advice to state agencies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist in the development and implementation of strategies for the evaluation and management of the state’s federal legislative program and intergovernmental efforts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To facilitate the activities of Florida officials traveling to Washington, D.C., in the performance of their official duties.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The head of the office shall be the director, who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COOPERATION.<EmDash />For the purpose of centralizing the state-federal relations efforts of the state, state agencies and their representatives shall cooperate and coordinate their state-federal efforts and activities with the office. State agencies which have representatives headquartered in Washington, D.C., are encouraged to station their representatives in the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL REPORT.<EmDash />By January 1 of each year, the office shall submit a report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives detailing the office’s budget, personnel, and activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOMINATIONS TO FEDERAL REGIONAL FISHERIES MANAGEMENT COUNCILS.—The Governor is prohibited from nominating for appointment to any one of the federal fisheries management councils established under 16 U.S.C. ss. 1801 et seq., as amended, the name of any person who is, or who has been at any time during the 24 months preceding such nomination, a lobbyist for any entity of any kind whatsoever whose interests are or could be affected by actions or decisions of such fisheries management councils.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “lobbyist” means any natural person who is required to register pursuant to s. 11.045 or the equivalent federal statute and who, for compensation, seeks, or sought during the preceding 24 months, to influence the governmental decisionmaking of a reporting individual or procurement employee, as those terms are defined under s. 112.3148, or his or her agency, to encourage the passage, defeat, or modification of any proposal or recommendation by such reporting individual or procurement employee or his or her agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 6, ch. 77-419; s. 9, ch. 79-190; s. 1, ch. 95-303; s. 1, ch. 98-188; s. 2, ch. 2011-155.</History>
</Section>