<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0014.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Citizen’s Assistance Office.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created in the Executive Office of the Governor the Citizen’s Assistance Office. The head of the Citizen’s Assistance Office shall be appointed by and shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Citizen’s Assistance Office may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigate, on complaint or on its own motion, any administrative action of any state agency, the administration of which is under the direct supervision of the Governor, regardless of the finality of the administrative action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request, and shall be given by any state agency, such assistance and information as may be necessary for the performance of its duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Examine the records and reports of any state agency, the administration of which is under the direct supervision of the Governor, not made specifically confidential by law when the office determines that it is necessary.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate individual state agency complaint-handling activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Citizen’s Assistance Office shall report to the Governor on:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of complaints and investigations and the disposition of such investigations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The types of complaints made and an assessment as to the cause of the complaints.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for the alleviation of the cause of complaints disclosed by investigations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other information as the Executive Office of the Governor shall require.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Citizen’s Assistance Office shall refer consumer-oriented complaints to the Division of Consumer Services of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Citizen’s Assistance Office shall perform such other duties as the Executive Office of the Governor shall direct.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 79-190; s. 27, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>