<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0014.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Office of Chief Inspector General.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created in the Executive Office of the Governor the Office of Chief Inspector General. The Chief Inspector General shall be responsible for promoting accountability, integrity, and efficiency in the agencies under the jurisdiction of the Governor. The Chief Inspector General shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Governor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Inspector General shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate, supervise, and coordinate investigations, recommend policies, and carry out other activities designed to deter, detect, prevent, and eradicate fraud, waste, abuse, mismanagement, and misconduct in government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigate, upon receipt of a complaint or for cause, any administrative action of any agency, the administration of which is under the direct supervision of the Governor, regardless of the finality of the administrative action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request such assistance and information as may be necessary for the performance of the duties of the Chief Inspector General.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Examine the records and reports of any agency the administration of which is under the direct supervision of the Governor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate complaint-handling activities with agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate the activities of the Whistle-blower’s Act pursuant to chapter 112 and maintain the whistle-blower’s hotline to receive complaints and information concerning the possible violation of law or administrative rules, mismanagement, fraud, waste, abuse of authority, malfeasance, or a substantial or specific danger to the health, welfare, or safety of the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report expeditiously to and cooperate fully with the Department of Law Enforcement, the Department of Legal Affairs, and other law enforcement agencies when there are recognizable grounds to believe that there has been a violation of criminal law or that a civil action should be initiated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act as liaison with outside agencies and the Federal Government to promote accountability, integrity, and efficiency in state government.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act as liaison and monitor the activities of the inspectors general in the agencies under the Governor’s jurisdiction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review, evaluate, and monitor the policies, practices, and operations of the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct special investigations and management reviews at the request of the Governor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Related to public-private partnerships, the Chief Inspector General:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall advise public-private partnerships, including Enterprise Florida, Inc., in their development, utilization, and improvement of internal control measures necessary to ensure fiscal accountability.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May conduct, direct, and supervise audits relating to the programs and operations of public-private partnerships.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall receive and investigate complaints of fraud, abuses, and deficiencies relating to programs and operations of public-private partnerships.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May request and have access to any records, data, and other information in the possession of public-private partnerships which the Chief Inspector General deems necessary to carry out his or her responsibilities with respect to accountability.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall monitor public-private partnerships for compliance with the terms and conditions of contracts with the department and report noncompliance to the Governor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall advise public-private partnerships in the development, utilization, and improvement of performance measures for the evaluation of their operations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall review and make recommendations for improvements in the actions taken by public-private partnerships to meet performance standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Inspector General shall serve as the inspector general for the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 94-235; s. 14, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>