<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0014.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Governor; emergency powers to quell violence.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor of Florida is hereby authorized and empowered to take such measures and to do all and every act and thing which she or he may deem necessary in order to prevent overt threats of violence or violence, to the person or property of citizens of the state and to maintain peace, tranquillity, and good order in the state, and in any political subdivision thereof, and in any area of the state designated by the Governor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor when, in her or his opinion, the facts warrant, shall, by proclamation, declare that, because of unlawful assemblage, violence, overt threats of violence, or otherwise, a danger exists to the person or property of any citizen or citizens of the state and that the peace and tranquillity of the state, or any political subdivision thereof, or any area of the state designated by the Governor, is threatened, and because thereof an emergency, with reference to said threats and danger, exists. In all such cases when the Governor shall issue a proclamation as herein provided she or he shall be and is hereby further authorized and empowered, to cope with said threats and danger, to order and direct any individual person, corporation, association, or group of persons to do any act which would in the Governor’s opinion prevent danger to life, limb, or property, prevent a breach of the peace or the Governor may order such individual person, corporation, association, or group of persons to refrain from doing any act or thing which would, in the Governor’s opinion, endanger life, limb, or property, or cause, or tend to cause, a breach of the peace, or endanger the peace and good order of society, and shall have full power by appropriate means to enforce such order or proclamation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor, upon the issuance of a proclamation as provided for in subsection (2), is hereby authorized and empowered to take and exercise any, either, or all of the following actions, powers, and prerogatives:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Call out the military forces of the state (state militia) and order and direct said forces to take such action as in the Governor’s judgment may be necessary to avert the threatened danger and to maintain peace and good order in the particular circumstances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order any sheriff or sheriffs of this state, pursuant to a proclamation as herein provided, to exercise fully the powers granted them, and each of them, under s. 30.15(1)(f) (suppress tumults, riots, and unlawful assemblies in their counties with force and strong hand when necessary) and to do all things necessary to maintain peace and good order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order and direct the State Highway Patrol, and each and every officer thereof, to do and perform such acts and services as the Governor may direct and in the Governor’s judgment are necessary in the circumstances to maintain peace and good order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorize, order or direct any state, county, or city official to enforce the provisions of such proclamation in each and every and all of the courts in the state by injunction, mandamus, or other appropriate legal action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor is hereby authorized and empowered to intervene in any situation where there exists violence, overt threats of violence to persons or property and take complete control thereof to prevent violence, or to quell violence or any disturbance or disorder which threatens the peace and good order of society.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers herein granted are supplemental to and in aid of powers now vested in the Governor under the constitution, statutory laws and police powers of said state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall continue in full force and effect until otherwise amended.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-6, ch. 31390, 1956; s. 2, ch. 61-239; s. 2, ch. 65-95; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 18, ch. 78-95; s. 2, ch. 91-95; s. 34, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>