<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0335.1825" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Access permit required; authority to close unpermitted connections.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A connection may not be constructed or substantially altered without obtaining an access permit in accordance with this act in advance of such action. The department has the authority to restrict or deny access to the State Highway System, in accordance with the provisions of this act, at the location specified in the permit until the permittee constructs or alters the connection in accordance with the permit requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost of construction or alteration of a connection shall be borne by the permittee, except for alterations which are not required by law, but are made at the request of and for the convenience of the department. The permittee, however, shall bear the cost of alteration of any connection which is required by the department due to increased or altered traffic flows generated by changes in the facilities or nature of business conducted at the location specified in the permit, if the department establishes the need for such alteration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this act, an unpermitted connection is subject to closure by the department which shall have the right to install barriers across or remove the connection. When the department determines that a connection is unpermitted and subject to closure, it shall provide reasonable notice of its impending action to the owner of property served by the connection. The department’s procedures for providing notice and preventing the operation of unpermitted connections shall be adopted by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may initiate injunctive proceedings as provided in s. 120.69 to enforce the provisions of this section or any rule or order issued or entered pursuant thereto.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 88-224; s. 3, ch. 89-232; s. 101, ch. 92-152.</History></Section>