<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0335.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bicycle and pedestrian ways along state roads and transportation facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bicycle and pedestrian ways shall be given full consideration in the planning and development of transportation facilities, including the incorporation of such ways into state, regional, and local transportation plans and programs. Bicycle and pedestrian ways shall be established in conjunction with the construction, reconstruction, or other change of any state transportation facility, and special emphasis shall be given to projects in or within 1 mile of an urban area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (a), bicycle and pedestrian ways are not required to be established:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where their establishment would be contrary to public safety;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the cost would be excessively disproportionate to the need or probable use;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where other available means or factors indicate an absence of need.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish construction standards and a uniform system of signing for bicycle and pedestrian ways.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in cooperation with the Department of Environmental Protection, shall establish a statewide integrated system of bicycle and pedestrian ways in such a manner as to take full advantage of any such ways which are maintained by any governmental entity. For the purposes of this section, bicycle facilities may be established as part of or separate from the actual roadway and may utilize existing road rights-of-way or other rights-of-way or easements acquired for public use.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 4, 5, ch. 73-339; s. 5, ch. 84-284; s. 38, ch. 84-309; s. 26, ch. 85-180; s. 163, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>