<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0335.074" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Safety inspection of bridges.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those bridges having an opening measured along the center of the roadway of more than 20 feet between undercopings of abutments or spring lines of arches or extreme ends of openings for multiple boxes and those bridges consisting of multiple pipes where the clear distance between openings is less than half of the smaller contiguous opening are subject to inspection in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At regular intervals not to exceed 2 years, each bridge on a public transportation facility shall be inspected for structural soundness and safety for the passage of traffic on such bridge. The thoroughness with which bridges are to be inspected shall depend on such factors as age, traffic characteristics, state of maintenance, and known deficiencies. The governmental entity having maintenance responsibility for any such bridge shall be responsible for having inspections performed and reports prepared in accordance with the provisions contained herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each bridge inspection required by subsection (2) shall be performed by an inspector who is qualified, as prescribed in subsection (4), who shall determine the load-carrying capacity and safety condition of the bridge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each inspection shall be reported on a format designated by the department and forwarded to the department. A copy of such report shall also be provided to the local governmental entities in the jurisdictions of which the bridge is located. Data on a newly completed structure, or on any modification of an existing structure, which would alter previously submitted data on any inspection report shall be submitted to the department and the appropriate local governmental entities within 90 days of completion of the new construction or modification by the governmental entity having maintenance responsibility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall maintain an inventory of bridges and appropriate records on the inspections of such bridges reported pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who inspects bridges and completes reports required by this section must possess the following minimum qualifications:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a registered professional engineer with expertise in civil engineering; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a minimum of 5 years’ experience in bridge construction or maintenance inspection assignments in a responsible capacity and have completed a comprehensive training course approved by the department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who executes reports required by this section shall be a registered professional engineer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of an inspection report that recommends reducing the weight, size, or speed limit on a bridge, the governmental entity having maintenance responsibility for the bridge must reduce the maximum limits for the bridge in accordance with the inspection report and shall post the limits in accordance with s. 316.555. The governmental entity must, within 30 days after receipt of an inspection report recommending lower limits, notify the department that the limitations have been implemented and the <Reference Number="1" />bridge has been posted accordingly. If the required actions are not taken within 30 days after receipt of an inspection report, the department shall post the limits on the bridge in accordance with the recommendations in the inspection report. <Reference Number="2" />All costs incurred by the department in connection with providing notice of the bridge’s limitations or restrictions shall be assessed against and collected from the governmental entity having maintenance responsibility for the bridge. If an inspection report recommends closure of a bridge, the bridge shall be immediately closed. If the governmental entity does not close the bridge immediately upon receipt of an inspection report recommending closure, the department shall close the bridge. <Reference Number="2" />All costs incurred by the department in connection with the bridge closure shall be assessed against and collected from the governmental entity having maintenance responsibility for the bridge. <Reference Number="3" />Nothing in this subsection alters existing jurisdictional responsibilities for the operation and maintenance of bridges.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 69-271; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 75-137; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 40, ch. 84-309; s. 16, ch. 85-81; s. 94, ch. 92-152; s. 77, ch. 99-385; s. 21, ch. 2012-128; s. 25, ch. 2012-174.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 25, ch. 2012-174. Section 21, ch. 2012-128, also created subsection (5), and that version used the words “limits have” instead of “bridge has.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 25, ch. 2012-174. Section 21, ch. 2012-128, also created subsection (5), and that version used the word “The” instead of the word “All.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 25, ch. 2012-174. Section 21, ch. 2012-128, also created subsection (5), and that version used the phrase “This subsection does not alter” instead of the phrase “Nothing in the subsection alters.”</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 338.071.</Text></Note></Section>