<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0335.187" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unpermitted connections; existing access permits; nonconforming permits; modification and revocation of permits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unpermitted connections to the State Highway System in existence on July 1, 1988, which have been in continuous use for a period of 1 year or more shall not require the issuance of a permit and may continue to provide access to the State Highway System. However, the department may require that a permit be obtained for such a connection if a significant change occurs in the use, design, or traffic flow of the connection. If a permit is not obtained, the connection may be closed pursuant to s. 335.1825(3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Access permits in effect on July 1, 1988, shall remain valid until modified or revoked. The department may, after written notification and a hearing, as provided for in s. 120.60, modify or revoke an access permit granted prior to July 1, 1988, by requiring relocation, alteration, or closure of the connection if a significant change occurs in the use, design, or traffic flow of the connection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a nonconforming access permit after finding that to deny an access permit would leave the property without a reasonable means of access to the State Highway System. The department may specify limits on the maximum vehicular use of the connection and may be conditioned on the availability of future alternative means of access for which access permits can be obtained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After written notice and the opportunity for a hearing, as provided for in s. 120.60, the department may modify or revoke an access permit issued after July 1, 1988, by requiring relocation, alteration, or closure of an existing connection if a significant change occurs in the use, design, or traffic flow of the connection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A means of reasonable access to an abutting state highway may not be denied to a property owner, except on the basis of safety or operational concerns as provided in s. 335.184.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 88-224; s. 105, ch. 92-152.</History></Section>