<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0335.167" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State highway construction and maintenance; Florida-friendly landscaping.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall use and require the use of Florida-friendly landscaping practices, as defined in s. 373.185, in the construction and maintenance of all new state highways, wayside parks, access roads, welcome stations, and other state highway rights-of-way constructed upon or acquired after June 30, 2009. The department shall develop a 5-year program for phasing in the use of Florida-friendly landscaping, including the use of solid waste compost, in state highway rights-of-way constructed upon or acquired before July 1, 2009. In accomplishing these tasks, the department shall employ the standards set out in s. 373.185.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the use of Florida-friendly landscaping and other water use and pollution prevention measures to conserve or protect the state’s water resources serves a compelling public interest and that the participation of homeowners’ associations and local governments is essential to the state’s efforts in water conservation and water quality protection and restoration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A deed restriction or covenant may not prohibit or be enforced so as to prohibit any property owner from implementing Florida-friendly landscaping on his or her land or create any requirement or limitation in conflict with any provision of part II of chapter 373 or a water shortage order, other order, consumptive use permit, or rule adopted or issued pursuant to part II of chapter 373.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government ordinance may not prohibit or be enforced so as to prohibit any property owner from implementing Florida-friendly landscaping on his or her land.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 91-41; s. 2, ch. 91-68; s. 5, ch. 2001-252; s. 24, ch. 2009-243.</History></Section>