<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0527.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimum storage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person who engages in the distribution of liquefied petroleum gas for resale to domestic, commercial, or industrial consumers as a prerequisite to obtaining a liquefied petroleum gas license shall install, own, or lease a bulk storage filling plant of not less than 18,000 gallons (water capacity) within the state and shall be located within a 75-mile radius of the licensed company’s business location. This bulk storage filling plant must have loading and unloading provisions solely for the licenseholder and be operated and maintained in compliance with this chapter for the duration of the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer in liquefied petroleum gas licensed as of August 31, 2000, who has entered or who enters into a written agreement with a wholesaler that the wholesaler will provide liquefied petroleum gas to the dealer for a period of 12 continuous months is exempt from the requirements of subsection (1), if the wholesaler has at least 18,000 gallons (water capacity) of bulk storage within this state permanently connected for storage, which is used as such for each dealer to whom gas is sold, and if the wholesaler has loading and unloading provisions. Such dealer must provide certification of this agreement on a form provided by the department to the department before her or his license may be issued. The form must be signed by both the wholesaler or his or her agent and the dealer or his or her agent and must be submitted annually with the license renewal application. A dealer who does not provide written proof of minimum storage may have her or his license denied, suspended, or revoked. A wholesaler may not enter into written agreements that allocate an amount of storage that exceeds the wholesaler’s total storage capacity minus 18,000 gallons (water capacity).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer in liquefied petroleum gas operating a single dispensing unit for the sole purpose of direct product sale to customers, including delivery of cylinders of 40 pounds or less of propane gas capacity for use with outdoor equipment or appliances that are not connected to or part of the permanent interior piping of a structure, or an operator of a cylinder exchange unit is exempt from the requirements of this section. A person may not deliver liquefied petroleum gas by cargo vehicle unless the person complies with requirements for minimum storage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 57-219; s. 1, ch. 61-158; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 18, 19, ch. 81-175; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 2, ch. 82-6; s. 5, ch. 84-126; ss. 2, 3, ch. 87-34; s. 9, ch. 90-215; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 727, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 2000-269; s. 6, ch. 2003-132; s. 8, ch. 2006-165.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 526.21.</Text></Note></Section>