<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0527.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Short title and purpose.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 527.20-527.23 may be cited as the “Florida Propane Gas Education, Safety, and Research Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the finding of the Legislature that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educating propane gas producers, distributors, and consumers about propane gas and about the mechanical, technical, and safety practices related to propane gas and propane gas equipment furthers the public interest by reducing accidents and improving safety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improved and increased marketing of propane gas will increase the consumption and use of propane gas, thereby furthering the public interest by creating additional employment opportunities in the state and expanding revenue.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes of the act are to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the Florida Propane Gas Education, Safety, and Research Council to study problems arising in the production, transportation, marketing, and use of propane gas and to formulate and provide to the commissioner recommendations and policy alternatives. The council is to investigate, research, study, or perform other activities in order to advance the safety, efficiency, desirability, usage, and marketability of propane gas and propane gas use equipment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for education of propane gas producers, distributors, and consumers about:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Propane gas and its uses;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Safety issues related to propane gas and the mechanical, technical, and safety practices related to propane gas and propane gas equipment; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other issues related to propane gas which the council determines would be beneficial to producers, distributors, and consumers.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a method of funding for the activities established in the act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-105.</History></Section>