<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0527.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notification of accidents; leak calls.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediately upon discovery, all liquefied petroleum gas licensees shall notify the department of any liquefied petroleum gas-related accident involving a liquefied petroleum gas licensee or customer account:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which caused a death or personal injury requiring professional medical treatment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where uncontrolled ignition of liquefied petroleum gas resulted in death, personal injury, or property damage exceeding $1,000; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which caused estimated damage to property exceeding $1,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Uncontrolled ignition” means any ignition of liquefied petroleum gas that occurs outside normal maintenance, service testing, or operation of LP gas equipment or appliances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All licensees who maintain bulk storage of liquefied petroleum gas shall supply their local fire department with the name and phone number of an emergency contact for after-hour emergencies. This shall also be posted in a prominent location on the premises. If this number is answered by a service or machine, the message must be relayed to the appropriate person within an hour of receipt.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon notification by a consumer, the supplier shall physically respond to any verifiable leak call within a reasonable time, not to exceed 24 hours.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that the licensee is contacted by an emergency response unit which requires the licensee’s presence at the scene because the incident involves the licensee’s equipment, the licensee shall physically respond within 2 hours.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 10, ch. 86-69; ss. 2, 3, ch. 87-34; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-248; s. 5, ch. 2003-132.</History></Section>