<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0527.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension and revocation of license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The violation by any person possessed of a license or required to possess a license as provided in s. 527.02 of any provision of this chapter or any rule adopted pursuant thereto or of a cease and desist order shall be cause for revocation or suspension of such license or eligibility for licensure by the department after the department determines such person guilty of such violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order of suspension shall state the period of time of such suspension which period shall not be in excess of 1 year from the date of such order. An order of revocation may be entered for a period of not exceeding 2 years; and such order shall effect revocation of license then held by such person and during such period of time no license shall be issued such person. If during the period between the beginning of proceedings and entry of an order of suspension or revocation by the department a new license has been issued the person so charged, any order of suspension or revocation shall operate effectively with respect to the new license held by such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are cumulative and shall not affect the penalty and injunctive provisions of ss. 527.08 and 527.09.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 29742, 1955; s. 1, ch. 61-158; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 73-286; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 14, 18, 19, ch. 81-175; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 2, ch. 82-6; s. 6, ch. 86-69; ss. 2, 3, ch. 87-34; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 526.181(2).</Text></Note></Section>