<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0527.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Liquefied petroleum gas” means any material which is composed predominantly of any of the following hydrocarbons, or mixtures of the same: propane, propylene, butanes (normal butane or isobutane), and butylenes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, firm, partnership, corporation, company, association, organization, or cooperative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ultimate consumer” means the person last purchasing liquefied petroleum gas in its liquid or vapor state for industrial, commercial, or domestic use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualifier” means any person who has passed a competency examination administered by the department and is employed by a licensed business in one or more of the following classifications:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Category I liquefied petroleum gas dealer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Category II liquefied petroleum gas dispenser.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LP gas installer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specialty installer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requalifier of cylinders.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fabricator, repairer, and tester of vehicles and cargo tanks.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Category IV liquefied petroleum gas dispensing unit operator and recreational vehicle servicer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Category V liquefied petroleum gases dealer for industrial uses only.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Category I liquefied petroleum gas dealer” means any person selling or offering to sell by delivery or at a stationary location any liquefied petroleum gas to the ultimate consumer for industrial, commercial, or domestic use; any person leasing or offering to lease, or exchanging or offering to exchange, any apparatus, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum gas; any person installing, servicing, altering, or modifying apparatus, piping, tubing, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum or natural gas; any person installing carburetion equipment; or any person requalifying cylinders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Category II liquefied petroleum gas dispenser” means any person engaging in the business of operating a liquefied petroleum gas dispensing unit for the purpose of serving liquid products to the ultimate consumer for industrial, commercial, or domestic use, and selling or offering to sell, or leasing or offering to lease, apparatus, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum gas, including maintaining a cylinder storage rack at the licensed business location for the purpose of storing cylinders filled by the licensed business for sale or use at a later date.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Category III liquefied petroleum gas cylinder exchange operator” means any person operating a storage facility used for the purpose of storing filled propane cylinders of not more than 43.5 pounds propane capacity or 104 pounds water capacity, while awaiting sale to the ultimate consumer, or a facility used for the storage of empty or filled containers which have been offered for exchange.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Category IV liquefied petroleum gas dispenser and recreational vehicle servicer” means any person engaging in the business of operating a liquefied petroleum gas dispensing unit for the purpose of serving liquid product to the ultimate consumer for industrial, commercial, or domestic use, and selling or offering to sell, or leasing or offering to lease, apparatus, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum gas, and whose services include the installation, service, or repair of recreational vehicle liquefied petroleum gas appliances and equipment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“LP gas installer” means any person who is engaged in the liquefied petroleum gas business and whose services include the installation, servicing, altering, or modifying of apparatus, piping, tubing, tanks, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum or natural gas and selling or offering to sell, or leasing or offering to lease, apparatus, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum or natural gas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Specialty installer” means any person involved in the installation, service, or repair of liquefied petroleum or natural gas appliances and equipment, and selling or offering to sell, or leasing or offering to lease, apparatus, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum gas, whose activities are limited to specific types of appliances and equipment as designated by department rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer in appliances and equipment for use of liquefied petroleum gas” means any person selling or offering to sell, or leasing or offering to lease, apparatus, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum gas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer of liquefied petroleum gas appliances and equipment” means any person in this state manufacturing and offering for sale or selling tanks, cylinders, or other containers and necessary appurtenances for use in the storage, transportation, or delivery of such gas to the ultimate consumer, or manufacturing and offering for sale or selling apparatus, appliances, and equipment for the use of liquefied petroleum gas to the ultimate consumer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wholesaler” means any person, as defined by subsection (2), selling or offering to sell any liquefied petroleum gas for industrial, commercial, or domestic use to any person except the ultimate consumer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Requalifier of cylinders” means any person involved in the retesting, repair, qualifying, or requalifying of liquefied petroleum gas tanks or cylinders manufactured under specifications of the United States Department of Transportation or former Interstate Commerce Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fabricator, repairer, and tester of vehicles and cargo tanks” means any person involved in the hydrostatic testing, fabrication, repair, or requalifying of any motor vehicles or cargo tanks used for the transportation of liquefied petroleum gases, when such tanks are permanently attached to or forming a part of the motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recreational vehicle” means a motor vehicle designed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use, which has its own propulsion or is mounted on or towed by another motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pipeline system operator” means any person who owns or operates a liquefied petroleum gas pipeline system that is used to transmit liquefied petroleum gas from a common source to the ultimate customer and that serves 10 or more customers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Category V liquefied petroleum gases dealer for industrial uses only” means any person engaged in the business of filling, selling, and transporting liquefied petroleum gas containers for use in welding, forklifts, or other industrial applications.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 24302, 1947; s. 11, ch. 25035, 1949; s. 1, ch. 57-174; s. 1, ch. 61-158; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 202, ch. 71-377; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 1, 6, ch. 80-390; ss. 1, 18, 19, ch. 81-175; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 2, ch. 82-6; s. 124, ch. 83-218; s. 1, ch. 86-69; ss. 2, 3, ch. 87-34; s. 1, ch. 90-215; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 92-324; s. 7, ch. 93-142; ss. 1, 7, ch. 93-248; s. 1, ch. 2000-269; s. 23, ch. 2001-63; s. 1, ch. 2003-132.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 526.12.</Text></Note></Section>