<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0527.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to Florida Propane Gas Education, Safety, and Research Act.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 527.20-527.23, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Council” means the Florida Propane Gas Education, Safety, and Research Council created by this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Agriculture or the commissioner’s designee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” means a business engaged primarily in selling propane gas and its appliances and equipment to the ultimate consumer or to retail propane gas dispensers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Education” means any action to provide information to consumers and to members of the propane gas industry concerning propane gas, propane gas use equipment, mechanical and technical practices, and propane gas uses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer and distributor of propane gas use equipment” means any person or firm engaged in manufacturing, assembling, and marketing appliances, containers, and products used in the propane gas industry, and any person or firm engaged in the wholesale marketing of appliances, containers, and products used in the propane gas industry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marketing” means the establishment of plans and programs for advertising, sales promotion, and education to maintain present markets or to create new or larger markets for propane gas without reference to a private brand or trade name.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marketing order” means an order issued by the department prescribing rules governing the distribution, or handling in any manner, of propane gas in the state during any specified period or periods.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, group of individuals, association, cooperative, corporation, firm, or other entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Producer” means the owner of propane gas at the time it is recovered at a manufacturing facility, irrespective of the state where production occurs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Propane” includes propane, butane, mixtures, and liquefied petroleum gas as defined by National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 58, Liquefied Petroleum Gas Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public member” means a state resident, citizen-at-large member of the council who is representative of the views of the general public toward propane gas use and selected from among private nonindustrial or noncommercial users of propane gas.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified industry organization” means the National Propane Gas Association, the Florida Propane Gas Association, or a successor association.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Research” means any type of study, investigation, or other activity designed to advance the image, desirability, usage, marketability, efficiency, and safety of propane gas and propane gas use equipment and to further the development of such information and products.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail marketer class” means those persons who sell or produce propane gas.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transporter” means any person involved in the commercial transportation of propane gas by pipeline, truck, rail, or water.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wholesaler” or “reseller” means a seller of propane gas who is not a producer and who does not sell propane gas to the ultimate consumer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-105; s. 2, ch. 2011-106; s. 20, ch. 2011-222.</History>
</Section>