<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0527.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is empowered to enforce all provisions of this chapter and rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter relating to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The safe handling, installing, storing, selling, utilizing, transporting, servicing, testing, repairing, or maintaining of liquefied petroleum gas, liquefied petroleum gas equipment, and liquefied petroleum gas systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable standards of competency required of persons to safely engage in the business of handling, installing, storing, selling, utilizing, transporting, servicing, testing, repairing, or maintaining liquefied petroleum gas, liquefied petroleum gas equipment, or liquefied petroleum gas systems, including, but not limited to, the training, licensure, testing, and qualifying of such persons.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the powers and authority expressly conferred on it by, or reasonably implied from, the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may conduct such investigations as it may deem proper to determine whether any person has violated any provision of this chapter or rule promulgated pursuant to this chapter or to secure information useful in the lawful administration of any such provision or rule promulgated pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may collect, propose, publish, and disseminate information relating to the subject matter of any duties imposed upon it by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 10, ch. 86-69; ss. 2, 3, ch. 87-34; s. 6, ch. 90-215; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>