<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0527.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration of transport vehicles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each liquefied petroleum gas bulk delivery vehicle owned or leased by a liquefied petroleum gas licensee must be registered with the department annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, a “liquefied petroleum gas bulk delivery vehicle” means any vehicle that is used to transport liquefied petroleum gas on any public street or highway as liquid cargo in a cargo tank, which tank is mounted on a conventional truck chassis or is an integral part of a transporting vehicle in which the tank constitutes, in whole or in part, the stress member used as a frame and is a permanent part of the transporting vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vehicle registrations shall be submitted by the vehicle owner or lessee in conjunction with the annual renewal of his or her liquefied petroleum gas license, but no later than August 31 of each year. A dealer who does not submit the required vehicle registration by August 31 of each year is subject to the penalties in s. 527.13.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inspection fee of $50 shall be assessed for each registered vehicle inspected by the department pursuant to s. 527.061. All inspection fees collected in connection with this section shall be deposited in the General Inspection Trust Fund for the purpose of administering the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a decal to be placed on each vehicle that is inspected by the department and found to be in compliance with applicable codes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 90-215; s. 16, ch. 91-201; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 92-324; s. 7, ch. 94-335; s. 723, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>