<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Citrus; power to establish standards; rulemaking authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the power to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish state grades and minimum maturity and quality standards not inconsistent with existing laws for citrus fruits and food products thereof containing 20 percent or more citrus or citrus juice, whether canned, concentrated, or otherwise processed, including standards for frozen concentrate for manufacturing purposes, and for containers therefor. These standards must be designed to increase the acceptance and consumption by the consuming public of such regulated citrus fruits and food products thereof and may include, but are not limited to, standards for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Color break, predominant color, total soluble solids, juice content, and ratio of soluble solids of the juice to anhydrous citric acid of oranges, grapefruit, and tangerines.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Total soluble solids, juice content, and ratio of soluble solids of the juice to anhydrous citric acid of citrus fruit grown in the state for export to foreign countries other than Canada and Mexico.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Canned orange juice or frozen concentrated orange juice that is sold, offered for sale, shipped, or offered for shipment, including, but not limited to, standards for total soluble solids, ratio of soluble solids of juice to anhydrous citric acid, amount of anhydrous citric acid, amount of recoverable oil, color, taste, flavor, and absence of additives or defects, and labeling requirements for substandard juice. These standards may establish separate density, compositional, labeling, and inspection requirements for high-density frozen concentrated orange juice that is sold, offered for sale, shipped, or offered for shipment in retail, institutional, or bulk size containers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The processing, shipping, and sale of frozen concentrated orange juice and concentrated orange juice for manufacturing to which nutritive sweetening ingredients are added, including, but not limited to, total soluble solids of orange juice exclusive of the added nutritive sweetening ingredients; labeling requirements; and requirements for the inspection and reinspection of such concentrated orange juice before and after nutritive sweetening ingredients are added.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grapefruit juice products, including, but not limited to, standards for the ratio of soluble solids of juice to anhydrous citric acid and any other standards designed to increase the acceptance and consumption by the consuming public of such regulated grapefruit juice products.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Canned blends of orange juice and grapefruit juice that are sold, offered for sale, shipped, or offered for shipment, including, but not limited to, standards for total soluble solids, ratio of soluble solids of juice to anhydrous citric acid, amount of anhydrous citric acid, amount of recoverable oil, color, taste, flavor, absence of defects, and labeling requirements for substandard juice blends.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue permits for the export to foreign countries other than Canada and Mexico of citrus fruit grown in the state that complies with the standards established under subparagraph (a)2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish standards limiting any increase of spacing between stacked field boxes caused by the placement of cleats or other devices on the field boxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue and renew permits for processors of frozen concentrated orange juice and concentrated orange juice for manufacturing to which nutritive sweetening ingredients are added and, in addition to disciplinary action that may be taken by the Department of Agriculture against a citrus fruit dealer for violations of this chapter, suspend or revoke the permit of any processor that does not comply with the standards established under subparagraph (1)(a)4.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine whether freezing temperatures have caused damage or freeze-related injury as described in s. 601.89 to citrus fruit and, if the commission determines that such damage has been caused, issue emergency quality assurance orders that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Temporarily prohibit the preparation for market, sale, offer for sale, or shipment of any citrus fruit showing freeze damage or freeze-related injury.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the degree of freeze damage or freeze-related injury that is temporarily permitted in citrus fruit used in frozen concentrated products, including concentrate for manufacturing purposes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules governing:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The marking, branding, labeling, tagging, or stamping of citrus fruit, or products thereof, whether canned, concentrated, or otherwise processed, and upon containers therefor for the purpose of showing the name and address of the person marketing such citrus fruit or products thereof, whether canned, concentrated, or otherwise processed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grade, quality, variety, type, or size of citrus fruit; the grade, quality, variety, type, and amount of the products thereof, whether canned, concentrated, or otherwise processed; and the quality, type, size, dimensions, and shape of containers therefor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regulation or prohibition of the use of containers that previously have been used for the sale, transportation, or shipment of citrus fruit or the products thereof, whether canned, concentrated, or otherwise processed, or any other commodity. However, the department may not prohibit the use of secondhand containers for the sale or delivery of citrus fruit for retail consumption within the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not adopt any standard, rule, or order under this section that is inconsistent with any requirement of federal law or regulations that applies to citrus fruit, or the products thereof, whether canned, concentrated, or otherwise processed, or to containers therefor, that are being shipped from this state in interstate commerce.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All citrus fruit and the products thereof, whether canned, concentrated, or otherwise processed, sold, offered for sale, or offered for shipment within or without the state shall be graded and marked as required by this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules and orders adopted under this section, to the extent that they are not inconsistent with state or federal law, shall have the force and effect of law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 25149, 1949; s. 1, ch. 57-30; s. 22, ch. 71-186; s. 15, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>