<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Maturity standards; modification by emergency rule.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that emergencies creating abnormal conditions in the state’s citrus industry, which may include, but are not limited to, unusual climatic conditions that produce unusual growing conditions of citrus fruit, freezes and hurricanes, or other acts of God that may affect a substantial part of the citrus industry, require that the department have the power and authority to modify the maturity standards established by rule for citrus fruit or any variety thereof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the determination by the department that an emergency exists that creates abnormal conditions in the state’s citrus industry, the department, in addition to all other powers and authority provided by law, may adopt emergency rules pursuant to s. 120.54(4) that temporarily modify the maturity standards previously adopted by rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An emergency rule adopted under this subsection does not take effect unless the emergency rule is adopted by the affirmative vote of at least seven members of the commission. Notwithstanding the limitation on the effective period for emergency rules in s. 120.54(4)(c), each such emergency rule adopted under this section must contain an expiration date of not later than 1 year after its effective date.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not repeal any other section or part of this chapter and shall be deemed as supplemental and additional to the express power vested in the department, subject only to the limitations, restrictions, conditions, provisions, and standards provided in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-104; s. 22, ch. 71-186; s. 10, ch. 78-95; s. 1, ch. 92-347; s. 16, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>