<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.46" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Condition precedent to sale of citrus fruit.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful, except as provided in s. 601.50, for any person to sell or offer for sale, transport, prepare, receive, or deliver for transportation or market any citrus fruit in fresh form unless such fruit has matured in accordance with the maturity standards and is accompanied by a certificate of inspection and maturity thereof issued by a duly authorized citrus fruit inspector of the Department of Agriculture. However, the Department of Citrus may adopt rules providing that, in lieu of the accompaniment of such shipment by a certificate of inspection and maturity, the fact of such inspection may be shown by appropriate means on the manifest or bill of lading covering such shipment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspection for maturity may be made at any time, anywhere, after the fruit is severed from the tree until the shipment, after inspection and certification, is accepted by common carrier or until it has been transported beyond the state lines where being transported other than by a common carrier.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shipments in bulk, either by common carrier or otherwise, to a packinghouse for repacking in Florida must be reinspected and certified before final delivery to a carrier. However, only one inspection fee shall be paid by the shipper.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful at any time for any person to sell or offer for sale, transport, prepare, receive, or deliver for transportation or market any citrus fruit which is immature or otherwise unfit for human consumption, or for any person to receive any such citrus fruit under a contract of sale, or for the purpose of sale, offering for sale, transportation, or delivery for transportation thereof. However, these provisions shall not apply to sale of citrus fruit “on the trees” or to common carriers or their agents when the fruit accepted for transportation or transported by any common carrier is accompanied by proper proof of inspection, maturity, and grade.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 46, ch. 25149, 1949; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 71-185; ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 73-11; s. 35, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>