<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Citrus Commission; creation and membership.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the department the Florida Citrus Commission, which shall be composed of nine members appointed by the Governor. Each member must be a resident citizen of the state who is and has been actively engaged in the growing, growing and shipping, or growing and processing of citrus fruit in the state for at least 5 years immediately before appointment to the commission and has, during that 5-year period:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Derived a major portion of her or his income from such growing, growing and shipping, or growing and processing of citrus fruit; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Been the owner of, member of, officer of, or paid employee of a corporation, firm, or partnership that has, during that 5-year period, derived the major portion of its income from such growing, growing and shipping, or growing and processing of citrus fruit.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Six members of the commission shall be classified as grower members and shall be primarily engaged in the growing of citrus fruit as an individual owner; as the owner of, or as stockholder of, a corporation; or as a member of a firm or partnership primarily engaged in citrus growing. Such members may not receive any compensation from any licensed citrus fruit dealer or handler, as defined in s. 601.03, other than gift fruit shippers, but any of the grower members shall not be disqualified as a member if, individually, or as the owner of, a member of, an officer of, or a stockholder of a corporation, firm, or partnership primarily engaged in citrus growing which processes, packs, and markets its own fruit and whose business is primarily not purchasing and handling fruit grown by others.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members of the commission shall be classified as grower-handler members and shall be engaged as owners, or as paid officers or employees, of a corporation, firm, partnership, or other business unit engaged in handling citrus fruit. One such member shall be primarily engaged in the fresh fruit business, and two such members shall be primarily engaged in the processing of citrus fruits.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three commission members shall be appointed from each of the three citrus districts designated in s. 601.09. Members appointed from the same citrus district shall serve staggered terms, such that the term of one of the district’s three members expires each year. Each member must reside in the district from which she or he was appointed. For the purposes of this section, a member’s residence is her or his actual physical and permanent residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members shall be appointed to terms of 3 years each, except that, to establish staggered terms of members from each citrus district, the terms of members appointed before July 1, 2012, shall be shortened as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of one member from each citrus district shall expire June 30, 2012, and her or his successor shall be appointed to a term beginning July 1, 2012, and expiring May 31, 2015.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of one member from each citrus district shall expire June 30, 2013, and her or his successor shall be appointed to a term beginning July 1, 2013, and expiring May 31, 2016.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of one member from each citrus district shall expire June 30, 2014, and her or his successor shall be appointed to a term beginning July 1, 2014, and ending May 31, 2017.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequent appointments shall be made in accordance with this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Appointments shall be made by February 1 preceding the commencement of the term and are subject to confirmation by the Senate in the following legislative session. Each member is eligible for reappointment and shall serve until her or his successor is appointed and qualified. The regular terms begin on June 1 and expire on May 31 of the third year after such appointment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When appointments are made, the Governor shall publicly announce the actual classification and district that each appointee represents. A majority of the members of the commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of all business and the carrying out of the duties of the commission. Before entering upon the discharge of their duties as members of the commission, each member shall take and subscribe to the oath of office prescribed in s. 5, Art. II of the State Constitution. The qualifications and classification required of each member by this section continue to be required throughout the respective term of office, and if a member, after appointment, fails to meet the qualifications or classification that she or he possessed at the time of appointment, the member must resign or be removed and be replaced with a member possessing the proper qualifications and classification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When making an appointment to the commission, the Governor shall announce the district, classification, and term of the person appointed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall elect a chair and secretary and may elect a vice chair and such other officers as the commission deems advisable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair, subject to commission concurrence, may appoint such advisory committees or councils composed of industry representatives as the chair deems appropriate, setting forth the committee or council concerns that are consistent with the statutory powers and duties of the commission and the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 16854, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. (57); s. 1, ch. 20449, 1941; s. 1, ch. 22535, 1945; s. 4, ch. 25149, 1949; s. 10, ch. 26484, 1951; s. 1, ch. 59-11; s. 1, ch. 65-71; s. 33, ch. 69-216; ss. 29, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 257, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 79-84; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 1, ch. 85-49; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 88-55; s. 1, ch. 90-127; s. 1, ch. 91-11; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 95-174; s. 968, ch. 97-103; s. 78, ch. 2000-154; s. 2, ch. 2005-6; s. 1, ch. 2009-112; s. 13, ch. 2011-56; s. 6, ch. 2012-182.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 595.01; s. 601.10.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>