<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grading of fresh citrus fruit.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All citrus fruit, except as provided in s. 601.50, sold or shipped, or offered for sale or shipment, for consumption in fresh form shall be graded in a registered packinghouse in this state according to standards established by the department, and the grade of such fruit shall be indicated as provided in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fresh citrus fruit being transported in bulk form shall have stamped upon such fruit, subject to department rules:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actual grade thereof; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Brands or trademarks properly registered with the department to represent state or U.S. grades, as provided in subsection (4).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For fresh citrus fruit being transported when packed in a closed container approved or otherwise authorized by the department, it shall be sufficient if the closed container has the grade indicated thereon, in accordance with department rules, by:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stamping the grade of the fruit on the container; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of labels, brands, or trademarks properly registered with the department to represent state or U.S. grades, as provided in subsection (4).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with such rules as the department may prescribe, licensed citrus fruit dealers in this state are entitled to register labels, brands, or trademarks for grade identification purposes. The department shall maintain a record of all labels, brands, or trademarks registered for grade identification purposes, which record may be purged as necessary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 45, ch. 25149, 1949; s. 1, ch. 57-29; s. 22, ch. 71-186; s. 1, ch. 77-4; s. 34, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>