<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Citrus fruit dealers; unlawful acts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful in, or in connection with, any transaction relative to the purchase, handling, sale, and accounting of sales of citrus fruit:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any citrus fruit dealer to make or exact any fraudulent charge to or from any person;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any citrus fruit dealer to reject or fail to deliver in accordance with the terms of the contract without reasonable cause any citrus fruit bought, sold, or contracted to be bought or sold by such citrus fruit dealer;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any citrus fruit dealer to discard, dump, or destroy without reasonable cause any citrus fruit received by such citrus fruit dealer;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any citrus fruit dealer to make, for a fraudulent purpose, any false or misleading statement concerning the condition, quality, quantity, or disposition of, or the condition of the market for, any citrus fruit which is received by such citrus fruit dealer or bought or sold or contracted to be bought or sold by such citrus fruit dealer; or the purchase or sale of which is negotiated by such citrus fruit dealer; or to fail or refuse truly and correctly to account and make full payment promptly in respect of any such transaction in any such citrus fruit to the person with whom such transaction is had, or to fail or refuse on such account to make full payment of such amounts as may be due thereon, or to fail without reasonable cause to perform any specification or duty express or implied arising out of any undertaking in connection with any such transaction;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any citrus fruit dealer to knowingly buy, sell, receive, process, or handle stolen citrus fruit;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any citrus fruit dealer to violate, or aid or abet in the violation of, any law of Florida governing or applicable to citrus fruit dealers, including any of the provisions of this chapter not herein specifically set forth;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any citrus fruit dealer to violate or aid or abet in the violation of any rule adopted by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 64, ch. 25149, 1949; s. 10, ch. 26484, 1951; s. 1, ch. 65-82; s. 22, ch. 71-186; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 3, ch. 85-129; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 49, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>