<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of dealers’ licenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever an application bears the approved endorsement of the Department of Citrus and satisfactions of conditions of approval, if any, and the applicant has paid the prescribed fee, the Department of Agriculture shall issue to such applicant a license, as approved by the Department of Citrus, which shall entitle the licensee to do business as a citrus fruit dealer during the effective term of such license in accordance with s. 601.55 or, if applicable, until such license is suspended or revoked by the Department of Agriculture in accordance with law. The Department of Agriculture may issue a provisional license for a period of no longer than 1 year to an applicant who is under investigation for an action that would constitute a violation of this chapter or has pending against such applicant an administrative or civil proceeding that alleges an action that would constitute a violation of this chapter. The department shall establish by rule requirements for renewal of a provisional license. When the investigation is complete or the pending proceeding has been disposed of, the Department of Agriculture may issue a regular license under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the effective term of such license, there is any change in the ownership, officers, managership, or stockholders of any copartnership, association, corporation, or other business unit to which a license has been issued, the licensee shall immediately notify the Department of Citrus in writing specifying the change in detail. The Department of Citrus may receive, and the licensee must promptly furnish, such additional information as if the licensee were applying for a new license. If, after investigating the facts and applying the standards prescribed for the issuance of new licenses, the commission finds that the licensee is not entitled to a citrus fruit dealer’s license, the commission shall recommend to the Department of Agriculture that such existing license be suspended or revoked, and upon such recommendation, the Department of Agriculture shall immediately take necessary steps to suspend or revoke such existing license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 60, ch. 25149, 1949; s. 1, ch. 65-81; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 71-185; s. 22, ch. 71-186; s. 1, ch. 76-11; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 3, ch. 85-129; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 12, ch. 97-220; s. 46, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>