<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0601.641" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fraudulent representations, penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, association, or corporation to claim or represent to be a licensed citrus fruit dealer, licensed and bonded citrus dealer, or agent of a licensed citrus fruit dealer unless such person, firm, association, or corporation is licensed, licensed and bonded, or a registered agent of a licensed citrus fruit dealer under the Laws of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, association, or corporation to advertise or in any way represent falsely as to her or his status as a seller of citrus fruit, to make any false claim as to the status of such seller of citrus fruit, or to make any false claim as to the condition, grade, quality, quantity, grove origin, or producer’s name and address of any citrus fruit sold by any such person, firm, association, or corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, association, or corporation licensed under this chapter to advertise or to use on her or his letterhead, or on any advertising material, or in any way pretend to be a bonded shipper unless said person, firm, association, or corporation has filed and had approved a performance bond in addition to the bond required under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is supplemental, making provisions in addition to any other provisions of law and shall be construed liberally.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, association, or corporation violating any of the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Such criminal penalties shall be in addition to any other penalties provided by law. If the violator be a licensed citrus fruit dealer, then such license may be revoked or suspended in the manner provided by s. 601.67.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-5, ch. 57-4; s. 1, ch. 61-92; s. 1, ch. 65-84; s. 625, ch. 71-136; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 3, ch. 85-129; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 980, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>