<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.69" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Records to be kept by citrus fruit dealers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every citrus fruit dealer shall make and keep a correct record showing in detail the following with reference to the purchase, handling, sale, and accounting of sale of citrus fruit handled by her or him, namely:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the producers or other persons from whom the citrus fruit was procured, and, if same was procured from some person other than a licensed citrus fruit dealer, the name and address of the producer of said fruit;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date citrus fruit is received, the amount thereof, and the purchase price paid therefor if purchased for the purpose of resale;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The condition of such citrus fruit upon receipt by the citrus fruit dealer;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the citrus fruit is handled on consignment for the account of the producer, the date of sale and the selling price;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An itemized statement of the charges to be paid by the producer in connection with any sale;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A detailed statement of all claims made by producers against the citrus fruit dealer, a copy of each when received to be certified and filed with the Department of Agriculture;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the record and account of sale of citrus fruit handled on consignment or commission shall be delivered to the producer upon the consummation of the sale, together with all moneys received by the citrus fruit dealer in payment for such transaction made upon account of the producer, less the agreed commission and other charges which must be separately itemized, and said payment and accounting must be made by said citrus fruit dealer to the producer within 15 days after said citrus fruit dealer receives the money in payment of said citrus fruit unless otherwise specified in contract between citrus fruit dealers and producer;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A detailed statement and record of the resale or commercial disposition of citrus fruit so purchased by the dealer for purpose of resale or other commercial disposition, showing the number of boxes resold, the moneys received by such dealer upon such resale of the fruit, the person or dealer and address thereof to whom sold, the date of such resale, and how delivered to such purchaser;</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other record or account required to be kept and maintained by such dealer by rule adopted by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 69, ch. 25149, 1949; s. 1, ch. 65-78; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 71-185; s. 22, ch. 71-186; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 3, ch. 85-129; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 984, ch. 97-103; s. 52, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>