<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0601.601" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration of dealers’ agents.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed citrus fruit dealer shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Register with the Department of Agriculture each agent as defined in s. 601.03 who is authorized to represent such dealer; apply for registration of such agent or agents on a form approved by the Department of Agriculture and filed with the Department of Agriculture at least 5 days before the active participation of the agent or agents on behalf of such dealer in any transaction described in s. 601.03; and be held fully liable for and legally bound by all contracts and agreements, verbal or written, involving the consignment, purchase, or sale of citrus fruit executed by a duly registered agent on the dealer’s behalf during the entire period of valid registration of such agent the same as though such contracts or agreements were executed by the dealer. Registration of each agent shall be for the entire shipping season for which the applying dealer’s license is issued; however, a licensed dealer may cancel the registration of any agent registered by her or him by returning the agent’s identification card to the Department of Agriculture and giving formal written notice to the Department of Agriculture of at least 10 days. In addition, such dealer shall make every effort to alert the public to the fact that the agent is no longer authorized to represent her or him. An agent may be registered by more than one licensed dealer for the same shipping season, provided that each licensed dealer applies individually for registration of the agent and further provided that written consent is given by each and every dealer under whose license the agent has valid prior registration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the requirements of subsection (1) and such additional requirements set forth by rules adopted by the Department of Citrus for registration of an agent are met and the fee required by s. 601.59(2) is paid, the Department of Agriculture shall duly register the agent and issue an identification card certifying such registration. The identification card, among other things, shall show in a prominent manner:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the agent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authorizing dealer’s name, address, and license number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective date and season for which registration is made.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A space for signature of the agent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A space to be countersigned by the licensed dealer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement providing that the card is not valid unless so signed and countersigned.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department may periodically adopt, as necessary, additional requirements or conditions relating to the registration of agents.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-75; s. 1, ch. 65-86; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 71-185; s. 22, ch. 71-186; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 2, ch. 83-142; ss. 1, 3, ch. 85-129; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 978, ch. 97-103; s. 47, ch. 2012-182.</History>
</Section>