<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0680.529" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lessor’s action for the rent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After default by the lessee under the lease contract of the type described in s. 680.523(1) or (3)(a) or, if agreed, after other default by the lessee, if the lessor complies with subsection (2), the lessor may recover from the lessee as damages:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For goods accepted by the lessee and not repossessed by or tendered to the lessor and for conforming goods lost or damaged after risk of loss passes to the lessee (s. 680.219):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of entry of judgment in favor of the lessor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The present value as of the same date of the rent for the then remaining lease term of the lease agreement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any incidental damages allowed under s. 680.53, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For goods identified to the lease contract if the lessor is unable after reasonable effort to dispose of them at a reasonable price or the circumstances reasonably indicate that such an effort will be unavailing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of entry of judgment in favor of the lessor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The present value as of the same date of the rent for the then remaining lease term of the lease agreement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any incidental damages allowed under s. 680.53, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (3), the lessor shall hold for the lessee for the remaining lease term of the lease agreement any goods that have been identified to the lease contract and are in the lessor’s control.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lessor may dispose of the goods at any time before collection of the judgment for damages obtained pursuant to subsection (1). If the disposition is before the end of the remaining lease term of the lease agreement, the lessor’s recovery against the lessee for damages is governed by s. 680.527 or s. 680.528, and the lessor will cause an appropriate credit to be provided against any judgment for damages to the extent that the amount of the judgment exceeds the recovery available pursuant to s. 680.527 or s. 680.528.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of the judgment for damages obtained pursuant to subsection (1) entitles the lessee to the use and possession of the goods not then disposed of for the remaining lease term of and in accordance with the lease agreement, provided that the lessee complies with all other terms and conditions of the lease agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a default by the lessee under the lease contract of the type described in s. 680.523(1) or (3)(a) or, if agreed, after other default by the lessee, a lessor who is held not entitled to rent under this section must nevertheless be awarded damages for nonacceptance under ss. 680.527 and 680.528.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-278; s. 45, ch. 98-11.</History></Section>