<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0680.518" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cover; substitute goods.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After default by a lessor under the lease contract of the type described in s. 680.508, or, if agreed, after another default by the lessor, the lessee may cover by making any purchase or lease of or contract to purchase or lease goods in substitution for those due from the lessor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided with respect to damages liquidated in the lease agreement (s. 680.504) or otherwise determined pursuant to agreement of the parties (ss. 671.102(2) and 680.503), if a lessee’s cover is by lease agreement substantially similar to the original lease agreement and the new lease agreement is made in good faith and in a commercially reasonable manner, the lessee may recover from the lessor as damages:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The present value, as of the date of the commencement of the term of the new lease agreement, of the rent under the new lease agreement and applicable to that period of the new lease term which is comparable to the then remaining term of the original lease agreement minus the present value as of the same date of the total rent for the then remaining lease term of the original lease agreement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any incidental or consequential damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessor’s default.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a lessee’s cover is by lease agreement that qualifies for treatment under subsection (2), the lessee may elect to proceed under subsection (2) or s. 680.519. If a lessee’s cover is by lease agreement that for any reason does not qualify for treatment under subsection (2), or is by purchase or otherwise, the lessee may recover from the lessor as if the lessee had elected not to cover.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-278; s. 38, ch. 98-11; s. 27, ch. 2007-134.</History></Section>