<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0680.219" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Risk of loss.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except in the case of a finance lease, the risk of loss is retained by the lessor and does not pass to the lessee, unless the loss resulted from the lessee’s negligence. In the case of a finance lease, the risk of loss passes to the lessee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of this chapter on the effect of default on the risk of loss (s. 680.22), if the risk of loss is to pass to the lessee and the time of passage is not stated, the following rules apply:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the lease contract requires or authorizes the goods to be shipped by carrier and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the lease contract does not require delivery at a particular destination, the risk of loss passes to the lessee when the goods are duly delivered to the carrier.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the lease contract does require delivery at a particular destination and the goods are there tendered while in the possession of the carrier, the risk of loss passes to the lessee when the goods are there duly so tendered as to enable the lessee to take delivery.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the goods are held by a bailee to be delivered without being moved, the risk of loss passes to the lessee on acknowledgment by the bailee of the lessee’s right to possession of the goods.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case not within paragraph (a) or paragraph (b), the risk of loss passes to the lessee on the lessee’s receipt of the goods if the lessor, or, in the case of a finance lease, the supplier, is a merchant; otherwise, the risk passes to the lessee on tender of delivery.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-278.</History></Section>