<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0689.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Termination by servicemember of agreement to purchase real property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law and for the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Closing” means the finalizing of the sale of property, upon which title to the property is transferred from the seller to the buyer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contract” means an instrument purporting to contain an agreement to purchase real property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property” means a house, condominium, or mobile home that a servicemember intends to purchase to serve as his or her primary residence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Servicemember” shall have the same meaning as provided in s. 250.01.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any servicemember may terminate a contract to purchase property, prior to closing on such property, by providing the seller or mortgagor of the property with a written notice of termination to be effective immediately, if any of the following criteria are met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The servicemember is required, pursuant to permanent change of station orders received after entering into a contract for the property and prior to closing, to move 35 miles or more from the location of the property;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The servicemember is released from active duty or state active duty after having agreed to purchase the property and prior to closing while serving on active duty or state active duty status, and the property is 35 miles or more from the servicemember’s home of record prior to entering active duty or state active duty;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to closing, the servicemember receives military orders requiring him or her to move into government quarters or the servicemember becomes eligible to live in and opts to move into government quarters; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to closing, the servicemember receives temporary duty orders, temporary change of station orders, or active duty or state active duty orders to an area 35 miles or more from the location of the property, provided such orders are for a period exceeding 90 days.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice to the seller or mortgagor canceling the contract must be accompanied by either a copy of the official military orders or a written verification signed by the servicemember’s commanding officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon termination of a contract under this section, the seller or mortgagor or his or her agent shall refund any funds provided by the servicemember under the contract within 7 days. The servicemember is not liable for any other fees due to the termination of the contract as provided for in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section may not be waived or modified by the agreement of the parties under any circumstances.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 2003-72.</History></Section>