<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0689.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inter vivos trusts; powers retained by settlor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trust which is otherwise valid and which complies with s. 736.0403, including, but not limited to, a trust the principal of which is composed of real property, intangible personal property, tangible personal property, the possible expectancy of receiving as a named beneficiary death benefits as described in s. 733.808, or any combination thereof, and which has been created by a written instrument shall not be held invalid or an attempted testamentary disposition for any one or more of the following reasons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the settlor or another person or both possess the power to revoke, amend, alter, or modify the trust in whole or in part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the settlor or another person or both possess the power to appoint by deed or will the persons and organizations to whom the income shall be paid or the principal distributed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the settlor or another person or both possess the power to add to, or withdraw from, the trust all or any part of the principal or income at one time or at different times;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the settlor or another person or both possess the power to remove the trustee or trustees and appoint a successor trustee or trustees;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the settlor or another person or both possess the power to control the trustee or trustees in the administration of the trust;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the settlor has retained the right to receive all or part of the income of the trust during her or his life or for any part thereof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the settlor is, at the time of the execution of the instrument, or thereafter becomes, sole trustee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained herein shall affect the validity of those accounts, including but not limited to bank accounts, share accounts, deposits, certificates of deposit, savings certificates, and other similar arrangements, heretofore or hereafter established at any bank, savings and loan association, or credit union by one or more persons, in trust for one or more other persons, which arrangements are, by their terms, revocable by the person making the same until her or his death or incompetency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fact that any one or more of the powers specified in subsection (1) are in fact exercised once, or more than once, shall not affect the validity of the trust or its nontestamentary character.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be applicable to trusts executed before or after July 1, 1969, by persons who are living on or after said date.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amendment of this section, by chapter 75-74, Laws of Florida, is intended to clarify the legislative intent of this section at the time of its original enactment that it apply to all otherwise valid trusts which are created by written instrument and which are not expressly excluded by the terms of this section and that no such trust shall be declared invalid for any of the reasons stated in subsections (1) and (3) regardless of whether the trust involves or relates to an interest in real property.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-192; s. 1, ch. 69-1747; ss. 1, 2, ch. 71-126; s. 169, ch. 73-333; s. 1, ch. 74-78; ss. 1, 2, ch. 75-74; s. 5, ch. 95-401; s. 756, ch. 97-102; s. 22, ch. 2006-217.</History></Section>