<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0337.404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Removal or relocation of utility facilities; notice and order; court review.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever it becomes necessary for the authority to perform utility work as provided in s. 337.403, the owner of the utility or the owner’s chief agent shall be given notice that the authority will perform such work and, after the work is completed, shall be given an order requiring the payment of the cost thereof and a reasonable time, which may not be less than 20 or more than 30 days, in which to appear before the authority to contest the reasonableness of the order. Should the owner or the owner’s representative not appear, the determination of the cost to the owner shall be final. Authorities considered agencies for the purposes of chapter 120 shall adjudicate removal or relocation of utilities pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final order of the authority shall constitute a lien on any property of the owner and may be enforced by filing an authenticated copy of the order in the office of the clerk of the circuit court of the county wherein the owner’s property is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner may obtain judicial review of the final order of the authority within the time and in the manner provided by the Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure by filing in the circuit court of the county in which the utility was relocated a petition for a writ of certiorari in the manner prescribed by said rules or in the manner provided by chapter 120 when the respondent is an agency for purposes of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 130, ch. 29965, 1955; s. 16, ch. 63-512; s. 1, ch. 69-267; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 56, ch. 78-95; s. 144, ch. 84-309; s. 500, ch. 95-148; s. 36, ch. 2012-174.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 338.20.</Text></Note></Section>