<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0337.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exercise of power of eminent domain by department; procedure; title; cost.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The power of eminent domain is vested in the department to condemn all necessary lands and property, including rights of access, air, view, and light, whether public or private, for the purpose of securing and utilizing transportation rights-of-way, including, but not limited to, any lands reasonably necessary for securing applicable permits, areas necessary for management of access, borrow pits, drainage ditches, water retention areas, rest areas, replacement access for landowners whose access is impaired due to the construction of a facility, and replacement rights-of-way for relocated rail and utility facilities; for existing, proposed, or anticipated transportation facilities on the State Highway System or State Park Road System; or in a transportation corridor designated by the department; or for the purposes of screening, relocation, removal, or disposal of junkyards and scrap metal processing facilities. The department shall also have the power to condemn any material and property necessary for such purposes. The secretary of the Department of Transportation may delegate the authority to execute eminent domain resolutions to the department’s chief administrative officer of the district in which the property is located, or to the chief administrative officer of the Office of Florida Turnpike if the property is to be acquired for a turnpike system project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Title to any land acquired in the name of the department vests in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to pay the judgment or compensation, including deposits required, awarded in any such proceedings out of any funds available to the department for the maintenance or construction of any transportation facility on the State Highway System, on the State Park Road System, or in a transportation corridor designated by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department acquires property for a transportation facility or in a transportation corridor through the exercise of eminent domain authority, or by purchase or donation, it is not subject to any liability imposed by chapter 376 or chapter 403 for preexisting soil or groundwater contamination due solely to its ownership. This section does not affect the rights or liabilities of any past or future owners of the acquired property nor does it affect the liability of any governmental entity for the results of its actions which create or exacerbate a pollution source. The department and the Department of Environmental Protection may enter into interagency agreements for the performance, funding, and reimbursement of the investigative and remedial acts necessary for property acquired by the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 106, ch. 29965, 1955; s. 18, ch. 57-318; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 80-312; s. 165, ch. 84-309; s. 2, ch. 84-319; s. 3, ch. 87-164; s. 1, ch. 87-242; s. 18, ch. 88-168; s. 6, ch. 89-232; s. 132, ch. 92-152; s. 166, ch. 94-356; s. 64, ch. 99-385.</History></Section>