<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0337.139" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Efforts to encourage awarding contracts to disadvantaged business enterprises.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In implementing chapter 90-136, Laws of Florida, the Department of Transportation shall institute procedures to encourage the awarding of contracts for professional services and construction to disadvantaged business enterprises. For the purposes of this section, the term “disadvantaged business enterprise” means a small business concern certified by the Department of Transportation to be owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals as defined by the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU). The Department of Transportation shall develop and implement activities to encourage the participation of disadvantaged business enterprises in the contracting process. Such efforts may include:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Presolicitation or prebid meetings for the purpose of informing disadvantaged business enterprises of contracting opportunities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written notice to disadvantaged business enterprises of contract opportunities for commodities or contractual and construction services which the disadvantaged business provides.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision of adequate information to disadvantaged business enterprises about the plans, specifications, and requirements of contracts or the availability of jobs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Breaking large contracts into several single-purpose contracts of a size which may be obtained by certified disadvantaged business enterprises.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 45, ch. 90-136; s. 84, ch. 99-385; s. 32, ch. 2012-174.</History></Section>