<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0337.167" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administrative procedures; stays and injunctions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate to bid on a department contract, or to supply services to the department, is intended to assist the department in determining in advance the performance capabilities of entities seeking to supply goods and services to the department and is not a “license” as defined in s. 120.52. The denial or revocation of a certificate is not subject to the provisions of s. 120.60 or s. 120.68(3). The provisions of ss. 120.569 and 120.57 are applicable to the denial or revocation of such certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of promulgating emergency rules, the continuation of the bidding, contracting, or supplying privileges of a convicted contractor or its affiliate represents an immediate danger to the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The denial or revocation of a certificate for reasons of contract crime may not be stayed by the department or by the Division of Administrative Hearings during the pendency of any judicial review proceedings concerning a final order of denial or revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court may grant a stay or injunction in an action relating to the denial or revocation of a certificate only upon the posting of a bond by the petitioner seeking a stay or injunction, and provided the court granting the stay or injunction finds that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petitioner has a substantial likelihood of success on the merits;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The threatened harm or injury to the petitioner clearly outweighs any possible injury to the state occasioned by granting the stay or injunction; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is in the public interest to grant the stay or injunction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 83-4; s. 40, ch. 91-221; s. 73, ch. 96-410.</History></Section>