<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0337.2735" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recording of municipal maps of reservation for transportation corridors and transportation facilities; establishment of building setback lines; restrictions on issuance of development permits; hearings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a municipality may approve maps of reservation for any transportation facility or transportation corridor within the municipality’s jurisdiction. Any such maps shall delineate the limits of the transportation corridor or of the proposed rights-of-way for the eventual widening of an existing or proposed transportation facility. Before recording such map, the municipality shall advertise and hold a public hearing and shall notify all property owners of record within the limits of the transportation corridor or rights-of-way of the transportation facility shown on the proposed map, as recorded in the property appraiser’s office, by mail at least 20 days prior to the date set for the hearing. After the public hearing, the municipality shall send the map to the clerk of the court of the county, who shall forthwith record the map in accordance with chapter 177 in the public land records of the county. Minor amendments to such maps are not subject to the notice and public hearing provisions of this section, except that property owners directly affected by changes in a minor amendment must be notified by mail. Minor amendments are defined as those changes which affect less than 5 percent of the total area within the map.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon recording, such map shall establish a building setback line from the centerline of any transportation facility and an area of proposed right-of-way and shall cite the ordinance which defines building restrictions for such maps.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to filing any map pursuant to this section, a municipality shall have adopted an ordinance defining the types of restrictions on nonresidential and residential construction within the proposed rights-of-way and building setback lines. In no case, however, shall said ordinance restrict the renovation of an existing residential structure when the renovation does not exceed 20 percent of the appraised value of the structure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon petition by any property owner of record within the limits of the map alleging that such property regulation is unreasonable or arbitrary and that its effect is to deny a substantial portion of the beneficial use of such property, the municipality shall hold a hearing. When such a hearing results in a finding in favor of the petitioning property owner, the municipality shall have 180 days from the date of such finding to acquire such property, to amend the map, to withdraw the map, to issue the permit, or to file appropriate proceedings. Either party may seek appellate review.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be regarded as supplemental and additional to the powers conferred upon municipalities by s. 2, Art. VIII of the State Constitution and by law and shall not be regarded as in derogation of any powers now existing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 88-168.</History></Section>