<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0337.406" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful use of state transportation facility right-of-way; penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except when leased as provided in s. 337.25(5) or otherwise authorized by the rules of the department, it is unlawful to make any use of the right-of-way of any state transportation facility, including appendages thereto, outside of an incorporated municipality in any manner that interferes with the safe and efficient movement of people and property from place to place on the transportation facility. Failure to prohibit the use of right-of-way in this manner will endanger the health, safety, and general welfare of the public by causing distractions to motorists, unsafe pedestrian movement within travel lanes, sudden stoppage or slowdown of traffic, rapid lane changing and other dangerous traffic movement, increased vehicular accidents, and motorist injuries and fatalities. Such prohibited uses include, but are not limited to, the free distribution or sale, or display or solicitation for free distribution or sale, of any merchandise, goods, property or services; the solicitation for charitable purposes; the servicing or repairing of any vehicle, except the rendering of emergency service; the storage of vehicles being serviced or repaired on abutting property or elsewhere; and the display of advertising of any sort, except that any portion of a state transportation facility may be used for an art festival, parade, fair, or other special event if permitted by the appropriate local governmental entity. Local government entities may issue permits of limited duration for the temporary use of the right-of-way of a state transportation facility for any of these prohibited uses if it is determined that the use will not interfere with the safe and efficient movement of traffic and the use will cause no danger to the public. The permitting authority granted in this subsection shall be exercised by the municipality within incorporated municipalities and by the county outside an incorporated municipality. Before a road on the State Highway System may be temporarily closed for a special event, the local governmental entity which permits the special event to take place must determine that the temporary closure of the road is necessary and must obtain the prior written approval for the temporary road closure from the department. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize such activities on any limited access highway. Local governmental entities may, within their respective jurisdictions, initiate enforcement action by the appropriate code enforcement authority or law enforcement authority for a violation of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons holding valid peddlers’ licenses issued by appropriate governmental entities may make sales from vehicles standing on the right-of-way to occupants of abutting property only.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles and other law enforcement agencies are authorized and directed to enforce this statute.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Camping is prohibited on any portion of the right-of-way of the State Highway System that is within 100 feet of a bridge, causeway, overpass, or ramp.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The violation of any provision of this section or any rule promulgated by the department pursuant to this section constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, and each day a violation continues to exist constitutes a separate offense.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-188; s. 1, ch. 79-30; s. 206, ch. 81-259; s. 168, ch. 84-309; s. 3, ch. 86-37; s. 3, ch. 87-266; s. 25, ch. 88-168; s. 9, ch. 90-227; s. 43, ch. 95-257; s. 10, ch. 2005-281; s. 23, ch. 2010-225.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 339.301.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>