<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0337.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contracting for monuments and memorials to military veterans at rest areas.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation is authorized to enter into contract with any not-for-profit group or organization that has been operating for not less than 2 years for the installation of monuments and memorials honoring Florida’s military veterans at highway rest areas around the state pursuant to the provisions of this section.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proposals for contracts must be approved by a committee composed of the Secretary of Transportation or the secretary’s designee, the executive director of the Department of Veterans’ Affairs or the executive director’s designee, and three members of the board of directors of the direct-support organization established under s. 292.055, appointed by the executive director of the Department of Veterans’ Affairs. The terms of the appointed members may not exceed 2 years and shall run concurrently with the members’ terms on the board of directors of the direct-support organization. Appointed members may be reappointed to the committee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Installations may consist of monuments or other memorials, plaques, markers, or retired military equipment that honor the accomplishments of military veterans and the sacrifices made by them and their families.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The group or organization making the proposal shall be responsible for all costs of the monument and its installation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The group or organization making the proposal shall provide an annual renewable bond, an irrevocable letter of credit, or another form of security as approved by the department’s comptroller, for the purpose of securing the cost of removal of the monument and any modifications made to the site as part of the placement of the monument should the Department of Transportation determine it necessary to remove or relocate the monument. Such removal or relocation shall be approved by the committee described in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2005-43; s. 4, ch. 2008-84; s. 29, ch. 2012-174.</History></Section>