<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0337.243" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notification of land use changes in designated transportation corridors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local government designates a transportation corridor that includes a facility on the State Highway System in its local government comprehensive plan and has adopted a transportation corridor management ordinance, the local governmental entity shall give reasonable notice by certified mail to the department prior to approving any substantial zoning change or subdivision plat changes or granting of a building permit or development permit, as defined in s. 380.031(4), for land use or the erection, alteration, or moving of a building for property within the designated transportation corridor which would substantially impair the viability of the corridor for future transportation uses. This notification requirement shall not apply to any routine maintenance or emergency repairs to existing structures. Upon notification, the department shall determine whether to purchase the property affected or to initiate eminent domain proceedings. The department’s determination shall not affect the granting or denial of the permit by the local government. The local government shall not be liable to the department for failure to make notification to the department pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any right-of-way located within a designated transportation corridor may be acquired at any time by the department when the acquisition is determined by the department to be in the public interest to protect the designated transportation corridor from development or when the transportation corridor designation creates an undue hardship on the affected property owner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 90-227; s. 40, ch. 95-143; s. 36, ch. 95-257.</History></Section>