<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0709.2111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Co-agents and successor agents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A principal may designate two or more persons to act as co-agents. Unless the power of attorney otherwise provides, each co-agent may exercise its authority independently.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A principal may designate one or more successor agents to act if an agent resigns, dies, becomes incapacitated, is not qualified to serve, or declines to serve. Unless the power of attorney otherwise provides, a successor agent:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has the same authority as that granted to the original agent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not act until the predecessor agents have resigned, have died, have become incapacitated, are no longer qualified to serve, or have declined to serve.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in the power of attorney and subsection (4), an agent who does not participate in or conceal a breach of fiduciary duty committed by another agent, including a predecessor agent, is not liable for the actions or omissions of the other agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent who has actual knowledge of a breach or imminent breach of fiduciary duty by another agent, including a predecessor agent, must take any action reasonably appropriate in the circumstances to safeguard the principal’s best interests. If the agent in good faith believes that the principal is not incapacitated, giving notice to the principal is a sufficient action. An agent who fails to take action as required by this subsection is liable to the principal for the principal’s reasonably foreseeable damages that could have been avoided if the agent had taken such action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A successor agent does not have a duty to review the conduct or decisions of a predecessor agent. Except as provided in subsection (4), a successor agent does not have a duty to institute any proceeding against a predecessor agent, or to file any claim against a predecessor agent’s estate, for any of the predecessor agent’s actions or omissions as agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a power of attorney requires that two or more persons act together as co-agents, notwithstanding the requirement that they act together, one or more of the agents may delegate to a co-agent the authority to conduct banking transactions as provided in s. 709.2208(1), whether the authority to conduct banking transactions is specifically enumerated or incorporated by reference to that section in the power of attorney.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 2011-210.</History></Section>