<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0709.2201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority of agent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section or other applicable law, an agent may only exercise authority specifically granted to the agent in the power of attorney and any authority reasonably necessary to give effect to that express grant of specific authority. General provisions in a power of attorney which do not identify the specific authority granted, such as provisions purporting to give the agent authority to do all acts that the principal can do, are not express grants of specific authority and do not grant any authority to the agent. Court approval is not required for any action of the agent in furtherance of an express grant of specific authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a confirmation of the law in effect in this state when this part became effective, such authorization may include, without limitation, authority to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute stock powers or similar documents on behalf of the principal and delegate to a transfer agent or similar person the authority to register any stocks, bonds, or other securities into or out of the principal’s or nominee’s name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Convey or mortgage homestead property. However, if the principal is married, the agent may not mortgage or convey homestead property without joinder of the principal’s spouse or the spouse’s guardian. Joinder by a spouse may be accomplished by the exercise of authority in a power of attorney executed by the joining spouse, and either spouse may appoint the other as his or her agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such authority is specifically granted in a durable power of attorney, make all health care decisions on behalf of the principal, including, but not limited to, those set forth in chapter 765.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, an agent may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform duties under a contract that requires the exercise of personal services of the principal;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any affidavit as to the personal knowledge of the principal;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vote in any public election on behalf of the principal;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute or revoke any will or codicil for the principal; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise powers and authority granted to the principal as trustee or as court-appointed fiduciary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to s. 709.2202, if the subjects over which authority is granted in a power of attorney are similar or overlap, the broadest authority controls.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authority granted in a power of attorney is exercisable with respect to property that the principal has when the power of attorney is executed and to property that the principal acquires later, whether or not the property is located in this state and whether or not the authority is exercised or the power of attorney is executed in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act performed by an agent pursuant to a power of attorney has the same effect and inures to the benefit of and binds the principal and the principal’s successors in interest as if the principal had performed the act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 2011-210.</History></Section>