<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0709.2106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Validity of power of attorney.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A power of attorney executed on or after October 1, 2011, is valid if its execution complies with s. 709.2105.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A power of attorney executed before October 1, 2011, is valid if its execution complied with the law of this state at the time of execution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A power of attorney executed in another state which does not comply with the execution requirements of this part is valid in this state if, when the power of attorney was executed, the power of attorney and its execution complied with the law of the state of execution. A third person who is requested to accept a power of attorney that is valid in this state solely because of this subsection may in good faith request, and rely upon, without further investigation, an opinion of counsel as to any matter of law concerning the power of attorney, including the due execution and validity of the power of attorney. An opinion of counsel requested under this subsection must be provided at the principal’s expense. A third person may accept a power of attorney that is valid in this state solely because of this subsection if the agent does not provide the requested opinion of counsel, and in such case, a third person has no liability for refusing to accept the power of attorney. This subsection does not affect any other rights of a third person who is requested to accept the power of attorney under this part, or any other provisions of applicable law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A military power of attorney is valid if it is executed in accordance with 10 U.S.C. s. 1044b, as amended. A deployment-contingent power of attorney may be signed in advance, is effective upon the deployment of the principal, and shall be afforded full force and effect by the courts of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in the power of attorney, a photocopy or electronically transmitted copy of an original power of attorney has the same effect as the original.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2011-210.</History></Section>