<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0709.2202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority that requires separate signed enumeration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 709.2201, an agent may exercise the following authority only if the principal signed or initialed next to each specific enumeration of the authority, the exercise of the authority is consistent with the agent’s duties under s. 709.2114, and the exercise is not otherwise prohibited by another agreement or instrument:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create an inter vivos trust;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a trust created by or on behalf of the principal, amend, modify, revoke, or terminate the trust, but only if the trust instrument explicitly provides for amendment, modification, revocation, or termination by the settlor’s agent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make a gift, subject to subsection (3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create or change rights of survivorship;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create or change a beneficiary designation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waive the principal’s right to be a beneficiary of a joint and survivor annuity, including a survivor benefit under a retirement plan; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclaim property and powers of appointment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding a grant of authority to do an act described in subsection (1), unless the power of attorney otherwise provides, an agent who is not an ancestor, spouse, or descendant of the principal may not exercise authority to create in the agent, or in an individual to whom the agent owes a legal obligation of support, an interest in the principal’s property, whether by gift, right of survivorship, beneficiary designation, disclaimer, or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the power of attorney otherwise provides, a provision in a power of attorney granting general authority with respect to gifts authorizes the agent to only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make outright to, or for the benefit of, a person a gift of any of the principal’s property, including by the exercise of a presently exercisable general power of appointment held by the principal, in an amount per donee not to exceed the annual dollar limits of the federal gift tax exclusion under 26 U.S.C. s. 2503(b), as amended, without regard to whether the federal gift tax exclusion applies to the gift, or if the principal’s spouse agrees to consent to a split gift pursuant to 26 U.S.C. s. 2513, as amended, in an amount per donee not to exceed twice the annual federal gift tax exclusion limit; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent, pursuant to 26 U.S.C. s. 2513, as amended, to the splitting of a gift made by the principal’s spouse in an amount per donee not to exceed the aggregate annual gift tax exclusions for both spouses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), if a power of attorney is otherwise sufficient to grant an agent authority to conduct banking transactions, as provided in s. 709.2208(1), conduct investment transactions as provided in s. 709.2208(2), or otherwise make additions to or withdrawals from an account of the principal, making a deposit to or withdrawal from an insurance policy, retirement account, individual retirement account, benefit plan, bank account, or any other account held jointly or otherwise held in survivorship or payable on death, is not considered to be a change to the survivorship feature or beneficiary designation, and no further specific authority is required for the agent to exercise such authority. A bank or other financial institution does not have a duty to inquire as to the appropriateness of the agent’s exercise of that authority and is not liable to the principal or any other person for actions taken in good faith reliance on the appropriateness of the agent’s actions. This subsection does not eliminate the agent’s fiduciary duties to the principal with respect to any exercise of the power of attorney.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a power of attorney executed before October 1, 2011.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 2011-210.</History></Section>