<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0709.2109" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Termination or suspension of power of attorney or agent’s authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A power of attorney terminates when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal dies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal becomes incapacitated, if the power of attorney is not durable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal is adjudicated totally or partially incapacitated by a court, unless the court determines that certain authority granted by the power of attorney is to be exercisable by the agent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal revokes the power of attorney;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The power of attorney provides that it terminates;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the power of attorney is accomplished; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent’s authority terminates and the power of attorney does not provide for another agent to act under the power of attorney.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent’s authority is exercisable until the authority terminates. An agent’s authority terminates when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent dies, becomes incapacitated, resigns, or is removed by a court;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action is filed for the dissolution or annulment of the agent’s marriage to the principal or for their legal separation, unless the power of attorney otherwise provides; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The power of attorney terminates.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person initiates judicial proceedings to determine the principal’s incapacity or for the appointment of a guardian advocate, the authority granted under the power of attorney is suspended until the petition is dismissed or withdrawn or the court enters an order authorizing the agent to exercise one or more powers granted under the power of attorney.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an emergency arises after initiation of proceedings to determine incapacity and before adjudication regarding the principal’s capacity, the agent may petition the court in which the proceeding is pending for authorization to exercise a power granted under the power of attorney. The petition must set forth the nature of the emergency, the property or matter involved, and the power to be exercised by the agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, unless otherwise ordered by the court, a proceeding to determine incapacity does not affect the authority of the agent to make health care decisions for the principal, including, but not limited to, those provided in chapter 765. If the principal has executed a health care advance directive designating a health care surrogate, the terms of the directive control if the directive and the power of attorney are in conflict unless the power of attorney is later executed and expressly states otherwise.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Termination or suspension of an agent’s authority or of a power of attorney is not effective as to an agent who, without knowledge of the termination or suspension, acts in good faith under the power of attorney. An act so performed, unless otherwise invalid or unenforceable, binds the principal and the principal’s successors in interest.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2011-210.</History></Section>