<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0709.2116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Judicial relief; conflicts of interests.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court may construe or enforce a power of attorney, review the agent’s conduct, terminate the agent’s authority, remove the agent, and grant other appropriate relief.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons may petition the court:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal or the agent, including any nominated successor agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guardian, conservator, trustee, or other fiduciary acting for the principal or the principal’s estate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person authorized to make health care decisions for the principal if the health care of the principal is affected by the actions of the agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other interested person if the person demonstrates to the court’s satisfaction that the person is interested in the welfare of the principal and has a good faith belief that the court’s intervention is necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A governmental agency having regulatory authority to protect the welfare of the principal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person asked to honor the power of attorney.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any proceeding commenced by filing a petition under this section, including, but not limited to, the unreasonable refusal of a third person to allow an agent to act pursuant to the power of attorney, and in challenges to the proper exercise of authority by the agent, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees and costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an agent’s exercise of a power is challenged in a judicial proceeding brought by or on behalf of the principal on the grounds that the exercise of the power was affected by a conflict of interest, and evidence is presented that the agent or an affiliate of the agent had a personal interest in the exercise of the power, the agent or affiliate has the burden of proving, by clear and convincing evidence that the agent acted:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solely in the interest of the principal; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In good faith in the principal’s best interest, and the conflict of interest was expressly authorized in the power of attorney.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of subsection (4):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision authorizing an agent to engage in a transaction affected by a conflict of interest which is inserted into a power of attorney as the result of the abuse of a fiduciary or confidential relationship with the principal by the agent or the agent’s affiliate is invalid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affiliates of an agent include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent’s spouse;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent’s descendants, siblings, parents, or their spouses;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation or other entity in which the agent, or a person who owns a significant interest in the agent, has an interest that might affect the agent’s best judgment;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or entity that owns a significant interest in the agent; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent acting in a fiduciary capacity for someone other than the principal.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2011-210.</History></Section>