<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0048.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service on partnerships and limited partnerships.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Process against a partnership shall be served on any partner and is as valid as if served on each individual partner. If a partner is not available during regular business hours to accept service on behalf of the partnership, he or she may designate an employee to accept such service. After one attempt to serve a partner or designated employee has been made, process may be served on the person in charge of the partnership during regular business hours. After service on any partner, plaintiff may proceed to judgment and execution against that partner and the assets of the partnership. After service on a designated employee or other person in charge, plaintiff may proceed to judgment and execution against the partnership assets but not against the individual assets of any partner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Process against a domestic limited partnership may be served on any general partner or on the agent for service of process specified in its certificate of limited partnership or in its certificate as amended or restated and is as valid as if served on each individual member of the partnership. After service on a general partner or the agent, the plaintiff may proceed to judgment and execution against the limited partnership and all of the general partners individually. If a general partner cannot be found in this state and service cannot be made on an agent because of failure to maintain such an agent or because the agent cannot be found or served with the exercise of reasonable diligence, service of process may be effected by service upon the Secretary of State as agent of the limited partnership as provided for in s. 48.181. Service of process may be made under ss. 48.071 and 48.21 on limited partnerships.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Process against a foreign limited partnership may be served on any general partner found in the state or on any agent for service of process specified in its application for registration and is as valid as if served on each individual member of the partnership. If a general partner cannot be found in this state and an agent for service of process has not been appointed or, if appointed, the agent’s authority has been revoked or the agent cannot be found or served with the exercise of reasonable diligence, service of process may be effected by service upon the Secretary of State as agent of the limited partnership as provided for in s. 48.181, or process may be served as provided in ss. 48.071 and 48.21.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, Nov. 23, 1828; RS 1017; GS 1404; RGS 2601; CGL 4248; s. 4, ch. 67-254; s. 74, ch. 86-263; s. 3, ch. 87-405; s. 272, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 47.15.</Text></Note></Section>