<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0048.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service on corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Process against any private corporation, domestic or foreign, may be served:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the president or vice president, or other head of the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of any person described in paragraph (a), on the cashier, treasurer, secretary, or general manager;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of any person described in paragraph (a) or paragraph (b), on any director; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of any person described in paragraph (a), paragraph (b), or paragraph (c), on any officer or business agent residing in the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foreign corporation has none of the foregoing officers or agents in this state, service may be made on any agent transacting business for it in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an alternative to all of the foregoing, process may be served on the agent designated by the corporation under s. 48.091. However, if service cannot be made on a registered agent because of failure to comply with s. 48.091, service of process shall be permitted on any employee at the corporation’s principal place of business or on any employee of the registered agent. A person attempting to serve process pursuant to this paragraph may serve the process on any employee of the registered agent during the first attempt at service even if the registered agent is temporarily absent from his or her office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the address provided for the registered agent, officer, director, or principal place of business is a residence or private mailbox, service on the corporation may be made by serving the registered agent, officer, or director in accordance with s. 48.031.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to service of process on insurance companies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a corporation engages in substantial and not isolated activities within this state, or has a business office within the state and is actually engaged in the transaction of business therefrom, service upon any officer or business agent while on corporate business within this state may personally be made, pursuant to this section, and it is not necessary in such case that the action, suit, or proceeding against the corporation shall have arisen out of any transaction or operation connected with or incidental to the business being transacted within the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, Nov. 21, 1829; s. 2, Feb. 11, 1834; s. 1, ch. 3590, 1885; RS 1019; GS 1406; s. 1, ch. 6908, 1915; s. 1, ch. 7752, 1918; RGS 2604; CGL 4251; s. 1, ch. 57-97; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 59-46; s. 4, ch. 67-254; s. 1, ch. 67-399; s. 6, ch. 79-396; s. 7, ch. 83-216; s. 1, ch. 84-2; s. 2, ch. 2004-273; s. 3, ch. 2011-159.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 47.17.</Text></Note></Section>