<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0048.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service on nonresident engaging in business in state.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acceptance by any person or persons, individually or associated together as a copartnership or any other form or type of association, who are residents of any other state or country, and all foreign corporations, and any person who is a resident of the state and who subsequently becomes a nonresident of the state or conceals his or her whereabouts, of the privilege extended by law to nonresidents and others to operate, conduct, engage in, or carry on a business or business venture in the state, or to have an office or agency in the state, constitutes an appointment by the persons and foreign corporations of the Secretary of State of the state as their agent on whom all process in any action or proceeding against them, or any of them, arising out of any transaction or operation connected with or incidental to the business or business venture may be served. The acceptance of the privilege is signification of the agreement of the persons and foreign corporations that the process against them which is so served is of the same validity as if served personally on the persons or foreign corporations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foreign corporation has a resident agent or officer in the state, process shall be served on the resident agent or officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, or corporation which sells, consigns, or leases by any means whatsoever tangible or intangible personal property, through brokers, jobbers, wholesalers, or distributors to any person, firm, or corporation in this state is conclusively presumed to be both engaged in substantial and not isolated activities within this state and operating, conducting, engaging in, or carrying on a business or business venture in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 6224, 1911; RGS 2602; CGL 4249; s. 1, ch. 26657, 1951; s. 1, ch. 57-747; s. 4, ch. 67-254; s. 2, ch. 84-2; s. 279, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 47.16.</Text></Note></Section>