<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0048.193" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Acts subjecting person to jurisdiction of courts of state.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, whether or not a citizen or resident of this state, who personally or through an agent does any of the acts enumerated in this subsection thereby submits himself or herself and, if he or she is a natural person, his or her personal representative to the jurisdiction of the courts of this state for any cause of action arising from the doing of any of the following acts:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operating, conducting, engaging in, or carrying on a business or business venture in this state or having an office or agency in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing a tortious act within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owning, using, possessing, or holding a mortgage or other lien on any real property within this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracting to insure any person, property, or risk located within this state at the time of contracting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a proceeding for alimony, child support, or division of property in connection with an action to dissolve a marriage or with respect to an independent action for support of dependents, maintaining a matrimonial domicile in this state at the time of the commencement of this action or, if the defendant resided in this state preceding the commencement of the action, whether cohabiting during that time or not. This paragraph does not change the residency requirement for filing an action for dissolution of marriage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Causing injury to persons or property within this state arising out of an act or omission by the defendant outside this state, if, at or about the time of the injury, either:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant was engaged in solicitation or service activities within this state; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Products, materials, or things processed, serviced, or manufactured by the defendant anywhere were used or consumed within this state in the ordinary course of commerce, trade, or use.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Breaching a contract in this state by failing to perform acts required by the contract to be performed in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a proceeding for paternity, engaging in the act of sexual intercourse within this state with respect to which a child may have been conceived.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant who is engaged in substantial and not isolated activity within this state, whether such activity is wholly interstate, intrastate, or otherwise, is subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of this state, whether or not the claim arises from that activity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service of process upon any person who is subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of this state as provided in this section may be made by personally serving the process upon the defendant outside this state, as provided in s. 48.194. The service shall have the same effect as if it had been personally served within this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a defendant in his or her pleadings demands affirmative relief on causes of action unrelated to the transaction forming the basis of the plaintiff’s claim, the defendant shall thereafter in that action be subject to the jurisdiction of the court for any cause of action, regardless of its basis, which the plaintiff may by amendment assert against the defendant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this section limits or affects the right to serve any process in any other manner now or hereinafter provided by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-179; s. 3, ch. 84-2; s. 3, ch. 88-176; s. 3, ch. 93-250; s. 281, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>