<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0048.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Method of substituted service on nonresident.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When authorized by law, substituted service of process on a nonresident or a person who conceals his or her whereabouts by serving a public officer designated by law shall be made by leaving a copy of the process with a fee of $8.75 with the public officer or in his or her office or by mailing the copies by certified mail to the public officer with the fee. The service is sufficient service on a defendant who has appointed a public officer as his or her agent for the service of process. Notice of service and a copy of the process shall be sent forthwith by registered or certified mail by the plaintiff or his or her attorney to the defendant, and the defendant’s return receipt and the affidavit of the plaintiff or his or her attorney of compliance shall be filed on or before the return day of the process or within such time as the court allows, or the notice and copy shall be served on the defendant, if found within the state, by an officer authorized to serve legal process, or if found without the state, by a sheriff or a deputy sheriff of any county of this state or any duly constituted public officer qualified to serve like process in the state or jurisdiction where the defendant is found. The officer’s return showing service shall be filed on or before the return day of the process or within such time as the court allows. The fee paid by the plaintiff to the public officer shall be taxed as cost if he or she prevails in the action. The public officer shall keep a record of all process served on him or her showing the day and hour of service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person on whom service of process is authorized under subsection (1) dies, service may be made on his or her administrator, executor, curator, or personal representative in the same manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to persons on whom service is authorized under s. 48.151.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public officer may designate some other person in his or her office to accept service.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 4, ch. 17254, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4274 (8), (10); s. 1, ch. 59-382; s. 4, ch. 67-254; s. 4, ch. 71-114; s. 1, ch. 71-308; s. 57, ch. 90-132; s. 277, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 47.30, 47.32.</Text></Note></Section>