<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0960.0021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent; advisement to victims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that in order to ensure that crime victims can effectively understand and exercise their rights under s. 16, Art. I of the State Constitution, and to promote law enforcement that considers the interests of crime victims, victims must be properly advised in the courts of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The courts may fulfill their obligation to advise crime victims by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making the following announcement at any arraignment, sentencing, or case-management proceeding:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">“If you are the victim of a crime with a case pending before this court, you are advised that you have the right:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">1. To be informed.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">2. To be present.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">3. To be heard, when relevant, at all crucial stages of criminal proceedings to the extent that these rights do not interfere with the constitutional rights of the accused.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">4. To receive advance notification, when possible, of judicial proceedings and notification of scheduling changes, pursuant to section 960.001, Florida Statutes.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">5. To seek crimes compensation and restitution.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">6. To consult with the state attorney’s office in certain felony cases regarding the disposition of the case.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">7. To make an oral or written victim impact statement at the time of sentencing of a defendant.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">For further information regarding additional rights afforded to victims of crime, you may contact the state attorney’s office or obtain a listing of your rights from the Clerk of Court.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush">; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Displaying prominently on the courtroom doors posters giving notification of the existence and general provisions of this chapter. The Department of Legal Affairs shall provide the courts with the posters specified by this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court administrator shall coordinate efforts to ensure that victim rights information, as established in s. 960.001(1)(o), is provided to the clerk of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is only for the benefit of crime victims. Accordingly, a failure to comply with this section shall not affect the validity of any hearing, conviction, or sentence.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-56.</History></Section>