<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0960.0015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Victim’s right to a speedy trial; speedy trial demand by the state attorney.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney may file a demand for a speedy trial if the state has met its obligations under the rules of discovery, the charge is a felony or misdemeanor, the court has granted at least three continuances upon the request of the defendant over the objection of the state attorney, and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a felony case, it is not resolved within 125 days after the date that formal charges are filed and the defendant is arrested or the date that notice to appear in lieu of arrest is served upon the defendant; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a misdemeanor case, it is not resolved within 45 days after the date that formal charges are filed and the defendant is arrested or the date that notice to appear in lieu of arrest is served upon the defendant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a demand for a speedy trial, the trial court shall schedule a calendar call within 5 days, at which time the court shall schedule the trial to commence no sooner than 5 days or later than 45 days following the date of the calendar call. The court may, however, grant whatever further extension may be required to prevent deprivation of the defendant’s right to due process.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trial court may postpone the trial date for up to 30 additional days upon a showing by the defendant that a necessary witness who was properly served failed to attend the deposition and also failed to attend a subsequently scheduled deposition following a court order to appear. The court may, however, grant whatever further extension may be required to prevent deprivation of the defendant’s right to due process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trial court may also postpone the trial date for no fewer than 30 days but no more than 70 days if the court grants a motion by counsel to withdraw and the court appoints other counsel. The court may, however, grant whatever further extension may be required to prevent deprivation of the defendant’s right to due process.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-44.</History></Section>