<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0960.28" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment for victims’ initial forensic physical examinations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A medical provider who performs an initial forensic physical examination may not bill a victim or the victim’s parent or guardian if the victim is a minor directly or indirectly for that examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Crime Victims’ Services Office of the department shall pay for medical expenses connected with an initial forensic physical examination of a victim of sexual battery as defined in chapter 794 or a lewd or lascivious offense as defined in chapter 800. Such payment shall be made regardless of whether the victim is covered by health or disability insurance and whether the victim participates in the criminal justice system or cooperates with law enforcement. The payment shall be made only out of moneys allocated to the Crime Victims’ Services Office for the purposes of this section, and the payment may not exceed $500 with respect to any violation. The department shall develop and maintain separate protocols for the initial forensic physical examination of adults and children. Payment under this section is limited to medical expenses connected with the initial forensic physical examination, and payment may be made to a medical provider using an examiner qualified under part I of chapter 464, excluding s. 464.003(16); chapter 458; or chapter 459. Payment made to the medical provider by the department shall be considered by the provider as payment in full for the initial forensic physical examination associated with the collection of evidence. The victim may not be required to pay, directly or indirectly, the cost of an initial forensic physical examination performed in accordance with this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may allow, deny, controvert, or litigate claims made against it under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information received or maintained by the department identifying an alleged victim who seeks payment of medical expenses under this section is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant or juvenile offender who pleads guilty or nolo contendere to, or is convicted of or adjudicated delinquent for, a violation of chapter 794 or chapter 800 shall be ordered by the court to make restitution to the Crimes Compensation Trust Fund in an amount equal to the compensation paid to the medical provider by the Crime Victims’ Services Office for the cost of the initial forensic physical examination. The order may be enforced by the department in the same manner as a judgment in a civil action.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 82-192; s. 1, ch. 83-17; s. 194, ch. 83-216; s. 6, ch. 85-326; s. 15, ch. 91-23; s. 14, ch. 92-107; s. 24, ch. 92-287; s. 1, ch. 94-94; s. 15, ch. 94-342; ss. 1, 3, ch. 95-185; s. 455, ch. 96-406; s. 9, ch. 99-373; s. 148, ch. 2000-318; s. 7, ch. 2001-209; s. 4, ch. 2007-129; s. 10, ch. 2010-37.</History>
</Section>