<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0960.294" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of civil restitution liens.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROPERTY SUBJECT TO CIVIL RESTITUTION LIEN.<EmDash />The civil restitution lien is a lien upon any real or personal property of the convicted offender. If the full amount of the civil restitution lien is not satisfied from the real or personal property owned at the time of conviction, the civil restitution lien also is a lien upon any real or personal property which the convicted offender comes to possess subsequent to conviction, until the full amount of the lien is satisfied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICABILITY OF ALL JUDGMENT ENFORCEMENT REMEDIES.<EmDash />A civil restitution lien order may be enforced by the crime victims, the state and its local subdivisions, or other aggrieved parties named in the civil restitution lien order, in the same manner as a judgment in a civil action, including levy against personal property by the sheriffs of this state and foreclosure against nonexempt real property. The provisions of chapter 726 apply to the transfer of the convicted offender’s assets to a third party and all other judgment enforcement remedies that are available by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDING OF THE CIVIL RESTITUTION LIEN; LEVY BY SHERIFF.<EmDash />The civil restitution lien order may be recorded in the public records. No charge may be assessed for the recording of the civil restitution lien order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DURATION OF THE CIVIL RESTITUTION LIEN.<EmDash />The civil restitution lien continues for a period of 20 years after the date of entry of the civil restitution lien.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RATE OF INTEREST.<EmDash />A civil restitution lien under this section bears the rate of interest set forth in s. 55.03, from the date of its entry.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 94-342; s. 32, ch. 95-184.</History></Section>