<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0960.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Crime Victims’ Services Office.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby created within the Department of Legal Affairs a Crime Victims’ Services Office, which shall be the organizational unit through which the department exercises its duties and responsibilities pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Crime Victims’ Services Office is established for the following purposes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To emphasize the rights and needs of crime victims statewide.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To ensure that the rights of victims are properly publicized and encouraged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To administer federally funded victim assistance services programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To coordinate the flow of information between all agencies and organizations which provide services for victims of crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist the development and administration of crime victim programs and services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To seek to identify the victims of crime and inform them of the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To serve as a clearinghouse for information relating to the problems encountered by the victims of crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enlist the assistance of public and voluntary health, education, welfare, and rehabilitation agencies or groups in a concerted effort to aid persons who are victims of crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist public agencies and local governments to provide assistance for victims of crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act as an advocate for the victims of crime to obtain aid and services from public or private health, education, welfare, or rehabilitation agencies or groups to treat persons who have been victims of crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive from the state attorney or from the law enforcement agencies involved such investigation and data, including confidential records, as will enable the department to determine if, in fact, a crime was committed or attempted, and the extent, if any, to which the victim or claimant was responsible for his or her own injury or death.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To investigate all claims for awards filed with the department pursuant to this chapter, considering all other available programs providing valid and collectible benefits to the claimant, and to reinvestigate or reopen cases as the department deems appropriate and equitable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require the submission of such records as are required and, when necessary, to direct medical examination of the victim or intervenor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-452; s. 5, ch. 80-146; s. 3, ch. 85-326; s. 3, ch. 91-23; s. 6, ch. 92-107; s. 1710, ch. 97-102; s. 3, ch. 99-373.</History></Section>