<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0960.292" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement of the civil restitution lien through civil restitution lien order.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The civil restitution lien shall be made enforceable by means of a civil restitution lien order.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon conviction, the convicted offender shall incur civil liability for damages and losses to crime victims, the state, its local subdivisions, and aggrieved parties as set forth in s. 960.293. The conviction shall estop the convicted offender from denying the essential allegations of that offense in any subsequent proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon motion by the state, upon petition of the local subdivision, crime victim, or aggrieved party, or on its own motion, the court in which the convicted offender is convicted shall enter civil restitution lien orders in favor of crime victims, the state, its local subdivisions, and other aggrieved parties. The court shall retain continuing jurisdiction over the convicted offender for the sole purpose of entering civil restitution lien orders for the duration of the sentence and up to 5 years from release from incarceration or supervision, whichever occurs later.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall enter separate civil restitution lien orders as appropriate in favor of the crime victims, the state, its local subdivisions, or aggrieved parties. The civil restitution lien order shall include the name of the convicted offender, the case number assigned to the applicable criminal case, and the names and social security numbers of the crime victim, state, its local subdivisions, or aggrieved parties, as appropriate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 94-342; s. 31, ch. 95-184; s. 15, ch. 2009-63.</History></Section>