<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0085.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Remedies against personal property only; all lienors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BY INJUNCTION AND ATTACHMENT.<EmDash />If any person entitled to a lien under part II of chapter 713 on personal property has reason to believe that it is about to be removed from the county in which it is, the person may enjoin its removal in the manner provided for enjoining the removal of property subject to a mortgage or, if the lien has been perfected, may attach it in the manner provided for attachment in aid of foreclosure of mortgages.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BY SALE WITHOUT JUDICIAL PROCEEDINGS.<EmDash />When any person entrusts to any mechanic or laborer, materials with which to construct, alter, or repair any article of value, or any article of value to be altered or repaired, and if the article is completed and not taken away, and the reasonable charges not paid, such mechanic or laborer may sell it after 3 months from the time such charges become due at public auction for cash but before the sale the mechanic or laborer shall give public notice of the time and place thereof, by notices posted for 10 days in 3 public places in the county, one of which shall be at the courthouse, and another in some conspicuous part of his or her shop or place of business. The proceeds of the sale, after payment of charges for construction or repair with the costs of the sale, shall be deposited with the clerk of the circuit court for the county, if the owner is absent, where they shall remain subject to the order of the person legally entitled thereto. The clerk shall be entitled to receive 5 percent on the proceeds for the care and disbursement thereof. Any person claiming a lien under s. 713.65, of part II of chapter 713, may enforce it by sale without judicial proceedings in the manner set forth herein after 1 month after the time the charges for which a lien is claimed become due.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">RS 1745; GS 2214; RGS 3521; CGL 5384; s. 2, ch. 25048, 1949; s. 1, ch. 57-94; s. 37, ch. 67-254; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-89; s. 2, ch. 79-244; s. 457, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 86.08.</Text></Note></Section>