<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0063.172" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of judgment of adoption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A judgment of adoption, whether entered by a court of this state, another state, or of any other place, has the following effect:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It relieves the birth parents of the adopted person, except a birth parent who is a petitioner or who is married to a petitioner, of all parental rights and responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It terminates all legal relationships between the adopted person and the adopted person’s relatives, including the birth parents, except a birth parent who is a petitioner or who is married to a petitioner, so that the adopted person thereafter is a stranger to his or her former relatives for all purposes, including the interpretation or construction of documents, statutes, and instruments, whether executed before or after entry of the adoption judgment, that do not expressly include the adopted person by name or by some designation not based on a parent and child or blood relationship, except that rights of inheritance shall be as provided in the Florida Probate Code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for rights of inheritance, it creates the relationship between the adopted person and the petitioner and all relatives of the petitioner that would have existed if the adopted person were a blood descendant of the petitioner born within wedlock. This relationship shall be created for all purposes, including applicability of statutes, documents, and instruments, whether executed before or after entry of the adoption judgment, that do not expressly exclude an adopted person from their operation or effect.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If one or both parents of a child die without the relationship of parent and child having been previously terminated and a spouse of the living parent or a close relative of the child thereafter adopts the child, the child’s right of inheritance from or through the deceased parent is unaffected by the adoption and, unless the court orders otherwise, the adoption will not terminate any grandparental rights delineated under chapter 752. For purposes of this subsection, a close relative of a child is the child’s brother, sister, grandparent, aunt, or uncle.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 73-159; s. 11, ch. 75-226; s. 1, ch. 79-369; s. 1, ch. 87-27; s. 1, ch. 90-139; s. 18, ch. 92-96; s. 1, ch. 93-192; s. 342, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 2001-226.</History></Section>