<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0063.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Final home investigation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The final home investigation must be conducted before the adoption becomes final. The investigation may be conducted by a licensed child-placing agency or a professional in the same manner as provided in s. 63.092 to ascertain whether the adoptive home is a suitable home for the minor and whether the proposed adoption is in the best interest of the minor. Unless directed by the court, an investigation and recommendation are not required if the petitioner is a stepparent or if the minor is related to one of the adoptive parents within the third degree of consanguinity. The department is required to perform the home investigation only if there is no licensed child-placing agency or professional pursuant to s. 63.092 in the county in which the prospective adoptive parent resides.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, the licensed child-placing agency, or the professional that performs the investigation must file a written report of the investigation with the court and the petitioner within 90 days after placement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report of the investigation must contain an evaluation of the placement with a recommendation on the granting of the petition for adoption and any other information the court requires regarding the petitioner or the minor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, the licensed child-placing agency, or the professional making the required investigation may request other state agencies or child-placing agencies within or outside this state to make investigations of designated parts of the inquiry and to make a written report to the department, the professional, or other person or agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The final home investigation must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information from the preliminary home study.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the minor is placed in the intended adoptive home, two scheduled visits with the minor and the minor’s adoptive parent or parents, one of which visits must be in the home, to determine the suitability of the placement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The family social and medical history as provided in s. 63.082.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information relevant to the suitability of the intended adoptive home.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other relevant information, as provided in rules that the department may adopt.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 92-96; s. 24, ch. 2001-3; s. 25, ch. 2003-58.</History></Section>