<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0063.092" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Report to the court of intended placement by an adoption entity; at-risk placement; preliminary study.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORT TO THE COURT.<EmDash />The adoption entity must report any intended placement of a minor for adoption with any person who is not a relative or a stepparent if the adoption entity participates in the intended placement. The report must be made to the court before the minor is placed in the home or within 2 business days thereafter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AT-RISK PLACEMENT.<EmDash />If the minor is placed in the prospective adoptive home before the parental rights of the minor’s parents are terminated under s. 63.089, the placement is an at-risk placement. If the placement is an at-risk placement, the prospective adoptive parents must acknowledge in writing before the minor may be placed in the prospective adoptive home that the placement is at risk. The prospective adoptive parents shall be advised by the adoption entity, in writing, that the minor is subject to removal from the prospective adoptive home by the adoption entity or by court order at any time prior to the finalization of the adoption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRELIMINARY HOME STUDY.<EmDash />Before placing the minor in the intended adoptive home, a preliminary home study must be performed by a licensed child-placing agency, a child-caring agency registered under s. 409.176, a licensed professional, or an agency described in s. 61.20(2), unless the adoptee is an adult or the petitioner is a stepparent or a relative. If the adoptee is an adult or the petitioner is a stepparent or a relative, a preliminary home study may be required by the court for good cause shown. The department is required to perform the preliminary home study only if there is no licensed child-placing agency, child-caring agency registered under s. 409.176, licensed professional, or agency described in s. 61.20(2), in the county where the prospective adoptive parents reside. The preliminary home study must be made to determine the suitability of the intended adoptive parents and may be completed prior to identification of a prospective adoptive minor. A favorable preliminary home study is valid for 1 year after the date of its completion. Upon its completion, a signed copy of the home study must be provided to the intended adoptive parents who were the subject of the home study. A minor may not be placed in an intended adoptive home before a favorable preliminary home study is completed unless the adoptive home is also a licensed foster home under s. 409.175. The preliminary home study must include, at a minimum:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An interview with the intended adoptive parents;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records checks of the department’s central abuse registry and criminal records correspondence checks under s. 39.0138 through the Department of Law Enforcement on the intended adoptive parents;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the physical environment of the home;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination of the financial security of the intended adoptive parents;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation of counseling and education of the intended adoptive parents on adoptive parenting;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation that information on adoption and the adoption process has been provided to the intended adoptive parents;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation that information on support services available in the community has been provided to the intended adoptive parents; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of each signed acknowledgment of receipt of disclosure required by s. 63.085.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the preliminary home study is favorable, a minor may be placed in the home pending entry of the judgment of adoption. A minor may not be placed in the home if the preliminary home study is unfavorable. If the preliminary home study is unfavorable, the adoption entity may, within 20 days after receipt of a copy of the written recommendation, petition the court to determine the suitability of the intended adoptive home. A determination as to suitability under this subsection does not act as a presumption of suitability at the final hearing. In determining the suitability of the intended adoptive home, the court must consider the totality of the circumstances in the home. A minor may not be placed in a home in which there resides any person determined by the court to be a sexual predator as defined in s. 775.21 or to have been convicted of an offense listed in s. 63.089(4)(b)2.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 73-159; s. 5, ch. 75-226; s. 18, ch. 77-147; s. 5, ch. 78-190; s. 4, ch. 80-296; s. 3, ch. 82-166; s. 2, ch. 84-28; s. 1, ch. 85-189; s. 9, ch. 92-96; s. 126, ch. 98-403; s. 19, ch. 2001-3; s. 20, ch. 2003-58; s. 14, ch. 2004-371; s. 33, ch. 2006-86; s. 15, ch. 2008-151; s. 18, ch. 2012-81.</History>
</Section>