<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0063.167" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State adoption information center.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a state adoption information center for the purpose of increasing public knowledge about adoption and promoting to adolescents and pregnant women the availability of adoption services. The department shall contract with one or more licensed child-placing agencies to operate the state adoption information center.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The functions of the state adoption information center shall include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing a training program for persons who counsel adolescents, including, but not limited to, school counselors, county child welfare services employees, and family planning clinic employees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recruiting adoption services specialist trainees, and providing a training program for such specialists.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operating a toll-free telephone number to provide information and referral services. The state adoption information center shall provide contact information for all adoption entities in the caller’s county or, if no adoption entities are located in the caller’s county, the number of the nearest adoption entity when contacted for a referral to make an adoption plan and shall rotate the order in which the names of adoption entities are provided to callers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distributing pamphlets which provide information on the availability of adoption services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting adoption through the communications media.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintaining a list of licensed child-placing agencies eligible and willing to take custody of and place newborn infants left at a hospital, pursuant to s. 383.50. The names and contact information for the licensed child-placing agencies on the list shall be provided on a rotating basis to the statewide central abuse hotline.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall ensure equitable distribution of referrals to licensed child-placing agencies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 62, ch. 90-306; s. 4, ch. 2000-188; s. 31, ch. 2003-58; s. 21, ch. 2012-81; s. 22, ch. 2012-116.</History>
</Section>