<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0583.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposal of dead poultry and hatchery residue; inspection and quarantine; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, where the context permits, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Egg producer” means any person, firm, or corporation that produces eggs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hatchery residue” means dead chicks, down, egg shells, or unhatched and unused eggs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Poultry hatchery” means any person, firm, or corporation engaged in the business of hatching eggs of chickens, turkeys, ducks, or other fowl.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Poultry producer” means any person, firm, or corporation that grows chickens, turkeys, ducks, or other fowl.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SANITARY DISPOSAL OF DEAD POULTRY AND HATCHERY RESIDUE.<EmDash />Every poultry producer, egg producer, and poultry hatchery doing business in this state shall provide for the sanitary disposal of dead birds and hatchery residue. The disposal may be accomplished by incineration, processing in approved rendering plants, feeding to swine in permitted garbage feeding establishments after adequate heat treatment, burial in sanitary disposal pits or sanitary landfills, or other methods which may be approved by the department. If dead birds or hatchery residue is not disposed of on the premises where produced, the materials must be transported to the disposal site in containers sufficiently sealed so as to prevent spillage thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS AND DUTIES.<EmDash />In the discharge of its duties under this section, the department has the power:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promulgate rules prescribing satisfactory facilities and equipment for the handling, destruction, and disposal of dead birds and hatchery residue so as to prevent the spread or dissemination of diseases of poultry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter upon any premises where poultry is kept by poultry producers, poultry hatcheries, and egg producers and make such inspections as are necessary to ensure the proper disposal of dead birds and hatchery residue as required by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To quarantine any premises found to be in violation of this section or the rules adopted hereunder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS.<EmDash />The provisions of this section do not apply to poultry producers or egg producers with flocks of 500 birds or less, unless it is determined by the department that such producer’s means of disposal constitutes a disease threat.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PENALTY.<EmDash />Any person who violates the provisions of this section or the rules adopted hereunder is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in ss. 775.082 and 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4A, ch. 71-143; s. 1, ch. 72-115; s. 15, ch. 84-102; s. 1, ch. 86-63.</History></Section>