<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0583.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of department to make inspections, issue stop-sale orders, or condemn and destroy eggs, egg products, or poultry.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter and upon good and sufficient cause, the department:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall have free access at all reasonable hours to any establishment, premises, or building where eggs, egg products, or poultry are processed, stored, or offered for sale, and to any vehicle used to transport or hold eggs, egg products, or poultry, for the purpose of inspecting such establishment, premises, building, or vehicle or the eggs, egg products, or poultry therein in order to determine compliance with this chapter and chapter 500, the Florida Food Safety Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall have free access at all reasonable hours to any kitchen of a restaurant, of a hotel dining room, or of another public eating place where eggs, egg products, or poultry are served as food to determine if such eggs, egg products, or poultry are in compliance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May issue and enforce a stop-sale order on any lot of eggs, egg products, or poultry which the department finds, or has good reason to believe, is in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter or any rule issued hereunder, which stop-sale order prohibits the further sale, barter, exchange, or distribution of the eggs, egg products, or poultry until the department is satisfied that compliance with this chapter or rule issued hereunder has been effected and has issued a written release notice to the owner or custodian of such eggs, egg products, or poultry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May condemn or destroy any eggs, egg products, or poultry which are unsound; which contain any filthy, decomposed, or putrid substances; or which may be poisonous, injurious to health, or otherwise unsafe.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 16982, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4126(11); s. 2, ch. 24106, 1947; s. 3, ch. 57-151; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 84-102; s. 38, ch. 94-180.</History></Section>