<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0583.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Labeling, marking, and advertising eggs; sales between dealers; unlawful acts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any dealer:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To offer for sale or sell in this state any case, partial case, or carton containing eggs which is not labeled with the date of pack; grade; size; and name and address of the packer, distributor, or dealer. However, the department may permit a dealer to sell or consign eggs to another dealer in this state without labeling provided such eggs are accompanied by a proper bill of lading, and provided further that the consignee, upon receipt of the eggs and prior to selling or offering them for sale, affixes to each case the labeling required by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To offer for sale or sell eggs in bulk (not in cases or cartons) from any open case, box, basket, or other receptacle holding such eggs in bulk without displaying conspicuously on every such case, box, basket, or other receptacle a placard or heavy cardboard not smaller than 7 inches by 7 inches in size, on which shall be legibly and plainly printed, in letters not smaller than 1 inch in height, wording showing whether the eggs offered for sale or sold are “cold storage eggs,” “unclassified eggs,” or “graded eggs,” and also stating the grade and size to which the eggs contained therein conform.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To offer eggs for sale in any newspaper advertisement, circular, radio, or other form of advertising without plainly designating in such advertisement the grade and size to which the eggs being offered for sale properly belong.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To use the name, logo, or certificate or permit number of the department on any egg or poultry advertisement or packaging material without written approval from the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 16012, 1933; ss. 2, 3, ch. 16982, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4126(2),(3); s. 2, ch. 57-151; s. 2, ch. 61-413; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 73-81; s. 2, ch. 84-102.</History></Section>