<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.0084" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application fees for migrant labor camps and residential migrant housing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each migrant labor camp operator or owner of residential migrant housing who is subject to s. 381.0081 shall pay to the department the following annual application fees:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Camps or residential migrant housing that have capacity for 5 to 50 occupants: $125.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Camps or residential migrant housing that have capacity for 51 to 100 occupants: $225.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Camps or residential migrant housing that have capacity for 101 or more occupants: $500.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deposit fees collected under this section in the County Health Department Trust Fund for use in the migrant labor camp program and shall use those fees solely for actual costs incurred in enforcing ss. 381.008-381.00895.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any existing migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing that is substantially renovated or newly constructed is exempt from the annual application fee described in this section for the next annual permit after the renovations or construction occurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any existing migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing that, during any permit year, has no major deficiencies cited by the department, no uncorrected deficiencies, and no administrative action taken against it is exempt from the annual application fee described in this section for the next annual permit period.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 10, ch. 83-249; s. 36, ch. 91-297; ss. 6, 15, ch. 93-133; s. 41, ch. 97-101.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.455.</Text></Note></Section>