<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.0083" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permit for migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is planning to construct, enlarge, remodel, use, or occupy a migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing or convert property for use as a migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing must give written notice to the department of the intent to do so at least 45 days before beginning such construction, enlargement, or renovation. If the department is satisfied, after causing an inspection to be made, that the camp or the residential migrant housing meets the minimum standards of construction, sanitation, equipment, and operation required by rules issued under s. 381.0086 and that the applicant has paid the application fees required by s. 381.0084, it shall issue in the name of the department the necessary permit in writing on a form to be prescribed by the department. The permit, unless sooner revoked, shall expire on September 30 next after the date of issuance, and it shall not be transferable. An application for a permit shall be filed with the department 30 days prior to operation. When there is a change in ownership of a currently permitted migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing, the new owner must file an application with the department at least 15 days before the change. In the case of a facility owned or operated by a public housing authority, an annual satisfactory sanitation inspection of the living units by the Farmers Home Administration or the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall substitute for the pre-permitting inspection required by the department.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 59-476; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 87, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 9, 10, ch. 83-249; s. 35, ch. 91-297; ss. 5, 15, ch. 93-133; s. 10, ch. 98-151.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.452.</Text></Note></Section>