<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.00775" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tattoo artists; licensure; registration of guest tattoo artists.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 381.00773, a person may not tattoo the body of any human being in this state unless the person is licensed as a tattoo artist or registered as a guest tattoo artist under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person seeking licensure as a tattoo artist must apply to the department in the format prescribed by the department. An application must include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and residence address of the applicant.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and street address of each tattoo establishment and temporary establishment at which the applicant intends to practice tattooing in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license to an applicant who:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age or older.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits a completed application.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pays the applicable license fee established in s. 381.00781.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits proof of successful completion of an education course approved by the department on blood-borne pathogens and communicable diseases.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits proof of passage of an examination approved by the department on the material presented in the education course.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall approve one or more education courses and examinations that allows a person to complete the requirements of subparagraphs (b)4. and 5. in person or through an Internet website.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tattoo artist must, within 30 days after a change, notify the department of any change in the following information disclosed in his or her most recent application for issuance or renewal of his or her tattoo artist license in the format prescribed by the department:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and residence address of the tattoo artist.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and street address of each tattoo establishment in this state at which the tattoo artist has practiced tattooing for more than 14 days since the most recent renewal of his or her tattoo artist license or, if the license has not been renewed, since the license was issued.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person seeking registration as a guest tattoo artist must apply to the department in the format prescribed by the department. An application must include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and residence address of the applicant.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and street address of each tattoo establishment and temporary establishment at which the applicant will practice under the guest tattoo artist registration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a guest tattoo artist registration to an applicant who:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age or older.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits a completed application.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pays the applicable registration fee established in s. 381.00781.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds an active license, registration, or certification issued by a jurisdiction outside this state, whether by another state, the District of Columbia, any possession or territory of the United States, or any foreign jurisdiction, if:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The education and examination requirements of the license, registration, or certification substantially meet or exceed the requirements of subparagraphs (2)(b)4. and 5.; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant submits proof of successful completion of an education course approved by the department under subparagraph (2)(b)4. and proof of passage of an examination approved by the department under subparagraph (2)(b)5.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tattoo artist license is valid for 1 year and must be renewed annually.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guest tattoo artist registration is valid for 14 days. A guest tattoo artist may apply for reregistration before or after expiration of his or her current registration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license or registration issued by the department under this section is not transferable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2010-220.</History>
</Section>