<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.785" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recovery of third-party payments for funded services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Third-party coverage for funded services constitutes primary coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for or recipient of services funded under the brain and spinal cord injury program must inform the brain and spinal cord injury program of any rights she or he has to third-party payments for such services, and the brain and spinal cord injury program shall be subrogated to her or his rights to such third-party payments. The brain and spinal cord injury program may recover directly from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any third party that is liable to make a benefit payment to the provider of the recipient’s funded services or to the recipient under the terms of any contract, settlement, or award;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recipient, if she or he has received a third-party payment for funded services provided to her or him; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provider of the recipient’s funded services, if third-party payment for such services has been recovered by the provider.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for or a recipient of funded services is deemed to have assigned to the brain and spinal cord injury program her or his rights to any payments for such services from a third party and to have authorized the brain and spinal cord injury program to release information with respect to such services for the sole purpose of obtaining reimbursement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The brain and spinal cord injury program may, in order to enforce its rights under this section, institute, intervene in, or join any legal proceeding against a third party against whom recovery rights arise. Action taken by the brain and spinal cord injury program does not preclude the recipient’s recovery for that portion of her or his damages not subrogated to the brain and spinal cord injury program, and action taken by the recipient does not prejudice the rights of the brain and spinal cord injury program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the brain and spinal cord injury program provides, pays for, or becomes liable for funded services, it has a lien for the amount of such services upon all causes of action that accrue to the recipient or to her or his legal representatives as a result of sickness, injury, disease, disability, or death due to the liability of a third party which necessitated funded services. To perfect such lien, a notice of lien must be filed with the clerk of the circuit court in the recipient’s county of residence. The notice of lien must contain the name and address of the person to whom services were furnished and the name, address, and telephone number of a person at the brain and spinal cord injury program from whom information regarding the lien can be obtained. Failure of the brain and spinal cord injury program to file a notice of lien does not affect the program’s other rights provided in this section. Any notice of lien filed as provided under this subsection is valid for 5 years after filing, and may be extended for an additional 5-year period by filing a new notice of lien at any time prior to the expiration of the original notice of lien.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In recovering any payments in accordance with this section, the brain and spinal cord injury program may make appropriate settlements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, payments made for funded services are neither collateral payments nor collateral sources within the meaning of chapter 86-160, Laws of Florida, or chapter 88-1, Laws of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, the brain and spinal cord injury program retains all rights and remedies granted under this section as against moneys paid under chapter 440.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2000-367.</History></Section>