<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.00779" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Practice requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tattoo establishment or temporary establishment must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display an active license for the establishment in a manner that is easily visible to the public at all times while tattooing is performed at the establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that each tattoo artist and guest tattoo artist, while practicing tattooing at the establishment, meets all applicable requirements of ss. 381.00771-381.00791.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain sanitary conditions of the establishment at all times.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with all state and local health codes and ordinances.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow the department to inspect the establishment pursuant to subsection (4).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with s. 381.0098 and rules adopted under that section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tattoo artist or guest tattoo artist must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display his or her active license in a manner that is easily visible to the public at all times while practicing tattooing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice tattooing exclusively at an establishment licensed under ss. 381.00771-381.00791.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain sanitary conditions of the establishment at all times.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with all state and local health codes and ordinances.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tattoo artist or guest tattoo artist may tattoo the body of a minor child only to the extent authorized in s. 381.00787. A tattoo establishment or temporary establishment must keep, for the period prescribed by the department, each written notarized consent submitted under s. 381.00787(2)(c) by the parent or legal guardian of a minor child who is tattooed at the establishment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may inspect and investigate each tattoo establishment and temporary establishment as necessary to ensure compliance with ss. 381.00771-381.00791. However, the department shall inspect each tattoo establishment at least annually and shall inspect each temporary establishment before and, as necessary, during a convention or similar event with which the establishment is connected.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2010-220.</History>
</Section>