<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.00777" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tattoo establishments; licensure; temporary establishments.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 381.00773, a person may not tattoo the body of any human being in this state except at a tattoo establishment or temporary establishment licensed under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not operate a tattoo establishment or temporary establishment in this state unless the establishment is licensed under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person seeking licensure of a tattoo establishment must apply to the department in the format prescribed by the department. An application must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registered business name, including any fictitious names under which the tattoo establishment conducts business in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address and telephone number of the tattoo establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, mailing address, and telephone number of the tattoo establishment’s operator.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the tattoo establishment’s registered agent for service of process in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a tattoo establishment license to an applicant, if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant submits a completed application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant pays the applicable license fee established in s. 381.00781.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The establishment complies with all applicable local building, occupational, zoning, and health codes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary establishment must meet the same requirements for licensure as a permanent tattoo establishment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license is valid only for the location listed on the license. A tattoo establishment must notify the department in the format prescribed by the department before any change of the licensed location. A tattoo establishment with more than one location must obtain a separate license for each location.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tattoo establishment license is valid for 1 year and must be renewed annually.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary establishment license is valid for the duration of a convention or other similar event for which the license is issued not to exceed 14 consecutive days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license issued by the department under this section is not transferable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2010-220.</History>
</Section>