<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.9315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gynecologic and ovarian cancer education and awareness.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Kelly Smith Gynecologic and Ovarian Cancer Education and Awareness Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall encourage health care providers, including, but not limited to, hospitals, birthing facilities, county health departments, physicians, midwives, and nurses, to disseminate and display information about gynecologic cancers, including the signs and symptoms, risk factors, benefits of early detection through appropriate diagnostic testing, and treatment options.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall encourage women to discuss the risks of gynecologic cancers with their health care providers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General shall make publicly available, by posting on the Internet website of the Department of Health, resources and an Internet website link to the federal Centers for Disease Control and Prevention website for gynecologic cancer information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is encouraged to seek any available grants from private or federal sources to promote gynecologic cancer awareness, including, but not limited to, early warning signs and risk factors associated with gynecologic cancers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is encouraged to collaborate with other agencies, organizations, and institutions to create a systematic approach to increasing public awareness regarding gynecologic cancers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2011-91.</History>
</Section>