<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.983" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Affected property” means a room or group of rooms within a property constructed before January 1, 1960, or within a property constructed between January 1, 1960, and January 1, 1978, where the owner has actual knowledge of the presence of lead-based paint, that form a single independent habitable dwelling unit for occupation by one or more individuals and that has living facilities with permanent provisions for living, sleeping, eating, cooking, and sanitation. Affected property does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area not used for living, sleeping, eating, cooking, or sanitation, such as an unfinished basement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit within a hotel, motel, or similar seasonal or transient facility, unless such unit is occupied by one or more persons at risk for a period exceeding 30 days;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area that is secured and inaccessible to occupants; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit that is not offered for rent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dust-lead hazard” means surface dust in a residential dwelling or a facility occupied by a person at risk which contains a mass-per-area concentration of lead equal to or exceeding 40 ug/ft2 on floors or 250 ug/ft2 on interior windowsills based on wipe samples.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Elevated blood-lead level” means a quantity of lead in whole venous blood, expressed in micrograms per deciliter (ug/dL), which exceeds 10 ug/dL or such other level as specifically provided in this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lead-based paint” means paint or other surface coatings that contain lead equal to or exceeding 1.0 milligram per square centimeter, 0.5 percent by weight, or 5,000 parts per million (ppm) by weight.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lead-based-paint hazard” means paint-lead hazards and dust-lead hazards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means a person, firm, corporation, nonprofit organization, partnership, government, guardian, conservator, receiver, trustee, executor, or other judicial officer, or other entity which, alone or with others, owns, holds, or controls the freehold or leasehold title or part of the title to property, with or without actually possessing it. The definition includes a vendee who possesses the title, but does not include a mortgagee or an owner of a reversionary interest under a ground rent lease. The term includes any authorized agent of the owner, including a property manager or leasing agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Paint-lead hazard” means any one of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lead-based paint on a friction surface that is subject to abrasion and where the dust-lead levels on the nearest horizontal surface underneath the friction surface, such as the windowsill or floor, are equal to or greater than the dust-lead-hazard levels defined in subsection (2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any damaged or otherwise deteriorated lead-based paint on an impact surface that is caused by impact from a related building material, such as a door knob that knocks into a wall or a door that knocks against its door frame;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any chewable lead-based painted surface on which there is evidence of teeth marks; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other deteriorated lead-based paint in or on the exterior of any residential building or any facility occupied by a person at risk.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person at risk” means a child under the age of 6 years or a pregnant woman who resides or regularly spends at least 24 hours per week in an affected property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tenant” means the individual named as the lessee in a lease, rental agreement, or occupancy agreement for a dwelling unit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2006-269; s. 34, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>