<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.0066" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Onsite sewage treatment and disposal systems; fees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may collect fees for services provided with respect to onsite sewage treatment and disposal systems. The total fees assessed under this section must be sufficient to meet the cost of administering this section and ss. 381.0065 and 381.00655.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum fees in the following fee schedule apply until changed by rule by the department within the following limits:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application review, permit issuance, or system inspection, including repair of a subsurface, mound, filled, or other alternative system or permitting of an abandoned system: a fee of not less than $25, or more than $125.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Site evaluation, site reevaluation, evaluation of a system previously in use, or a per annum septage disposal site evaluation: a fee of not less than $40, or more than $115.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Biennial operating permit for aerobic treatment units or performance-based treatment systems: a fee of not more than $100.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual operating permit for systems located in areas zoned for industrial manufacturing or equivalent uses or where the system is expected to receive wastewater which is not domestic in nature: a fee of not less than $150, or more than $300.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Innovative technology: a fee not to exceed $25,000.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Septage disposal service, septage stabilization facility, portable or temporary toilet service, tank manufacturer inspection: a fee of not less than $25, or more than $200, per year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for variance: a fee of not less than $150, or more than $300.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual operating permit for waterless, incinerating, or organic waste composting toilets: a fee of not less than $15, or more than $30.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aerobic treatment unit or performance-based treatment system maintenance entity permit: a fee of not less than $25, or more than $150, per year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reinspection fee per visit for site inspection after system construction approval or for noncompliant system installation per site visit: a fee of not less than $25, or more than $100.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research: An additional $5 fee shall be added to each new system construction permit issued to be used to fund onsite sewage treatment and disposal system research, demonstration, and training projects. Five dollars from any repair permit fee collected under this section shall be used for funding the hands-on training centers described in s. 381.0065(3)(j).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual operating permit, including annual inspection and any required sampling and laboratory analysis of effluent, for an engineer-designed performance-based system: a fee of not less than $150, or more than $300.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The funds collected pursuant to this subsection must be deposited in a trust fund administered by the department, to be used for the purposes stated in this section and ss. 381.0065 and 381.00655.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 44, 46, ch. 83-310; s. 39, ch. 85-81; s. 2, ch. 88-89; s. 27, ch. 91-297; ss. 3, 10, 11, ch. 93-151; ss. 2, 3, ch. 96-303; s. 2, ch. 99-395; s. 2, ch. 2001-234; s. 16, ch. 2002-402; s. 24, ch. 2003-399; s. 2, ch. 2004-245; ss. 10, 76, ch. 2004-269; s. 8, ch. 2004-350; s. 37, ch. 2010-205; s. 35, ch. 2012-184.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.273.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>