<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.006" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Environmental health.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall conduct an environmental health program as part of fulfilling the state’s public health mission. The purpose of this program is to detect and prevent disease caused by natural and manmade factors in the environment. The environmental health program shall include, but not be limited to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A drinking water function.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An environmental health surveillance function which shall collect, compile, and correlate information on public health and exposure to hazardous substances through sampling and testing of water, air, or foods. Environmental health surveillance shall include a comprehensive assessment of drinking water under the department’s supervision and an indoor air quality testing and monitoring program to assess health risks from exposure to chemical, physical, and biological agents in the indoor environment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A toxicology and hazard assessment function which shall conduct toxicological and human health risk assessments of exposure to toxic agents, for the purposes of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supporting determinations by the State Health Officer of safe levels of contaminants in water, air, or food if applicable standards or criteria have not been adopted. These determinations shall include issuance of health advisories to protect the health and safety of the public at risk from exposure to toxic agents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision of human toxicological health risk assessments to the public and other governmental agencies to characterize the risks to the public from exposure to contaminants in air, water, or food.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consultation and technical assistance to the Department of Environmental Protection and other governmental agencies on actions necessary to ameliorate exposure to toxic agents, including the emergency provision by the Department of Environmental Protection of drinking water in cases of drinking water contamination that present an imminent and substantial threat to the public’s health, as required by s. 376.30(3)(c)1.a.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitoring and reporting the body burden of toxic agents to estimate past exposure to these toxic agents, predict future health effects, and decrease the incidence of poisoning by identifying and eliminating exposure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sanitary nuisance function, as that term is defined in chapter 386.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A migrant labor function.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public facilities function, including sanitary practices relating to state, county, municipal, and private institutions serving the public; jointly with the Department of Education, publicly and privately owned schools; all places used for the incarceration of prisoners and inmates of state institutions for the mentally ill; toilets and washrooms in all public places and places of employment; any other condition, place, or establishment necessary for the control of disease or the protection and safety of public health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An onsite sewage treatment and disposal function.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A biohazardous waste control function.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A function to control diseases transmitted from animals to humans, including the segregation, quarantine, and destruction of domestic pets and wild animals having or suspected of having such diseases.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An environmental epidemiology function which shall investigate food-borne disease, waterborne disease, and other diseases of environmental causation, whether of chemical, radiological, or microbiological origin. A $10 surcharge for this function shall be assessed upon all persons permitted under chapter 500. This function shall include an educational program for physicians and health professionals designed to promote surveillance and reporting of environmental diseases, and to further the dissemination of knowledge about the relationship between toxic substances and human health which will be useful in the formulation of public policy and will be a source of information for the public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mosquito and pest control functions as provided in chapters 388 and 482.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A radiation control function as provided in chapter 404 and part IV of chapter 468.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public swimming and bathing facilities function as provided in chapter 514.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home park, lodging park, recreational vehicle park, and recreational camp function as provided in chapter 513.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sanitary facilities function, which shall include minimum standards for the maintenance and sanitation of sanitary facilities; public access to sanitary facilities; and fixture ratios for special or temporary events and for homeless shelters.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A group-care-facilities function. As used in this subsection, the term “group care facility” means any public or private school, assisted living facility, adult family-care home, adult day care center, short-term residential treatment center, residential treatment facility, home for special services, transitional living facility, crisis stabilization unit, hospice, prescribed pediatric extended care center, intermediate care facility for persons with developmental disabilities, or boarding school. The department may adopt rules necessary to protect the health and safety of residents, staff, and patrons of group care facilities. Rules related to public and private schools shall be developed by the Department of Education in consultation with the department. Rules adopted under this subsection may include definitions of terms; provisions relating to operation and maintenance of facilities, buildings, grounds, equipment, furnishings, and occupant-space requirements; lighting; heating, cooling, and ventilation; food service; water supply and plumbing; sewage; sanitary facilities; insect and rodent control; garbage; safety; personnel health, hygiene, and work practices; and other matters the department finds are appropriate or necessary to protect the safety and health of the residents, staff, students, faculty, or patrons. The department may not adopt rules that conflict with rules adopted by the licensing or certifying agency. The department may enter and inspect at reasonable hours to determine compliance with applicable statutes or rules. In addition to any sanctions that the department may impose for violations of rules adopted under this section, the department shall also report such violations to any agency responsible for licensing or certifying the group care facility. The licensing or certifying agency may also impose any sanction based solely on the findings of the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A function for investigating elevated levels of lead in blood. Each participating county health department may expend funds for federally mandated certification or recertification fees related to conducting investigations of elevated levels of lead in blood.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A food service inspection function for domestic violence centers that are certified by the Department of Children and Family Services and monitored by the Florida Coalition Against Domestic Violence under part XII of chapter 39 and group care homes as described in subsection (16), which shall be conducted annually and be limited to the requirements in department rule applicable to community-based residential facilities with five or fewer residents.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department may adopt rules to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 91-297; s. 1, ch. 92-180; s. 27, ch. 93-150; s. 4, ch. 93-151; s. 351, ch. 94-356; s. 5, ch. 98-151; s. 10, ch. 99-397; s. 17, ch. 2000-141; s. 8, ch. 2000-242; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372; s. 6, ch. 2004-350; s. 1, ch. 2010-28; s. 17, ch. 2010-161; s. 45, ch. 2011-213; s. 6, ch. 2012-147.</History>
</Section>