<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.98" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Florida Public Health Institute, Inc.; establishment; purpose; mission; duties; board of directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Public Health Institute, Inc., referred to in this section as “the corporation,” is established for the purpose of advancing the knowledge and practice of public health, including promoting health awareness in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose and objective of the corporation shall be to operate exclusively for charitable, scientific, and educational purposes; to protect and improve the health and well-being of Florida’s people and environment through partnerships committed to program innovation, education, applied research, and policy development; and to engage in charitable programs dedicated to improving the health of Floridians.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall be established as a not-for-profit entity qualifying under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. The corporation may receive, hold, invest, and administer property and any moneys acquired from private, local, state, and federal sources, as well as technical and professional income generated or derived from the mission-related activities of the corporation. The corporation shall have all of the powers conferred upon corporations organized under chapter 617.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation’s duties include procuring funds necessary for accomplishing the purpose and mission of the corporation. The corporation shall strive to complement, supplement, and enhance the missions of the various organizations, entities, and departments that provide public health initiatives by serving as the lead corporation in the state for promoting public health awareness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The affairs of the corporation shall be managed by an executive director appointed by a board of directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors shall be elected in accordance with the bylaws of the corporation and shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General or his or her designee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Florida Public Health Association.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives of local health departments, with at least one representative each from the southern, central, and northern geographic areas of the state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives of institutions of higher learning.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representatives of the private health care provider sector, industry or business groups, or philanthropic foundations.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The majority of board members may not be state employees.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation and the Department of Health shall enter into partnerships with providers of continuing education for health care practitioners, including, but not limited to, hospitals and state and local medical organizations, to ensure that practitioners are aware of the most recent and complete diagnostic and treatment tools.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may provide personnel to the Department of Health for the purpose of performing duties and responsibilities outlined in private and public grants received by the Department of Health. These personnel are not state employees and are not entitled to retirement credit and other benefits provided to state employees under chapters 110 and 112. These personnel shall perform services pursuant to an agreement between the corporation and the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may purchase goods, services, and property for use by the Department of Health. These purchases are not subject to the provisions of chapters 253, 255, and 287, nor to the control or direction of the Department of Environmental Protection or the Department of Management Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall provide an annual report concerning its activities to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2004-2; s. 9, ch. 2006-182; s. 33, ch. 2008-6; s. 1, ch. 2009-161.</History></Section>