<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.984" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Educational programs.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEAD POISONING PREVENTION EDUCATIONAL PROGRAM ESTABLISHED.<EmDash />In order to achieve the purposes of this act, a statewide, multifaceted, ongoing educational program designed to meet the needs of tenants, property owners, health care providers, early childhood educators, care providers, and realtors is established.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PUBLIC INFORMATION INITIATIVE.<EmDash />The Governor, in conjunction with the State Surgeon General and his or her designee, shall sponsor a series of public service announcements on radio, television, the Internet, and print media about the nature of lead-based-paint hazards, the importance of standards for lead poisoning prevention in properties, and the purposes and responsibilities set forth in this act. In developing and coordinating this public information initiative, the sponsors shall seek the participation and involvement of private industry organizations, including those involved in real estate, insurance, mortgage banking, and pediatrics.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISTRIBUTION OF LITERATURE ABOUT CHILDHOOD LEAD POISONING.<EmDash />By January 1, 2007, the State Surgeon General or his or her designee shall develop culturally and linguistically appropriate information pamphlets regarding childhood lead poisoning, the importance of testing for elevated blood-lead levels, prevention of childhood lead poisoning, treatment of childhood lead poisoning, and, where appropriate, the requirements of this act. These information pamphlets shall be distributed to parents or the other legal guardians of children 6 years of age or younger on the following occasions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a health care provider at the time of a child’s birth and at the time of any childhood immunization or vaccination unless it is established that such information pamphlet has been provided previously to the parent or legal guardian by the health care provider within the prior 12 months.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the owner or operator of any child care facility or preschool or kindergarten class on or before October 15 of the calendar year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2006-269; s. 35, ch. 2008-6.</History>
</Section>