<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.0087" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement; citations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department personnel may issue citations that contain an order of correction or an order to pay a fine, or both, for violations of ss. 381.008-381.00895 or the field sanitation facility rules adopted by the department when a violation of those sections or rules is enforceable by an administrative or civil remedy, or when a violation of those sections or rules is a misdemeanor of the second degree. A citation issued under this section constitutes a notice of proposed agency action. The recipient of a citation for a major deficiency, as defined by rule of the department, will be given a maximum of 48 hours to make satisfactory correction or demonstrate that provisions for correction are satisfactory.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Citations must be in writing and must describe the particular nature of the violation, including specific reference to the provision of statute or rule allegedly violated. Continual or repeat violations of the same requirement will result in the issuance of a citation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fines imposed by a citation issued by the department may not exceed $500 for each violation. Each day the violation exists constitutes a separate violation for which a citation may be issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The citing official shall inform the recipient, by written notice pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57, of the right to an administrative hearing to contest the citation of the agency within 21 days after the date of receipt of the citation. The citation must contain a conspicuous statement that if the citation recipient fails to pay the fine within the time allowed, or fails to appear to contest the citation after having requested a hearing, the recipient is deemed to have waived the right to contest the citation and must pay an amount up to the maximum fine or penalty.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may reduce or waive the fine imposed by the citation. In determining whether to reduce or waive the fine, the department must give due consideration to such factors as the gravity of the violation, the good faith of the person who has allegedly committed the violation, and the person’s history of previous violations, including violations for which enforcement actions were taken under this section or other provisions of state law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully refuses to sign and accept a citation issued by the department commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deposit all fines collected under ss. 381.008-381.00895 in the County Health Department Trust Fund for use of the migrant labor camp inspection program and shall use such fines to improve migrant labor camp and residential migrant housing as described in s. 381.0086.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are an alternative means of enforcing ss. 381.008-381.00895 and the field sanitation facility rules. This section does not prohibit the department from enforcing those sections or rules by any other means. However, the agency shall elect to use only the procedure for enforcement under this section or another method of civil or administrative enforcement for a single violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department suspects that a law has been violated, it shall notify the entity that enforces the law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 39, ch. 91-297; s. 8, ch. 93-133; s. 118, ch. 96-410; s. 183, ch. 97-101; s. 12, ch. 98-151; s. 4, ch. 2004-64.</History></Section>