<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.00895" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts; application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner or operator of housing subject to the provisions of ss. 381.008-381.00897 may not, for the purpose of retaliating against a resident of that housing, discriminatorily terminate or discriminatorily modify a tenancy by increasing the resident’s rent; decreasing services to the resident; bringing or threatening to bring against the resident an action for eviction or possession or another civil action; refusing to renew the resident’s tenancy; or intimidating, threatening, restraining, coercing, blacklisting, or discharging the resident. Examples of conduct for which the owner or operator may not retaliate include, but are not limited to, situations in which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resident has complained in good faith, orally or in writing, to the owner or operator of the housing, the employer, or any government agency charged with the responsibility of enforcing the provisions of ss. 381.008-381.00897.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resident has exercised any legal right provided in this chapter with respect to the housing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resident who brings an action for or raises a defense of retaliatory conduct must have acted in good faith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply if the owner or operator of housing proves that the eviction or other action is for good cause, including, without limitation, a good faith action for nonpayment of rent, a violation of the resident’s rental or employment agreement, a violation of reasonable rules of the owner or operator of the housing or of the employer, or a violation of this chapter or the Florida Residential Landlord and Tenant Act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 93-133; s. 653, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>