<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.00783" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for discipline; administrative penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which disciplinary action specified in subsection (2) may be taken by the department against any tattoo establishment, temporary establishment, tattoo artist, guest tattoo artist, operator of a tattoo establishment, or unlicensed person engaged in activities regulated under ss. 381.00771-381.00791:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing false information on an application for licensure or registration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a state or local health code or ordinance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of ss. 381.00771-381.00791, rule adopted under those sections, or lawful order of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being found guilty of or pleading nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which relates to the practice of tattooing or the operation of a tattoo establishment or temporary establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing fraud, deceit, negligence, or misconduct in the practice of tattooing or the operation of a tattoo establishment or temporary establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, procuring, or assisting a person to unlawfully practice tattooing or unlawfully operate a tattoo establishment or temporary establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to keep the written notarized consent of the parent or legal guardian of a minor child who is tattooed at a tattoo establishment or temporary establishment for the period specified pursuant to s. 381.00779(3) or knowingly making false entries in a parent’s or legal guardian’s written notarized consent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department determines that a person commits any of the acts set forth in subsection (1), the department may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to issue a license or registration or renew a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suspension or revocation of a license or registration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,500 for each count or separate violation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the licensee or registrant on probation for a specified period and subject to the conditions that the department may specify.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a stop-use order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corrective action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall impose stricter penalties for the repetition of violations and as the severity of violations escalate, distinguishing lesser violations from those that endanger the public health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary proceedings shall be conducted as provided in chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2010-220.</History>
</Section>