<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.008" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions of terms used in ss. 381.008-381.00897.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 381.008-381.00897, the following words and phrases mean:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Common areas”<EmDash />That portion of a migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing not included within private living quarters and where migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing residents generally congregate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department”<EmDash />The Department of Health and its representative county health departments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Invited guest”<EmDash />Any person who is invited by a resident to a migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing to visit that resident.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Migrant farmworker”<EmDash />A person who is or has been employed in hand labor operations in planting, cultivating, or harvesting agricultural crops within the last 12 months and who has changed residence for purposes of employment in agriculture within the last 12 months.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Migrant labor camp”<EmDash />One or more buildings, structures, barracks, or dormitories, and the land appertaining thereto, constructed, established, operated, or furnished as an incident of employment as living quarters for seasonal or migrant farmworkers whether or not rent is paid or reserved in connection with the use or occupancy of such premises. The term does not include a single-family residence that is occupied by a single family.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Other authorized visitors”<EmDash />Any person, other than an invited guest, who is:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A federal, state, or county government official;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician or other health care provider whose sole purpose is to provide medical care or medical information;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of a bona fide religious organization who, during the visit, is engaged in the vocation or occupation of a religious professional or worker such as a minister, priest, or nun;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of a nonprofit legal services organization, who must comply with the Code of Professional Conduct of The Florida Bar; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other person who provides services for farmworkers which are funded in whole or in part by local, state, or federal funds but who does not conduct or attempt to conduct solicitations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private living quarters”<EmDash />A building or portion of a building, dormitory, or barracks, including its bathroom facilities, or a similar type of sleeping and bathroom area, which is a home, residence, or sleeping place for a resident of a migrant labor camp. The term includes residential migrant housing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residential migrant housing”<EmDash />A building, structure, mobile home, barracks, or dormitory, and any combination thereof on adjacent property which is under the same ownership, management, or control, and the land appertaining thereto, that is rented or reserved for occupancy by five or more seasonal or migrant farmworkers, except:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Housing furnished as an incident of employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A single-family residence or mobile home dwelling unit that is occupied only by a single family and that is not under the same ownership, management, or control as other farmworker housing to which it is adjacent or contiguous.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hotel or motel, as described in chapter 509, that is furnished for transient occupancy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any housing owned or operated by a public housing authority except for housing which is specifically provided for persons whose principal income is derived from agriculture.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal hygiene facilities”<EmDash />Adequate facilities for providing hot water at a minimum of 110 degrees Fahrenheit for bathing and dishwashing purposes, and an adequate and convenient approved supply of potable water available at all times in each migrant labor camp and residential migrant housing for drinking, culinary, bathing, dishwashing, and laundry purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lighting”<EmDash />At least one ceiling-type light fixture capable of providing 20 foot-candles of light at a point 30 inches from the floor, and at least one separate double electric wall outlet in each habitable room in a migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sewage disposal”<EmDash />Approved facilities for satisfactory disposal and treatment of human excreta and liquid waste.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Garbage disposal”<EmDash />Watertight receptacles of impervious material which are provided with tight-fitting covers suitable to protect the contents from flies, insects, rodents, and other animals.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-476; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 144, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 72-176; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 84, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 9, 10, ch. 83-249; s. 32, ch. 91-297; ss. 1, 15, ch. 93-133; s. 40, ch. 97-101; s. 9, ch. 98-151; s. 2, ch. 2004-64; s. 9, ch. 2011-119.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.422.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>