<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.0011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties and powers of the Department of Health.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the duty of the Department of Health to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assess the public health status and needs of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer and enforce laws and rules relating to sanitation, control of communicable diseases, illnesses and hazards to health among humans and from animals to humans, and the general health of the people of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate with federal, state, and local officials for the prevention and suppression of communicable and other diseases, illnesses, injuries, and hazards to human health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for a thorough investigation and study of the incidence, causes, modes of propagation and transmission, and means of prevention, control, and cure of diseases, illnesses, and hazards to human health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the dissemination of information to the public relative to the prevention, control, and cure of diseases, illnesses, and hazards to human health. </Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act as registrar of vital statistics.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manage and coordinate emergency preparedness and disaster response functions to: investigate and control the spread of disease; coordinate the availability and staffing of special needs shelters; support patient evacuation; ensure the safety of food and drugs; provide critical incident stress debriefing; and provide surveillance and control of radiological, chemical, biological, and other environmental hazards.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 91-297; s. 13, ch. 93-53; s. 29, ch. 97-101; s. 2, ch. 98-151; s. 94, ch. 98-200; s. 6, ch. 2000-367; s. 1, ch. 2002-269; s. 5, ch. 2004-350; s. 92, ch. 2010-102; s. 16, ch. 2010-161; s. 7, ch. 2012-184.</History>
</Section>