<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.7353" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reducing Racial and Ethnic Health Disparities: Closing the Gap grant program; administration; department duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Reducing Racial and Ethnic Health Disparities: Closing the Gap grant program shall be administered by the Department of Health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publicize the availability of funds and establish an application process for submitting a grant proposal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide technical assistance and training, including a statewide meeting promoting best practice programs, as requested, to grant recipients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop uniform data reporting requirements for the purpose of evaluating the performance of the grant recipients and demonstrating improved health outcomes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a monitoring process to evaluate progress toward meeting grant objectives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate with existing community-based programs, such as chronic disease community intervention programs, cancer prevention and control programs, diabetes control programs, the Healthy Start program, the Florida Kidcare Program, the HIV/AIDS program, immunization programs, and other related programs at the state and local levels, to avoid duplication of effort and promote consistency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 2000-256; s. 21, ch. 2008-6; s. 60, ch. 2012-184.</History>
</Section>