<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.88" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insect sting emergency treatment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Insect Sting Emergency Treatment Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to provide for the certification of persons who administer lifesaving treatment to persons who have severe adverse reactions to insect stings when a physician is not immediately available.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct educational training programs as described in subsection (4), and approve programs conducted by other persons or governmental agencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue and renew certificates of training to persons who have complied with this section and the rules adopted by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect fees necessary to administer this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational training programs required by this section must be conducted by a physician licensed to practice medicine in this state. The curriculum must include at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognition of the symptoms of systemic reactions to insect stings; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proper administration of a subcutaneous injection of epinephrine.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of training may be given to a person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age or older;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has, or reasonably expects to have, responsibility for at least one other person who has severe adverse reactions to insect stings as a result of his or her occupational or volunteer status, including a camp counselor, scout leader, school teacher, forest ranger, tour guide, or chaperone;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed an educational training program as described in subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who successfully completes an educational training program may obtain a certificate upon payment of an application fee of $25.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate issued pursuant to this section authorizes the holder thereof to receive, upon presentment of the certificate, from any physician licensed in this state or from the department, a prescription for premeasured doses of epinephrine and the necessary paraphernalia for administration. The certificate also authorizes the holder thereof to possess and administer, in an emergency situation when a physician is not immediately available, the prescribed epinephrine to a person suffering a severe adverse reaction to an insect sting.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 91-297; s. 816, ch. 95-148; s. 52, ch. 97-237.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 402.60.</Text></Note></Section>