<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.0035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Educational course on HIV and AIDS; employees and clients of certain health care facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall require all employees and clients of facilities licensed under chapter 393, chapter 394, or chapter 397 and employees of facilities licensed under chapter 395, part II, part III, or part IV of chapter 400, or part I of chapter 429 to complete a one-time educational course on the modes of transmission, infection control procedures, clinical management, and prevention of human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immune deficiency syndrome with an emphasis on appropriate behavior and attitude change. Such instruction shall include information on current Florida law and its impact on testing, confidentiality of test results, and treatment of patients and any protocols and procedures applicable to human immunodeficiency counseling and testing, reporting, the offering of HIV testing to pregnant women, and partner notification issues pursuant to ss. 381.004 and 384.25. An employee who has completed the educational course required in this subsection is not required to repeat the course upon changing employment to a different facility licensed under chapter 393, chapter 394, chapter 395, chapter 397, part II, part III, or part IV of chapter 400, or part I of chapter 429.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities licensed under chapter 393, chapter 394, chapter 395, or chapter 397, part II, part III, or part IV of chapter 400, or part I of chapter 429 shall maintain a record of employees and dates of attendance at human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immune deficiency syndrome educational courses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the authority to review the records of each facility to determine compliance with the requirements of this section. The department may adopt rules to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to an employee who is subject to the requirements of s. 456.033.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 88-380; ss. 17, 69, ch. 91-297; s. 63, ch. 92-289; s. 32, ch. 97-101; s. 1, ch. 98-171; s. 190, ch. 99-13; s. 13, ch. 2006-197; s. 1, ch. 2008-103.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.043.</Text></Note></Section>