<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.895" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards for compressed air used for recreational diving.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall establish maximum allowable levels for contaminants in compressed air used for recreational sport diving in this state. In developing the standards, the department must take into consideration the levels of contaminants allowed by the Grade “E” Recreational Diving Standards of the Compressed Gas Association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The standards prescribed under this section do not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person providing compressed air for his or her own use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any governmental entity using a governmentally owned compressed air source for work related to the governmental entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Foreign registered vessels upon which a compressor is used to provide compressed air for work related to the operation of the vessel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or entity that, for compensation, provides compressed air for recreational sport diving in this state, including compressed air provided as part of a dive package of equipment rental, dive boat rental, or dive boat charter, must ensure that the compressed air is tested quarterly by a laboratory that is accredited by either the American Industrial Hygiene Association or the American Association for Laboratory Accreditation and that the results of such tests are provided quarterly to the Department of Health. In addition, the person or entity must post the certificate issued by the laboratory accredited by the American Industrial Hygiene Association or the American Association for Laboratory Accreditation in a conspicuous location where it can readily be seen by any person purchasing compressed air.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall maintain a record of all quarterly test results provided under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a misdemeanor of the second degree for any person or entity to provide, for compensation, compressed air for recreational sport diving in this state, including compressed air provided as part of a dive package of equipment rental, dive boat rental, or dive boat charter, without:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having received a valid certificate issued by a laboratory accredited by the American Industrial Hygiene Association or the American Association for Laboratory Accreditation which certifies that the compressed air meets the standards for contaminant levels established by the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Posting the certificate issued by a laboratory accredited by the American Industrial Hygiene Association or the American Association for Laboratory Accreditation in a conspicuous location where it can readily be seen by persons purchasing compressed air.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, which must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maximum allowable levels of contaminants in compressed air used for sport diving.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for the submission of test results to the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 199, ch. 99-397; s. 55, ch. 2002-1.</History></Section>