<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.0038" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Education.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall establish a program to educate the public about the threat of acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquired immune deficiency syndrome education program shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be designed to reach all segments of Florida’s population;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain special components designed to reach non-English-speaking and other minority groups within the state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impart knowledge to the public about methods of transmission of acquired immune deficiency syndrome and methods of prevention;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educate the public about transmission risks in social, employment, and educational situations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educate health care workers and health facility employees about methods of transmission and prevention in their unique workplace environments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain special components designed to reach persons who may frequently engage in behaviors placing them at a high risk for acquiring acquired immune deficiency syndrome;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide information and consultation to state agencies to educate all state employees; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide information and consultation to state and local agencies to educate law enforcement and correctional personnel and inmates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide information and consultation to local governments to educate local government employees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make information available to private employers and encourage them to distribute this information to their employees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain special components which emphasize appropriate behavior and attitude change.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain components that include information about domestic violence and the risk factors associated with domestic violence and AIDS.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program designed by the Department of Health shall utilize all forms of the media and shall place emphasis on the design of educational materials that can be used by businesses, schools, and health care providers in the regular course of their business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may contract with other persons in the design, development, and distribution of the components of the education program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 88-380; s. 17, ch. 91-297; s. 1, ch. 95-187; s. 34, ch. 97-101.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.608.</Text></Note></Section>