<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.745" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; ss. 381.739-381.79.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 381.739-381.79, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Activity of daily living” means an activity required on a frequent basis which permits an individual to secure or maintain independence. Such activities include, but are not limited to, personal home care, transportation, personal assistance services, housekeeping, shopping, attending school, communication, and employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Brain or spinal cord injury” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lesion to the spinal cord or cauda equina, resulting from external trauma, with evidence of significant involvement of two of the following deficits or dysfunctions:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motor deficit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sensory deficit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bowel and bladder dysfunction.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insult to the skull, brain, or its covering, resulting from external trauma that produces an altered state of consciousness or anatomic motor, sensory, cognitive, or behavioral deficits.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Emergency medical evacuation system” means a department-approved transportation system that provides timely and skilled emergency care and movement of individuals believed to have sustained a brain or spinal cord injury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal assistance services” means a range of services, provided by one or more individuals, which are designed to assist an individual who has a disability to perform activities of daily living.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Funded services” means services paid for through the brain and spinal cord injury program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Designated facility” means a facility approved by the brain and spinal cord injury program which meets the criteria and standards of care of the brain and spinal cord injury program for individuals who have sustained a brain or spinal cord injury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Third-party coverage” means any claim for, right to receive payment for, or any coverage for the payment of any services under the brain and spinal cord injury program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Third-party payment” means any and all payments received or due as a result of any third-party obligation created by gift, coverage or other contract, settlement or judicial decision, or action of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transitional living facility” means a state-approved facility, as defined and licensed under chapter 400 or chapter 429, or a facility approved by the brain and spinal cord injury program in accordance with this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trauma center” means a department-approved acute care facility that provides diagnosis and treatment of individuals who have sustained a brain or spinal cord injury.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2000-367; s. 14, ch. 2006-197.</History></Section>