<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.0045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Targeted outreach for pregnant women.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Targeted Outreach for Pregnant Women Act of 1998.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the purpose of this section to establish a targeted outreach program for high-risk pregnant women who may not seek proper prenatal care, who suffer from substance abuse problems, or who are infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), and to provide these women with links to much needed services and information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct outreach programs through contracts with, grants to, or other working relationships with persons or entities where the target population is likely to be found.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide outreach that is peer-based, culturally sensitive, and performed in a nonjudgmental manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage high-risk pregnant women of unknown status to be tested for HIV.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educate women not receiving prenatal care as to the benefits of such care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide HIV-infected pregnant women with information so they can make an informed decision about the use of Zidovudine (AZT).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Link women with substance abuse treatment, when available, and act as a liaison with Healthy Start coalitions, children’s medical services, Ryan White-funded providers, and other services of the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide continued oversight to HIV-exposed newborns.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The types of entities the department is encouraged to contract with, provide grants to, or enter into other working relationships with may include, but are not limited to, faith-based organizations, academic institutions, religious organizations, nonprofit community centers, and other social-services-related entities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-307; s. 18, ch. 2001-62.</History></Section>