<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0381.0261" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Summary of patient’s bill of rights; distribution; penalty.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall publish on its Internet website a summary of the Florida Patient’s Bill of Rights and Responsibilities. In adopting and making available to patients the summary of the Florida Patient’s Bill of Rights and Responsibilities, health care providers and health care facilities are not limited to the format in which the department publishes the summary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care providers and health care facilities, if requested, shall inform patients of the address and telephone number of each state agency responsible for responding to patient complaints about a health care provider or health care facility’s alleged noncompliance with state licensing requirements established pursuant to law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care facilities shall adopt policies and procedures to ensure that inpatients are provided the opportunity during the course of admission to receive information regarding their rights and how to file complaints with the facility and appropriate state agencies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An administrative fine may be imposed by the Agency for Health Care Administration when any health care facility fails to make available to patients a summary of their rights, pursuant to s. 381.026 and this section. Initial nonwillful violations shall be subject to corrective action and shall not be subject to an administrative fine. The Agency for Health Care Administration may levy a fine against a health care facility of up to $5,000 for nonwillful violations and up to $25,000 for intentional and willful violations. Each intentional and willful violation constitutes a separate violation and is subject to a separate fine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An administrative fine may be imposed by the appropriate regulatory board, or the department if there is no board, when any health care provider fails to make available to patients a summary of their rights, pursuant to s. 381.026 and this section. Initial nonwillful violations shall be subject to corrective action and shall not be subject to an administrative fine. The appropriate regulatory board or department may levy a fine against a health care provider of up to $100 for nonwillful violations and up to $500 for willful violations. Each intentional and willful violation constitutes a separate violation and is subject to a separate fine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the amount of fine to be levied for a violation, as provided in subsection (4), the following factors shall be considered:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The scope and severity of the violation, including the number of patients found to not have received notice of patient rights, and whether the failure to provide notice to patients was willful.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken by the health care provider or health care facility to correct the violations or to remedy complaints.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous violations of this section by the health care provider or health care facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 91-127; s. 22, ch. 98-89; s. 179, ch. 98-166; s. 65, ch. 99-397; s. 43, ch. 2012-184.</History>
</Section>