<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0381.932" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Breast cancer early detection and treatment referral program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Breast cancer screening and referral services” means necessary breast cancer screening and referral services for a procedure intended to treat cancer of the human breast, including, but not limited to, surgery, radiation therapy, chemotherapy, hormonal therapy, and related medical followup services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unserved or underserved populations” means women who are:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At or below 200 percent of the federal poverty level for individuals;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without health insurance that covers breast cancer screenings; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nineteen to 64 years of age, inclusive.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established, within existing or specific appropriations, a breast cancer early detection and treatment referral program within the Department of Health. The purposes of the program are to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote referrals for the screening, detection, and treatment of breast cancer among unserved or underserved populations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educate the public regarding breast cancer and the benefits of early detection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide referral services for persons seeking treatment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall include, but not be limited to, the:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of a public education and outreach initiative to publicize breast cancer early detection services, the benefits of early detection of breast cancer, and the recommended frequency for receiving screening services, including clinical breast examinations and mammography guidelines established by the United States Preventive Services Task Force.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development of professional education programs that include information regarding the benefits of the early detection of breast cancer and the recommended frequency for receiving a mammogram, as recommended in the most current breast cancer screening guidelines established by the United States Preventive Services Task Force.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of a system to track and monitor all women screened for breast cancer in the program. The system shall include, but not be limited to, monitoring abnormal screening tests, referring women for treatment when needed, and tracking women to be screened at recommended screening intervals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General shall submit an annual report to the appropriate substantive committees of the Legislature. The report shall include, but not be limited to, a description of the rate of breast cancer morbidity and mortality in the state and the extent to which women are participating in breast cancer screening as reported by the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2009-120.</History></Section>