<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0330.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions, when used in ss. 330.29-330.36, 330.38, 330.39.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Aircraft” means a powered or unpowered machine or device capable of atmospheric flight, except a parachute or other such device used primarily as safety equipment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Airport” means an area of land or water used for, or intended to be used for, landing and takeoff of aircraft, including appurtenant areas, buildings, facilities, or rights-of-way necessary to facilitate such use or intended use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Transportation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited airport” means any airport limited exclusively to the specific conditions stated on the site approval order or license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private airport” means an airport, publicly or privately owned, which is not open or available for use by the public, but may be made available to others by invitation of the owner or manager.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public airport” means an airport, publicly or privately owned, which is open for use by the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Temporary airport” means any airport that will be used for a period of less than 30 days with no more than 10 operations per day.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ultralight aircraft” means any aircraft meeting the criteria established by part 103 of the Federal Aviation Regulations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 24046, 1947; s. 24, ch. 57-1; s. 2, ch. 65-178; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 103, ch. 71-377; s. 2, ch. 73-326; s. 1, ch. 75-16; s. 1, ch. 77-273; s. 1, ch. 84-205; s. 12, ch. 95-146; s. 475, ch. 95-148; s. 22, ch. 2003-286.</History></Section>