<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Procedure for and effect of administrative dissolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Department of State determines that one or more grounds exist under s. 607.1420 for dissolving a corporation, it shall serve the corporation with notice of its intention to administratively dissolve the corporation. If the corporation has provided the department with an electronic mail address, such notice shall be by electronic transmission. Administrative dissolution for failure to file an annual report shall occur on the fourth Friday in September of each year. The Department of State shall issue a certificate of dissolution to each dissolved corporation. Issuance of the certificate of dissolution may be by electronic transmission to any corporation that has provided the department with an electronic mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the corporation does not correct each ground for dissolution under s. 607.1420(1)(b), (c), (d), or (e) or demonstrate to the reasonable satisfaction of the Department of State that each ground determined by the department does not exist within 60 days of issuance of the notice, the department shall administratively dissolve the corporation by issuing a certificate of dissolution that recites the ground or grounds for dissolution and its effective date. Issuance of the certificate of dissolution may be by electronic transmission to any corporation that has provided the department with an electronic mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation administratively dissolved continues its corporate existence but may not carry on any business except that necessary to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs under s. 607.1405 and notify claimants under s. 607.1406.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director, officer, or agent of a corporation dissolved pursuant to this section, purporting to act on behalf of the corporation, is personally liable for the debts, obligations, and liabilities of the corporation arising from such action and incurred subsequent to the corporation’s administrative dissolution only if he or she has actual notice of the administrative dissolution at the time such action is taken; but such liability shall be terminated upon the ratification of such action by the corporation’s board of directors or shareholders subsequent to the reinstatement of the corporation under ss. 607.1401-607.14401.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrative dissolution of a corporation does not terminate the authority of its registered agent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 128, ch. 89-154; s. 1, ch. 95-211; s. 34, ch. 97-102; s. 10, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>