<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1330" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a shareholder makes demand for payment under s. 607.1326 which remains unsettled, the corporation shall commence a proceeding within 60 days after receiving the payment demand and petition the court to determine the fair value of the shares and accrued interest. If the corporation does not commence the proceeding within the 60-day period, any shareholder who has made a demand pursuant to s. 607.1326 may commence the proceeding in the name of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeding shall be commenced in the appropriate court of the county in which the corporation’s principal office, or, if none, its registered office, in this state is located. If the corporation is a foreign corporation without a registered office in this state, the proceeding shall be commenced in the county in this state in which the principal office or registered office of the domestic corporation merged with the foreign corporation was located at the time of the transaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All shareholders, whether or not residents of this state, whose demands remain unsettled shall be made parties to the proceeding as in an action against their shares. The corporation shall serve a copy of the initial pleading in such proceeding upon each shareholder party who is a resident of this state in the manner provided by law for the service of a summons and complaint and upon each nonresident shareholder party by registered or certified mail or by publication as provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of the court in which the proceeding is commenced under subsection (2) is plenary and exclusive. If it so elects, the court may appoint one or more persons as appraisers to receive evidence and recommend a decision on the question of fair value. The appraisers shall have the powers described in the order appointing them or in any amendment to the order. The shareholders demanding appraisal rights are entitled to the same discovery rights as parties in other civil proceedings. There shall be no right to a jury trial.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each shareholder made a party to the proceeding is entitled to judgment for the amount of the fair value of such shareholder’s shares, plus interest, as found by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall pay each such shareholder the amount found to be due within 10 days after final determination of the proceedings. Upon payment of the judgment, the shareholder shall cease to have any interest in the shares.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2004-378.</History></Section>