<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of meeting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation shall notify shareholders of the date, time, and place of each annual and special shareholders’ meeting no fewer than 10 or more than 60 days before the meeting date. Unless this act or the articles of incorporation require otherwise, the corporation is required to give notice only to shareholders entitled to vote at the meeting. Notice shall be given in the manner provided in s. 607.0141, by or at the direction of the president, the secretary, or the officer or persons calling the meeting. If the notice is mailed at least 30 days before the date of the meeting, it may be done by a class of United States mail other than first class. Notwithstanding s. 607.0141, if mailed, such notice shall be deemed to be delivered when deposited in the United States mail addressed to the shareholder at her or his address as it appears on the stock transfer books of the corporation, with postage thereon prepaid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless this act or the articles of incorporation require otherwise, notice of an annual meeting need not include a description of the purpose or purposes for which the meeting is called.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of a special meeting must include a description of the purpose or purposes for which the meeting is called.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the bylaws require otherwise, if an annual or special shareholders’ meeting is adjourned to a different date, time, or place, notice need not be given of the new date, time, or place if the new date, time, or place is announced at the meeting before an adjournment is taken, and any business may be transacted at the adjourned meeting that might have been transacted on the original date of the meeting. If a new record date for the adjourned meeting is or must be fixed under s. 607.0707, however, notice of the adjourned meeting must be given under this section to persons who are shareholders as of the new record date who are entitled to notice of the meeting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the foregoing, no notice of a shareholders’ meeting need be given to a shareholder if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual report and proxy statements for two consecutive annual meetings of shareholders or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All, and at least two checks in payment of dividends or interest on securities during a 12-month period,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">have been sent by first-class United States mail, addressed to the shareholder at her or his address as it appears on the share transfer books of the corporation, and returned undeliverable. The obligation of the corporation to give notice of a shareholders’ meeting to any such shareholder shall be reinstated once the corporation has received a new address for such shareholder for entry on its share transfer books.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 89-154; s. 11, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>