<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0128" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certificate of status.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Anyone may apply to the Department of State to furnish a certificate of status for a domestic corporation or a certificate of authorization for a foreign corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of status or authorization sets forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The domestic corporation’s corporate name or the foreign corporation’s corporate name used in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the domestic corporation is duly incorporated under the law of this state and the date of its incorporation, or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the foreign corporation is authorized to transact business in this state;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all fees and penalties owed to the department have been paid, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment is reflected in the records of the department, and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonpayment affects the existence or authorization of the domestic or foreign corporation;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That its most recent annual report required by s. 607.1622 has been delivered to the department; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That articles of dissolution have not been filed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to any qualification stated in the certificate, a certificate of status or authorization issued by the department may be relied upon as conclusive evidence that the domestic or foreign corporation is in existence or is authorized to transact business in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>