<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0505" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registered agent; duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization that owns real property located in this state, that owns a mortgage on real property located in this state, or that transacts business in this state shall have and continuously maintain in this state a registered office and a registered agent and shall file with the Department of State notice of the registered office and registered agent as provided in ss. 607.0501 and 607.0502. The appointment of a registered agent in compliance with s. 607.0501 or s. 607.1507 is sufficient for purposes of this section provided the registered agent so appointed files, in such form and manner as prescribed by the Department of State, an acceptance of the obligations provided for in this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each such corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization which fails to have and continuously maintain a registered office and a registered agent as required in this section will be liable to this state for $500 for each year, or part of a year, during which the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization fails to comply with these requirements; but such liability will be forgiven in full upon the compliance by the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization with the requirements of this subsection, even if such compliance occurs after an action to collect such liability is instituted. The Department of Legal Affairs may file an action in the circuit court for the judicial circuit in which the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization is found or transacts business, or in which real property belonging to the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization is located, to petition the court for an order directing that a registered agent be appointed and that a registered office be designated, and to obtain judgment for the amount owed under this subsection. In connection with such proceeding, the department may, without prior approval by the court, file a lis pendens against real property owned by the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization, which lis pendens shall set forth the legal description of the real property and shall be filed in the public records of the county where the real property is located. If the lis pendens is filed in any county other than the county in which the action is pending, the lis pendens which is filed must be a certified copy of the original lis pendens. The failure to comply timely or fully with an order directing that a registered agent be appointed and that a registered office be designated will result in a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for each day of noncompliance. A judgment or an order of payment entered pursuant to this subsection will become a judgment lien against any real property owned by the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization when a certified copy of the judgment or order is recorded as required by s. 55.10. The department will be able to avail itself of, and is entitled to use, any provision of law or of the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure to further the collecting or obtaining of payment pursuant to a judgment or order of payment. The state, through the Attorney General, may bid, at any judicial sale to enforce its judgment lien, any amount up to the amount of the judgment or lien obtained pursuant to this subsection. All moneys recovered under this subsection shall be treated as forfeitures under ss. 895.01-895.09 and used or distributed in accordance with the procedure set forth in s. 895.09. A corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization which fails to have and continuously maintain a registered office and a registered agent as required in this section may not defend itself against any action instituted by the Department of Legal Affairs or by any other agency of this state until the requirements of this subsection have been met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization that owns real property located in this state, that owns a mortgage on real property located in this state, or that transacts business in this state shall, pursuant to subpoena served upon the registered agent of the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization issued by the Department of Legal Affairs, produce, through its registered agent or through a designated representative within 30 days after service of the subpoena, testimony and records reflecting the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">True copies of documents evidencing the legal existence of the entity, including the articles of incorporation and any amendments to the articles of incorporation or the legal equivalent of the articles of incorporation and such amendments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of each current officer and director of the entity or persons holding equivalent positions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of all prior officers and directors of the entity or persons holding equivalent positions, for a period not to exceed the 5 years previous to the date of issuance of the subpoena.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of each current shareholder, equivalent equitable owner, and ultimate equitable owner of the entity, the number of which names is limited to the names of the 100 shareholders, equivalent equitable owners, and ultimate equitable owners that, in comparison to all other shareholders, equivalent equitable owners, or ultimate equitable owners, respectively, own the largest number of shares of stock of the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization or the largest percentage of an equivalent form of equitable ownership of the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of all prior shareholders, equivalent equitable owners, and ultimate equitable owners of the entity for the 12-month period preceding the date of issuance of the subpoena, the number of which names is limited to the 100 shareholders, equivalent equitable owners, and ultimate equitable owners that, in comparison to all other shareholders, equivalent equitable owners, or ultimate equitable owners, respectively, own the largest number of shares of stock of the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization or the largest percentage of an equivalent form of equitable ownership of the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of the person or persons who provided the records and information to the registered agent or designated representative of the entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of paragraphs (d) and (e) do not apply to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financial institution;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization the securities of which are registered pursuant to s. 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, 15 U.S.C. ss. 78a-78kk, if such corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization files with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission the reports required by s. 13 of that act; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization, the securities of which are regularly traded on an established securities market located in the United States or on an established securities market located outside the United States, if such non-United States securities market is designated by rule adopted by the Department of Legal Affairs;</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">upon a showing by the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization that the exception in subparagraph 1., subparagraph 2., or subparagraph 3. applies to the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization. Such exception in subparagraph 1., subparagraph 2., or subparagraph 3. does not, however, exempt the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization from the requirements for producing records, information, or testimony otherwise imposed under this section for any period of time when the requisite conditions for the exception did not exist.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time limit for producing records and testimony may be extended for good cause shown by the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person, corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization designating an attorney, accountant, or spouse as a registered agent or designated representative shall, with respect to this state or any agency or subdivision of this state, be deemed to have waived any privilege that might otherwise attach to communications with respect to the information required to be produced pursuant to subsection (2), which communications are among such corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization; the registered agent or designated representative of such corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization; and the beneficial owners of such corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization. The duty to comply with the provisions of this section will not be excused by virtue of any privilege or provision of law of this state or any other state or country, which privilege or provision authorizes or directs that the testimony or records required to be produced under subsection (2) are privileged or confidential or otherwise may not be disclosed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization fails without lawful excuse to comply timely or fully with a subpoena issued pursuant to subsection (2), the Department of Legal Affairs may file an action in the circuit court for the judicial circuit in which the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization is found or transacts business or in which real property belonging to the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization is located, for an order compelling compliance with the subpoena. The failure without a lawful excuse to comply timely or fully with an order compelling compliance with the subpoena will result in a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 for each day of noncompliance with the order. In connection with such proceeding, the department may, without prior approval by the court, file a lis pendens against real property owned by the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization, which lis pendens shall set forth the legal description of the real property and shall be filed in the public records of the county where the real property is located. If the lis pendens is filed in any county other than the county in which the action is pending, the lis pendens which is filed must be a certified copy of the original lis pendens. A judgment or an order of payment entered pursuant to this subsection will become a judgment lien against any real property owned by the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization when a certified copy of the judgment or order is recorded as required by s. 55.10. The department will be able to avail itself of, and is entitled to use, any provision of law or of the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure to further the collecting or obtaining of payment pursuant to a judgment or order of payment. The state, through the Attorney General, may bid, at any judicial sale to enforce its judgment lien, an amount up to the amount of the judgment or lien obtained pursuant to this subsection. All moneys recovered under this subsection shall be treated as forfeitures under ss. 895.01-895.09 and used or distributed in accordance with the procedure set forth in s. 895.09.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information provided to, and records and transcriptions of testimony obtained by, the Department of Legal Affairs pursuant to this section are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) while the investigation is active. For purposes of this section, an investigation shall be considered “active” while such investigation is being conducted with a reasonable, good faith belief that it may lead to the filing of an administrative, civil, or criminal proceeding. An investigation does not cease to be active so long as the department is proceeding with reasonable dispatch and there is a good faith belief that action may be initiated by the department or other administrative or law enforcement agency. Except for active criminal intelligence or criminal investigative information, as defined in s. 119.011, and information which, if disclosed, would reveal a trade secret, as defined in s. 688.002, or would jeopardize the safety of an individual, all information, records, and transcriptions become public record when the investigation is completed or ceases to be active. The department shall not disclose confidential information, records, or transcriptions of testimony except pursuant to the authorization by the Attorney General in any of the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a law enforcement agency participating in or conducting a civil investigation under chapter 895, or participating in or conducting a criminal investigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the course of filing, participating in, or conducting a judicial proceeding instituted pursuant to this section or chapter 895.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the course of filing, participating in, or conducting a judicial proceeding to enforce an order or judgment entered pursuant to this section or chapter 895.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the course of a criminal or civil proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A person or law enforcement agency which receives any information, record, or transcription of testimony that has been made confidential by this subsection shall maintain the confidentiality of such material and shall not disclose such information, record, or transcription of testimony except as provided for herein. Any person who willfully discloses any information, record, or transcription of testimony that has been made confidential by this subsection, except as provided for herein, is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. If any information, record, or testimony obtained pursuant to subsection (2) is offered in evidence in any judicial proceeding, the court may, in its discretion, seal that portion of the record to further the policies of confidentiality set forth herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is supplemental and shall not be construed to preclude or limit the scope of evidence gathering or other permissible discovery pursuant to any other subpoena or discovery method authorized by law or rule of procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, with respect to any record or testimony produced pursuant to a subpoena issued by the Department of Legal Affairs under subsection (2), to knowingly and willfully falsify, conceal, or cover up a material fact by a trick, scheme, or device; make any false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation; or make or use any false writing or document knowing the writing or document to contain any false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or entry. A person who violates this provision is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of a written agreement to the contrary, a registered agent is not liable for the failure to give notice of the receipt of a subpoena under subsection (2) to the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization which appointed such registered agent if such registered agent timely sends written notice of the receipt of such subpoena by first-class mail or domestic or international air mail, postage fees prepaid, to the last address that has been designated in writing to the registered agent by such appointing corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designation of a registered agent and a registered office as required by subsection (1) for a corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization which owns real property in this state or a mortgage on real property in this state is solely for the purposes of this act; and, notwithstanding s. 48.181, s. 607.1502, s. 607.1503, or any other relevant section of the Florida Statutes, such designation shall not be used in determining whether the corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization is actually doing business in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alien business organization” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporation, association, partnership, trust, joint stock company, or other entity organized under any laws other than the laws of the United States, of any United States territory or possession, or of any state of the United States; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporation, association, partnership, trust, joint stock company, or other entity or device 10 percent or more of which is owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by an entity described in subparagraph 1. or by a foreign natural person.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Financial institution” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank, banking organization, or savings association, as defined in s. 220.62;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurance company, trust company, credit union, or industrial savings bank, any of which is licensed or regulated by an agency of the United States or any state of the United States; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person licensed under part III of chapter 494.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgage” means a mortgage on real property situated in this state, except a mortgage owned by a financial institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Real property” means any real property situated in this state or any interest in such real property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ultimate equitable owner” means a natural person who, directly or indirectly, owns or controls an ownership interest in a corporation, foreign corporation, or alien business organization, regardless of whether such natural person owns or controls such ownership interest through one or other natural persons or one or more proxies, powers of attorney, nominees, corporations, associations, partnerships, trusts, joint stock companies, or other entities or devices, or any combination thereof.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any alien business organization may withdraw its registered agent designation by delivering an application for certificate of withdrawal to the Department of State for filing. Such application shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the alien business organization and the jurisdiction under the law of which it is incorporated or organized.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it is no longer required to maintain a registered agent in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 165, ch. 89-154; s. 141, ch. 90-179; s. 58, ch. 91-245; s. 1, ch. 92-14; s. 360, ch. 96-406; s. 7, ch. 2003-283; s. 68, ch. 2009-241.</History></Section>