<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0831" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liability of directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director is not personally liable for monetary damages to the corporation or any other person for any statement, vote, decision, or failure to act, regarding corporate management or policy, by a director, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director breached or failed to perform his or her duties as a director; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director’s breach of, or failure to perform, those duties constitutes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the criminal law, unless the director had reasonable cause to believe his or her conduct was lawful or had no reasonable cause to believe his or her conduct was unlawful. A judgment or other final adjudication against a director in any criminal proceeding for a violation of the criminal law estops that director from contesting the fact that his or her breach, or failure to perform, constitutes a violation of the criminal law; but does not estop the director from establishing that he or she had reasonable cause to believe that his or her conduct was lawful or had no reasonable cause to believe that his or her conduct was unlawful;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transaction from which the director derived an improper personal benefit, either directly or indirectly;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A circumstance under which the liability provisions of s. 607.0834 are applicable;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by or in the right of the corporation to procure a judgment in its favor or by or in the right of a shareholder, conscious disregard for the best interest of the corporation, or willful misconduct; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by or in the right of someone other than the corporation or a shareholder, recklessness or an act or omission which was committed in bad faith or with malicious purpose or in a manner exhibiting wanton and willful disregard of human rights, safety, or property.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “recklessness” means the action, or omission to act, in conscious disregard of a risk:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Known, or so obvious that it should have been known, to the director; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Known to the director, or so obvious that it should have been known, to be so great as to make it highly probable that harm would follow from such action or omission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director is deemed not to have derived an improper personal benefit from any transaction if the transaction and the nature of any personal benefit derived by the director are not prohibited by state or federal law or regulation and, without further limitation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an action other than a derivative suit regarding a decision by the director to approve, reject, or otherwise affect the outcome of an offer to purchase the stock of, or to effect a merger of, the corporation, the transaction and the nature of any personal benefits derived by a director are disclosed or known to all directors voting on the matter, and the transaction was authorized, approved, or ratified by at least two directors who comprise a majority of the disinterested directors (whether or not such disinterested directors constitute a quorum);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction and the nature of any personal benefits derived by a director are disclosed or known to the shareholders entitled to vote, and the transaction was authorized, approved, or ratified by the affirmative vote or written consent of such shareholders who hold a majority of the shares, the voting of which is not controlled by directors who derived a personal benefit from or otherwise had a personal interest in the transaction; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction was fair and reasonable to the corporation at the time it was authorized by the board, a committee, or the shareholders, notwithstanding that a director received a personal benefit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circumstances set forth in subsection (3) are not exclusive and do not preclude the existence of other circumstances under which a director will be deemed not to have derived an improper benefit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 85, ch. 89-154; s. 24, ch. 93-281; s. 27, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>