<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conversion of another business entity to a domestic corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “other business entity” means a limited liability company; a common law or business trust or association; a real estate investment trust; a general partnership, including a limited liability partnership; a limited partnership, including a limited liability limited partnership; or any other domestic or foreign entity that is organized under a governing law or other applicable law, provided such term shall not include a corporation and shall not include any entity that has not been organized for profit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other business entity may convert to a domestic corporation if the conversion is permitted by the laws of the jurisdiction that enacted the applicable laws governing the other business entity and the other business entity complies with such laws and the requirements of this section in effecting the conversion. The other business entity shall file with the Department of State in accordance with s. 607.0120:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of conversion that has been executed in accordance with s. 607.0120 and by the other business entity as required by applicable law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Articles of incorporation that comply with s. 607.0202 and have been executed in accordance with s. 607.0120.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate of conversion shall state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date on which, and the jurisdiction in which, the other business entity was first organized and, if the entity has changed, its jurisdiction immediately prior to its conversion.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the other business entity immediately prior to the filing of the certificate of conversion to a corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the corporation as set forth in its articles of incorporation filed in accordance with subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delayed effective date or time, which, subject to the limitations in s. 607.0123(2), shall be a date or time certain, of the conversion if the conversion is not to be effective upon the filing of the certificate of conversion and the articles of incorporation, provided such delayed effective date may not be different than the effective date and time of the articles of incorporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing with the Department of State of the certificate of conversion and the articles of incorporation, or upon the delayed effective date or time of the certificate of conversion and the articles of incorporation, the other business entity shall be converted into a domestic corporation and the corporation shall thereafter be subject to all of the provisions of this chapter, except notwithstanding s. 607.0123, the existence of the corporation shall be deemed to have commenced when the other business entity commenced its existence in the jurisdiction in which the other business entity was first organized.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conversion of any other business entity into a domestic corporation shall not affect any obligations or liabilities of the other business entity incurred prior to its conversion to a domestic corporation or the personal liability of any person incurred prior to such conversion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any conversion becomes effective under this section, for all purposes of the laws of this state, all of the rights, privileges, and powers of the other business entity that has been converted, and all property, real, personal, and mixed, and all debts due to such other business entity, as well as all other things and causes of action belonging to such other business entity, shall be vested in the domestic corporation into which it was converted and shall thereafter be the property of the domestic corporation as they were of the other business entity. Without limiting this provision, title to any real property, or any interest therein, vested by deed or otherwise in such other business entity at the time of conversion shall remain vested in the converted entity without reversion or impairment by operation of this chapter. All rights of creditors and all liens upon any property of such other business entity shall be preserved unimpaired, and all debts, liabilities, and duties of such other business entity shall thenceforth attach to the domestic corporation into which it was converted and may be enforced against the domestic corporation to the same extent as if said debts, liabilities, and duties had been incurred or contracted by the domestic corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise agreed, or as required under applicable laws of states other than this state, the converting entity shall not be required to wind up its affairs or pay its liabilities and distribute its assets and the conversion shall not constitute a dissolution of such entity and shall constitute a continuation of the existence of the converting entity in the form of a domestic corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to filing a certificate of conversion with the Department of State, the conversion shall be approved in the manner provided for by the document, instrument, agreement, or other writing, as the case may be, governing the internal affairs of the other business entity or by other applicable law, as appropriate, and the articles of incorporation and bylaws of the corporation shall be approved by the same authorization required to approve the conversion. As part of such an approval, a plan of conversion or other record may describe the manner and basis of converting the partnership interests, limited liability company interests, obligations, or securities of, or other interests or rights in, the other business entity, including any rights to acquire any such interests, obligations, securities, or other rights, into shares of the domestic corporation, or rights to acquire shares, obligations, securities, or other rights, or, in whole or in part, into cash or other consideration. Such a plan or other record may also contain other provisions relating to the conversion, including without limitation the right of the other business entity to abandon a proposed conversion, or an effective date for the conversion that is not inconsistent with paragraph (2)(d).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-267; s. 3, ch. 2008-187.</History></Section>