<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1508" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Change of registered office and registered agent of foreign corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation authorized to transact business in this state may change its registered office or registered agent by delivering to the Department of State for filing a statement of change that sets forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its name;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of its current registered office;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the current registered office is to be changed, the street address of its new registered office;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of its current registered agent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the current registered agent is to be changed, the name of its new registered agent and the new agent’s written consent (either on the statement or attached to it) to the appointment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, after the change or changes are made, the street address of its registered office and the business office of its registered agent will be identical; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That such change was authorized by resolution duly adopted by its board of directors or by an officer of the corporation so authorized by the board of directors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a registered agent changes the street address of her or his business office, she or he may change the street address of the registered office of any foreign corporation for which she or he is the registered agent by notifying the corporation in writing of the change and signing (either manually or in facsimile) and delivering to the Department of State for filing a statement of change that complies with the requirements of paragraphs (1)(a)-(f) and recites that the corporation has been notified of the change.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 143, ch. 89-154; s. 163, ch. 90-179; s. 41, ch. 93-281; s. 39, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>