<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0728" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Voting for directors; cumulative voting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation, or in a bylaw that fixes a greater voting requirement for the election of directors and that is adopted by the board of directors or shareholders of a corporation having shares listed on a national securities exchange at the time of adoption, directors are elected by a plurality of the votes cast by the shares entitled to vote in the election at a meeting at which a quorum is present. A bylaw provision or amendment adopted by shareholders which specifies the votes necessary for the election of directors may not be further amended or repealed by the board of directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each shareholder who is entitled to vote at an election of directors has the right to vote the number of shares owned by him or her for as many persons as there are directors to be elected and for whose election the shareholder has a right to vote. Shareholders do not have a right to cumulate their votes for directors unless the articles of incorporation so provide.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement included in the articles of incorporation that “all or a designated voting group of shareholders are entitled to cumulate their votes for directors,” or words of similar import, means that the shareholders designated are entitled to multiply the number of votes they are entitled to cast by the number of directors for whom they are entitled to vote and cast the product for a single candidate or distribute the product among two or more candidates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 64, ch. 89-154; s. 16, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>