<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1107" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Merger or share exchange with foreign corporations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more foreign corporations may merge or enter into a share exchange with one or more domestic corporations if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a merger, the merger is permitted by the law of the state or country under the law of which each foreign corporation is incorporated and each foreign corporation complies with that law in effecting the merger;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a share exchange, the corporation the shares of which will be acquired is a domestic corporation, whether or not a share exchange is permitted by law of the state or country under the law of which the acquiring corporation is incorporated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign corporation complies with s. 607.1105 if it is the surviving corporation of the merger or acquiring corporation of the share exchange; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each domestic corporation complies with the applicable provisions of ss. 607.1101-607.1104 and, if it is the surviving corporation of the merger or acquiring corporation of the share exchange, with s. 607.1105.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the merger becoming effective, the surviving foreign corporation of a merger, and the acquiring foreign corporation in a share exchange, is deemed:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To appoint the Secretary of State as its agent for service of process in a proceeding to enforce any obligation or the rights of dissenting shareholders of each domestic corporation party to the merger or share exchange; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To agree that it will promptly pay to the dissenting shareholders of each domestic corporation party to the merger or share exchange the amount, if any, to which they are entitled under s. 607.1302.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not limit the power of a foreign corporation to acquire all or part of the shares of one or more classes or series of a domestic corporation through a voluntary exchange or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect of such merger shall be the same as in the case of the merger of domestic corporations if the surviving corporation is to be governed by the laws of this state. If the surviving corporation is to be governed by the laws of any state other than this state, the effect of such merger shall be the same as in the case of the merger of domestic corporations except insofar as the laws of such other state provide otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The redomestication of a foreign insurer to this state under s. 628.520 shall be deemed a merger of a foreign corporation and a domestic corporation, and the surviving corporation shall be deemed to be a domestic corporation incorporated under the laws of this state. The redomestication of a Florida corporation to a foreign jurisdiction under s. 628.525 shall be deemed a merger of a domestic corporation and a foreign corporation, and the surviving corporation shall be deemed to be a foreign corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 115, ch. 89-154; s. 5, ch. 2004-378.</History></Section>