<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amendment by board of directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the articles of incorporation provide otherwise, a corporation’s board of directors may adopt one or more amendments to the corporation’s articles of incorporation without shareholder action:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To extend the duration of the corporation if it was incorporated at a time when limited duration was required by law;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To delete the names and addresses of the initial directors;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To delete the name and address of the initial registered agent or registered office, if a statement of change is on file with the Department of State;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To delete any other information contained in the articles of incorporation that is solely of historical interest;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To delete the authorization for a class or series of shares authorized pursuant to s. 607.0602, if no shares of such class or series are issued;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To change the corporate name by substituting the word “corporation,” “incorporated,” or “company,” or the abbreviation “corp.,” “Inc.,” or “Co.,” for a similar word or abbreviation in the name, or by adding, deleting, or changing a geographical attribution for the name;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To change the par value for a class or series of shares;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide that if the corporation acquires its own shares, such shares belong to the corporation and constitute treasury shares until disposed of or canceled by the corporation; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make any other change expressly permitted by this act to be made without shareholder action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 98, ch. 89-154; s. 28, ch. 93-281; s. 7, ch. 97-230.</History></Section>