<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1402" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dissolution by board of directors and shareholders; dissolution by written consent of shareholders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation’s board of directors may propose dissolution for submission to the shareholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a proposal to dissolve to be adopted:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors must recommend dissolution to the shareholders, unless the board of directors determines that because of conflict of interest or other special circumstances it should make no recommendation and communicates the basis for its determination to the shareholders; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The shareholders entitled to vote must approve the proposal to dissolve as provided in subsection (5).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may condition its submission of the proposal for dissolution on any basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall notify each shareholder of record, whether or not entitled to vote, of the proposed shareholders’ meeting in accordance with s. 607.0705. The notice must also state that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of the meeting is to consider dissolving the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the articles of incorporation or the board of directors (acting pursuant to subsection (3)) require a greater vote or a vote by voting groups, the proposal to dissolve to be adopted must be approved by a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast on that proposal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alternatively, without action of the board of directors, action to dissolve a corporation may be taken by the written consent of the shareholders pursuant to s. 607.0704.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 122, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>