<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Merger of subsidiary corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent corporation owning at least 80 percent of the outstanding shares of each class of a subsidiary corporation may merge the subsidiary into itself, may merge itself into the subsidiary, or may merge the subsidiary into and with another subsidiary in which the parent corporation owns at least 80 percent of the outstanding shares of each class of the subsidiary without the approval of the shareholders of the parent or subsidiary. In a merger of a parent corporation into its subsidiary corporation, the approval of the shareholders of the parent corporation shall be required if the articles of incorporation of the surviving corporation will differ, except for amendments enumerated in s. 607.1002, from the articles of incorporation of the parent corporation before the merger, and the required vote shall be the greater of the vote required to approve the merger and the vote required to adopt each change to the articles of incorporation as if each change had been presented as an amendment to the articles of incorporation of the parent corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of the parent shall adopt a plan of merger that sets forth:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of the parent and subsidiary corporations;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner and basis of converting the shares of the subsidiary or parent into shares, obligations, or other securities of the parent or any other corporation or, in whole or in part, into cash or other property, and the manner and basis of converting rights to acquire shares of each corporation into rights to acquire shares, obligations, and other securities of the surviving or any other corporation or, in whole or in part, into cash or other property;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the merger is between the parent and a subsidiary corporation and the parent is not the surviving corporation, a provision for the pro rata issuance of shares of the subsidiary to the holders of the shares of the parent corporation upon surrender of any certificates therefor; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear and concise statement that shareholders of the subsidiary who, except for the applicability of this section, would be entitled to vote and who dissent from the merger pursuant to s. 607.1321, may be entitled, if they comply with the provisions of this act regarding appraisal rights, to be paid the fair value of their shares.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent shall mail a copy or summary of the plan of merger to each shareholder of the subsidiary who does not waive the mailing requirement in writing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent may not deliver articles of merger to the Department of State for filing until at least 30 days after the date it mailed a copy of the plan of merger to each shareholder of the subsidiary who did not waive the mailing requirement, or, if earlier, upon the waiver thereof by the holders of all of the outstanding shares of the subsidiary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Articles of merger under this section may not contain amendments to the articles of incorporation of the parent corporation (except for amendments enumerated in s. 607.1002).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two or more subsidiaries may be merged into the parent pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 112, ch. 89-154; s. 33, ch. 93-281; s. 17, ch. 2003-283.</History></Section>