<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0602" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Terms of class or series determined by board of directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the articles of incorporation so provide, the board of directors may determine, in whole or part, the preferences, limitations, and relative rights (within the limits set forth in s. 607.0601) of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any class of shares before the issuance of any shares of that class, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more series within a class before the issuance of any shares of that series.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each series of a class must be given a distinguishing designation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All shares of a series must have preferences, limitations, and relative rights identical with those of other shares of the same series and, except to the extent otherwise provided in the description of the series, of those of other series of the same class.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before issuing any shares of a class or series created under this section, the corporation must deliver to the Department of State for filing articles of amendment, which are effective without shareholder action, that set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The text of the amendment determining the terms of the class or series of shares;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the amendment was adopted; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the amendment was duly adopted by the board of directors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>