<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.07401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Shareholders’ derivative actions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not commence a proceeding in the right of a domestic or foreign corporation unless the person was a shareholder of the corporation when the transaction complained of occurred or unless the person became a shareholder through transfer by operation of law from one who was a shareholder at that time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A complaint in a proceeding brought in the right of a corporation must be verified and allege with particularity the demand made to obtain action by the board of directors and that the demand was refused or ignored by the board of directors for a period of at least 90 days from the first demand unless, prior to the expiration of the 90 days, the person was notified in writing that the corporation rejected the demand, or unless irreparable injury to the corporation would result by waiting for the expiration of the 90-day period. If the corporation commences an investigation of the charges made in the demand or complaint, the court may stay any proceeding until the investigation is completed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may dismiss a derivative proceeding if, on motion by the corporation, the court finds that one of the groups specified below has made a determination in good faith after conducting a reasonable investigation upon which its conclusions are based that the maintenance of the derivative suit is not in the best interests of the corporation. The corporation shall have the burden of proving the independence and good faith of the group making the determination and the reasonableness of the investigation. The determination shall be made by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority vote of independent directors present at a meeting of the board of directors, if the independent directors constitute a quorum;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority vote of a committee consisting of two or more independent directors appointed by a majority vote of independent directors present at a meeting of the board of directors, whether or not such independent directors constitute a quorum; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A panel of one or more independent persons appointed by the court upon motion by the corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proceeding commenced under this section may not be discontinued or settled without the court’s approval. If the court determines that a proposed discontinuance or settlement will substantially affect the interest of the corporation’s shareholders or a class, series, or voting group of shareholders, the court shall direct that notice be given to the shareholders affected. The court may determine which party or parties to the proceeding shall bear the expense of giving the notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On termination of the proceeding, the court may require the plaintiff to pay any defendant’s reasonable expenses, including reasonable attorney’s fees, incurred in defending the proceeding if it finds that the proceeding was commenced without reasonable cause.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may award reasonable expenses for maintaining the proceeding, including reasonable attorney’s fees, to a successful plaintiff or to the person commencing the proceeding who receives any relief, whether by judgment, compromise, or settlement, and require that the person account for the remainder of any proceeds to the corporation; however, this subsection does not apply to any relief rendered for the benefit of injured shareholders only and limited to a recovery of the loss or damage of the injured shareholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, “shareholder” includes a beneficial owner whose shares are held in a voting trust or held by a nominee on his or her behalf.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 67, ch. 89-154; s. 148, ch. 90-179; s. 19, ch. 97-102; s. 11, ch. 2003-283.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 607.0740.</Text></Note></Section>