<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1801" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Domestication of foreign corporations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “corporation” includes any incorporated organization, private law corporation (whether or not organized for business purposes), public law corporation, partnership, proprietorship, joint venture, foundation, trust, association, or similar entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any foreign corporation may become domesticated in this state by filing with the Department of State:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of domestication which shall be executed in accordance with subsection (7) and filed and recorded in accordance with s. 607.0120; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Articles of incorporation, which shall be executed, filed, and recorded in accordance with ss. 607.0120 and 607.0202.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate of domestication shall certify:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date on which and jurisdiction where the corporation was first formed, incorporated, or otherwise came into being;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the corporation immediately prior to the filing of the certificate of domestication;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the corporation as set forth in its articles of incorporation filed in accordance with paragraph (2)(b); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction that constituted the seat, siege social, or principal place of business or central administration of the corporation, or any other equivalent thereto under applicable law, immediately prior to the filing of the certificate of domestication.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon filing with the Department of State of the certificate of domestication and articles of incorporation, the corporation shall be domesticated in this state, and the corporation shall thereafter be subject to this act, except that notwithstanding the provision of s. 607.0203 the existence of the corporation shall be deemed to have commenced on the date the corporation commenced its existence in the jurisdiction in which the corporation was first formed, incorporated, or otherwise came into being.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The domestication of any corporation in this state shall not be deemed to affect any obligations or liabilities of the corporation incurred prior to its domestication.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a certificate of domestication shall not affect the choice of law applicable to the corporation, except that, from the date the certificate of domestication is filed, the law of this state, including this act, shall apply to the corporation to the same extent as if the corporation has been incorporated as a corporation of this state on that date.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate of domestication shall be signed by any corporation officer, director, trustee, manager, partner, or other person performing functions equivalent to those of an officer or director, however named or described, and who is authorized to sign the certificate of domestication on behalf of the corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 160, ch. 89-154; s. 169, ch. 90-179; s. 5, ch. 96-212.</History></Section>