<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0604" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fractional shares.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue fractions of a share or pay in money the fair value of fractions of a share;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make arrangements, or provide reasonable opportunity, for any person entitled to or holding a fractional interest in a share to sell such fractional interest or to purchase such additional fractional interests as may be necessary to acquire a full share;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue scrip in registered or bearer form, over the manual or facsimile signature of an officer of the corporation or its agent, entitling the holder to receive a full share upon surrendering enough scrip to equal a full share.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may authorize the issuance of scrip subject to any condition considered desirable, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the scrip will become void if not exchanged for full shares before a specified date; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the shares for which the scrip is exchangeable may be sold and the proceeds paid to the scripholders.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each certificate representing scrip must be conspicuously labeled “scrip” and must contain the information required by s. 607.0625.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder of a fractional share is entitled to exercise the rights of a shareholder, including the right to vote, to receive dividends, and to participate in the assets of the corporation upon liquidation. The holder of scrip is not entitled to any of these rights unless the scrip provides for them.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a corporation is to pay in money the value of fractions of a share, the good faith judgment of the board of directors as to the fair value shall be conclusive.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>