<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1406" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Known claims against dissolved corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity, as defined in subsection (15), may dispose of the known claims against it by following the procedures described in subsections (2), (3), and (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dissolved corporation or successor entity shall deliver to each of its known claimants written notice of the dissolution at any time after its effective date. The written notice shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a reasonable description of the claim that the claimant may be entitled to assert;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State whether the claim is admitted or not admitted, in whole or in part, and, if admitted:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount that is admitted, which may be as of a given date; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interest obligation if fixed by an instrument of indebtedness;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a mailing address where a claim may be sent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State the deadline, which may not be fewer than 120 days after the effective date of the written notice, by which confirmation of the claim must be delivered to the dissolved corporation or successor entity; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State that the corporation or successor entity may make distributions thereafter to other claimants and the corporation’s shareholders or persons interested as having been such without further notice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity may reject, in whole or in part, any claim made by a claimant pursuant to this subsection by mailing notice of such rejection to the claimant within 90 days after receipt of such claim and, in all events, at least 150 days before expiration of 3 years following the effective date of dissolution. A notice sent by the dissolved corporation or successor entity pursuant to this subsection shall be accompanied by a copy of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity electing to follow the procedures described in subsections (2) and (3) shall also give notice of the dissolution of the corporation to persons with known claims, that are contingent upon the occurrence or nonoccurrence of future events or otherwise conditional or unmatured, and request that such persons present such claims in accordance with the terms of such notice. Such notice shall be in substantially the same form, and sent in the same manner, as described in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity shall offer any claimant whose known claim is contingent, conditional, or unmatured such security as the corporation or such entity determines is sufficient to provide compensation to the claimant if the claim matures. The dissolved corporation or successor entity shall deliver such offer to the claimant within 90 days after receipt of such claim and, in all events, at least 150 days before expiration of 3 years following the effective date of dissolution. If the claimant offered such security does not deliver in writing to the dissolved corporation or successor entity a notice rejecting the offer within 120 days after receipt of such offer for security, the claimant is deemed to have accepted such security as the sole source from which to satisfy his or her claim against the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity which has given notice in accordance with subsections (2) and (4) shall petition the circuit court in the county where the corporation’s principal office is located or was located at the effective date of dissolution to determine the amount and form of security that will be sufficient to provide compensation to any claimant who has rejected the offer for security made pursuant to subsection (5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity which has given notice in accordance with subsection (2) shall petition the circuit court in the county where the corporation’s principal office is located or was located at the effective date of dissolution to determine the amount and form of security which will be sufficient to provide compensation to claimants whose claims are known to the corporation or successor entity but whose identities are unknown. The court shall appoint a guardian ad litem to represent all claimants whose identities are unknown in any proceeding brought under this subsection. The reasonable fees and expenses of such guardian, including all reasonable expert witness fees, shall be paid by the petitioner in such proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The giving of any notice or making of any offer pursuant to the provisions of this section shall not revive any claim then barred or constitute acknowledgment by the dissolved corporation or successor entity that any person to whom such notice is sent is a proper claimant and shall not operate as a waiver of any defense or counterclaim in respect of any claim asserted by any person to whom such notice is sent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity which has followed the procedures described in subsections (2)-(7):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall pay the claims admitted or made and not rejected in accordance with subsection (3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall post the security offered and not rejected pursuant to subsection (5);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall post any security ordered by the circuit court in any proceeding under subsections (6) and (7); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall pay or make provision for all other known obligations of the corporation or such successor entity.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such claims or obligations shall be paid in full, and any such provision for payments shall be made in full if there are sufficient funds. If there are insufficient funds, such claims and obligations shall be paid or provided for according to their priority and, among claims of equal priority, ratably to the extent of funds legally available therefor. Any remaining funds shall be distributed to the shareholders of the dissolved corporation; however, such distribution may not be made before the expiration of 150 days from the date of the last notice of rejections given pursuant to subsection (3). In the absence of actual fraud, the judgment of the directors of the dissolved corporation or the governing persons of such successor entity as to the provisions made for the payment of all obligations under paragraph (d) is conclusive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved corporation or successor entity which has not followed the procedures described in subsections (2) and (3) shall pay or make reasonable provision to pay all known claims and obligations, including all contingent, conditional, or unmatured claims known to the corporation or such successor entity and all claims which are known to the dissolved corporation or such successor entity but for which the identity of the claimant is unknown. Such claims shall be paid in full, and any such provision for payment made shall be made in full if there are sufficient funds. If there are insufficient funds, such claims and obligations shall be paid or provided for according to their priority and, among claims of equal priority, ratably to the extent of funds legally available therefor. Any remaining funds shall be distributed to the shareholders of the dissolved corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directors of a dissolved corporation or governing persons of a successor entity which has complied with subsection (9) or subsection (10) are not personally liable to the claimants of the dissolved corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A shareholder of a dissolved corporation the assets of which were distributed pursuant to subsection (9) or subsection (10) is not liable for any claim against the corporation in an amount in excess of such shareholder’s pro rata share of the claim or the amount distributed to the shareholder, whichever is less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A shareholder of a dissolved corporation, the assets of which were distributed pursuant to subsection (9), is not liable for any claim against the corporation, which claim is known to the corporation or successor entity, on which a proceeding is not begun prior to the expiration of 3 years following the effective date of dissolution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The aggregate liability of any shareholder of a dissolved corporation for claims against the dissolved corporation arising under this section, s. 607.1407, or otherwise, may not exceed the amount distributed to the shareholder in dissolution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section or s. 607.1407, the term “successor entity” includes any trust, receivership, or other legal entity governed by the laws of this state to which the remaining assets and liabilities of a dissolved corporation are transferred and which exists solely for the purposes of prosecuting and defending suits by or against the dissolved corporation, enabling the dissolved corporation to settle and close the business of the dissolved corporation, to dispose of and convey the property of the dissolved corporation, to discharge the liabilities of the dissolved corporation, and to distribute to the dissolved corporation’s shareholders any remaining assets, but not for the purpose of continuing the business for which the dissolved corporation was organized.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 126, ch. 89-154; s. 155, ch. 90-179; s. 37, ch. 93-281; s. 33, ch. 97-102; s. 34, ch. 2003-283; s. 5, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>