<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1422" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reinstatement following administrative dissolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation administratively dissolved under s. 607.1421 may apply to the Department of State for reinstatement at any time after the effective date of dissolution. The corporation must submit a reinstatement form prescribed and furnished by the Department of State or a current uniform business report signed by the registered agent and an officer or director and all fees then owed by the corporation, computed at the rate provided by law at the time the corporation applies for reinstatement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Department of State determines that the application contains the information required by subsection (1) and that the information is correct, it shall reinstate the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the reinstatement is effective, it relates back to and takes effect as of the effective date of the administrative dissolution and the corporation resumes carrying on its business as if the administrative dissolution had never occurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the dissolved corporation shall not be available for assumption or use by another corporation until 1 year after the effective date of dissolution unless the dissolved corporation provides the Department of State with an affidavit executed as required by s. 607.0120 permitting the immediate assumption or use of the name by another corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the name of the dissolved corporation has been lawfully assumed in this state by another corporation, the Department of State shall require the dissolved corporation to amend its articles of incorporation to change its name before accepting its application for reinstatement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 129, ch. 89-154; s. 157, ch. 90-179; s. 36, ch. 2003-283.</History></Section>