<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0725" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Quorum and voting requirements for voting groups.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shares entitled to vote as a separate voting group may take action on a matter at a meeting only if a quorum of those shares exists with respect to that matter. Unless the articles of incorporation or this act provides otherwise, a majority of the votes entitled to be cast on the matter by the voting group constitutes a quorum of that voting group for action on that matter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once a share is represented for any purpose at a meeting, it is deemed present for quorum purposes for the remainder of the meeting and for any adjournment of that meeting unless a new record date is or must be set for that adjourned meeting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a quorum exists, action on a matter (other than the election of directors) by a voting group is approved if the votes cast within the voting group favoring the action exceed the votes cast opposing the action, unless the articles of incorporation or this act requires a greater number of affirmative votes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holders of a majority of the shares represented, and who would be entitled to vote at a meeting if a quorum were present, where a quorum is not present, may adjourn such meeting from time to time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation may provide for a greater voting requirement or a greater or lesser quorum requirement for shareholders, or voting groups of shareholders, than is provided by this act, but in no event shall a quorum consist of less than one-third of the shares entitled to vote.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amendment to the articles of incorporation that adds, changes, or deletes a greater or lesser quorum or voting requirement shall meet the same quorum requirement and be adopted by the same vote and voting groups required to take action under the quorum and voting requirements then in effect or proposed to be adopted, whichever is greater.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election of directors is governed by s. 607.0728.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 61, ch. 89-154; s. 16, ch. 93-281.</History></Section>