<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1008" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amendment pursuant to reorganization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation’s articles of incorporation may be amended without action by the board of directors or shareholders to carry out a plan of reorganization ordered or decreed by a court of competent jurisdiction under any federal or Florida statute if the articles of incorporation after amendment contain only provisions required or permitted by s. 607.0202.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual or individuals designated by the court shall deliver to the Department of State for filing articles of amendment setting forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The text of each amendment approved by the court;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of the court’s order or decree approving the articles of amendment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The title of the reorganization proceeding in which the order or decree was entered; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the court had jurisdiction of the proceeding under a federal or Florida statute.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shareholders of a corporation undergoing reorganization do not have dissenters’ rights except as and to the extent provided in the reorganization plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply after entry of a final decree in the reorganization proceeding even though the court retains jurisdiction of the proceeding for limited purposes unrelated to consummation of the reorganization plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 104, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>