<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0501" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registered office and registered agent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporation shall have and continuously maintain in this state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered office which may be the same as its place of business; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered agent, who may be either:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who resides in this state whose business office is identical with such registered office;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Another corporation or not-for-profit corporation as defined in chapter 617, authorized to transact business or conduct its affairs in this state, having a business office identical with the registered office; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation or not-for-profit foreign corporation authorized pursuant to this chapter or chapter 617 to transact business or conduct its affairs in this state, having a business office identical with the registered office.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to corporations which are required by law to designate the Chief Financial Officer as their attorney for the service of process, associations subject to the provisions of chapter 665, and banks and trust companies subject to the provisions of the financial institutions codes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered agent appointed pursuant to this section or a successor registered agent appointed pursuant to s. 607.0502 on whom process may be served shall each file a statement in writing with the Department of State, in such form and manner as shall be prescribed by the department, accepting the appointment as a registered agent simultaneously with his or her being designated. Such statement of acceptance shall state that the registered agent is familiar with, and accepts, the obligations of that position.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State shall maintain an accurate record of the registered agents and registered offices for the service of process and shall furnish any information disclosed thereby promptly upon request and payment of the required fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation may not maintain any action in a court in this state until the corporation complies with the provisions of this section or s. 607.1507, as applicable, and pays to the Department of State a penalty of $5 for each day it has failed to so comply or $500, whichever is less.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 89-154; s. 139, ch. 90-179; s. 203, ch. 92-303; s. 8, ch. 93-281; s. 6, ch. 97-102; s. 745, ch. 2003-261; s. 4, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>