<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Merger of domestic corporation and other business entity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section and ss. 607.1109 and 607.11101, the term “other business entity” means a limited liability company, a foreign corporation, a not-for-profit corporation, a business trust or association, a real estate investment trust, a common law trust, an unincorporated business, a general partnership, a limited partnership, or any other entity that is formed pursuant to the requirements of applicable law. Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 617, a domestic not-for-profit corporation acting under a plan of merger approved pursuant to s. 617.1103 shall be governed by the provisions of ss. 607.1108, 607.1109, and 607.11101.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to a plan of merger complying and approved in accordance with this section, one or more domestic corporations may merge with or into one or more other business entities formed, organized, or incorporated under the laws of this state or any other state, the United States, foreign country, or other foreign jurisdiction, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each domestic corporation which is a party to the merger complies with the applicable provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each domestic partnership that is a party to the merger complies with the applicable provisions of chapter 620.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each domestic limited liability company that is a party to the merger complies with the applicable provisions of chapter 608.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The merger is permitted by the laws of the state, country, or jurisdiction under which each other business entity that is a party to the merger is formed, organized, or incorporated and each such other business entity complies with such laws in effecting the merger.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of merger shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each domestic corporation and the name and jurisdiction of formation, organization, or incorporation of each other business entity planning to merge, and the name of the surviving or resulting domestic corporation or other business entity into which each other domestic corporation or other business entity plans to merge, which is hereinafter and in ss. 607.1109 and 607.11101 designated as the surviving entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and conditions of the merger.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner and basis of converting the shares of each domestic corporation that is a party to the merger and the partnership interests, interests, shares, obligations or other securities of each other business entity that is a party to the merger into partnership interests, interests, shares, obligations or other securities of the surviving entity or any other domestic corporation or other business entity or, in whole or in part, into cash or other property, and the manner and basis of converting rights to acquire the shares of each domestic corporation that is a party to the merger and rights to acquire partnership interests, interests, shares, obligations or other securities of each other business entity that is a party to the merger into rights to acquire partnership interests, interests, shares, obligations or other securities of the surviving entity or any other domestic corporation or other business entity or, in whole or in part, into cash or other property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a partnership is to be the surviving entity, the names and business addresses of the general partners of the surviving entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a limited liability company is to be the surviving entity and management thereof is vested in one or more managers, the names and business addresses of such managers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All statements required to be set forth in the plan of merger by the laws under which each other business entity that is a party to the merger is formed, organized, or incorporated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of merger may set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a domestic corporation is to be the surviving entity, any amendments to, or a restatement of, the articles of incorporation of the surviving entity, and such amendments or restatement shall be effective at the effective date of the merger.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective date of the merger, which may be on or after the date of filing the certificate of merger.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other provisions relating to the merger.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of merger required by subsection (3) shall be adopted and approved by each domestic corporation that is a party to the merger in the same manner as is provided in s. 607.1103. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if the surviving entity is a partnership, no shareholder of a domestic corporation that is a party to the merger shall, as a result of the merger, become a general partner of the surviving entity, unless such shareholder specifically consents in writing to becoming a general partner of the surviving entity, and unless such written consent is obtained from each such shareholder who, as a result of the merger, would become a general partner of the surviving entity, such merger shall not become effective under s. 607.11101. Any shareholder providing such consent in writing shall be deemed to have voted in favor of the plan of merger for purposes of s. 607.1103.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 607.1103 and 607.1301-607.1333 shall, insofar as they are applicable, apply to mergers of one or more domestic corporations with or into one or more other business entities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of this section or ss. 607.1109 and 607.11101, any merger consisting solely of the merger of one or more domestic corporations with or into one or more foreign corporations shall be consummated solely in accordance with the requirements of s. 607.1107.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 98-101; s. 18, ch. 2003-283.</History></Section>