<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Organizational meeting of directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After incorporation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If initial directors are named in the articles of incorporation, the initial directors shall hold an organizational meeting, at the call of a majority of the directors, to complete the organization of the corporation by appointing officers, adopting bylaws, and carrying on any other business brought before the meeting;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If initial directors are not named in the articles, the incorporators shall hold an organizational meeting at the call of a majority of the incorporators:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To elect directors and complete the organization of the corporation; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To elect a board of directors who shall complete the organization of the corporation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Action required or permitted by this act to be taken by incorporators or directors at an organizational meeting may be taken without a meeting if the action taken is evidenced by one or more written consents describing the action taken and signed by each incorporator or director.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The directors or incorporators calling the organizational meeting shall give at least 3 days’ notice thereof to each director or incorporator so named, stating the time and place of the meeting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An organizational meeting may be held in or out of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>