<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0902" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Control-share acquisitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“CONTROL SHARES.”<EmDash />As used in this section, “control shares” means shares that, except for this section, would have voting power with respect to shares of an issuing public corporation that, when added to all other shares of the issuing public corporation owned by a person or in respect to which that person may exercise or direct the exercise of voting power, would entitle that person, immediately after acquisition of the shares, directly or indirectly, alone or as a part of a group, to exercise or direct the exercise of the voting power of the issuing public corporation in the election of directors within any of the following ranges of voting power:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One-fifth or more but less than one-third of all voting power.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One-third or more but less than a majority of all voting power.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority or more of all voting power.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“CONTROL-SHARE ACQUISITION.”<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “control-share acquisition” means the acquisition, directly or indirectly, by any person of ownership of, or the power to direct the exercise of voting power with respect to, issued and outstanding control shares.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, all shares, the beneficial ownership of which is acquired within 90 days before or after the date of the acquisition of the beneficial ownership of shares which result in a control share acquisition, and all shares the beneficial ownership of which is acquired pursuant to a plan to make a control-share acquisition shall be deemed to have been acquired in the same acquisition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, a person who acquires shares in the ordinary course of business for the benefit of others in good faith and not for the purpose of circumventing this section has voting power only of shares in respect of which that person would be able to exercise or direct the exercise of votes without further instruction from others.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition of any shares of an issuing public corporation does not constitute a control-share acquisition if the acquisition is consummated in any of the following circumstances:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before July 2, 1987.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to a contract existing before July 2, 1987.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the laws of intestate succession or pursuant to a gift or testamentary transfer.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the satisfaction of a pledge or other security interest created in good faith and not for the purpose of circumventing this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to a merger or share exchange effected in compliance with s. 607.1101, s. 607.1102, s. 607.1103, s. 607.1104, or s. 607.1107, if the issuing public corporation is a party to the agreement of merger or plan of share exchange.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to any savings, employee stock ownership, or other employee benefit plan of the issuing public corporation or any of its subsidiaries or any fiduciary with respect to any such plan when acting in such fiduciary capacity.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to an acquisition of shares of an issuing public corporation if the acquisition has been approved by the board of directors of such issuing public corporation before acquisition.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition of shares of an issuing public corporation in good faith and not for the purpose of circumventing this section by or from:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person whose voting rights had previously been authorized by shareholders in compliance with this section; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person whose previous acquisition of shares of an issuing public corporation would have constituted a control-share acquisition but for paragraph (d),</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">does not constitute a control-share acquisition, unless the acquisition entitles any person, directly or indirectly, alone or as a part of a group, to exercise or direct the exercise of voting power of the corporation in the election of directors in excess of the range of the voting power otherwise authorized.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this section, persons shall not be deemed to be part of a “group” if such persons join together to exercise or direct the exercise of the voting power of an issuing public corporation (whether through a voting trust, a shareholder agreement, or through other arrangements), and the voting trustee of any voting trust shall not be deemed to be an “acquiring person” if such persons or all the parties to the voting trust:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are related by blood or marriage or are the personal representatives or trustees of such persons; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such persons were shareholders (or the beneficial owners of shares) of the issuing public corporation (or were trustees, personal representatives, or heirs of such shareholders or beneficial owners) on July 1, 1987, and have continued to be shareholders (or the beneficial owners of shares) of the issuing public corporation (or have been trustees, personal representatives, or heirs of such shareholders or beneficial owners) since that time.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“INTERESTED SHARES.”<EmDash />As used in this section, “interested shares” means the shares of an issuing public corporation in respect of which any of the following persons may exercise or direct the exercise of the voting power of the corporation in the election of directors:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An acquiring person or member of a group with respect to a control-share acquisition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer of the issuing public corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any employee of the issuing public corporation who is also a director of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“ISSUING PUBLIC CORPORATION.”<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “issuing public corporation” means a corporation that has:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred or more shareholders;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its principal place of business, its principal office, or substantial assets within this state; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Either:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">More than 10 percent of its shareholders resident in this state;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">More than 10 percent of its shares owned by residents of this state; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One thousand shareholders resident in this state.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The residence of a shareholder is presumed to be the address appearing in the records of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shares held by banks (except as trustee or guardian), brokers, or nominees shall be disregarded for purposes of calculating the percentages or numbers described in this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LAW APPLICABLE TO CONTROL-SHARE VOTING RIGHTS.<EmDash />Unless the corporation’s articles of incorporation or bylaws provide that this section does not apply to control-share acquisitions of shares of the corporation before the control-share acquisition, control shares of an issuing public corporation acquired in a control-share acquisition have only such voting rights as are conferred by subsection (9).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTICE OF CONTROL-SHARE ACQUISITION.<EmDash />Any person who proposes to make or has made a control-share acquisition may at the person’s election deliver an acquiring person statement to the issuing public corporation at the issuing public corporation’s principal office. The acquiring person statement must set forth all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of the acquiring person and each other member of any group of which the person is a part for purposes of determining control shares.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the acquiring person statement is given pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of shares of the issuing public corporation owned, directly or indirectly, by the acquiring person and each other member of the group.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The range of voting power under which the control-share acquisition falls or would, if consummated, fall.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the control-share acquisition has not taken place:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description in reasonable detail of the terms of the proposed control-share acquisition; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representations of the acquiring person, together with a statement, in reasonable detail of the facts upon which they are based, that the proposed control-share acquisition, if consummated, will not be contrary to law and that the acquiring person has the financial capacity to make the proposed control-share acquisition.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHAREHOLDER MEETING TO DETERMINE CONTROL-SHARE VOTING RIGHTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the acquiring person so requests at the time of delivery of an acquiring person statement and gives an undertaking to pay the corporation’s expenses of a special meeting, within 10 days thereafter, the directors of the issuing public corporation or others authorized to call such a meeting under the issuing public corporation’s articles of incorporation or bylaws shall call a special meeting of shareholders of the issuing public corporation for the purpose of considering the voting rights to be accorded the shares acquired or to be acquired in the control-share acquisition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the acquiring person agrees in writing to another date, the special meeting of shareholders shall be held within 50 days after receipt by the issuing public corporation of the request.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the acquiring person so requests in writing at the time of delivery of the acquiring person statement, the special meeting must not be held sooner than 30 days after receipt by the issuing public corporation of the acquiring person statement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no request is made, the voting rights to be accorded the shares acquired in the control-share acquisition shall be presented to the next special or annual meeting of the shareholders.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTICE OF SHAREHOLDER MEETING.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a special meeting is requested, notice of the special meeting of shareholders shall be given as promptly as reasonably practicable by the issuing public corporation to all shareholders of record as of the record date set for the meeting, whether or not entitled to vote at the meeting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the special or annual shareholder meeting at which the voting rights are to be considered must include or be accompanied by each of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the acquiring person statement delivered to the issuing public corporation pursuant to this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement by the board of directors of the corporation, authorized by its directors, of its position or recommendation, or that it is taking no position or making no recommendation, with respect to the proposed control-share acquisition.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESOLUTION GRANTING CONTROL-SHARE VOTING RIGHTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Control shares acquired in a control-share acquisition have the same voting rights as were accorded the shares before the control-share acquisition only to the extent granted by resolution approved by the shareholders of the issuing public corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be approved under this subsection, the resolution must be approved by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each class or series entitled to vote separately on the proposal by a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast by the class or series, with the holders of the outstanding shares of a class or series being entitled to vote as a separate class if the proposed control-share acquisition would, if fully carried out, result in any of the changes described in s. 607.1004; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each class or series entitled to vote separately on the proposal by a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast by that group, excluding all interested shares.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any control shares that do not have voting rights because such rights were not accorded to such shares by approval of a resolution by the shareholders pursuant to paragraph (b) shall regain voting rights and shall no longer be deemed control shares upon a transfer to a person other than the acquiring person or associate or affiliate, as defined in s. 607.0901, of the acquiring person unless the acquisition of the shares by the other person constitutes a control-share acquisition, in which case the voting rights of the shares remain subject to the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REDEMPTION OF CONTROL SHARES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If authorized in a corporation’s articles of incorporation or bylaws before a control-share acquisition has occurred, control shares acquired in a control-share acquisition with respect to which no acquiring person statement has been filed with the issuing public corporation may, at any time during the period ending 60 days after the last acquisition of control shares by the acquiring person, be subject to redemption by the corporation at the fair value thereof pursuant to the procedures adopted by the corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Control shares acquired in a control-share acquisition are not subject to redemption after an acquiring person statement has been filed unless the shares are not accorded full voting rights by the shareholders as provided in subsection (9).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 95, ch. 89-154; s. 27, ch. 93-281; s. 4, ch. 94-327; s. 6, ch. 97-230; s. 12, ch. 2003-283.</History></Section>