<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.15101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service of process, notice, or demand on a foreign corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registered agent of a foreign corporation authorized to transact business in this state is the corporation’s agent for service of process, notice, or demand required or permitted by law to be served on the foreign corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation may be served by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, addressed to the secretary of the foreign corporation at its principal office shown in its application for a certificate of authority or in its most recent annual report if the foreign corporation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has no registered agent or its registered agent cannot with reasonable diligence be served;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has withdrawn from transacting business in this state under s. 607.1520; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has had its certificate of authority revoked under s. 607.1531.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service is perfected under subsection (2) at the earliest of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the foreign corporation receives the mail;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date shown on the return receipt, if signed on behalf of the foreign corporation; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five days after its deposit in the United States mail, as evidenced by the postmark, if mailed postpaid and correctly addressed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prescribe the only means, or necessarily the required means, of serving a foreign corporation. Process against any foreign corporation may also be served in accordance with chapter 48 or chapter 49.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any notice to or demand on a foreign corporation made pursuant to this act may be made in accordance with the procedures for notice to or demand on domestic corporations under s. 607.0504.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 145, ch. 89-154; s. 165, ch. 90-179.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 607.1510.</Text></Note></Section>