<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0720" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Shareholders’ list for meeting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After fixing a record date for a meeting, a corporation shall prepare an alphabetical list of the names of all its shareholders who are entitled to notice of a shareholders’ meeting, arranged by voting group with the address of, and the number and class and series, if any, of shares held by, each.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The shareholders’ list must be available for inspection by any shareholder for a period of 10 days prior to the meeting or such shorter time as exists between the record date and the meeting and continuing through the meeting at the corporation’s principal office, at a place identified in the meeting notice in the city where the meeting will be held, or at the office of the corporation’s transfer agent or registrar. A shareholder or the shareholder’s agent or attorney is entitled on written demand to inspect the list (subject to the requirements of s. 607.1602(3)), during regular business hours and at his or her expense, during the period it is available for inspection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall make the shareholders’ list available at the meeting, and any shareholder or the shareholder’s agent or attorney is entitled to inspect the list at any time during the meeting or any adjournment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The shareholders’ list is prima facie evidence of the identity of shareholders entitled to examine the shareholders’ list or to vote at a meeting of shareholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the requirements of this section have not been substantially complied with or if the corporation refuses to allow a shareholder or the shareholder’s agent or attorney to inspect the shareholders’ list before or at the meeting, the meeting shall be adjourned until such requirements are complied with on the demand of any shareholder in person or by proxy who failed to get such access, or, if not adjourned upon such demand and such requirements are not complied with, the circuit court of the county where a corporation’s principal office (or, if none in this state, its registered office) is located, on application of the shareholder, may summarily order the inspection or copying at the corporation’s expense and may postpone the meeting for which the list was prepared until the inspection or copying is complete.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal or failure to comply with the requirements of this section shall not affect the validity of any action taken at such meeting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A shareholder may not sell or otherwise distribute any information or records inspected under this section, except to the extent that such use is for a proper purpose as defined in s. 607.1602(3). Any person who violates this provision shall be subject to a civil penalty of $5,000.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 56, ch. 89-154; s. 15, ch. 93-281; s. 1, ch. 94-327; s. 13, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>