<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1109" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Articles of merger.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a plan of merger is approved by each domestic corporation and other business entity that is a party to the merger, the surviving entity shall deliver to the Department of State for filing articles of merger, which shall be executed by each domestic corporation as required by s. 607.0120 and by each other business entity as required by applicable law, and which shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of merger.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the plan of merger was approved by each domestic corporation that is a party to the merger in accordance with the applicable provisions of this chapter, and, if applicable, a statement that the written consent of each shareholder of such domestic corporation who, as a result of the merger, becomes a general partner of the surviving entity has been obtained pursuant to s. 607.1108(5).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the plan of merger was approved by each domestic partnership that is a party to the merger in accordance with the applicable provisions of chapter 620.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the plan of merger was approved by each domestic limited liability company that is a party to the merger in accordance with the applicable provisions of chapter 608.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the plan of merger was approved by each other business entity that is a party to the merger, other than domestic corporations, limited liability companies, and partnerships formed, organized, or incorporated under the laws of this state, in accordance with the applicable laws of the state, country, or jurisdiction under which such other business entity is formed, organized, or incorporated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective date of the merger, which may be on or after the date of filing the articles of merger, provided, if the articles of merger do not provide for an effective date of the merger, the effective date shall be the date on which the articles of merger are filed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the surviving entity is another business entity formed, organized, or incorporated under the laws of any state, country, or jurisdiction other than this state:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address, including street and number, if any, of its principal office under the laws of the state, country, or jurisdiction in which it was formed, organized, or incorporated.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the surviving entity is deemed to have appointed the Secretary of State as its agent for service of process in a proceeding to enforce any obligation or the rights of dissenting shareholders of each domestic corporation that is a party to the merger.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the surviving entity has agreed to promptly pay to the dissenting shareholders of each domestic corporation that is a party to the merger the amount, if any, to which they are entitled under s. 607.1302.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the articles of merger, certified by the Department of State, may be filed in the office of the official who is the recording officer of each county in this state in which real property of a party to the merger other than the surviving entity is situated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A domestic corporation is not required to file articles of merger pursuant to subsection (1) if the domestic corporation is named as a party or constituent organization in articles of merger or a certificate of merger filed for the same merger in accordance with s. 608.4382(1), s. 617.1108, s. 620.2108(3), or s. 620.8918(1) and (2), and if the articles of merger or certificate of merger substantially complies with the requirements of this section. In such a case, the other articles of merger or certificate of merger may also be used for purposes of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 98-101; s. 6, ch. 2004-378; s. 1, ch. 2008-187.</History></Section>