<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0620" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Subscriptions for shares.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subscription for shares entered into before incorporation is irrevocable for 6 months unless the subscription agreement provides a longer or shorter period or all the subscribers agree to revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A subscription for shares, whether made before or after incorporation, is not enforceable unless in writing and signed by the subscriber.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may determine the payment terms of subscriptions for shares that were entered into before incorporation, unless the subscription agreement specifies them. A call for payment by the board of directors must be uniform as to all shares of the same class or series, unless the subscription agreement specifies otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shares issued pursuant to subscriptions entered into before incorporation are fully paid and nonassessable when the corporation receives the consideration specified in the subscription agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a subscriber defaults in payment of money or property under a subscription agreement entered into before incorporation, the corporation may collect the amount owed as any other debt. Alternatively, unless the subscription agreement provides otherwise, the corporation may rescind the agreement and may sell the shares if the debt remains unpaid more than 20 days after the corporation sends written demand for payment to the subscriber. If mailed, such written demand shall be deemed to be made when deposited in the United States mail in a sealed envelope addressed to the subscriber at his or her last post office address known to the corporation, with first-class postage thereon prepaid. The defaulting subscriber or his or her legal representative shall be entitled to be paid the excess of the sale proceeds over the sum of the amount due and unpaid on the subscription and the reasonable expenses incurred in selling the shares, but in no event shall the defaulting subscriber or his or her legal representative be entitled to be paid an amount greater than the amount paid by the subscriber on the subscription.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 89-154; s. 12, ch. 93-281; s. 8, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>