<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In anticipation of or during any emergency defined in subsection (5), the board of directors of a corporation may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Modify lines of succession to accommodate the incapacity of any director, officer, employee, or agent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relocate the principal office or designate alternative principal offices or regional offices or authorize the officers to do so.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During an emergency defined in subsection (5), unless emergency bylaws provide otherwise:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of a meeting of the board of directors need be given only to those directors whom it is practicable to reach and may be given in any practicable manner, including by publication and radio;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more officers of the corporation present at a meeting of the board of directors may be deemed to be directors for the meeting, in order of rank and within the same rank in order of seniority, as necessary to achieve a quorum; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director or directors in attendance at a meeting, or any greater number affixed by the emergency bylaws, constitute a quorum.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corporate action taken in good faith during an emergency under this section to further the ordinary business affairs of the corporation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Binds the corporation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not be used to impose liability on a corporate director, officer, employee, or agent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No officer, director, or employee acting in accordance with any emergency bylaws shall be liable except for willful misconduct.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An emergency exists for purposes of this section if a quorum of the corporation’s directors cannot readily be assembled because of some catastrophic event.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent not inconsistent with any emergency bylaws so adopted, the bylaws of the corporation shall remain in effect during any emergency, and upon termination of the emergency, the emergency bylaws will cease to be operative.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>