<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1506" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corporate name of foreign corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation is not entitled to file an application for a certificate of authority unless the corporate name of such corporation satisfies the requirements of s. 607.0401. If the corporate name of a foreign corporation does not satisfy the requirements of s. 607.0401, the foreign corporation, to obtain or maintain a certificate of authority to transact business in this state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May add the word “corporation,” “company,” or “incorporated” or the abbreviation “Corp.,” “Inc.,” “Co.,” or the designation “Corp,” “Inc,” or “Co,” as will clearly indicate that it is a corporation instead of a natural person, partnership, or other business entity; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May use an alternate name to transact business in this state if its real name is unavailable. Any such alternate corporate name, adopted for use in this state, shall be cross-referenced to the real corporate name in the records of the Division of Corporations. If the corporation’s real corporate name becomes available in this state or the corporation chooses to change its alternate name, a copy of the resolution of its board of directors changing or withdrawing the alternate name, executed as required by s. 607.0120, shall be delivered for filing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporate name (including the alternate name) of a foreign corporation must be distinguishable upon the records of the Division of Corporations from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporate name of a corporation incorporated or authorized to transact business in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The alternate name of another foreign corporation authorized to transact business in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporate name of a not-for-profit corporation incorporated or authorized to transact business in this state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of all other entities or filings, except fictitious name registrations pursuant to s. 865.09, organized or registered under the laws of this state that are on file with the Division of Corporations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foreign corporation authorized to transact business in this state changes its corporate name to one that does not satisfy the requirements of s. 607.0401, it may not transact business in this state under the changed name until it adopts a name satisfying the requirements of s. 607.0401 and obtains an amended certificate of authority under s. 607.1504.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 141, ch. 89-154; s. 161, ch. 90-179; s. 39, ch. 93-281; s. 15, ch. 98-101; s. 39, ch. 2003-283.</History></Section>