<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Action on plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After adopting a plan of merger or share exchange, the board of directors of each corporation party to the merger, and the board of directors of the corporation the shares of which will be acquired in the share exchange, shall submit the plan of merger (except as provided in subsection (7)) or the plan of share exchange for approval by its shareholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a plan of merger or share exchange to be approved:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors must recommend the plan of merger or share exchange to the shareholders, unless the board of directors determines that it should make no recommendation because of conflict of interest or other special circumstances and communicates the basis for its determination to the shareholders with the plan; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The shareholders entitled to vote must approve the plan as provided in subsection (5).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may condition its submission of the proposed merger or share exchange on any basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation the shareholders of which are entitled to vote on the matter shall notify each shareholder, whether or not entitled to vote, of the proposed shareholders’ meeting in accordance with s. 607.0705. The notice shall also state that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of the meeting is to consider the plan of merger or share exchange, regardless of whether or not the meeting is an annual or a special meeting, and contain or be accompanied by a copy or summary of the plan. Furthermore, the notice shall contain a clear and concise statement that, if the plan of merger or share exchange is effected, shareholders dissenting therefrom may be entitled, if they comply with the provisions of this act regarding appraisal rights, to be paid the fair value of their shares, and shall be accompanied by a copy of ss. 607.1301-607.1333.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless this act, the articles of incorporation, or the board of directors (acting pursuant to subsection (3)) requires a greater vote or a vote by classes, the plan of merger or share exchange to be authorized shall be approved by each class entitled to vote on the plan by a majority of all the votes entitled to be cast on the plan by that class.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Voting by a class or series as a separate voting group is required:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a plan of merger if the plan contains a provision which, if contained in a proposed amendment to articles of incorporation, would entitle the class or series to vote as a separate voting group on the proposed amendment under s. 607.1004; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a plan of share exchange if the shares of such class or series of shares are to be converted or exchanged under such plan or if the plan contains any provisions which, if contained in a proposed amendment to articles of incorporation, would entitle the class or series to vote as a separate voting group on the proposed amendment under s. 607.1004.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the requirements of this section, unless required by its articles of incorporation, action by the shareholders of the surviving corporation on a plan of merger is not required if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation of the surviving corporation will not differ (except for amendments enumerated in s. 607.1002) from its articles before the merger; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each shareholder of the surviving corporation whose shares were outstanding immediately prior to the effective date of the merger will hold the same number of shares, with identical designations, preferences, limitations, and relative rights, immediately after the merger.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any plan of merger or share exchange may authorize the board of directors of each corporation party to the merger or share exchange to amend the plan at any time prior to the filing of the articles of merger or share exchange. An amendment made subsequent to the approval of the plan by the shareholders of any corporation party to the merger or share exchange may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change the amount or kind of shares, securities, cash, property, or rights to be received in exchange for or on conversion of any or all of the shares of any class or series of such corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change any other terms and conditions of the plan if such change would materially and adversely affect such corporation or the holders of the shares of any class or series of such corporation; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as specified in s. 607.1002 or without the vote of shareholders entitled to vote on the matter, change any term of the articles of incorporation of any corporation the shareholders of which must approve the plan of merger or share exchange.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If articles of merger or share exchange already have been filed with the Department of State, amended articles of merger or share exchange shall be filed with the Department of State prior to the effective date of the merger or share exchange.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless a plan of merger or share exchange prohibits abandonment of the merger or share exchange without shareholder approval after a merger or share exchange has been authorized, the planned merger or share exchange may be abandoned (subject to any contractual rights) at any time prior to the filing of articles of merger or share exchange by any corporation party to the merger or share exchange, without further shareholder action, in accordance with the procedure set forth in the plan of merger or share exchange or, if none is set forth, in the manner determined by the board of directors of such corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 111, ch. 89-154; s. 32, ch. 93-281; s. 16, ch. 2003-283.</History></Section>