<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.06401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Distributions to shareholders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board of directors may authorize and the corporation may make distributions to its shareholders subject to restriction by the articles of incorporation and the limitations in subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board of directors does not fix the record date for determining shareholders entitled to a distribution (other than one involving a purchase, redemption, or other acquisition of the corporation’s shares), it is the date the board of directors authorizes the distribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No distribution may be made if, after giving it effect:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation would not be able to pay its debts as they become due in the usual course of business; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation’s total assets would be less than the sum of its total liabilities plus (unless the articles of incorporation permit otherwise) the amount that would be needed, if the corporation were to be dissolved at the time of the distribution, to satisfy the preferential rights upon dissolution of shareholders whose preferential rights are superior to those receiving the distribution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may base a determination that a distribution is not prohibited under subsection (3) either on financial statements prepared on the basis of accounting practices and principles that are reasonable in the circumstances or on a fair valuation or other method that is reasonable in the circumstances. In the case of any distribution based upon such a valuation, each such distribution shall be identified as a distribution based upon a current valuation of assets, and the amount per share paid on the basis of such valuation shall be disclosed to the shareholders concurrent with their receipt of the distribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the articles of incorporation of a corporation engaged in the business of exploiting natural resources or other wasting assets so provide, distributions may be paid in cash out of depletion or similar reserves; and each such distribution shall be identified as a distribution based upon such reserves, and the amount per share paid on the basis of such reserves shall be disclosed to the shareholders concurrent with their receipt of the distribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (8), the effect of a distribution under subsection (3) is measured:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of distribution by purchase, redemption, or other acquisition of the corporation’s shares, as of the earlier of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date money or other property is transferred or debt incurred by the corporation, or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the shareholder ceases to be a shareholder with respect to the acquired shares;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of any other distribution of indebtedness, as of the date the indebtedness is distributed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all other cases, as of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the distribution is authorized if the payment occurs within 120 days after the date of authorization, or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the payment is made if it occurs more than 120 days after the date of authorization.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation’s indebtedness to a shareholder incurred by reason of a distribution made in accordance with this section is at parity with the corporation’s indebtedness to its general, unsecured creditors except to the extent subordinated by agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indebtedness of a corporation, including indebtedness issued as a distribution, is not considered a liability for purposes of determinations under subsection (3) if its terms provide that payment of principal and interest are made only if and to the extent that payment of a distribution to shareholders could then be made under this section. If the indebtedness is issued as a distribution, each payment of principal or interest is treated as a distribution, the effect of which is measured on the date the payment is actually made.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 48, ch. 89-154; s. 144, ch. 90-179.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 607.0640.</Text></Note></Section>