<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0130" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of Department of State.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may propound to any corporation subject to the provisions of this act, and to any officer or director thereof, such interrogatories as may be reasonably necessary and proper to enable it to ascertain whether the corporation has complied with all applicable provisions of this act. Such interrogatories must be answered within 30 days after mailing or within such additional time as fixed by the department. Answers to interrogatories must be full and complete, in writing, and under oath. Interrogatories directed to an individual must be answered by the individual, and interrogatories directed to a corporation must be answered by the president, vice president, secretary, or assistant secretary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State is not required to file any document:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To which interrogatories, as propounded pursuant to subsection (1), relate, until the interrogatories are answered in full;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When interrogatories or other relevant evidence discloses that such document is not in conformity with the provisions of this act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department has determined that the parties to such document have not paid all fees, taxes, and penalties due and owing this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may, based upon its findings hereunder or as provided in s. 213.053(15), bring an action in circuit court to collect any penalties, fees, or taxes determined to be due and owing the state and to compel any filing, qualification, or registration required by law. In connection with such proceeding the department may, without prior approval by the court, file a lis pendens against any property owned by the corporation and may further certify any findings to the Department of Legal Affairs for the initiation of any action permitted pursuant to s. 607.0505 which the Department of Legal Affairs may deem appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State shall have the power and authority reasonably necessary to enable it to administer this act efficiently, to perform the duties herein imposed upon it, and to promulgate reasonable rules necessary to carry out its duties and functions under this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 89-154; s. 4, ch. 91-214; s. 3, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 2006-85; s. 131, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>