<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.0202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Articles of incorporation; content.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation must set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporate name for the corporation that satisfies the requirements of s. 607.0401;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of the initial principal office and, if different, the mailing address of the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of shares the corporation is authorized to issue;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any preemptive rights are to be granted to shareholders, the provision therefor;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of the corporation’s initial registered office and the name of its initial registered agent at that office together with a written acceptance as required in s. 607.0501(3); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of each incorporator.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation may set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of the individuals who are to serve as the initial directors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions not inconsistent with law regarding:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose or purposes for which the corporation is organized;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managing the business and regulating the affairs of the corporation;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defining, limiting, and regulating the powers of the corporation and its board of directors and shareholders;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A par value for authorized shares or classes of shares;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The imposition of personal liability on shareholders for the debts of the corporation to a specified extent and upon specified conditions; and</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provision that under this act is required or permitted to be set forth in the bylaws.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation need not set forth any of the corporate powers enumerated in this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 89-154; s. 138, ch. 90-179; s. 5, ch. 93-281.</History></Section>