<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0607.1620" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Financial statements for shareholders.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless modified by resolution of the shareholders within 120 days of the close of each fiscal year, a corporation shall furnish its shareholders annual financial statements which may be consolidated or combined statements of the corporation and one or more of its subsidiaries, as appropriate, that include a balance sheet as of the end of the fiscal year, an income statement for that year, and a statement of cash flows for that year. If financial statements are prepared for the corporation on the basis of generally accepted accounting principles, the annual financial statements must also be prepared on that basis.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the annual financial statements are reported upon by a public accountant, his or her report must accompany them. If not, the statements must be accompanied by a statement of the president or the person responsible for the corporation’s accounting records:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stating his or her reasonable belief whether the statements were prepared on the basis of generally accepted accounting principles and, if not, describing the basis of preparation; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describing any respects in which the statements were not prepared on a basis of accounting consistent with the statements prepared for the preceding year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporation required by subsection (1) to furnish annual financial statements to its shareholders shall furnish such annual financial statements to each shareholder within 120 days after the close of each fiscal year or within such additional time thereafter as is reasonably necessary to enable the corporation to prepare its financial statements if, for reasons beyond the corporation’s control, it is unable to prepare its financial statements within the prescribed period. Thereafter, on written request from a shareholder who was not furnished the statements, the corporation shall furnish him or her the latest annual financial statements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a corporation does not comply with the shareholder’s request for annual financial statements pursuant to this section within 30 days of delivery of such request to the corporation, the circuit court in the county where the corporation’s principal office (or, if none in this state, its registered office) is located may, upon application of the shareholder, summarily order the corporation to furnish such financial statements. If the court orders the corporation to furnish the shareholder with the financial statements demanded, it shall also order the corporation to pay the shareholder’s costs, including reasonable attorney’s fees, reasonably incurred to obtain the order and otherwise enforce its rights under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirement to furnish annual financial statements as described in this section shall be satisfied by sending such annual financial statements by mail or electronic transmission. If a corporation has an outstanding class of securities registered under s. 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, as amended, the requirement to furnish annual financial statements may be satisfied by complying with 17 C.F.R. s. 240.14a-16, as amended, with respect to the obligation of a corporation to furnish an annual financial report to shareholders pursuant to 17 C.F.R. s. 240.14a-3(b), as amended.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 154, ch. 89-154; s. 45, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 2009-118; s. 6, ch. 2009-205.</History>
</Section>