<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1601" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corporate records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation shall keep as permanent records minutes of all meetings of its shareholders and board of directors, a record of all actions taken by the shareholders or board of directors without a meeting, and a record of all actions taken by a committee of the board of directors in place of the board of directors on behalf of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation shall maintain accurate accounting records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation or its agent shall maintain a record of its shareholders in a form that permits preparation of a list of the names and addresses of all shareholders in alphabetical order by class of shares showing the number and series of shares held by each.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation shall maintain its records in written form or in another form capable of conversion into written form within a reasonable time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation shall keep a copy of the following records:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its articles or restated articles of incorporation and all amendments to them currently in effect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its bylaws or restated bylaws and all amendments to them currently in effect;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resolutions adopted by its board of directors creating one or more classes or series of shares and fixing their relative rights, preferences, and limitations, if shares issued pursuant to those resolutions are outstanding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minutes of all shareholders’ meetings and records of all action taken by shareholders without a meeting for the past 3 years;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written communications to all shareholders generally or all shareholders of a class or series within the past 3 years, including the financial statements furnished for the past 3 years under s. 607.1620;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of the names and business street addresses of its current directors and officers; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its most recent annual report delivered to the Department of State under s. 607.1622.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 150, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>