<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amendment by board of directors and shareholders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation’s board of directors may propose one or more amendments to the articles of incorporation for submission to the shareholders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the amendment to be adopted:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors must recommend the amendment to the shareholders, unless the board of directors determines that because of conflict of interest or other special circumstances it should make no recommendation and communicates the basis for its determination to the shareholders with the amendment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The shareholders entitled to vote on the amendment must approve the amendment as provided in subsection (5).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may condition its submission of the proposed amendment on any basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall notify each shareholder, whether or not entitled to vote, of the proposed shareholders’ meeting in accordance with s. 607.0705. The notice of meeting must also state that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of the meeting is to consider the proposed amendment and contain or be accompanied by a copy or summary of the amendment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless this act, the articles of incorporation, or the board of directors (acting pursuant to subsection (3)) requires a greater vote or a vote by voting groups, the amendment to be adopted must be approved by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the votes entitled to be cast on the amendment by any voting group with respect to which the amendment would create dissenters’ rights; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The votes required by ss. 607.0725 and 607.0726 by every other voting group entitled to vote on the amendment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation, the shareholders of a corporation having 35 or fewer shareholders may amend the articles of incorporation without an act of the directors at a meeting for which notice of the changes to be made is given.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 99, ch. 89-154.</History></Section>