<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0607.1502" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Consequences of transacting business without authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation transacting business in this state without a certificate of authority may not maintain a proceeding in any court in this state until it obtains a certificate of authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The successor to a foreign corporation that transacted business in this state without a certificate of authority and the assignee of a cause of action arising out of that business may not maintain a proceeding based on that cause of action in any court in this state until the foreign corporation or its successor obtains a certificate of authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court may stay a proceeding commenced by a foreign corporation or its successor or assignee until it determines whether the foreign corporation or its successor requires a certificate of authority. If it so determines, the court may further stay the proceeding until the foreign corporation or its successor obtains the certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation which transacts business in this state without authority to do so shall be liable to this state for the years or parts thereof during which it transacted business in this state without authority in an amount equal to all fees and taxes which would have been imposed by this act upon such corporation had it duly applied for and received authority to transact business in this state as required by this act. In addition to the payments thus prescribed, such corporation shall be liable for a civil penalty of not less than $500 or more than $1,000 for each year or part thereof during which it transacts business in this state without a certificate of authority. The Department of State may collect all penalties due under this subsection and may bring an action in circuit court to recover all penalties and fees due and owing the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsections (1) and (2), the failure of a foreign corporation to obtain a certificate of authority does not impair the validity of any of its contracts, deeds, mortgages, security interests, or corporate acts or prevent it from defending any proceeding in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 137, ch. 89-154; s. 5, ch. 91-214.</History></Section>