<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0078.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Order to show cause; waiver.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right to be heard provided in ss. 78.065 and 78.067 is waived if the defendant, after receiving a show cause order, engages in any conduct that clearly shows that he or she wants to forego the right to be heard on that order. The defendant’s failure to appear at the hearing duly scheduled on the order to show cause presumptively constitutes conduct that clearly shows that he or she wants to forego the right to be so heard. If the defendant, after service of the order to show cause, sends or delivers to the plaintiff or the court issuing the order to show cause a writing prepared by anyone but signed by the defendant after service of the order to show cause, indicating in any language that the defendant does not want to be heard on the show cause order, the defendant shall be presumed to have waived the right to be heard. For this purpose, a writing containing the following language is sufficient: “I, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of the defendant)</Directions>, am aware that I have the right and opportunity to be heard on a show cause order that has been served upon me concerning the right of plaintiff to obtain a writ of replevin authorizing the appropriate officer of the court to take <Directions xml:space="preserve">(describe property)</Directions> from my possession prior to final judgment against me. I hereby state that I do not want to be heard on this matter and that I expressly waive my right to be heard. I understand that the effect of my signing this paper probably will be a court order authorizing the issuance of a writ of replevin directing an officer of the court to take possession of the property described above prior to final judgment against me with respect to the claim under which the property is taken.”</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-20; s. 406, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>