<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0078.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Order to show cause; contents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court without delay shall examine the complaint filed; and, if on the basis of the complaint and further showing of the plaintiff in support of it the court finds that the defendant has waived in accordance with s. 78.075 his or her right to be notified and heard, the court shall promptly issue an order authorizing the clerk of the court to issue a writ of replevin.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, upon examination of the complaint filed and on further showing of the plaintiff in support of it, the court finds that the defendant has not waived in accordance with s. 78.075 his or her right to be notified and heard, the court shall promptly issue an order directed to the defendant to show cause why the claimed property should not be taken from the possession of the defendant and delivered to plaintiff. Such order shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fix the date and time for hearing on the order. However, the date for the hearing shall not be set sooner than 5 days after the service of the order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct the time within which service of the order and the complaint shall be made upon the defendant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fix the manner in which service of the order shall be made on the defendant. The order shall direct that service as provided by law shall be made on the defendant if such service is possible or, in the event the officer serving the order is unable to serve such defendant as provided by law within the time specified in paragraph (b), that the officer shall place the order, together with the summons, on or in the claimed property or on the main entrance of the defendant’s residence. The officer’s return shall state that the officer was unable to locate the defendant and how the order was served.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State that the nonpersonal service as provided herein shall be effective to afford notice to the defendant of the show cause order, but for no other purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State that the defendant has the right to file affidavits on his or her behalf with the court and may appear personally or by way of an attorney and present testimony on his or her behalf at the time of the hearing, or that the defendant may, upon a finding by the court pursuant to s. 78.067(2) that the plaintiff is entitled to the possession of the claimed property pending final adjudication of the claims of the parties, file with the court a written undertaking executed by a surety approved by the court in an amount equal to the value of the property to stay an order authorizing the delivery of the property to the plaintiff.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State that if the defendant fails to appear the defendant shall be deemed to have waived his or her right to a hearing and that in such case the court may order the clerk of the court to issue a writ of replevin.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-20; s. 10, ch. 79-396; s. 5, ch. 83-255; s. 403, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>