<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0078.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Complaint; requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To obtain an order authorizing the issuance of a writ of replevin prior to final judgment, the plaintiff shall first file with the clerk of the court a complaint reciting and showing the following information:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the claimed property that is sufficient to make possible its identification and a statement, to the best knowledge, information, and belief of the plaintiff of the value of such property and its location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the plaintiff is the owner of the claimed property or is entitled to possession of it, describing the source of such title or right. If the plaintiff’s interest in such property is based on a written instrument, a copy of said instrument must be attached to the complaint.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the property is wrongfully detained by the defendant, the means by which the defendant came into possession thereof, and the cause of such detention according to the best knowledge, information, and belief of the plaintiff.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the claimed property has not been taken for a tax, assessment, or fine pursuant to law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the property has not been taken under an execution or attachment against the property of the plaintiff or, if so taken, that it is by law exempt from such taking, setting forth a reference to the exemption law relied upon.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-20; s. 3, ch. 76-19.</History></Section>