<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0684.0048" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for refusing recognition or enforcement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognition or enforcement of an arbitral award, irrespective of the country in which it was made, may be refused only:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the request of the party against whom it is invoked, if that party furnishes to the competent court where recognition or enforcement is sought proof that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party to the arbitration agreement defined in s. 684.0003(1)(c) was under some incapacity or the arbitration agreement is not valid under the law to which the parties have subjected it or, failing any indication thereon, under the law of the country where the award was made;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The party against whom the award is invoked was not given proper notice of the appointment of an arbitrator or of the arbitral proceedings or was otherwise unable to present its case;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The award deals with a dispute not contemplated by or not falling within the terms of the submission to arbitration, or it contains decisions on matters beyond the scope of the submission to arbitration. However, if the decisions on matters submitted to arbitration can be separated from those not so submitted, that part of the award which contains decisions on matters submitted to arbitration may be recognized and enforced;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The composition of the arbitral tribunal or the arbitral procedure was not in accordance with the agreement of the parties or, failing such agreement, was not in accordance with the law of the country where the arbitration took place; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The award has not yet become binding on the parties or has been set aside or suspended by a court of the country in which, or under the law of which, that award was made; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The subject matter of the dispute is not capable of settlement by arbitration under the laws of this state; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recognition or enforcement of the award would be contrary to the public policy of this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an application for setting aside or suspension of an award has been made to a court referenced in subparagraph (1)(a)5., the court where recognition or enforcement is sought may, if it considers it proper, adjourn its decision and may also, on the application of the party claiming recognition or enforcement of the award, order the other party to provide appropriate security.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 49, ch. 2010-60.</History>
</Section>