<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0684.0027" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for refusing recognition or enforcement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognition or enforcement of an interim measure may be refused only:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the request of the party against whom it is invoked if the court is satisfied that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such refusal is warranted on the grounds set forth in s. 684.0048(1)(a)1., 2., 3., or 4.;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The arbitral tribunal’s decision with respect to the provision of security in connection with the interim measure issued by the arbitral tribunal has not been complied with; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interim measure was terminated or suspended by the arbitral tribunal or, if so empowered, by the court of the state or country in which the arbitration takes place or under the law of which that interim measure was granted; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interim measure is incompatible with the powers conferred upon the court, unless the court decides to reformulate the interim measure to the extent necessary to adapt it to its own powers and procedures for the purpose of enforcing that interim measure and without modifying its substance; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the grounds set forth in s. 684.0048(1)(b)1. or 2. apply to the recognition and enforcement of the interim measure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination made by the court on any ground in subsection (1) is effective only for the purposes of the application to recognize and enforce the interim measure. The court may not in making that determination undertake a review of the substance of the interim measure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 2010-60.</History>
</Section>