<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0684.0002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Scope of application.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter applies to international commercial arbitration, subject to any agreement in force between the United States of America and any other country or countries.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter, except ss. 684.0009, 684.001, 684.0026, 684.0027, 684.0028, 684.0047, and 684.0048, applies only if the place of arbitration is in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An arbitration is international if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parties to an arbitration agreement have, at the time of the conclusion of that agreement, their places of business in different countries;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One of the following places is situated outside the country in which the parties have their places of business:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The place of arbitration if determined in, or pursuant to, the arbitration agreement; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any place where a substantial part of the obligations of the commercial relationship are to be performed or the place with which the subject matter of the dispute is most closely connected; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parties have expressly agreed that the subject matter of the arbitration agreement relates to more than one country.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of subsection (3):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a party has more than one place of business, the place of business is that which has the closest relationship to the arbitration agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a party does not have a place of business, reference shall be made to his or her habitual residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not affect any law that may prohibit a matter from being resolved by arbitration or that specifies the manner in which a specific matter may be submitted or resolved by arbitration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2010-60.</History>
</Section>