<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0298.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual election of supervisors; term of office; vacancy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every year in the same month after the time for the election of the first board of supervisors, it shall call a meeting of the landowners in the district in the same manner as is provided for in s. 298.11, and the owners of land in such district shall meet at the stated time and place and elect one supervisor. Owners whose assessments have not been paid for the previous year are not entitled to vote. In case of their failure to elect, the Governor shall appoint such supervisor, who shall hold the supervisor’s office for 3 years or until his or her successor is elected and qualified; and in case of a vacancy in any office of supervisor elected by the landowners, the remaining supervisors or, if they fail to act within 30 days, the Governor may fill such vacancy until the next annual meeting, when a successor shall be elected for the unexpired term.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vacancy in any of the three elected positions on the Melbourne-Tillman Water Control District Board of Supervisors which is not filled by a vote of the district’s landowners pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be filled by the Brevard County Board of County Commissioners within 30 days. The supervisor so appointed shall fill such vacancy until the next annual meeting when a successor shall be elected by the landowners for the unexpired portion of the term. A vacancy in any of the two appointed supervisor positions shall be filled by the Brevard County Board of County Commissioners within 30 days.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 6458, 1913; RGS 1102; CGL 1455; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 76-181; s. 5, ch. 79-5; s. 121, ch. 94-356; s. 886, ch. 95-148; s. 3, ch. 97-40; s. 3, ch. 98-329; s. 6, ch. 2000-308.</History></Section>