<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0298.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment and duties of treasurer of district; appointment of deputies; bond of treasurer; audit of books; disbursements by warrant; form of warrant.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of supervisors in any district shall select and appoint some competent person, bank or trust company, organized under the laws of the state, as treasurer of such district, who shall receive and receipt for all the drainage taxes collected by the county collector or collectors, and the treasurer shall also receive and receipt for the proceeds of all tax sales made under the provisions of this chapter. Said treasurer shall receive such compensation as may be fixed by the board of supervisors. Said board of supervisors shall also have the authority to employ a fiscal agent, who shall be either a resident of the state or some corporation organized under the laws of Florida and authorized by such laws to act as such fiscal agent for municipal corporations, who shall assist in the keeping of the tax books, collections of taxes, the remitting of funds to pay maturing bonds and coupons, and perform such other service in the general management of the fiscal and clerical affairs of the district as may be determined by such board; and said board shall have the right to define the duties of such fiscal agent and fix its compensation. Said board of supervisors shall furnish the secretary and the treasurer with necessary office room, furniture, stationery, maps, plats, typewriter, and postage. The secretary and the treasurer, or either of them, may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the board of supervisors, one or more deputies as may be necessary. Said treasurer shall give bond in such amount as shall be fixed by the board of supervisors, conditioned that the treasurer will well and truly account for and pay out, as provided by law, all moneys received by him or her as taxes from the county collector, and the proceeds from tax sales for delinquent taxes, and from any other source whatever on account or claim of said district, which bond shall be signed by at least two sureties, or by some surety or bonding company, approved and accepted by said board of supervisors, and said bond shall be in addition to the bond for proceeds of sales of bonds, which is required by s. 298.47. Said bond shall be placed and remain in the custody of the president of the board of supervisors, and shall be kept separate from all papers in the custody of the secretary or treasurer. Said treasurer shall keep all funds received by him or her from any source whatever deposited at all times in some bank, banks, or trust company to be designated by the board of supervisors. All interest accruing on such funds shall, when paid, be credited to the district. The board of supervisors shall audit or have audited the books of the said treasurer of said district at least once each year and make a report thereof to the landowners at the annual meeting and publish a statement within 30 days thereafter, showing the amount of money received, the amount paid out during such year, and the amount in the treasury at the beginning and end of the year. A certified copy of said annual audit shall be filed with the state auditor. The treasurer of the district shall pay out funds of the district only on warrants issued by the district, said warrants to be signed by the president of the board of supervisors and attested by the signature of the secretary. All warrants shall be in the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">$<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Fund <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> No. of Warrant <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Treasurer of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Water Control District, State of Florida. Pay to <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Dollars out of the money in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> fund of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Water Control District. For <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">By order of board of supervisors of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> Water Control District, Florida.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(President of District.)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Attest:<FlushRight /><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Secretary of District.)</Directions></Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 6458, 1913; RGS 1122; s. 1, ch. 9129, 1923; CGL 1475; s. 10, ch. 72-291; s. 7, ch. 79-5; s. 263, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>