<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0298.401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Property appraisers and tax collectors; compensation; characterization of services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any district or subdistrict whose area shall extend into not more than two counties, the property appraisers of each county containing lands within such districts where drainage taxes are assessed on the county tax roll by the county property appraiser shall be paid an amount equal to 1 percent of the total of taxes of the district, by each assessed within his or her county, except errors, and 1 percent on delinquent taxes when redeemed. The tax collectors of each county containing lands within the district shall be paid an amount equal to 1 percent of the total of taxes of the district by each collected, and 1 percent upon delinquent taxes when collected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services of the property appraisers and tax collectors in assessing and collecting such district taxes are hereby declared to be special services performed directly for these districts, and any payment therefor shall not be considered a part of the general income of the official’s office nor come under the provisions of s. 116.03. The personnel required to do said special work shall be paid for such special services from the receipts provided in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not apply to, repeal, or affect any local law or general law of local application heretofore passed, fixing and establishing the compensation of county property appraisers or tax collectors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-4, ch. 25196, 1949; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 18, ch. 79-5; s. 62, ch. 79-164; s. 183, ch. 81-259; s. 269, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>