<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0298.305" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assessing land for development; apportionment of assessment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the engineer’s report has been approved by the board of supervisors, the proposed water control plan or plan amendment has been finally adopted, and the lists of lands with the assessed benefits have been filed in the office of the secretary of the district, then the board of supervisors shall levy a non-ad valorem assessment as approved by the board on all lands in the district to which benefits have been assessed, to pay the costs of the completion of the proposed works and improvements, as shown in the adopted plan or plan amendment and in carrying out the objectives of the district; and, in addition thereto, 10 percent of the total amount for contingencies. The assessment must be apportioned to and levied on each assessable tract of land in the district. Under s. 298.54, the board of supervisors may also levy a maintenance assessment on all lands in the district to which benefits have been assessed as may be necessary to operate and maintain the district works and activities and to defray the current expenses of the district. A maintenance assessment recommendation for the operation and maintenance of the district works and activities must be included in each engineer’s report considered by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of supervisors may issue bonds in accordance with s. 298.47 to pay the cost of the works and improvements described in the water control plan. Upon such determination, the board of supervisors shall levy a non-ad valorem assessment in a sum not less than an amount, 90 percent of which shall be equal to the principal of said bonds. In no event shall the total amount of all bonds to be issued by the district exceed 90 percent of the benefits assessed upon the lands of the district. Bonds issued under this section shall draw interest at a rate provided by general law and shall be made payable at such time and place as the board of supervisors may determine. The amount of the interest that will accrue on the bonds, as estimated by the board of supervisors, shall be included and added to the assessment, but the interest to accrue on the bonds shall not be included as part of the cost of construction in determining whether or not the expenses and costs of making the improvements shown in the water control plan are equal to, or in excess of, the benefits assessed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 97-40.</History></Section>