<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0720.30851" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Estoppel certificates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 days after the date on which a request for an estoppel certificate is received from a parcel owner or mortgagee, or his or her designee, the association shall provide a certificate signed by an officer or authorized agent of the association stating all assessments and other moneys owed to the association by the parcel owner or mortgagee with respect to the parcel. An association may charge a fee for the preparation of such certificate, and the amount of such fee must be stated on the certificate.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person other than a parcel owner who relies upon a certificate receives the benefits and protection thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary proceeding pursuant to s. 51.011 may be brought to compel compliance with this section, and the prevailing party is entitled to recover reasonable attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority to charge a fee for the certificate shall be established by a written resolution adopted by the board or provided by a written management, bookkeeping, or maintenance contract and is payable upon the preparation of the certificate. If the certificate is requested in conjunction with the sale or mortgage of a parcel but the closing does not occur and no later than 30 days after the closing date for which the certificate was sought the preparer receives a written request, accompanied by reasonable documentation, that the sale did not occur from a payor that is not the parcel owner, the fee shall be refunded to that payor within 30 days after receipt of the request. The refund is the obligation of the parcel owner, and the association may collect it from that owner in the same manner as an assessment as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>