<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0720.3075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited clauses in association documents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is declared that the public policy of this state prohibits the inclusion or enforcement of certain types of clauses in homeowners’ association documents, including declaration of covenants, articles of incorporation, bylaws, or any other document of the association which binds members of the association, which either have the effect of or provide that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer has the unilateral ability and right to make changes to the homeowners’ association documents after the transition of homeowners’ association control in a community from the developer to the nondeveloper members, as set forth in s. 720.307, has occurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A homeowners’ association is prohibited or restricted from filing a lawsuit against the developer, or the homeowners’ association is otherwise effectively prohibited or restricted from bringing a lawsuit against the developer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the transition of homeowners’ association control in a community from the developer to the nondeveloper members, as set forth in s. 720.307, has occurred, a developer is entitled to cast votes in an amount that exceeds one vote per residential lot.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such clauses are declared null and void as against the public policy of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public policy described in subsection (1) prohibits the inclusion or enforcement of such clauses created on or after the effective date of s. 3, chapter 98-261, Laws of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Homeowners’ association documents, including declarations of covenants, articles of incorporation, or bylaws, may not preclude the display of one portable, removable United States flag by property owners. However, the flag must be displayed in a respectful manner, consistent with Title 36 U.S.C. chapter 10.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the use of Florida-friendly landscaping and other water use and pollution prevention measures to conserve or protect the state’s water resources serves a compelling public interest and that the participation of homeowners’ associations and local governments is essential to the state’s efforts in water conservation and water quality protection and restoration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Homeowners’ association documents, including declarations of covenants, articles of incorporation, or bylaws, may not prohibit or be enforced so as to prohibit any property owner from implementing Florida-friendly landscaping, as defined in s. 373.185, on his or her land or create any requirement or limitation in conflict with any provision of part II of chapter 373 or a water shortage order, other order, consumptive use permit, or rule adopted or issued pursuant to part II of chapter 373.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 98-261; s. 49, ch. 2000-258; s. 47, ch. 2000-302; s. 8, ch. 2001-252; s. 2, ch. 2002-50; s. 28, ch. 2009-243.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 617.3075.</Text></Note></Section>