<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0720.307" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transition of association control in a community.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to homeowners’ associations:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members other than the developer are entitled to elect at least a majority of the members of the board of directors of the homeowners’ association when the earlier of the following events occurs:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three months after 90 percent of the parcels in all phases of the community that will ultimately be operated by the homeowners’ association have been conveyed to members; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other percentage of the parcels has been conveyed to members, or such other date or event has occurred, as is set forth in the governing documents in order to comply with the requirements of any governmentally chartered entity with regard to the mortgage financing of parcels.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of this section, the term “members other than the developer” shall not include builders, contractors, or others who purchase a parcel for the purpose of constructing improvements thereon for resale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer is entitled to elect at least one member of the board of directors of the homeowners’ association as long as the developer holds for sale in the ordinary course of business at least 5 percent of the parcels in all phases of the community. After the developer relinquishes control of the homeowners’ association, the developer may exercise the right to vote any developer-owned voting interests in the same manner as any other member, except for purposes of reacquiring control of the homeowners’ association or selecting the majority of the members of the board of directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the members are entitled to elect at least a majority of the board of directors of the homeowners’ association, the developer shall, at the developer’s expense, within no more than 90 days deliver the following documents to the board:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All deeds to common property owned by the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The original of the association’s declarations of covenants and restrictions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified copy of the articles of incorporation of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the bylaws.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minute books, including all minutes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The books and records of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policies, rules, and regulations, if any, which have been adopted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resignations of directors who are required to resign because the developer is required to relinquish control of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial records of the association from the date of incorporation through the date of turnover.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All association funds and control thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All tangible property of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of all contracts which may be in force with the association as one of the parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of the names and addresses and telephone numbers of all contractors, subcontractors, or others in the current employ of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any and all insurance policies in effect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any permits issued to the association by governmental entities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any and all warranties in effect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A roster of current homeowners and their addresses and telephone numbers and section and lot numbers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employment and service contracts in effect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other contracts in effect to which the association is a party.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial records, including financial statements of the association, and source documents from the incorporation of the association through the date of turnover. The records shall be audited by an independent certified public accountant for the period from the incorporation of the association or from the period covered by the last audit, if an audit has been performed for each fiscal year since incorporation. All financial statements shall be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and shall be audited in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards, as prescribed by the Board of Accountancy, pursuant to chapter 473. The certified public accountant performing the audit shall examine to the extent necessary supporting documents and records, including the cash disbursements and related paid invoices to determine if expenditures were for association purposes and the billings, cash receipts, and related records of the association to determine that the developer was charged and paid the proper amounts of assessments. This paragraph applies to associations with a date of incorporation after December 31, 2007.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a homeowners’ association in existence on the effective date of this act, or to a homeowners’ association, no matter when created, if such association is created in a community that is included in an effective development-of-regional-impact development order as of the effective date of this act, together with any approved modifications thereof.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 95-274; s. 2, ch. 98-261; s. 48, ch. 2000-258; s. 14, ch. 2007-173.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 617.307.</Text></Note></Section>