<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0720.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assessment” or “amenity fee” means a sum or sums of money payable to the association, to the developer or other owner of common areas, or to recreational facilities and other properties serving the parcels by the owners of one or more parcels as authorized in the governing documents, which if not paid by the owner of a parcel, can result in a lien against the parcel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Common area” means all real property within a community which is owned or leased by an association or dedicated for use or maintenance by the association or its members, including, regardless of whether title has been conveyed to the association:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property the use of which is dedicated to the association or its members by a recorded plat; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property committed by a declaration of covenants to be leased or conveyed to the association.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community” means the real property that is or will be subject to a declaration of covenants which is recorded in the county where the property is located. The term “community” includes all real property, including undeveloped phases, that is or was the subject of a development-of-regional-impact development order, together with any approved modification thereto.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Declaration of covenants,” or “declaration,” means a recorded written instrument or instruments in the nature of covenants running with the land which subject the land comprising the community to the jurisdiction and control of an association or associations in which the owners of the parcels, or their association representatives, must be members.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Developer” means a person or entity that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Creates the community served by the association; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Succeeds to the rights and liabilities of the person or entity that created the community served by the association, provided that such is evidenced in writing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes in the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Governing documents” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recorded declaration of covenants for a community, and all duly adopted and recorded amendments, supplements, and recorded exhibits thereto; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation and bylaws of the homeowners’ association, and any duly adopted amendments thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Homeowners’ association” or “association” means a Florida corporation responsible for the operation of a community or a mobile home subdivision in which the voting membership is made up of parcel owners or their agents, or a combination thereof, and in which membership is a mandatory condition of parcel ownership, and which is authorized to impose assessments that, if unpaid, may become a lien on the parcel. The term “homeowners’ association” does not include a community development district or other similar special taxing district created pursuant to statute.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Member” means a member of an association, and may include, but is not limited to, a parcel owner or an association representing parcel owners or a combination thereof, and includes any person or entity obligated by the governing documents to pay an assessment or amenity fee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Parcel” means a platted or unplatted lot, tract, unit, or other subdivision of real property within a community, as described in the declaration:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which is capable of separate conveyance; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of which the parcel owner, or an association in which the parcel owner must be a member, is obligated:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the governing documents to be a member of an association that serves the community; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay to the homeowners’ association assessments that, if not paid, may result in a lien.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Parcel owner” means the record owner of legal title to a parcel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Voting interest” means the voting rights distributed to the members of the homeowners’ association, pursuant to the governing documents.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 92-49; s. 52, ch. 95-274; s. 4, ch. 99-382; s. 44, ch. 2000-258; s. 16, ch. 2004-345; s. 13, ch. 2004-353; s. 62, ch. 2008-240; s. 16, ch. 2011-196.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 617.301.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>