<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0495.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Abandoned” applies to a mark when either of the following occurs:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When its use has been discontinued with intent not to resume such use. Intent not to resume use may be inferred from circumstances. Nonuse for 3 consecutive years shall constitute prima facie evidence of abandonment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any course of conduct of the owner, including acts of omission or commission, causes the mark to lose its significance as a mark.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicant” means the person filing an application for registration of a mark under this chapter and the legal representatives, successors, or assigns of such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certification mark” means any word, name, symbol, or device, or any combination thereof, used by a person other than the owner of the mark to certify regional or other origin, material, mode of manufacture, quality, accuracy, or other characteristics of such person’s goods or services or that the work or labor on the goods or services was performed by members of a union or other organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Collective mark” means a trademark or service mark used by the members of a cooperative, an association, or other collective group or organization, and includes marks used to indicate membership in a union, an association, or other organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Florida Department of State or its designee charged with the administration of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dilution” means the lessening of the capacity of a mark to identify and distinguish goods or services, regardless of the presence or absence of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Competition between the owner of the mark and other parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Likelihood of confusion, mistake, or deception.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mark” includes any trademark, service mark, certification mark, or collective mark entitled to registration under this chapter, whether or not registered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person,” and any other word or term used to designate the applicant or other party entitled to a benefit or privilege or rendered liable under the provisions of this chapter, means a juristic person as well as a natural person. “Juristic person” includes a firm, partnership, corporation, union, association, or other organization capable of suing and being sued in a court of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registrant” means the person to whom the registration of a mark under this chapter is issued and the legal representatives, successors, or assigns of such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Related company” means any person whose use of a mark is controlled by the owner of the mark with respect to the nature and quality of the goods or services on or in connection with which the mark is used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service mark” means any word, name, symbol, or device, or any combination thereof, used by a person to identify and distinguish the services of such person, including a unique service, from the services of others, and to indicate the source of the services, even if that source is unknown. Titles, character names, and other distinctive features of radio or television programs may be registered as service marks notwithstanding that the person or the programs may advertise the goods of the sponsor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trade name” means any name used by a person to identify a business or vocation of such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trademark” means any word, name, symbol, or device, or any combination thereof, used by a person to identify and distinguish the goods of such person, including a unique product, from those manufactured or sold by others, and to indicate the source of the goods, even if the source is unknown.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Use” means the bona fide use of a mark in the ordinary course of trade and not used merely for the purpose of reserving a right in a mark. For purposes of this chapter, a mark is deemed to be in use:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On goods when:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mark is placed in any manner on the goods, their containers or the displays associated therewith, or on the tags or labels affixed thereto, or, if the nature of the goods makes such placement impracticable, on documents associated with the goods or their sale; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The goods are sold or transported in this state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On services when the mark is used or displayed in the sale or advertising of services and the services are rendered in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-58; s. 1, ch. 90-222; s. 551, ch. 97-103; s. 2, ch. 2006-191.</History></Section>