<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0495.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the limitations set forth in this chapter, any person who uses a trademark or service mark in this state may file with the department, in a manner and form complying with the requirements of the department, an application for registration of that mark setting forth, but not limited to, the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and business address of the person applying for such registration, and, if a business entity, the place of incorporation or organization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The goods or services on or in connection with which the mark is used and the mode or manner in which the mark is used in connection with such goods or services and the class or classes in which such goods or services fall;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the mark was first used anywhere and the date it was first used in this state by the applicant, the applicant’s predecessor in interest, or a related company of the applicant; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the applicant is the owner of the mark, that the mark is in use, and that, to the best of the applicant’s knowledge, no other person except a related company has registered such mark in this state, or has the right to use such mark in this state, either in the identical form thereof or in such near resemblance thereto as to be likely, when applied to the goods or services of such other person, to cause confusion, to cause mistake, or to deceive.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every applicant for registration of a certification mark in this state shall file with the department, in a manner and form complying with the requirements of the department, an application setting forth, but not limited to, the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information required by paragraph (1)(a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date when the certification mark was first used anywhere and the date when it was first used in this state under the authority of the applicant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which and the conditions under which the certification mark is used in this state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the applicant is exercising control over the use of the mark, that the applicant is not herself or himself engaged in the production or marketing of the goods or services to which the mark is applied, and that no person except the applicant or persons authorized by the applicant, or related companies thereof, has the right to use such mark in this state, either in the identical form thereof or in such near resemblance thereto as to be likely, when applied to the goods or services of such other person, to cause confusion, to cause mistake, or to deceive.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every applicant for registration of a collective mark in this state shall file with the department, in a manner and form complying with the requirements of the department, an application setting forth, but not limited to, the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information required by paragraphs (1)(a) and (b);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date when the collective mark was first used anywhere and the date when it was first used in this state by any member of the applicant or a related company of such member;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The class of persons entitled to use the mark, indicating their relationship to the applicant, and the nature of the applicant’s control over the use of the mark; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that no person except the applicant or members of the applicant, or related companies thereof, has the right to use such mark in this state, either in the identical form thereof or in such near resemblance thereto as to be likely, when applied to the goods or services of such other person, to cause confusion, to cause mistake, or to deceive.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may also require that a drawing of the mark, complying with the requirements of the department, accompany the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every application under this section shall be signed and verified by the applicant or by a member of the firm or an officer or other authorized representative of the business entity applying.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every application under this section shall be accompanied by three specimens or facsimiles showing the mark as actually used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every application under this section shall be accompanied by a filing fee payable to the department in accordance with s. 495.191.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-58; s. 1, ch. 67-560; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 71-114; s. 2, ch. 87-265; s. 59, ch. 90-132; s. 4, ch. 90-222; s. 553, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 2006-191.</History></Section>