<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0495.151" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dilution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of a mark that is famous in this state shall be entitled, subject to the principles of equity and upon such terms as the court deems reasonable, to an injunction and to obtain such other relief against another person’s commercial use of a mark or trade name if such use begins after the mark has become famous and is likely to cause dilution of the distinctive quality of the famous mark, as provided in this section. In determining whether a mark is distinctive and famous, a court may consider factors, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The degree of inherent or acquired distinctiveness of the mark in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration and extent of use of the mark in connection with the goods and services with which the mark is used.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration and extent of advertising and publicity of the mark in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The geographical extent of the trading area in which the mark is used.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The channels of trade for the goods or services with which the mark is used.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The degree of recognition of the mark in the trading areas and channels of trade in this state used by the mark’s owner and the person against whom the injunction is sought.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and extent of use of the same or similar mark by third parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the mark is the subject of a state registration in this state or a federal registration under the Federal Trademark Act of March 3, 1881, or the Federal Trademark Act of February 20, 1905, or a principal register registration under the Federal Trademark Act of July 5, 1946.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an action brought under this section, the owner of a famous mark shall be entitled only to injunctive relief in this state unless the person against whom the injunctive relief is sought willfully intended to trade on the owner’s reputation or to cause dilution of the famous mark. If such willful intent is proven, and the mark is registered in this state, the owner shall also be entitled to all remedies set forth in this chapter, subject to the discretion of the court and the principles of equity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following shall not be actionable under this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fair use of a famous mark by another person in comparative commercial advertising or promotion to identify the competing goods or services of the owner of the famous mark.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Noncommercial use of the mark.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All forms of news reporting and news commentary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-58; s. 557, ch. 97-103; s. 17, ch. 2006-191.</History></Section>