<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0907.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pretrial detention and release.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is the policy of this state that persons committing serious criminal offenses, posing a threat to the safety of the community or the integrity of the judicial process, or failing to appear at trial be detained upon arrest. However, persons found to meet specified criteria shall be released under certain conditions until proceedings are concluded and adjudication has been determined. The Legislature finds that this policy of pretrial detention and release will assure the detention of those persons posing a threat to society while reducing the costs for incarceration by releasing, until trial, those persons not considered a danger to the community who meet certain criteria. It is the intent of the Legislature that the primary consideration be the protection of the community from risk of physical harm to persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES OF PROCEDURE.<EmDash />Procedures for pretrial release determinations shall be governed by rules adopted by the Supreme Court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RELEASE ON NONMONETARY CONDITIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to create a presumption in favor of release on nonmonetary conditions for any person who is granted pretrial release unless such person is charged with a dangerous crime as defined in subsection (4). Such person shall be released on monetary conditions if it is determined that such monetary conditions are necessary to assure the presence of the person at trial or at other proceedings, to protect the community from risk of physical harm to persons, to assure the presence of the accused at trial, or to assure the integrity of the judicial process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall be released on nonmonetary conditions under the supervision of a pretrial release service, unless the service certifies to the court that it has investigated or otherwise verified:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circumstances of the accused’s family, employment, financial resources, character, mental condition, and length of residence in the community;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accused’s record of convictions, of appearances at court proceedings, of flight to avoid prosecution, or of failure to appear at court proceedings; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other facts necessary to assist the court in its determination of the indigency of the accused and whether she or he should be released under the supervision of the service.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRETRIAL DETENTION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, “dangerous crime” means any of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arson;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aggravated assault;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aggravated battery;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Illegal use of explosives;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Child abuse or aggravated child abuse;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abuse of an elderly person or disabled adult, or aggravated abuse of an elderly person or disabled adult;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aircraft piracy;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Kidnapping;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Homicide;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manslaughter;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual battery;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Robbery;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carjacking;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lewd, lascivious, or indecent assault or act upon or in presence of a child under the age of 16 years;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sexual activity with a child, who is 12 years of age or older but less than 18 years of age, by or at solicitation of person in familial or custodial authority;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Burglary of a dwelling;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stalking and aggravated stalking;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act of domestic violence as defined in s. 741.28;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home invasion robbery;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act of terrorism as defined in s. 775.30;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufacturing any substances in violation of chapter 893; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting or conspiring to commit any such crime.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person charged with a dangerous crime shall be granted nonmonetary pretrial release at a first appearance hearing; however, the court shall retain the discretion to release an accused on electronic monitoring or on recognizance bond if the findings on the record of facts and circumstances warrant such a release.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may order pretrial detention if it finds a substantial probability, based on a defendant’s past and present patterns of behavior, the criteria in s. 903.046, and any other relevant facts, that any of the following circumstances exists:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant has previously violated conditions of release and that no further conditions of release are reasonably likely to assure the defendant’s appearance at subsequent proceedings;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant, with the intent to obstruct the judicial process, has threatened, intimidated, or injured any victim, potential witness, juror, or judicial officer, or has attempted or conspired to do so, and that no condition of release will reasonably prevent the obstruction of the judicial process;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant is charged with trafficking in controlled substances as defined by s. 893.135, that there is a substantial probability that the defendant has committed the offense, and that no conditions of release will reasonably assure the defendant’s appearance at subsequent criminal proceedings; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant is charged with DUI manslaughter, as defined by s. 316.193, and that there is a substantial probability that the defendant committed the crime and that the defendant poses a threat of harm to the community; conditions that would support a finding by the court pursuant to this subparagraph that the defendant poses a threat of harm to the community include, but are not limited to, any of the following:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant has previously been convicted of any crime under s. 316.193, or of any crime in any other state or territory of the United States that is substantially similar to any crime under s. 316.193;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant was driving with a suspended driver’s license when the charged crime was committed; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant has previously been found guilty of, or has had adjudication of guilt withheld for, driving while the defendant’s driver’s license was suspended or revoked in violation of s. 322.34;</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant poses the threat of harm to the community. The court may so conclude, if it finds that the defendant is presently charged with a dangerous crime, that there is a substantial probability that the defendant committed such crime, that the factual circumstances of the crime indicate a disregard for the safety of the community, and that there are no conditions of release reasonably sufficient to protect the community from the risk of physical harm to persons.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant was on probation, parole, or other release pending completion of sentence or on pretrial release for a dangerous crime at the time the current offense was committed; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant has violated one or more conditions of pretrial release or bond for the offense currently before the court and the violation, in the discretion of the court, supports a finding that no conditions of release can reasonably protect the community from risk of physical harm to persons or assure the presence of the accused at trial.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person charged with a crime for which pretrial detention could be ordered is arrested, the arresting agency shall promptly notify the state attorney of the arrest and shall provide the state attorney with such information as the arresting agency has obtained relative to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and circumstances of the offense charged;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of any physical evidence seized and the contents of any statements obtained from the defendant or any witness;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant’s family ties, residence, employment, financial condition, and mental condition; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant’s past conduct and present conduct, including any record of convictions, previous flight to avoid prosecution, or failure to appear at court proceedings.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person charged with a crime for which pretrial detention could be ordered is arrested, the arresting agency may detain such defendant, prior to the filing by the state attorney of a motion seeking pretrial detention, for a period not to exceed 24 hours.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pretrial detention hearing shall be held within 5 days of the filing by the state attorney of a complaint to seek pretrial detention. The defendant may request a continuance. No continuance shall be for longer than 5 days unless there are extenuating circumstances. The defendant may be detained pending the hearing. The state attorney shall be entitled to one continuance for good cause.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state attorney has the burden of showing the need for pretrial detention.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant is entitled to be represented by counsel, to present witnesses and evidence, and to cross-examine witnesses. The court may admit relevant evidence without complying with the rules of evidence, but evidence secured in violation of the United States Constitution or the Constitution of the State of Florida shall not be admissible. No testimony by the defendant shall be admissible to prove guilt at any other judicial proceeding, but such testimony may be admitted in an action for perjury, based upon the defendant’s statements made at the pretrial detention hearing, or for impeachment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pretrial detention order of the court shall be based solely upon evidence produced at the hearing and shall contain findings of fact and conclusions of law to support it. The order shall be made either in writing or orally on the record. The court shall render its findings within 24 hours of the pretrial detention hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant convicted at trial following the issuance of a pretrial detention order shall have credited to his or her sentence, if imprisonment is imposed, the time the defendant was held under the order, pursuant to s. 921.161.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant shall be entitled to dissolution of the pretrial detention order whenever the court finds that a subsequent event has eliminated the basis for detention.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that a person who manufactures any substances in violation of chapter 893 poses a threat of harm to the community and that the factual circumstances of such a crime indicate a disregard for the safety of the community. The court shall order pretrial detention if the court finds that there is a substantial probability that a defendant charged with manufacturing any substances in violation of chapter 893 committed such a crime and if the court finds that there are no conditions of release reasonably sufficient to protect the community from the risk of physical harm to persons.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 82-398; s. 48, ch. 84-103; s. 1, ch. 89-127; s. 2, ch. 89-281; s. 7, ch. 93-212; s. 12, ch. 95-195; s. 25, ch. 96-322; s. 1834, ch. 97-102; s. 106, ch. 99-3; s. 10, ch. 99-188; s. 2, ch. 2000-178; s. 2, ch. 2000-229; s. 24, ch. 2000-320; s. 2, ch. 2001-356; s. 1, ch. 2002-212; s. 16, ch. 2005-128; s. 4, ch. 2006-306.</History></Section>