<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0907.043" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pretrial release; citizens’ right to know.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Citizens’ Right-to-Know Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonsecured release” means the release of a defendant from pretrial custody when no secured surety or cash bond is required as a condition of the release.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pretrial release program” means an entity, public or private, that conducts investigations of pretrial detainees, makes pretrial release recommendations to a court, and electronically monitors and supervises pretrial defendants. However, the term “pretrial release program” shall not apply to the Department of Corrections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Register” means a public record prepared by a pretrial release program which furnishes specified data and is readily available to the public at the office of the clerk of the circuit court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secured release” means the release of a defendant from pretrial custody with a financial guarantee, such as cash or a surety bond, required as a condition of the release.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each pretrial release program must prepare a register displaying information that is relevant to the defendants released through such a program. A copy of the register must be located at the office of the clerk of the circuit court in the county where the program is located and must be readily accessible to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The register must be updated weekly and display accurate data regarding the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, location, and funding source of the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of defendants assessed and interviewed for pretrial release.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of indigent defendants assessed and interviewed for pretrial release.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and number of defendants accepted into the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and number of indigent defendants accepted into the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The charges filed against and the case numbers of defendants accepted into the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of any prior criminal conviction of a defendant accepted into the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court appearances required of defendants accepted into the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of each defendant’s failure to appear for a scheduled court appearance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of warrants, if any, which have been issued for a defendant’s arrest for failing to appear at a scheduled court appearance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and type of program noncompliance infractions committed by a defendant in the pretrial release program and whether the pretrial release program recommended that the court revoke the defendant’s release.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than March 31 of every year, each pretrial release program must submit an annual report for the previous calendar year to the governing body and to the clerk of the circuit court in the county where the pretrial release program is located. The annual report must be readily accessible to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual report must contain, but need not be limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, location, and funding sources of the pretrial release program, including the amount of public funds, if any, received by the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operating and capital budget of each pretrial release program receiving public funds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage of the pretrial release program’s total budget representing receipt of public funds.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage of the total budget which is allocated to assisting defendants obtain release through a nonpublicly funded program.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of fees paid by defendants to the pretrial release program.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of persons employed by the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of defendants assessed and interviewed for pretrial release.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of defendants recommended for pretrial release.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of defendants for whom the pretrial release program recommended against nonsecured release.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of defendants granted nonsecured release after the pretrial release program recommended nonsecured release.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of defendants assessed and interviewed for pretrial release who were declared indigent by the court.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and case number of each person granted nonsecured release who:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to attend a scheduled court appearance.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was issued a warrant for failing to appear.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was arrested for any offense while on release through the pretrial release program.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional information deemed necessary by the governing body to assess the performance and cost efficiency of the pretrial release program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2008-224.</History></Section>