<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0905.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Testimony not to be disclosed; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A grand juror, state attorney, assistant state attorney, reporter, stenographer, interpreter, or any other person appearing before the grand jury shall not disclose the testimony of a witness examined before the grand jury or other evidence received by it except when required by a court to disclose the testimony for the purpose of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ascertaining whether it is consistent with the testimony given by the witness before the court;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining whether the witness is guilty of perjury; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furthering justice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person knowingly to publish, broadcast, disclose, divulge, or communicate to any other person, or knowingly to cause or permit to be published, broadcast, disclosed, divulged, or communicated to any other person, in any manner whatsoever, any testimony of a witness examined before the grand jury, or the content, gist, or import thereof, except when such testimony is or has been disclosed in a court proceeding. When a court orders the disclosure of such testimony pursuant to subsection (1) for use in a criminal case, it may be disclosed to the prosecuting attorney of the court in which such criminal case is pending, and by the prosecuting attorney to his or her assistants, legal associates, and employees, and to the defendant and the defendant’s attorney, and by the latter to his or her legal associates and employees. When such disclosure is ordered by a court pursuant to subsection (1) for use in a civil case, it may be disclosed to all parties to the case and to their attorneys and by the latter to their legal associates and employees. However, the grand jury testimony afforded such persons by the court can only be used in the defense or prosecution of the civil or criminal case and for no other purpose whatsoever.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall affect the attorney-client relationship. A client shall have the right to communicate to his or her attorney any testimony given by the client to the grand jury, any matters involving the client discussed in the client’s presence before the grand jury, and any evidence involving the client received by or proffered to the grand jury in the client’s presence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons convicted of violating this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.083, or by fine not exceeding $5,000, or both.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section shall constitute criminal contempt of court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 106, ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(106); s. 1, ch. 26940, 1951; s. 66, ch. 70-339; ss. 1, 1A, ch. 71-66; s. 1, ch. 94-285; s. 1503, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>