<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0261.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative findings and intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that off-highway vehicles are becoming increasingly popular in this state and that the use of these vehicles should be controlled and managed to minimize negative effects on the environment, wildlife habitats, native wildlife, and native flora and fauna.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature declares that effectively managed areas and adequate facilities for the use of off-highway vehicles are compatible with this state’s overall recreation plan and the underlying goal of multiple use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing off-highway vehicle recreational areas, facilities, and opportunities be improved and appropriately expanded and be managed in a manner consistent with this chapter, in particular to maintain natural resources and sustained long-term use of off-highway vehicle trails and areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">New off-highway vehicle recreational areas, facilities, and opportunities be provided and managed pursuant to this chapter in a manner that will sustain both long-term use and the environment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained within this chapter shall be construed to require the construction or maintenance of off-highway vehicle recreation areas, facilities, or trails on public lands where such construction or maintenance would be inconsistent with the property’s management objectives or land management plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 2002-295.</History></Section>