<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0261.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties and responsibilities of the Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Advisory Committee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall establish policies to guide the department regarding the Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Program and the system of off-highway vehicle recreation areas and trails.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall make recommendations to the department regarding off-highway vehicle safety and training and education programs in the operation of such vehicles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee must be informed regarding all governmental activities affecting the program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee must be informed regarding off-highway vehicle impacts and effects on the environment, wildlife habitats, and native flora and fauna and shall make recommendations to avoid or minimize adverse environmental impacts and promote sustained long-term use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee must be fully informed regarding the inventory of off-highway vehicle access and opportunities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall meet at various times and locations throughout the state to receive public comments on the implementation of the program and shall take these public comments into consideration when making its recommendations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall review and make recommendations annually regarding the department’s proposed budget of expenditures from the designated off-highway vehicle funds in the trust fund, which may include providing funds to match grant funds available from other sources.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall make recommendations regarding all capital outlay expenditures from the trust fund proposed for inclusion in the budget and shall identify additional funding sources for management, enforcement, education, rehabilitation, and other duties of the land management agencies related to the system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory committee shall review grant applications submitted by any governmental agency or entity or nongovernmental entity requesting moneys from the trust fund to create, operate, manage, or improve off-highway vehicle recreation areas or trails within the state, protect and restore affected natural areas in the system, or provide off-highway vehicle driver education. The advisory committee shall recommend to the department approval or denial of such grant applications based upon criteria established by the advisory committee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 2002-295.</History></Section>