<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0261.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Functions, duties, and responsibilities of the department.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are functions, duties, and responsibilities of the department through the Florida Forest Service:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordination of the planning, development, conservation, and rehabilitation of state lands in and for the system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordination of the management, maintenance, administration, and operation of state lands in the system and the provision of law enforcement and appropriate public safety activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management of the trust fund and approval of the advisory committee’s budget recommendations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implementation of the program, including the ultimate approval of grant applications submitted by governmental agencies or entities or nongovernmental entities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordination to help ensure compliance with environmental laws and regulations of the program and lands in the system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implementation of the policies established by the advisory committee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision of staff assistance to the advisory committee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preparation of plans for lands in, or proposed to be included in, the system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting surveys and the preparation of studies as are necessary or desirable for implementing the program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recruitment and utilization of volunteers to further the program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rulemaking authority to implement the provisions of ss. 261.01-261.10.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 2002-295; s. 4, ch. 2004-6; s. 14, ch. 2012-7.</History>
</Section>