<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0261.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Designated off-highway vehicle funds within the Incidental Trust Fund of the Florida Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designated off-highway vehicle funds of the trust fund shall consist of deposits from the following sources:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees paid to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for the titling of off-highway vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues and income from any other sources required by law or as appropriated by the Legislature to be deposited into the trust fund as designated off-highway vehicle funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Donations from private sources that are designated as off-highway vehicle funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest earned on designated off-highway vehicle funds on deposit in the trust fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designated off-highway vehicle funds in the trust fund shall be available for recommended allocation by the Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Advisory Committee and the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and upon annual appropriation by the Legislature, exclusively for the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implementation of the Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Program by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, which includes personnel and other related expenses; administrative and operating expenses; expenses related to safety, training, rider education programs, management, maintenance, and rehabilitation of lands in the Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Program’s system of lands and trails; and, if funds are available, acquisition of lands to be included in the system and the management, maintenance, and rehabilitation of such lands.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approved grants to governmental agencies or entities or nongovernmental entities that wish to provide or improve off-highway vehicle recreation areas or trails for public use on public lands, provide environmental protection and restoration to affected natural areas in the system, provide enforcement of applicable regulations related to the system and off-highway vehicle activities, or provide education in the operation of off-highway vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Matching funds to be used to match grant funds available from other sources.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance of designated off-highway vehicle funds in the trust fund at the end of any fiscal year shall remain therein and shall be available for the purposes set out in this section and as otherwise provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 2002-295; s. 15, ch. 2012-7.</History>
</Section>