<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Voluntary disclosure of customer communications or records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2) or subsection (3):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider of electronic communication service to the public may not knowingly divulge to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity the contents of a communication while in electronic storage by that service; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any governmental entity a record or other information pertaining to a subscriber to or customer of such service.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider of remote computing service to the public may not knowingly divulge to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity the contents of any communication that is carried or maintained on that service:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On behalf of a subscriber or customer of such service and received by means of electronic transmission from, or created by means of computer processing of communications received by means of electronic transmission from, a subscriber or customer of such remote computing service; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solely for the purpose of providing storage or computer processing services to its subscriber or customer, if the provider is not authorized to access the contents of any such communication for purposes of providing any service other than storage or computer processing; or</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any governmental entity a record or other information pertaining to a subscriber to or customer of such service.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider described in subsection (1) may divulge the contents of a communication:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To an addressee or intended recipient of such communication or an agent of such addressee or intended recipient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As otherwise authorized in s. 934.03(2)(a), s. 934.07, or s. 934.23.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the lawful consent of the originator or an addressee or intended recipient of such communication, or the subscriber in the case of a remote computing service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a person employed or authorized, or whose facilities are used, to forward such communication to its destination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As may be necessarily incident to the rendition of the service or to the protection of the rights or property of the provider of that service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a law enforcement agency, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contents were inadvertently obtained by the service provider;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contents appear to pertain to the commission of a crime; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provider reasonably believes an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to another person requires disclosure of the contents without delay.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider described in subsection (1) may disclose a record or other information pertaining to a subscriber to or customer of such service:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As is otherwise authorized in s. 934.23.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the lawful consent of the customer or subscriber.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As is necessary incident to rendering service or protecting the rights or property of the provider of that service.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a governmental entity if the provider reasonably believes that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person justifies disclosure of the information.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person other than a governmental entity.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), a provider may not disclose the contents of communications specified in paragraph (1)(a) or paragraph (1)(b).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 88-184; s. 7, ch. 2002-72.</History></Section>