<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General prohibition on pen register and trap and trace device use; exception.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, no person may install or use a pen register or a trap and trace device without first obtaining a court order under s. 934.33.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prohibition of subsection (1) does not apply with respect to the use of a pen register or a trap and trace device by a provider of electronic or wire communication service:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which relates to the operation, maintenance, and testing of a wire or electronic communication service or to the protection of the rights or property of the provider or to the protection of users of that service from abuse of service or unlawful use of service;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To record the fact that a wire or electronic communication was initiated or completed in order to protect the provider thereof, another provider furnishing service toward the completion of the wire communication, or a user of the service, from fraudulent, unlawful, or abusive use of service; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the consent of the user of the service has been obtained.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investigative or law enforcement officer authorized to install and use a pen register or trap and trace device under ss. 934.31-934.34 shall use technology reasonably available to him or her which restricts the recording or decoding of electronic or other impulses to the dialing, routing, addressing, and signaling information used in processing and transmitting wire or electronic communications so that the contents of any wire or electronic communications are not recorded or decoded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, any investigative or law enforcement officer specially designated by the Governor, the Attorney General, the statewide prosecutor, or a state attorney acting pursuant to this chapter, who reasonably determines that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An emergency exists which:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Involves immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person or the danger of escape of a prisoner; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requires the installation and use of a pen register or a trap and trace device before an order authorizing such installation and use can, with due diligence, be obtained; and</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There are grounds upon which an order could be entered under this chapter to authorize such installation and use,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">may have installed and use a pen register or trap and trace device if, within 48 hours after the installation has occurred or begins to occur, an order approving the installation or use is issued in accordance with s. 934.33.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of an authorizing order, such use shall immediately terminate when the information sought is obtained, when the application for the order is denied, or when 48 hours have lapsed since the installation of the pen register or trap and trace device, whichever is earlier.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The knowing installation or use by any investigative or law enforcement officer of a pen register or trap and trace device pursuant to paragraph (a) without application for the authorizing order within 48 hours after the installation constitutes a violation of s. 934.31.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider of wire or electronic service, landlord, custodian, or other person who has furnished facilities or technical assistance pursuant to this subsection shall be held harmless from any claims and civil liability resulting from the disclosure of information pursuant to this subsection and shall be reasonably compensated for reasonable expenses incurred in providing such facilities and assistance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever knowingly violates subsection (1) is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 934.41.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 88-184; s. 12, ch. 89-269; s. 15, ch. 2000-369; s. 10, ch. 2002-72.</History></Section>