<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Civil action: relief; damages; defenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 934.23(5), any provider of electronic communication service, or subscriber or customer thereof, aggrieved by any violation of ss. 934.21-934.28 in which the conduct constituting the violation is engaged in with a knowing or intentional state of mind may, in a civil action, recover from the person or entity which engaged in that violation such relief as is appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a civil action under this section, appropriate relief includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such preliminary and other equitable or declaratory relief as is appropriate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damages under subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reasonable attorney’s fee and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may assess as damages in a civil action under this section the sum of the actual damages suffered by the plaintiff and any profits made by the violator as a result of the violation, but in no case shall a plaintiff entitled to recover be awarded less than $1,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A good faith reliance on any of the following is a complete defense to any civil or criminal action brought under ss. 934.21-934.28:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court warrant or order, a subpoena, or a statutory authorization, including, but not limited to, a request of an investigative or law enforcement officer to preserve records or other evidence, as provided in s. 934.23(7).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request of an investigative or law enforcement officer under s. 934.09(7).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A good faith determination that s. 934.03(3) permitted the conduct complained of.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil action under this section may not be commenced later than 2 years after the date upon which the claimant first discovered or had a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 88-184; s. 11, ch. 89-269; s. 14, ch. 2000-369; s. 9, ch. 2002-72.</History></Section>