<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.33" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of an order for a pen register or a trap and trace device.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application made under s. 934.32, the court shall enter an ex parte order authorizing the installation and use of a pen register or a trap and trace device within the jurisdiction of the court if the court finds that the applicant specified in s. 934.32(1) has certified to the court that the information likely to be obtained by such installation and use is relevant to an ongoing criminal investigation. Whenever such order is served on any person or entity not specifically named in the order, upon request of such person or entity, the person specified in s. 934.32 who has requested and is serving such order shall provide written or electronic certification that such order applies to the person or entity being served.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order issued under this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must specify the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity, if known, of the person to whom is leased or in whose name is listed the telephone line or other facility to which the pen register or trap and trace device is to be attached or applied.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity, if known, of the person who is the subject of the criminal investigation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The attributes of the communications to which the order applies, including the number or other identifier and, if known, the location of the telephone line or other facility to which the pen register or trap and trace device is to be attached or applied and, in the case of an order authorizing installation and use of a trap and trace device, the geographic limits of the order.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the offense to which the information likely to be obtained by the pen register or trap and trace device relates.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must direct, upon the request of the applicant, the furnishing of information, facilities, and technical assistance necessary to accomplish the installation of the pen register or trap and trace device under s. 934.34.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order issued under this section may not authorize the installation and use of a pen register or a trap and trace device for more than 60 days.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extensions of such an order may be granted but only upon an application for an order under s. 934.32 and upon the judicial finding required by subsection (1). The period of extension may not exceed 60 days.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order authorizing or approving the installation and use of a pen register or a trap and trace device must direct that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order be sealed until otherwise ordered by the court, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person owning or leasing the line or other facility to which the pen register or a trap and trace device is attached or applied, or who is obligated by the order to provide assistance to the applicant, not disclose the existence of the pen register or trap and trace device or the existence of the investigation to the listed subscriber or to any other person except as otherwise ordered by the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court may not require greater specificity or additional information beyond that which is required under s. 934.32 and this section as a requisite for issuing an order as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an investigative or law enforcement agency implementing an ex parte order under this section seeks to do so by installing and using its own pen register or trap and trace device on a packet-switched data network of a provider of electronic communication service to the public, the agency must ensure that a record is maintained which identifies:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each officer who installed the device and each officer who accessed the device to obtain information from the network;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and time the device was installed; the date and time the device was uninstalled; and the date, time, and duration of each occasion the device was accessed to obtain information;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The configuration of the device at the time of its installation and any subsequent modification of that configuration; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information that was collected by the device.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that the pen register or trap and trace device can be set automatically to record electronically the information required in paragraph (a), the record shall be maintained electronically throughout the installation and use of the device.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The record maintained under subsection (6) shall be provided ex parte and under seal to the court that entered the ex parte order authorizing the installation and use of the device within 30 days after termination of the order, including any extension of the order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 88-184; s. 13, ch. 89-269; s. 11, ch. 2002-72.</History></Section>