<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative findings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the basis of its own investigations and of published studies, the Legislature makes the following findings:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wire communications are normally conducted through the use of facilities which form part of an intrastate network. The same facilities are used for interstate and intrastate communications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to protect effectively the privacy of wire and oral communications, to protect the integrity of court and administrative proceedings, and to prevent the obstruction of intrastate commerce, it is necessary for the Legislature to define the circumstances and conditions under which the interception of wire and oral communications may be authorized and to prohibit any unauthorized interception of such communications and the use of the contents thereof in evidence in courts and administrative proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organized criminals make extensive use of wire and oral communications in their criminal activities. The interception of such communications to obtain evidence of the commission of crimes or to prevent their commission is an indispensable aid to law enforcement and the administration of justice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To safeguard the privacy of innocent persons, the interception of wire or oral communications when none of the parties to the communication has consented to the interception should be allowed only when authorized by a court of competent jurisdiction and should remain under the control and supervision of the authorizing court. Interception of wire and oral communications should further be limited to certain major types of offenses and specific categories of crime with assurance that the interception is justified and that the information obtained thereby will not be misused.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-17.</History></Section>