<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Manufacture, distribution, or possession of wire, oral, or electronic communication intercepting devices prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, any person who intentionally:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sends through the mail or otherwise sends or carries any electronic, mechanical, or other device, knowing or having reason to know that the design of such device renders it primarily useful for the purpose of the illegal interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications as specifically defined by this chapter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufactures, assembles, possesses, or sells any electronic, mechanical, or other device, knowing or having reason to know that the design of such device renders it primarily useful for the purpose of the illegal interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications as specifically defined by this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall be guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is not unlawful under this section for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider of wire or electronic communication service or an officer, agent, or employee of, or a person under contract with, such a provider, in the normal course of the business of providing that wire or electronic communication service; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer, agent, or employee of, or a person under contract with, bidding upon contracts with, or in the course of doing business with, the United States, a state, or a political subdivision thereof, in the normal course of the activities of the United States, a state, or a political subdivision thereof,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">to send through the mail; send or carry in intrastate, interstate, or foreign commerce; or manufacture, assemble, possess, or sell any electronic, mechanical, or other device, knowing or having reason to know that the design of such device renders it primarily useful for the purpose of the surreptitious interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 69-17; s. 1164, ch. 71-136; s. 3, ch. 88-184; s. 3, ch. 89-269.</History></Section>