<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mobile tracking device authorization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investigative or law enforcement officer may make application to a judge of competent jurisdiction for an order authorizing or approving the installation and use of a mobile tracking device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application under subsection (1) of this section must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the identity of the applicant and the identity of the law enforcement agency conducting the investigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification by the applicant that the information likely to be obtained is relevant to an ongoing criminal investigation being conducted by the investigating agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the offense to which the information likely to be obtained relates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement whether it may be necessary to use and monitor the mobile tracking device outside the jurisdiction of the court from which authorization is being sought.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application made as provided under subsection (2), the court, if it finds that the certification and statements required by subsection (2) have been made in the application, shall enter an ex parte order authorizing the installation and use of a mobile tracking device. Such order may authorize the use of the device within the jurisdiction of the court and outside that jurisdiction but within the State of Florida if the device is installed within the jurisdiction of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court may not require greater specificity or additional information beyond that which is required by this section as a requisite for issuing an order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The standards established by the United States Supreme Court for the installation and monitoring of mobile tracking devices shall apply to the installation and use of any device as authorized by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, a “tracking device” means an electronic or mechanical device which permits the tracking of the movement of a person or object.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 89-269.</History></Section>