<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Civil remedies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person whose wire, oral, or electronic communication is intercepted, disclosed, or used in violation of ss. 934.03-934.09 shall have a civil cause of action against any person or entity who intercepts, discloses, or uses, or procures any other person or entity to intercept, disclose, or use, such communications and shall be entitled to recover from any such person or entity which engaged in that violation such relief as may be appropriate, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preliminary or equitable or declaratory relief as may be appropriate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actual damages, but not less than liquidated damages computed at the rate of $100 a day for each day of violation or $1,000, whichever is higher;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Punitive damages; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reasonable attorney’s fee and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A good faith reliance on:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court order, subpoena, or legislative authorization as provided in ss. 934.03-934.09,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request of an investigative or law enforcement officer under s. 934.09(7), or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A good faith determination that Florida or federal law, other than 18 U.S.C. s. 2511(2)(d), permitted the conduct complained of</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall constitute a complete defense to any civil or criminal, or administrative action arising out of such conduct under the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil action under this section may not be commenced later than 2 years after the date upon which the claimant first has a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 69-17; s. 3, ch. 78-376; s. 8, ch. 88-184; s. 8, ch. 89-269; s. 12, ch. 2000-369.</History></Section>