<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0934.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Required disclosure of customer communications or records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investigative or law enforcement officer may require the disclosure by a provider of electronic communication service of the contents of a wire or electronic communication that has been in electronic storage in an electronic communications system for 180 days or less only pursuant to a warrant issued by the judge of a court of competent jurisdiction. As used in this section, the term “a court of competent jurisdiction” means a court that has jurisdiction over the investigation or that is otherwise authorized by law. An investigative or law enforcement officer may require the disclosure by a provider of electronic communication services of the contents of a wire or electronic communication that has been in electronic storage in an electronic communications system for more than 180 days by the means available under subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investigative or law enforcement officer may require a provider of remote computing service to disclose the contents of any wire or electronic communication to which this subsection is made applicable by subsection (3):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without required notice to the subscriber or customer if the investigative or law enforcement officer obtains a warrant issued by the judge of a court of competent jurisdiction; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With prior notice, or with delayed notice pursuant to s. 934.25, from the investigative or law enforcement officer to the subscriber or customer if the investigative or law enforcement officer:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses a subpoena; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtains a court order for such disclosure under subsection (5).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (2) is applicable with respect to any electronic communication that is held or maintained on a remote computing service:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On behalf of a subscriber or customer of such service and received by means of electronic transmission from, or created by means of computer processing of communications received by means of electronic transmission from, a subscriber or customer of such service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solely for the purposes of providing storage or computer processing services to a subscriber or customer, if the provider is not authorized to access the contents of any such communication for purposes of providing any service other than storage or computer processing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investigative or law enforcement officer may require a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service to disclose a record or other information pertaining to a subscriber or customer of such service, not including the contents of a communication, only when the investigative or law enforcement officer:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtains a warrant issued by the judge of a court of competent jurisdiction;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtains a court order for such disclosure under subsection (5);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has the consent of the subscriber or customer to such disclosure; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seeks information under paragraph (b).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service shall disclose to an investigative or law enforcement officer the name; address; local and long-distance telephone connection records, or records of session times or durations; length of service, including the starting date of service; types of services used; telephone or instrument number or other subscriber number or identity, including any temporarily assigned network address; and means and source of payment, including any credit card or bank account number of a subscriber to or customer of such service when the governmental entity uses a subpoena or obtains such information in the manner specified in paragraph (a) for obtaining information under that paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investigative or law enforcement officer who receives records or information under this subsection is not required to provide notice to a subscriber or customer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court order for disclosure under subsection (2), subsection (3), or subsection (4) shall issue only if the investigative or law enforcement officer offers specific and articulable facts showing that there are reasonable grounds to believe the contents of a wire or electronic communication or the records of other information sought are relevant and material to an ongoing criminal investigation. A court issuing an order pursuant to this section, on a motion made promptly by the service provider, may quash or modify such order if the information or records requested are unusually voluminous in nature or compliance with such order otherwise would cause an undue burden on such provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No cause of action shall lie in any court against any provider of wire or electronic communication service, its officers, employees, agents, or other specified persons for providing information, facilities, or assistance in accordance with the terms of a court order, warrant, subpoena, or certification under ss. 934.21-934.28.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider of wire or electronic communication services or a remote computing service, upon the request of an investigative or law enforcement officer, shall take all necessary steps to preserve records and other evidence in its possession pending the issuance of a court order or other process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records referred to in paragraph (a) shall be retained for a period of 90 days, which shall be extended for an additional 90 days upon a renewed request by an investigative or law enforcement officer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider of electronic communication service, a remote computing service, or any other person who furnished assistance pursuant to this section shall be held harmless from any claim and civil liability resulting from the disclosure of information pursuant to this section and shall be reasonably compensated for reasonable expenses incurred in providing such assistance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 88-184; s. 10, ch. 89-269; s. 13, ch. 2000-369; s. 8, ch. 2002-72; s. 2, ch. 2003-71.</History></Section>