<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0677.502" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rights acquired by due negotiation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to ss. 677.205 and 677.503, a holder to which a negotiable document of title has been duly negotiated acquires thereby:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Title to the document;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Title to the goods;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rights accruing under the law of agency or estoppel, including rights to goods delivered to the bailee after the document was issued; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct obligation of the issuer to hold or deliver the goods according to the terms of the document free of any defense or claim by the issuer except those arising under the terms of the document or under this chapter, but in the case of a delivery order, the bailee’s obligation accrues only upon the bailee’s acceptance of the delivery order and the obligation acquired by the holder is that the issuer and any indorser will procure the acceptance of the bailee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the following section, title and rights so acquired by due negotiation are not defeated by any stoppage of the goods represented by the document of title or by surrender of the goods by the bailee and are not impaired even if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The due negotiation or any prior due negotiation constituted a breach of duty; </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person has been deprived of possession of a negotiable tangible document or control of a negotiable electronic document by misrepresentation, fraud, accident, mistake, duress, loss, theft, or conversion; or </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A previous sale or other transfer of the goods or document has been made to a third person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-254; s. 639, ch. 97-102; s. 46, ch. 2010-131.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">s. 7-502, U.C.C.; supersedes ss. 678.43, 678.49-678.51.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>