<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0677.503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Document of title to goods defeated in certain cases.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A document of title confers no right in goods against a person that before issuance of the document had a legal interest or a perfected security interest in the goods and that did not:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver or entrust the goods or any document of title covering the goods to the bailor or the bailor’s nominee with:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actual or apparent authority to ship, store, or sell;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Power to obtain delivery under s. 677.403; or </Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Power of disposition under s. 672.403, s. 680.304(2), s. 680.305(2), s. 679.320, or s. 679.321(3) or other statute or rule of law; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquiesce in the procurement by the bailor or its nominee of any document.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Title to goods based upon an unaccepted delivery order is subject to the rights of any person to which a negotiable warehouse receipt or bill of lading covering the goods has been duly negotiated. That title may be defeated under the next section to the same extent as the rights of the issuer or a transferee from the issuer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Title to goods based upon a bill of lading issued to a freight forwarder is subject to the rights of any person to which a bill issued by the freight forwarder is duly negotiated. However, delivery by the carrier in accordance with part IV of this chapter pursuant to its own bill of lading discharges the carrier’s obligation to deliver.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-254; s. 640, ch. 97-102; s. 18, ch. 2001-198; s. 47, ch. 2010-131.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">s. 7-503, U.C.C.; supersedes s. 678.43.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>