<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0677.403" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obligation of bailee to deliver; excuse.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bailee shall deliver the goods to a person entitled under a document of title if the person complies with subsections (2) and (3), unless and to the extent that the bailee establishes any of the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delivery of the goods to a person whose receipt was rightful as against the claimant;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damage to or delay, loss or destruction of the goods for which the bailee is not liable, but the burden of establishing negligence in such cases when value of such damage, delay, loss, or destruction exceeds $10,000 is on the person entitled under the document;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Previous sale or other disposition of the goods in lawful enforcement of a lien or on a warehouse’s lawful termination of storage;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exercise by a seller of its right to stop delivery pursuant to s. 672.705 or by a lessor of its right to stop delivery pursuant to s. 680.526;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A diversion, reconsignment, or other disposition pursuant to s. 677.303;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Release, satisfaction, or any other personal defense against the claimant; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other lawful excuse.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person claiming goods covered by a document of title shall satisfy the bailee’s lien if the bailee so requests or if the bailee is prohibited by law from delivering the goods until the charges are paid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless a person claiming the goods is a person against which the document of title does not confer a right under s. 677.503(1):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person claiming under a document shall surrender possession or control of any outstanding negotiable document covering the goods for cancellation or indication of partial deliveries; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> The bailee shall cancel the document or conspicuously indicate in the document the partial delivery or the bailee is liable to any person to which the document is duly negotiated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-254; s. 1, ch. 71-292; s. 636, ch. 97-102; s. 43, ch. 2010-131.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">s. 7-403, U.C.C.; supersedes ss. 678.08-678.12, 678.16, 678.19.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>