<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0760.35" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Civil actions and relief; administrative procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil action shall be commenced no later than 2 years after an alleged discriminatory housing practice has occurred. However, the court shall continue a civil case brought pursuant to this section or s. 760.34 from time to time before bringing it to trial if the court believes that the conciliation efforts of the commission or local agency are likely to result in satisfactory settlement of the discriminatory housing practice complained of in the complaint made to the commission or to the local agency and which practice forms the basis for the action in court. Any sale, encumbrance, or rental consummated prior to the issuance of any court order issued under the authority of ss. 760.20-760.37 and involving a bona fide purchaser, encumbrancer, or tenant without actual notice of the existence of the filing of a complaint or civil action under the provisions of ss. 760.20-760.37 shall not be affected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that a discriminatory housing practice has occurred, it shall issue an order prohibiting the practice and providing affirmative relief from the effects of the practice, including injunctive and other equitable relief, actual and punitive damages, and reasonable attorney’s fees and costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the commission is unable to obtain voluntary compliance with ss. 760.20-760.37 or has reasonable cause to believe that a discriminatory practice has occurred:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may institute an administrative proceeding under chapter 120; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person aggrieved may request administrative relief under chapter 120 within 30 days after receiving notice that the commission has concluded its investigation under s. 760.34.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrative hearings shall be conducted pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57(1). The respondent must be served written notice by certified mail. If the administrative law judge finds that a discriminatory housing practice has occurred or is about to occur, he or she shall issue a recommended order to the commission prohibiting the practice and recommending affirmative relief from the effects of the practice, including quantifiable damages and reasonable attorney’s fees and costs. The commission may adopt, reject, or modify a recommended order only as provided under s. 120.57(1). Judgment for the amount of damages and costs assessed pursuant to a final order by the commission may be entered in any court having jurisdiction thereof and may be enforced as any other judgment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district courts of appeal may, upon the filing of appropriate notices of appeal, review final orders of the commission pursuant to s. 120.68. Costs or fees may not be assessed against the commission in any appeal from a final order issued by the commission under this subsection. Unless specifically ordered by the court, the commencement of an appeal does not suspend or stay an order of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not prevent any other legal or administrative action provided by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-221; s. 8, ch. 89-321; s. 303, ch. 96-410; s. 1794, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>