<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0760.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigations; subpoenas; oaths.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting an investigation, the commission shall have access at all reasonable times to premises, records, documents, individuals, and other evidence or possible sources of evidence and may examine, record, and copy such materials and take and record the testimony or statements of such persons as are reasonably necessary for the furtherance of the investigation, provided the commission first complies with the provisions of the State Constitution relating to unreasonable searches and seizures. The commission may issue subpoenas to compel its access to or the production of such materials or the appearance of such persons, and may issue interrogatories to a respondent, to the same extent and subject to the same limitations as would apply if the subpoenas or interrogatories were issued or served in aid of a civil action in court. The commission may administer oaths.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon written application to the commission, a respondent shall be entitled to the issuance of a reasonable number of subpoenas by and in the name of the commission to the same extent and subject to the same limitations as subpoenas issued by the commission itself. A subpoena issued at the request of a respondent shall show on its face the name and address of such respondent and shall state that it was issued at her or his request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 5 days after service of a subpoena upon any person, such person may petition the commission to revoke or modify the subpoena. The commission shall grant the petition if it finds that the subpoena requires appearance or attendance at an unreasonable time or place, that it requires production of evidence which does not relate to any matter under investigation, that it does not describe with sufficient particularity the evidence to be produced, or that compliance would be unduly onerous or for other good reason.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of refusal to obey a subpoena, the commission or the person at whose request the subpoena was issued may petition for its enforcement in the circuit court for the county in which the person to whom the subpoena was addressed resides, was served, or transacts business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Witnesses summoned by subpoena of the commission shall be entitled to the same witness and mileage fees as are witnesses in proceedings in court. Fees payable to a witness summoned by a subpoena issued at the request of a respondent shall be paid by the respondent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 83-221; s. 1141, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>