<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0760.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of the commission.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within the limitations provided by law, the commission shall have the following powers:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To maintain offices in the State of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To meet and exercise its powers at any place within the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote the creation of, and to provide continuing technical assistance to, local commissions on human relations and to cooperate with individuals and state, local, and other agencies, both public and private, including agencies of the Federal Government and of other states.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To accept gifts, bequests, grants, or other payments, public or private, to help finance its activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive, initiate, investigate, seek to conciliate, hold hearings on, and act upon complaints alleging any discriminatory practice, as defined by the Florida Civil Rights Act of 1992.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To issue subpoenas for, administer oaths or affirmations to and compel the attendance and testimony of witnesses or to issue subpoenas for and compel the production of books, papers, records, documents, and other evidence pertaining to any investigation or hearing convened pursuant to the powers of the commission. In conducting an investigation, the commission and its investigators shall have access at all reasonable times to premises, records, documents, and other evidence or possible sources of evidence and may examine, record, and copy such materials and take and record the testimony or statements of such persons as are reasonably necessary for the furtherance of the investigation. The authority to issue subpoenas and administer oaths may be delegated by the commission, for investigations or hearings, to a commissioner or the executive director. In the case of a refusal to obey a subpoena issued to any person, the commission may make application to any circuit court of this state, which shall have jurisdiction to order the witness to appear before the commission to give testimony and to produce evidence concerning the matter in question. Failure to obey the court’s order may be punished by the court as contempt. If the court enters an order holding a person in contempt or compelling the person to comply with the commission’s order or subpoena, the court shall order the person to pay the commission reasonable expenses, including reasonable attorneys’ fees, accrued by the commission in obtaining the order from the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To recommend methods for elimination of discrimination and intergroup tensions and to use its best efforts to secure compliance with its recommendations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To furnish technical assistance requested by persons to facilitate progress in human relations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make or arrange for studies appropriate to effectuate the purposes and policies of the Florida Civil Rights Act of 1992 and to make the results thereof available to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To become a deferral agency for the Federal Government and to comply with the necessary federal regulations to effect the Florida Civil Rights Act of 1992.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To render, at least annually, a comprehensive written report to the Governor and the Legislature. The report may contain recommendations of the commission for legislation or other action to effectuate the purposes and policies of the Florida Civil Rights Act of 1992.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt, promulgate, amend, and rescind rules to effectuate the purposes and policies of the Florida Civil Rights Act of 1992 and govern the proceedings of the commission, in accordance with chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive complaints and coordinate all activities as required by the Whistle-blower’s Act pursuant to ss. 112.3187-112.31895.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 69-287; s. 3, ch. 72-48; s. 1, ch. 75-232; s. 5, ch. 77-341; s. 5, ch. 92-177; s. 4, ch. 92-282; s. 26, ch. 99-333.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 13.251, 23.166.</Text></Note></Section>