<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0760.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discriminatory practices of certain clubs prohibited; remedies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for a person to discriminate against any individual because of race, color, religion, gender, national origin, handicap, age above the age of 21, or marital status in evaluating an application for membership in a club that has more than 400 members, that provides regular meal service, and that regularly receives payment for dues, fees, use of space, facilities, services, meals, or beverages directly or indirectly from nonmembers for business purposes. It is unlawful for a person, on behalf of such a club, to publish, circulate, issue, display, post, or mail any advertisement, notice, or solicitation that contains a statement to the effect that the accommodations, advantages, facilities, membership, or privileges of the club are denied to any individual because of race, color, religion, gender, national origin, handicap, age above the age of 21, or marital status. This subsection does not apply to fraternal or benevolent organizations, ethnic clubs, or religious organizations where business activity is not prevalent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has been discriminated against in violation of this act may file a complaint with the Commission on Human Relations or with the Attorney General’s Office of Civil Rights. A complaint must be in writing and must contain such information and be in such form as the commission requires. Upon receipt of a complaint, the commission or the Attorney General shall provide a copy to the person who represents the club. Within 30 days after receiving a complaint, the commission or the Attorney General shall investigate the alleged discrimination and give notice in writing to the person who filed the complaint if it intends to resolve the complaint. If the commission or the Attorney General decides to resolve the complaint, it shall attempt to eliminate or correct the alleged discriminatory practices of a club by informal methods of conference, conciliation, and persuasion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the commission or the Attorney General fails, within 30 days after receiving a complaint filed pursuant to subsection (2), to give notice of its intent to eliminate or correct the alleged discriminatory practices of a club, or if the commission or the Attorney General fails to resolve the complaint within 30 days after giving such notice, the person or the Attorney General on behalf of the person filing the complaint may commence a civil action in a court against the club, its officers, or its members to enforce this section. If the court finds that a discriminatory practice occurs at the club, the court may enjoin the club, its officers, or its members from engaging in such practice or may order other appropriate action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 92-177.</History></Section>