<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0760.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discrimination in the financing of housing or in residential real estate transactions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any bank, building and loan association, insurance company, or other corporation, association, firm, or enterprise the business of which consists in whole or in part of the making of commercial real estate loans to deny a loan or other financial assistance to a person applying for the loan for the purpose of purchasing, constructing, improving, repairing, or maintaining a dwelling, or to discriminate against him or her in the fixing of the amount, interest rate, duration, or other term or condition of such loan or other financial assistance, because of the race, color, national origin, sex, handicap, familial status, or religion of such person or of any person associated with him or her in connection with such loan or other financial assistance or the purposes of such loan or other financial assistance, or because of the race, color, national origin, sex, handicap, familial status, or religion of the present or prospective owners, lessees, tenants, or occupants of the dwelling or dwellings in relation to which such loan or other financial assistance is to be made or given.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person or entity whose business includes engaging in residential real estate transactions to discriminate against any person in making available such a transaction, or in the terms or conditions of such a transaction, because of race, color, national origin, sex, handicap, familial status, or religion.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “residential real estate transaction” means any of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The making or purchasing of loans or providing other financial assistance:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purchasing, constructing, improving, repairing, or maintaining a dwelling; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secured by residential real estate.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selling, brokering, or appraising of residential real property.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 83-221; s. 4, ch. 84-117; s. 4, ch. 89-321; s. 17, ch. 90-275; s. 1140, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>