<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0760.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discrimination on the basis of AIDS, AIDS-related complex, and HIV prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that persons infected or believed to be infected with human immunodeficiency virus have suffered and will continue to suffer irrational and scientifically unfounded discrimination. The Legislature further finds and declares that society itself is harmed by this discrimination, as otherwise able-bodied persons are deprived of the means of supporting themselves, providing for their own health care, housing themselves, and participating in the opportunities otherwise available to them in society. The Legislature further finds and declares that remedies are needed to correct these problems.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person with or perceived as having acquired immune deficiency syndrome, acquired immune deficiency syndrome related complex, or human immunodeficiency virus shall have every protection made available to handicapped persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may require an individual to take a human immunodeficiency virus-related test as a condition of hiring, promotion, or continued employment unless the absence of human immunodeficiency virus infection is a bona fide occupational qualification for the job in question.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may fail or refuse to hire or discharge any individual, segregate or classify any individual in any way which would deprive or tend to deprive that individual of employment opportunities or adversely affect his or her status as an employee, or otherwise discriminate against any individual with respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment on the basis of knowledge or belief that the individual has taken a human immunodeficiency virus test or the results or perceived results of such test unless the absence of human immunodeficiency virus infection is a bona fide occupational qualification of the job in question.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who asserts that a bona fide occupational qualification exists for human immunodeficiency virus-related testing shall have the burden of proving that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The human immunodeficiency virus-related test is necessary to ascertain whether an employee is currently able to perform in a reasonable manner the duties of the particular job or whether an employee will present a significant risk of transmitting human immunodeficiency virus infection to other persons in the course of normal work activities; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There exists no means of reasonable accommodation short of requiring that the individual be free of human immunodeficiency virus infection.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not discriminate against an otherwise qualified individual in housing, public accommodations, or governmental services on the basis of the fact that such individual is, or is regarded as being, infected with human immunodeficiency virus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or other entity receiving or benefiting from state financial assistance may not discriminate against an otherwise qualified individual on the basis of the fact that such individual is, or is regarded as being, infected with human immunodeficiency virus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who asserts that an individual who is infected with human immunodeficiency virus is not otherwise qualified shall have the burden of proving that no reasonable accommodation can be made to prevent the likelihood that the individual will, under the circumstances involved, expose other individuals to a significant possibility of being infected with human immunodeficiency virus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not fail or refuse to hire or discharge any individual, segregate or classify any individual in any way which would deprive or tend to deprive that individual of employment opportunities or adversely affect his or her status as an employee, or otherwise discriminate against any individual with respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment on the basis of the fact that the individual is a licensed health care professional or health care worker who treats or provides patient care to persons infected with human immunodeficiency virus.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every employer who provides or administers health insurance benefits or life insurance benefits to its employees shall maintain the confidentiality of information relating to the medical condition or status of any person covered by such insurance benefits. Such information in the possession of a public employer is exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. An employer shall be liable in damages to any person damaged by its failure to implement such a procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person aggrieved by a violation of this section shall have a right of action in the circuit court and may recover for each violation:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Against any person who violates a provision of this section, liquidated damages of $1,000 or actual damages, whichever is greater.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Against any person who intentionally or recklessly violates a provision of this section, liquidated damages of $5,000 or actual damages, whichever is greater.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable attorney’s fees.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other relief, including an injunction, as the court may deem appropriate.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section limits the right of the person aggrieved by a violation of this section to recover damages or other relief under any other applicable law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 45, ch. 88-380; s. 14, ch. 89-350; s. 6, ch. 94-90; s. 421, ch. 96-406; s. 1796, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>