<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.0625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Environmental laboratory certification; water quality tests conducted by a certified laboratory.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assure the acceptable quality, reliability, and validity of testing results, the department and the Department of Health shall jointly establish criteria for certification of laboratories that perform analyses of environmental samples that are not covered by the provisions in s. 403.863. The Department of Health shall have the responsibility for the operation and implementation of such laboratory certification. The Department of Health may charge and collect fees for the certification of such laboratories. The fee schedule shall be based on the number of analytical functions for which certification is sought. Such fees shall be sufficient to meet the costs incurred by the Department of Health in administering this program in coordination with the department. All fees collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited in a trust fund to be administered by the Department of Health and shall be used only for the purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An environmental water quality test to determine the quality of the effluent of a domestic wastewater facility must be conducted by a laboratory certified under this section if such test results are to be submitted to the department or a local pollution control program pursuant to s. 403.182.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health may adopt and enforce rules to administer this section, including, but not limited to, definitions of terms, certified laboratory personnel requirements, sample collection methodology and proficiency testing, the format and frequency of reports, onsite inspections of laboratories, and quality assurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the disciplinary actions specified in subsection (5) may be taken:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making false statements on an application or on any document associated with certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making consistent errors in analyses or erroneous reporting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permitting personnel who are not qualified, as required by rules of the Department of Health, to perform analyses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Falsifying the results of analyses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to employ approved laboratory methods in performing analyses as outlined in rules of the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to properly maintain facilities and equipment according to the laboratory’s quality assurance plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report analytical test results or maintain required records of test results as outlined in rules of the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to participate successfully in a performance evaluation program approved by the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this section or of the rules adopted under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Falsely advertising services or credentials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to pay fees for initial certification or renewal certification or to pay inspection expenses incurred by the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report any change of an item included in the initial or renewal certification application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusing to allow representatives of the department or the Department of Health to inspect a laboratory and its records during normal business hours.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the Department of Health finds any applicant or certificateholder guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (4), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of an application for certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each count or separate offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the certification on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the Department of Health specifies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restricting the authorized scope of the certification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certification program shall be governed by chapter 120.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 85-269; s. 3, ch. 88-89; s. 358, ch. 94-356; s. 22, ch. 98-151.</History></Section>