<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.852" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; ss. 403.850-403.864.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 403.850-403.864:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection, which is charged with the primary responsibility for the administration and implementation of the Florida Safe Drinking Water Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public water system” means a system for the provision to the public of water for human consumption through pipes or other constructed conveyances if such system has at least 15 service connections or regularly serves at least 25 individuals daily at least 60 days out of the year. A public water system is either a community water system or a noncommunity water system. The term “public water system” includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any collection, treatment, storage, and distribution facility or facilities under control of the operator of such system and used primarily in connection with such system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any collection or pretreatment storage facility or facilities not under control of the operator of such system but used primarily in connection with such system.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community water system” means a public water system which serves at least 15 service connections used by year-round residents or regularly serves at least 25 year-round residents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Noncommunity water system” means a public water system that is not a community water system. A noncommunity water system is either a nontransient noncommunity water system or a transient noncommunity water system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual, public or private corporation, company, association, partnership, municipality, agency of the state, district, federal agency, or any other legal entity, or its legal representative, agent, or assigns.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Municipality” means a city, town, or other public body created by or pursuant to state law or an Indian tribal organization authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Federal agency” means any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supplier of water” means any person who owns or operates a public water system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contaminant” means any physical, chemical, biological, or radiological substance or matter in water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrator” means the administrator of the United States Environmental Protection Agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Federal act” means the Safe Drinking Water Act, Pub. L. No. 93-523.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Primary drinking water regulation” means a rule which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applies to public water systems;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifies contaminants which, in the judgment of the department, after consultation with the Department of Health, may have an adverse effect on the health of the public;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifies for each such contaminant either:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum contaminant level if, in the judgment of the department, it is economically and technologically feasible to ascertain the level of such contaminant in water in public water systems; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each treatment technique known to the department which leads to a reduction in the level of the contaminant sufficient to satisfy the requirements of s. 403.853 if, in the judgment of the department, it is not economically or technologically feasible to ascertain the level of such contaminant; and</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains criteria and procedures to assure a supply of drinking water which dependably complies with such maximum contaminant levels, including quality control and testing procedures to assure compliance with such levels and to ensure proper operation and maintenance of the system, and which contains requirements as to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum quality of water which may be taken into the system; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Siting for new facilities for public water systems.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secondary drinking water regulation” means a rule which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applies to public water systems; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifies the maximum contaminant levels which, in the judgment of the department after public hearings, are requisite to protect the public welfare. Such regulation may apply to any contaminant in drinking water:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which may adversely affect the odor or appearance of such water and consequently may cause a substantial number of the persons served by the public water system providing such water to discontinue its use; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Which may otherwise adversely affect the public welfare.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such regulations may vary according to geographic and other circumstances.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“National primary drinking water regulations” means primary drinking water regulations promulgated by the administrator pursuant to the federal act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“National secondary drinking water regulations” means secondary drinking water regulations promulgated by the administrator pursuant to the federal act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sanitary survey” means an onsite review of the water source, facilities, equipment, operation, and maintenance of a public water system for the purpose of evaluating the adequacy of such source, facilities, equipment, operation, and maintenance for producing and distributing safe drinking water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nontransient noncommunity water system” means a noncommunity water system that regularly serves at least 25 of the same persons over 6 months per year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transient noncommunity water system” means a noncommunity water system that has at least 15 service connections or regularly serves at least 25 persons daily at least 60 days out of the year but that does not regularly serve 25 or more of the same persons for more than 6 months per year.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 77-337; s. 1, ch. 82-80; s. 10, ch. 89-324; s. 38, ch. 91-305; s. 426, ch. 94-356; s. 165, ch. 99-8; s. 1, ch. 2001-270.</History></Section>