<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.9409" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of sufficiency.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 45 days after the distribution of the complete application or amendment, the department shall file a statement with the Division of Administrative Hearings and with the applicant declaring its position with regard to the sufficiency of the application or amendment. The department’s statement shall be based upon consultation with the affected agencies, which shall submit to the department recommendations on the sufficiency of the application within 30 days after distribution of the complete application.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department declares the application or amendment insufficient, the applicant may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withdraw the application or amendment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File additional information necessary to make the application or amendment sufficient; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contest the notice of insufficiency by filing a request for hearing with the administrative law judge within 15 days after the filing of the statement of insufficiency. If a hearing is requested by the applicant, all time schedules under ss. 403.9401-403.9425 shall be tolled as of the date of the department’s statement of insufficiency, pending the administrative law judge’s decision concerning the dispute. A hearing shall be held no later than 30 days after the filing of the statement by the department, and a decision shall be rendered within 10 days after the hearing, unless otherwise agreed by the department and the applicant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge determines, contrary to the department, that an application or amendment is sufficient, all time schedules under ss. 403.9401-403.9425 shall resume as of the date of the administrative law judge’s determination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge agrees that the application is insufficient, all time schedules under ss. 403.9401-403.9425 shall remain tolled until the applicant files additional information and the application or amendment is determined sufficient by the department or the administrative law judge.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, within 30 days after receipt of the additional information submitted pursuant to paragraph (1)(b), or paragraph (2)(b), based upon the recommendations of the affected agencies, the department determines that the additional information supplied by an applicant does not render the application or amendment sufficient, the applicant may exercise any of the options specified in subsection (1) as often as may be necessary to resolve the matter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-284; s. 174, ch. 96-410.</History></Section>