<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.7238" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Expanded local hazardous waste management programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes the need for increased participation by local governments in ensuring that small quantity generators are properly managing their hazardous waste and that waste reduction opportunities are promoted and realized. In order to promote this participation, the department shall establish a grant program on a competitive basis for counties that meet the following criteria:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county has established a funding mechanism to support its local hazardous waste management assessments and the expanded local hazardous waste management program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county has adopted a local ordinance approved by the department that addresses the compliance with and enforcement of the federal and state hazardous waste regulations for small quantity generators.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county has established a plan that is designed to reduce the generation of hazardous waste and hazardous emissions from local governmental agencies and departments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county certifies that it will continue to implement its expanded local hazardous waste management assessment program after the grant assistance ceases.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grants are authorized to cover startup costs incurred to establish the expanded local hazardous waste management program, including training for personnel, and materials and equipment necessary for education, compliance activities, and program administration. The total costs of administration shall not exceed 10 percent of the county’s grant award.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum amount of a grant for a county establishing an expanded local hazardous waste management program shall be $50,000.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 93-207; s. 3, ch. 97-98.</History></Section>