<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0403.7145" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recycling.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Capitol and the House and Senate office buildings constitute the Capitol recycling area. The Florida House of Representatives, the Florida Senate, and the Office of the Governor, the Secretary of State, and each Cabinet officer who heads a department that occupies office space in the Capitol, shall institute a recycling program for their respective offices in the House and Senate office buildings and the Capitol. Provisions shall be made to collect and sell wastepaper and empty beverage containers generated by employee activities in these offices. The collection and sale of such materials shall be reported to Leon County using the department’s designated reporting format and coordinated with Department of Management Services recycling activities to maximize the efficiency and economy of this program. The Governor, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, the Secretary of State, and the Cabinet officers may authorize the use of proceeds from recyclable material sales for employee benefits and other purposes, in order to provide incentives to their respective employees for participation in the recycling program. Such proceeds may also be used to offset any costs of the recycling program. As a demonstration of leading by example, the Capitol Building’s recycling rates shall be posted on the website of the Department of Management Services and shall include the details of the recycling rates for each Department of Management Services pool facility. The Department of Environmental Protection shall post recycling rates of each state-owned facility reported to the Department of Management Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state agency, the judicial branch of state government, and the State University System shall collect and sell, to the greatest extent practicable, recyclable materials and products used during the operation of facilities and offices and may use the proceeds of the sale of such materials and products for employee benefits and other purposes and thereby provide incentives for employees to participate in the recycling program. Such proceeds may also be used to offset any recycling program costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop and contract for an innovative recycling pilot project for the Capitol recycling area. The project shall be designed to collect recyclable materials and create a more sustainable recycling system. Components of the project shall be designed to increase convenience, incentivize and measure participation, reduce material volume, and assist in achieving the recycling goals enumerated in s. 403.706.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 88-130; s. 307, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 74, ch. 93-207; s. 37, ch. 2000-258; s. 12, ch. 2010-143.</History>
</Section>