<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.767" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification of used oil transporters.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who transports over public highways more than 500 gallons annually of used oil must be a certified transporter. This subsection does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local governments or private solid waste haulers under contract to a local government that transport used oil collected from households to a public used oil collection center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who transport less than 55 gallons of used oil at one time that is stored in tightly closed containers which are secured in a totally enclosed section of the transport vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who transport their own used oil, which is generated at their own noncontiguous facilities, to their own central collection facility for storage, processing, or energy recovery. However, such persons shall provide the same proof of liability insurance or other means of financial responsibility for liability which may be incurred in the transport of used oil as provided by certified transporters under subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a certification program for transporters of used oil and shall issue, deny, or revoke certifications authorizing the holder to transport used oil. Certification requirements shall help assure that a used oil transporter is familiar with appropriate rules and used oil management procedures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules governing certification, which shall include requirements for the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration and annual reporting pursuant to s. 403.754.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of familiarity with applicable state laws and rules governing used oil transportation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of liability insurance or other means of financial responsibility for any liability which may be incurred in the transport of used oil.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 88-130; s. 17, ch. 97-277; s. 30, ch. 2000-211.</History></Section>