<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0403.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Clean Fuel Act.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE AND PURPOSE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Florida Clean Fuel Act.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes of this act are to establish the Clean Fuel Florida Advisory Board under the Department of Environmental Protection to study the implementation of alternative fuel vehicles and to formulate and provide to the Secretary of Environmental Protection recommendations on expanding the use of alternative fuel vehicles in this state and make funding available for implementation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />For purposes of this act:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alternative fuels” include electricity, biodiesel, natural gas, propane, and any other fuel that may be deemed appropriate in the future by the Department of Environmental Protection with guidance from the Clean Fuel Florida Advisory Board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alternative fuel vehicles” include on-road and off-road transportation vehicles and light-duty, medium-duty, and heavy-duty vehicles that are powered by an alternative fuel or a combination of alternative fuels.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CLEAN FUEL FLORIDA ADVISORY BOARD ESTABLISHED; MEMBERSHIP; DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Clean Fuel Florida Advisory Board is established within the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory board shall consist of the Executive Director of the Department of Economic Opportunity, the Secretary of Environmental Protection, or a designee from that department, the Commissioner of Education, or a designee from that department, the Secretary of Transportation, or a designee from that department, the Commissioner of Agriculture, or a designee from that department, the Secretary of Management Services, or a designee from that department, and a representative of each of the following, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Environmental Protection:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida biodiesel industry.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida electric utility industry.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida natural gas industry.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida propane gas industry.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An automobile manufacturers’ association.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida Clean Cities Coalition designated by the United States Department of Energy.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enterprise Florida, Inc.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EV Ready Broward.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida petroleum industry.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="j">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida League of Cities.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="k">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Association of Counties.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="l">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Floridians for Better Transportation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="m">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor vehicle manufacturer.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="n">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Local Environment Resource Agencies.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="o">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Project for an Energy Efficient Florida.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="p">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Transportation Builders Association.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the advisory board is to serve as a resource for the department and to provide the Governor, the Legislature, and the Secretary of Environmental Protection with private sector and other public agency perspectives on achieving the goal of increasing the use of alternative fuel vehicles in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members shall be appointed to serve terms of 1 year each, with reappointment at the discretion of the Secretary of Environmental Protection. Vacancies shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall annually select a chairperson.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall meet at least once each quarter or more often at the call of the chairperson or the Secretary of Environmental Protection.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meetings are exempt from the notice requirements of chapter 120, and sufficient notice shall be given to afford interested persons reasonable notice under the circumstances.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the board are entitled to travel expenses while engaged in the performance of board duties.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall terminate 5 years after the effective date of this act.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall review the performance of the state with reference to alternative fuel vehicle implementation in complying with federal laws and maximizing available federal funding and may:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the Governor, Legislature, and the Secretary of Environmental Protection and make recommendations regarding implementation and use of alternative fuel vehicles in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify potential improvements in this act and the state’s alternative fuel policies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request from all state agencies any information the board determines relevant to board duties.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regularly report to the Secretary of Environmental Protection, the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives regarding the board’s findings and recommendations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory board shall make recommendations to the Department of Environmental Protection for establishing pilot programs in this state that provide experience and support the best use expansion of the alternative fuel vehicle industry in this state. No funds shall be released for a project unless there is at least a 50-percent private or local match.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the pilot programs, the advisory board shall assess federal, state, and local initiatives to identify incentives that encourage successful alternative fuel vehicle programs; obstacles to alternative fuel vehicle use including legislative, regulatory, and economic obstacles; and programs that educate and inform the public about alternative fuel vehicles.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory board is charged with determining a reasonable, fair, and equitable way to address current motor fuel taxes as they apply to alternative fuels and at what threshold of market penetration.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on its findings, the advisory board shall develop recommendations to the Legislature on future alternative fuel vehicle programs and legislative changes that provide the best use of state and other resources to enhance the alternative fuel vehicle market in this state and maximize the return on that investment in terms of job creation, economic development, and emissions reduction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory board, working with the Department of Environmental Protection, shall develop a budget for the department’s approval, and all expenditures shall be approved by the department. At the conclusion of the first year, the department shall conduct an audit of the board and board programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 72, ch. 99-248; s. 28, ch. 2000-153; s. 17, ch. 2004-243; s. 286, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>