<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.763" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grants to local governments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a grants program for local governments to encourage the collection, reuse, and proper disposal of used oil. No grant may be made for any project unless such project is approved by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall consider for grant assistance any local government project that uses one or more of the following programs or any activity that the department feels will reduce the improper disposal and reuse of used oil:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Curbside pickup of used oil containers by a local government or its designee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retrofitting of solid waste equipment to promote curbside pickup or disposal of used oil at used oil collection centers designated by the local government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of publicly operated used oil collection centers at landfills or other public places.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing containers and other materials and supplies that the public can utilize in an environmentally sound manner to store used oil for pickup or return to a used oil collection center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing incentives for the establishment of privately operated public used oil collection centers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligible projects shall be funded according to provisions established by the department. However, in no case shall one grant exceed $25,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall initiate rules on or before January 1, 1989, necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 88-130.</History></Section>