<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.722" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permits; hazardous waste disposal, storage, and treatment facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who intends to or is required to construct, modify, operate, or close a hazardous waste disposal, storage, or treatment facility shall obtain a construction permit, operation permit, postclosure permit, clean closure plan approval, or corrective action permit from the department prior to constructing, modifying, operating, or closing the facility. By rule, the department may provide for the issuance of a single permit instead of any two or more hazardous waste facility permits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any owner or operator of a hazardous waste facility in operation on the effective date of the department rule listing and identifying hazardous wastes shall file an application for a temporary operation permit within 6 months after the effective date of such rule. The department, upon receipt of a properly completed application, shall identify any department rules that are being violated by the facility and establish a compliance schedule. However, if the department determines that an imminent hazard exists, the department may take any necessary action pursuant to s. 403.726 to abate the hazard. The department shall issue a temporary operation permit to such facility within the time constraints of s. 120.60 upon submission of a properly completed application that is in conformance with this subsection. Temporary operation permits for such facilities shall be issued for up to 3 years only. Upon termination of the temporary operation permit and upon proper application by the facility owner or operator, the department shall issue an operation permit for such existing facilities if the applicant has corrected all of the deficiencies identified in the temporary operation permit and is in compliance with all other rules adopted pursuant to this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicants shall provide any information that will enable the department to determine that the proposed construction, modification, operation, closure, or corrective action will comply with this act and any applicable rules. In no instance shall any person construct, modify, operate, or close a facility or perform corrective actions at a facility in contravention of the standards, requirements, or criteria for a hazardous waste facility. Authorizations issued under this section may include any permit conditions necessary to achieve compliance with applicable hazardous waste rules and necessary to protect human health and the environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require, in an application, submission of information concerning matters specified in s. 403.721(6) as well as information respecting:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Estimates of the composition, quantity, and concentration of any hazardous waste identified or listed under this act or combinations of any such waste and any other solid waste, proposed to be disposed of, treated, transported, or stored and the time, frequency, or rate at which such waste is proposed to be disposed of, treated, transported, or stored; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The site to which such hazardous waste or the products of treatment of such hazardous waste will be transported and at which it will be disposed of, treated, or stored.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authorization issued pursuant to this section is not a vested right. The department may revoke or modify any such authorization.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizations may be revoked for failure of the holder to comply with this act, the terms of the authorization, the standards, requirements, or criteria adopted pursuant to this act, or an order of the department; for refusal by the holder to allow lawful inspection; for submission by the holder of false or inaccurate information in the permit application; or if necessary to protect the public health or the environment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizations may be modified, upon request of the holder, if such modification is not in violation of this act or department rules or if the department finds the modification necessary to enable the facility to remain in compliance with this act and department rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner or operator of a hazardous waste facility in existence on the effective date of a department rule changing an exemption or listing and identifying the hazardous wastes that require that facility to be permitted who notifies the department pursuant to s. 403.72, and who has applied for a permit pursuant to subsection (2), may continue to operate until issued a temporary operation permit. If such owner or operator intends to or is required to discontinue operation, the temporary operation permit must include final closure conditions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hazardous waste facility permit issued pursuant to this section shall satisfy the permit requirements of s. 403.707(1). The permit exemptions provided in s. 403.707(2) do not apply to hazardous waste.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish application procedures for hazardous waste facilities, which procedures may vary based on differences in amounts, types, and concentrations of hazardous waste and on differences in the size and location of facilities and which procedures may take into account permitting procedures of other laws not in conflict with this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For authorizations required by this section, the department may require that a fee be paid and may establish, by rule, a fee schedule based on the degree of hazard and the amount and type of hazardous waste disposed of, stored, or treated at the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall not be a requirement for the issuance of a hazardous waste authorization that the facility complies with an adopted local government comprehensive plan, local land use ordinances, zoning ordinances or regulations, or other local ordinances. However, the issuance of such an authorization by the department does not override any local plan, ordinance, or regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 120.60(1) and 403.815:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time specified by law for permit review shall be tolled by the request of the department for publication of notice of proposed agency action to issue a permit for a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility and shall resume 45 days after receipt by the department of proof of publication. If, within 45 days after publication of the notice of the proposed agency action, the department receives written notice of opposition to the intention of the agency to issue such permit and receives a request for a hearing, the department shall provide for a hearing pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57, if requested by a substantially affected party, or an informal public meeting, if requested by any other person. The failure to request a hearing within 45 days after publication of the notice of the proposed agency action constitutes a waiver of the right to a hearing under ss. 120.569 and 120.57. The permit review time period shall continue to be tolled until the completion of such hearing or meeting and shall resume within 15 days after conclusion of a public hearing held on the application or within 45 days after the recommended order is submitted to the agency and the parties, whichever is later.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 60 days after receipt of an application for a hazardous waste facility permit, the department shall examine the application, notify the applicant of any apparent errors or omissions, and request any additional information the department is permitted by law to require. The failure to correct an error or omission or to supply additional information shall not be grounds for denial of the permit unless the department timely notified the applicant within the 60-day period, except that this paragraph does not prevent the department from denying an application if the department does not possess sufficient information to ensure that the facility is in compliance with applicable statutes and rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall approve or deny each hazardous waste facility permit within 135 days after receipt of the original application or after receipt of the requested additional information or correction of errors or omissions. However, the failure of the department to approve or deny within the 135-day time period does not result in the automatic approval or denial of the permit and does not prevent the inclusion of specific permit conditions which are necessary to ensure compliance with applicable statutes and rules. If the department fails to approve or deny the permit within the 135-day period, the applicant may petition for a writ of mandamus to compel the department to act consistently with applicable regulatory requirements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hazardous waste facility operation permits shall be issued for no more than 5 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the same day of filing with the department of an application for a permit for the construction modification, or operation of a hazardous waste facility, the applicant shall notify each city and county within 1 mile of the facility of the filing of the application and shall publish notice of the filing of the application. The applicant shall publish a second notice of the filing within 14 days after the date of filing. Each notice shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the county in which the facility is located or is proposed to be located. Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 50, for purposes of this section, a “newspaper of general circulation” shall be the newspaper within the county in which the installation or facility is proposed which has the largest daily circulation in that county and has its principal office in that county. If the newspaper with the largest daily circulation has its principal office outside the county, the notice shall appear in both the newspaper with the largest daily circulation in that county, and a newspaper authorized to publish legal notices in that county. The notice shall contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the applicant and a brief description of the project and its location.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of the application file and when it is available for public inspection.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The notice shall be prepared by the applicant and shall comply with the following format:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">Notice of Application</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">The Department of Environmental Protection announces receipt of an application for a permit from <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of applicant)</Directions> to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(brief description of project)</Directions>. This proposed project will be located at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(location)</Directions> in <Directions xml:space="preserve">(county)</Directions> <Directions xml:space="preserve">(city)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">This application is being processed and is available for public inspection during normal business hours, 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m., Monday through Friday, except legal holidays, at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name and address of office)</Directions>.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A permit for the construction, modification, or operation of a hazardous waste facility which initially was issued under authority of this section, may not be transferred by the permittee to any other entity, except in conformity with the requirements of this subsection.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 30 days prior to the sale or legal transfer of a permitted facility, the permittee shall file with the department an application for transfer of the permits on such form as the department shall establish by rule. The form must be completed with the notarized signatures of both the transferring permittee and the proposed permittee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall approve the transfer of a permit unless it determines that the proposed permittee has not provided reasonable assurances that the proposed permittee has the administrative, technical, and financial capability to properly satisfy the requirements and conditions of the permit, as determined by department rule. The determination shall be limited solely to the ability of the proposed permittee to comply with the conditions of the existing permit, and it shall not concern the adequacy of the permit conditions. If the department proposes to deny the transfer, it shall provide both the transferring permittee and the proposed permittee a written objection to such transfer together with notice of a right to request a proceeding on such determination under chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days after receiving a properly completed application for transfer of permit, the department shall issue a final determination. The department may toll the time for making a determination on the transfer by notifying both the transferring permittee and the proposed permittee that additional information is required to adequately review the transfer request. Such notification shall be served within 30 days after receipt of an application for transfer of permit, completed pursuant to paragraph (a). However, the failure of the department to approve or deny within the 90-day time period does not result in the automatic approval or denial of the transfer. If the department fails to approve or deny the transfer within the 90-day period, the applicant may petition for a writ of mandamus to compel the department to act consistently with applicable regulatory requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transferring permittee is encouraged to apply for a permit transfer well in advance of the sale or legal transfer of a permitted facility. However, the transfer or the permit shall not be effective prior to the sale or legal transfer of the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Until the transfer of the permit is approved by the department, the transferring permittee and any other person constructing, operating, or maintaining the permitted facility shall be liable for compliance with the terms of the permit. Nothing in this section shall relieve the transferring permittee of liability for corrective actions that may be required as a result of any violations occurring prior to the legal transfer of the permit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 80-302; s. 2, ch. 82-79; s. 4, ch. 82-122; s. 64, ch. 83-218; s. 24, ch. 83-310; s. 34, ch. 86-186; s. 19, ch. 88-393; s. 2, ch. 91-284; s. 2, ch. 91-301; s. 408, ch. 94-356; s. 157, ch. 96-410; s. 44, ch. 99-5; s. 7, ch. 2000-304; s. 6, ch. 2003-173; s. 21, ch. 2007-184.</History></Section>