<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.9405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Applicability; certification; exemption; notice of intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of ss. 403.9401-403.9425 apply to each natural gas transmission pipeline, except as provided in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No construction of a natural gas transmission pipeline may be undertaken after October 1, 1992, without first obtaining certification under ss. 403.9401-403.9425, but these sections do not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Natural gas transmission pipelines which are less than 15 miles in length or which do not cross a county line, unless the applicant has elected to apply for certification under ss. 403.9401-403.9425.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Natural gas transmission pipelines for which a certificate of public convenience and necessity has been issued under s. 7(c) of the Natural Gas Act, 15 U.S.C. s. 717f, or a natural gas transmission pipeline certified as an associated facility to an electrical power plant pursuant to the Florida Electrical Power Plant Siting Act, ss. 403.501-403.518, unless the applicant elects to apply for certification of that pipeline under ss. 403.9401-403.9425.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Natural gas transmission pipelines that are owned or operated by a municipality or any agency thereof, by any person primarily for the local distribution of natural gas, or by a special district created by special act to distribute natural gas, unless the applicant elects to apply for certification of that pipeline under ss. 403.9401-403.9425.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the exemption of a natural gas transmission pipeline under ss. 403.9401-403.9425 does not constitute an exemption for the natural gas transmission pipeline from other applicable permitting processes under other provisions of law or local government ordinances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All natural gas transmission pipeline companies except those engaged in activities pursuant to paragraph (2)(c) shall notify the department in writing, prior to the start of construction, of their intent to construct a natural gas transmission pipeline exempted pursuant to this section. Such notice shall be only for information purposes, and no action by the department shall be required pursuant to such notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No natural gas transmission pipeline certified pursuant to ss. 403.9401-403.9425 shall be used for the transport of any substance other than natural gas.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-284.</History></Section>