<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.516" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Modification of certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification may be modified after issuance in any one of the following ways:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may delegate to the department the authority to modify specific conditions in the certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may modify specific conditions of a certification which are inconsistent with the terms of any federally delegated or approved permit for the certified electrical power plant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such modification may be made without further notice if the matter has been previously noticed under the requirements for any federally delegated or approved permit program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee may file a petition for modification with the department, or the department may initiate the modification upon its own initiative.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for modification must set forth:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed modification.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The factual reasons asserted for the modification.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The anticipated environmental effects of the proposed modification.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may modify the terms and conditions of the certification if no party to the certification hearing objects in writing to such modification within 45 days after notice by mail to such party’s last address of record, and if no other person whose substantial interests will be affected by the modification objects in writing within 30 days after issuance of public notice.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If objections are raised or the department denies the request, the applicant or department may file a request for a hearing on the modification with the department. Such request shall be handled pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requests referred to the Division of Administrative Hearings shall be disposed of in the same manner as an application, but with time periods established by the administrative law judge commensurate with the significance of the modification requested.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As required by s. 403.511(5).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agreement or modification under this section must be in accordance with the terms of this act. No modification to a certification shall be granted that constitutes a variance from standards or regulations of the department applicable under any federally delegated or approved permit program, except as expressly allowed in such program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 76-76; s. 10, ch. 81-131; s. 30, ch. 86-186; s. 21, ch. 90-331; s. 9, ch. 92-132; s. 143, ch. 96-410; s. 38, ch. 2006-230; s. 81, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>