<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.75" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to used oil.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 403.75-403.769 and s. 526.01, as amended by chapter 84-338, Laws of Florida, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public used oil collection center” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Automotive service facilities or governmentally sponsored collection facilities, which in the course of business accept for disposal small quantities of used oil from households; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities which store used oil in aboveground tanks, which are approved by the department, and which in the course of business accept for disposal small quantities of used oil from households.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, private or public corporation, partnership, cooperative, association, estate, political subdivision, or governmental agency or instrumentality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Processing” means chemical or physical operations designed to produce from used oil, or to make used oil more amenable for production of, fuel oils, lubricants, or other used oil-derived products. Processing includes, but is not limited to: blending used oil with virgin petroleum products, blending used oils to meet the fuel specifications, filtration, simple distillation, chemical or physical separation and rerefining.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recycling” means to prepare used oil for reuse as a petroleum product by rerefining, reclaiming, reprocessing, or other means or to use used oil in a manner that substitutes for a petroleum product made from new oil.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rerefining” means the use of refining processes on used oil to produce high-quality base stocks for lubricants or other petroleum products. Rerefining may include distillation, hydrotreating, or treatments employing acid, caustic, solvent, clay, or other chemicals, or other physical treatments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Used oil” means any oil which has been refined from crude oil or synthetic oil and, as a result of use, storage, or handling, has become contaminated and unsuitable for its original purpose due to the presence of physical or chemical impurities or loss of original properties.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 84-338; s. 25, ch. 88-130; s. 46, ch. 93-207; s. 416, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>