<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0403.941" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preliminary statements of issues, reports, and studies.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each affected agency which received an application in accordance with s. 403.9407(3) shall submit a preliminary statement of issues to the department and the applicant no later than 60 days after distribution of the complete application. Such statements of issues shall be made available to each local government for use as information for public meetings held pursuant to s. 403.9424. The failure to raise an issue in this preliminary statement of issues shall not preclude the issue from being raised in the agency’s report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The affected agencies shall prepare reports as provided in this paragraph and shall submit them to the department and the applicant within 60 days after the application is determined sufficient:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare a report as to the impact of each proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor as it relates to matters within its jurisdiction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each water management district in the jurisdiction of which a proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor is to be located shall prepare a report as to the impact on water resources and other matters within its jurisdiction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity shall prepare a report containing recommendations which address the impact upon the public of the proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor, based on the degree to which the proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor is consistent with the applicable portions of the state comprehensive plan and other matters within its jurisdiction. The Department of Economic Opportunity may also comment on the consistency of the proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor with applicable strategic regional policy plans or local comprehensive plans and land development regulations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission shall prepare a report as to the impact of each proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor on fish and wildlife resources and other matters within its jurisdiction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local government in which the natural gas transmission pipeline or natural gas transmission pipeline corridor will be located shall prepare a report as to the impact of each proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor on matters within its jurisdiction, including the consistency of the proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor with all applicable local ordinances, regulations, standards, or criteria that apply to the proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor, including local comprehensive plans, zoning regulations, land development regulations, and any applicable local environmental regulations adopted pursuant to s. 403.182 or by other means. No change by the responsible local government or local agency in local comprehensive plans, zoning ordinances, or other regulations made after the date required for the filing of the local government’s report required by this section shall be applicable to the certification of the proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor unless the certification is denied or the application is withdrawn.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each regional planning council in which the natural gas transmission pipeline or natural gas transmission pipeline corridor will be located shall present a report containing recommendations that address the impact upon the public of the proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor, based on the degree to which the natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor is consistent with the applicable provisions of the strategic regional policy plan adopted pursuant to chapter 186 and other impacts of each proposed natural gas transmission pipeline or corridor on matters within its jurisdiction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation shall prepare a report on the effect of the natural gas transmission pipeline or natural gas transmission pipeline corridor on matters within its jurisdiction, including roadway crossings by the pipeline. The report shall contain at a minimum:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report by the applicant to the department stating that all requirements of the department’s utilities accommodation guide have been or will be met in regard to the proposed pipeline or pipeline corridor; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement by the department as to the adequacy of the report to the department by the applicant.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State, Division of Historical Resources, shall prepare a report on the impact of the natural gas transmission pipeline or natural gas transmission pipeline corridor on matters within its jurisdiction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall prepare a report addressing matters within its jurisdiction. The commission’s report shall include its determination of need issued pursuant to s. 403.9422.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each report shall contain the information on variances required by s. 403.9416(2) and proposed conditions of certification on matters within the jurisdiction of each agency. For each condition proposed by an agency, the agency shall list the specific statute, rule, or ordinance, as applicable, which authorizes the proposed condition.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each reviewing agency shall initiate the activities required by this section no later than 15 days after the complete application is distributed. Each agency shall keep the applicant and the department informed as to the progress of its studies and any issues raised thereby.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare a written analysis which contains a compilation of agency reports and summaries of the material contained therein which shall be filed with the administrative law judge and served on all parties no later than 115 days after the application has been determined sufficient, and which shall include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The studies and reports required by this section and s. 403.9422.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comments received from any other agency or person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recommendation of the department as to the disposition of the application; of variances, exemptions, exceptions, or other relief identified by any party; and of any proposed conditions of certification which the department believes should be imposed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of any agency to submit a preliminary statement of issues or a report, or to submit its preliminary statement of issues or report within the allowed time, shall not be grounds for the alteration of any time limitation in ss. 403.9401-403.9425 pursuant to s. 403.9414. Neither the failure to submit a preliminary statement of issues or a report, nor the inadequacy of the preliminary statement of issues or report, shall be grounds to deny or condition certification. However, the failure of an agency to raise issues in its report shall preclude the agency from raising those issues at the certification hearing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-284; s. 433, ch. 94-356; s. 16, ch. 95-149; s. 175, ch. 96-410; s. 216, ch. 99-245; s. 294, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>