<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.509" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Final disposition of application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge has granted a request to cancel the certification hearing and has relinquished jurisdiction to the department under the provisions of s. 403.508(6), within 40 days thereafter, the secretary of the department shall act upon the application by written order in accordance with the terms of this act and the stipulation of the parties in requesting cancellation of the certification hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge has not granted a request to cancel the certification hearing under the provisions of s. 403.508(6), within 60 days after receipt of the designated administrative law judge’s recommended order, the board shall act upon the application by written order, approving or denying certification, in accordance with the terms of this act, and stating the reasons for issuance or denial. If certification is denied, the board shall set forth in writing the action the applicant would have to take to secure the board’s approval of the application.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issues that may be raised in any hearing before the board shall be limited to those matters raised in the certification proceeding before the administrative law judge or raised in the recommended order. All parties, or their representatives, or persons who appear before the board shall be subject to the provisions of s. 120.66.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining whether an application should be approved in whole, approved with modifications or conditions, or denied, the board, or secretary when applicable, shall consider whether, and the extent to which, the location, construction, and operation of the electrical power plant will:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide reasonable assurance that operational safeguards are technically sufficient for the public welfare and protection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with applicable nonprocedural requirements of agencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be consistent with applicable local government comprehensive plans and land development regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meet the electrical energy needs of the state in an orderly, reliable, and timely fashion.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effect a reasonable balance between the need for the facility as established pursuant to s. 403.519 and the impacts upon air and water quality, fish and wildlife, water resources, and other natural resources of the state resulting from the construction and operation of the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minimize, through the use of reasonable and available methods, the adverse effects on human health, the environment, and the ecology of the land and its wildlife and the ecology of state waters and their aquatic life.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve and protect the broad interests of the public.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transmission line corridor certified by the board, or secretary if applicable, shall meet the criteria of this section. When more than one transmission line corridor is proper for certification under s. 403.503(11) and meets the criteria of this section, the board, or secretary if applicable, shall certify the transmission line corridor that has the least adverse impact regarding the criteria in subsection (3), including costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board, or secretary if applicable, finds that an alternate corridor rejected pursuant to s. 403.5271 as incorporated by reference in s. 403.5064(1)(b) meets the criteria of subsection (3) and has the least adverse impact regarding the criteria in subsection (3), the board, or secretary if applicable, shall deny certification or shall allow the applicant to submit an amended application to include the corridor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board, or secretary if applicable, finds that two or more of the corridors that comply with subsection (3) have the least adverse impacts regarding the criteria in subsection (3), including costs, and that the corridors are substantially equal in adverse impacts regarding the criteria in subsection (3), including costs, the board, or secretary if applicable, shall certify the corridor preferred by the applicant if the corridor is one proper for certification under s. 403.503(11).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department’s action on a federally required new source review or prevention of significant deterioration permit shall differ from the actions taken by the siting board regarding the certification if the federally approved state implementation plan requires such a different action to be taken by the department. Nothing in this part shall be construed to displace the department’s authority as the final permitting entity under the federally approved permit program. Nothing in this part shall be construed to authorize the issuance of a new source review or prevention of significant deterioration permit which does not conform to the requirements of the federally approved state implementation plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For certifications issued by the board in regard to the properties and works of any agency which is a party to the certification hearing, the board shall have the authority to decide issues relating to the use, the connection thereto, or the crossing thereof, for the electrical power plant and to direct any such agency to execute, within 30 days after the entry of certification, the necessary license or easement for such use, connection, or crossing, subject only to the conditions set forth in such certification. For certifications issued by the department in regard to the properties and works of any agency that is a party to the proceeding, any stipulation filed pursuant to s. 403.508(6)(a) must include a stipulation regarding any issues relating to the use, the connection thereto, or the crossing thereof, for the electrical power plant. Any agency stipulating to the use of, connection to, or crossing of its property must agree to execute, within 30 days after the entry of certification, the necessary license or easement for such use, connection, or crossing, subject only to the conditions set forth in such certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuance or denial of the certification by the board or secretary of the department shall be the final administrative action required as to that application.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-33; s. 7, ch. 76-76; s. 141, ch. 77-104; s. 27, ch. 86-186; s. 12, ch. 90-331; s. 8, ch. 92-132; s. 10, ch. 93-94; s. 4, ch. 94-321; s. 141, ch. 96-410; s. 32, ch. 2006-230; s. 76, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>