<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.859" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts and the causing thereof are prohibited and are violations of this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by a supplier of water to comply with the requirements of s. 403.857 or dissemination by such supplier of any false or misleading information with respect to notices required pursuant to s. 403.857 or with respect to remedial actions being undertaken to achieve compliance with state primary and secondary drinking water regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by a supplier of water to comply with regulations adopted pursuant to s. 403.853, with any rule adopted by the department pursuant to this act, or with conditions for variances or exemptions authorized under s. 403.854.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by any person to comply with any order issued by the department pursuant to this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by a supplier of water to allow any duly authorized representative of the department or of the Department of Health to conduct inspections pursuant to s. 403.858.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission by any person of any false statement or representation in any application, record, report, plan, or other document filed, or required to be filed by this act or rules adopted by the department pursuant to its lawful authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by a supplier of water to comply with the requirements of a permit issued under s. 403.861(7).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The artificial recharge by the direct pumping of treated or untreated waste into any geologic formation of the Floridan Aquifer or the Biscayne Aquifer containing total dissolved solids of 500 milligrams per liter or less, except such injection of reclaimed water from domestic wastewater treatment reuse facilities if the effluent quality meets the water quality standards established by the Department of Environmental Protection as part of the operation permit to construct the treatment facility.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By January 1, 1995, the Department of Environmental Protection shall promulgate by rule effluent standards and conditions for any project proposing wastewater reuse of reclaimed water, for injection of the reclaimed water into the Floridan Aquifer or Biscayne Aquifer. Any injection into a geologic formation of the Floridan Aquifer or Biscayne Aquifer containing total dissolved solids of 500 milligrams per liter or less must meet the requirements of these rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event a facility does not receive, as a part of its operation permit, permission for injection which assures compliance with department rules promulgated pursuant to this subsection, the treated or untreated effluent shall be returned to the wastewater treatment plant from which the effluent was diverted during any testing period required by department rules or to another legally acceptable reuse or disposal alternative.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The provisions of this subsection do not apply to treated or untreated effluent currently discharging into the Floridan Aquifer or Biscayne Aquifer on June 22, 1983. However, any expansion of existing facilities on or after the effective date of this act are subject to the requirements of this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 77-337; s. 164, ch. 79-400; s. 1, ch. 83-161; s. 3, ch. 94-153; s. 169, ch. 99-8; s. 5, ch. 2001-270.</History></Section>