<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.1815" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Construction of water distribution mains and sewage collection and transmission systems; local regulation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, the department may, upon request, allow any county or municipality to independently regulate the construction of water distribution mains of 12 inches or less, gravity sewage collection systems of 12 inches or less, and sewage force mains of 12 inches or less, and pump stations appurtenant to such force mains, provided the plant is owned by the county or municipality making the request for approval or, pursuant to interlocal agreement, plant capacity is provided from a plant owned by another county or municipality or by a regional water supply authority of which the county or municipality requesting approval is a member. The approval may apply to all or any part of such systems. In considering such request, the department shall determine the administrative and engineering ability of a county or municipality to administer and comply with the requirements of this section. In the event the department allows any county or municipality to independently regulate the construction of such systems, these construction projects shall be exempt from department permit requirements. However, nothing in this section shall relieve a county or a municipality from any requirement to obtain the necessary permits for construction activities in waters of the state or of the United States or from complying with all other provisions of this chapter and rules promulgated thereunder. The exemption provided by this section shall not apply to any connection to any water or sewerage system which the department has deemed to be in substantial noncompliance with applicable laws and standards if the department has so notified the respective county or municipality. Each county or municipality granted such authority shall submit monthly reports to the department of the number of connections and geographical location of such connections made pursuant to any independent regulation allowed under this section and shall, not later than July 1 of each year, submit an updated map of any water distribution system and sewage collection and transmission system independently regulated pursuant to this section, which map also shows any plant to which such system connects or interconnects. Such map shall indicate the extensions of such systems constructed for the preceding year.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-394; s. 33, ch. 91-305; s. 1, ch. 94-132.</History></Section>