<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.311" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for weather modification licensing; fee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to do or perform any of the acts specified in s. 403.301 may file with the department an application for a license on a form to be supplied by the department for such purpose setting forth all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and post office address of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The education, experience, and qualifications of the applicant, or if the applicant is not an individual, the education, experience, and qualifications of the persons who will be in control and in charge of the operation of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and post office address of the person on whose behalf the weather modification operation is to be conducted if other than the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and object of the weather modification operation which the applicant proposes to conduct, including a general description of such operation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The method and type of equipment and the type and composition of materials that the applicant proposes to use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other pertinent information as the department may require.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application shall be accompanied by a filing fee in the sum of $1,000 and proof of financial responsibility as required by s. 403.321.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 57-128; ss. 26, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 18, ch. 88-393.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 373.291.</Text></Note></Section>