<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.519" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exclusive forum for determination of need.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On request by an applicant or on its own motion, the commission shall begin a proceeding to determine the need for an electrical power plant subject to the Florida Electrical Power Plant Siting Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall publish a notice of the proceeding in a newspaper of general circulation in each county in which the proposed electrical power plant will be located. The notice shall be at least one-quarter of a page and published at least 21 days prior to the scheduled date for the proceeding. The commission shall publish notice of the proceeding in the manner specified by chapter 120 at least 21 days prior to the scheduled date for the proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall be the sole forum for the determination of this matter, which accordingly shall not be raised in any other forum or in the review of proceedings in such other forum. In making its determination, the commission shall take into account the need for electric system reliability and integrity, the need for adequate electricity at a reasonable cost, the need for fuel diversity and supply reliability, whether the proposed plant is the most cost-effective alternative available, and whether renewable energy sources and technologies, as well as conservation measures, are utilized to the extent reasonably available. The commission shall also expressly consider the conservation measures taken by or reasonably available to the applicant or its members which might mitigate the need for the proposed plant and other matters within its jurisdiction which it deems relevant. The commission’s determination of need for an electrical power plant shall create a presumption of public need and necessity and shall serve as the commission’s report required by s. 403.507(4). An order entered pursuant to this section constitutes final agency action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In making its determination on a proposed electrical power plant using nuclear materials or synthesis gas produced by integrated gasification combined cycle power plant as fuel, the commission shall hold a hearing within 90 days after the filing of the petition to determine need and shall issue an order granting or denying the petition within 135 days after the date of the filing of the petition. The commission shall be the sole forum for the determination of this matter and the issues addressed in the petition, which accordingly shall not be reviewed in any other forum, or in the review of proceedings in such other forum. In making its determination to either grant or deny the petition, the commission shall consider the need for electric system reliability and integrity, including fuel diversity, the need for base-load generating capacity, the need for adequate electricity at a reasonable cost, and whether renewable energy sources and technologies, as well as conservation measures, are utilized to the extent reasonably available.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s petition shall include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the need for the generation capacity.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of how the proposed nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant will enhance the reliability of electric power production within the state by improving the balance of power plant fuel diversity and reducing Florida’s dependence on fuel oil and natural gas.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of and a nonbinding estimate of the cost of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant, including any costs associated with new, expanded, or relocated electrical transmission lines or facilities of any size that are necessary to serve the nuclear power plant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annualized base revenue requirement for the first 12 months of operation of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information on whether there were any discussions with any electric utilities regarding ownership of a portion of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant by such electric utilities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In making its determination, the commission shall take into account matters within its jurisdiction, which it deems relevant, including whether the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant will:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide needed base-load capacity.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enhance the reliability of electric power production within the state by improving the balance of power plant fuel diversity and reducing Florida’s dependence on fuel oil and natural gas.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the most cost-effective source of power, taking into account the need to improve the balance of fuel diversity, reduce Florida’s dependence on fuel oil and natural gas, reduce air emission compliance costs, and contribute to the long-term stability and reliability of the electric grid.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision of rule 25-22.082, Florida Administrative Code, shall be applicable to a nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant sited under this act, including provisions for cost recovery, and an applicant shall not otherwise be required to secure competitive proposals for power supply prior to making application under this act or receiving a determination of need from the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission’s determination of need for a nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant shall create a presumption of public need and necessity and shall serve as the commission’s report required by s. 403.507(4)(a). An order entered pursuant to this section constitutes final agency action. Any petition for reconsideration of a final order on a petition for need determination shall be filed within 5 days after the date of such order. The commission’s final order, including any order on reconsideration, shall be reviewable on appeal in the Florida Supreme Court. Inasmuch as delay in the determination of need will delay siting of a nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant or diminish the opportunity for savings to customers under the federal Energy Policy Act of 2005, the Supreme Court shall proceed to hear and determine the action as expeditiously as practicable and give the action precedence over matters not accorded similar precedence by law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a petition for determination of need for a nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant has been granted, the right of a utility to recover any costs incurred prior to commercial operation, including, but not limited to, costs associated with the siting, design, licensing, or construction of the plant and new, expanded, or relocated electrical transmission lines or facilities of any size that are necessary to serve the nuclear power plant, shall not be subject to challenge unless and only to the extent the commission finds, based on a preponderance of the evidence adduced at a hearing before the commission under s. 120.57, that certain costs were imprudently incurred. Proceeding with the construction of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant following an order by the commission approving the need for the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant under this act shall not constitute or be evidence of imprudence. Imprudence shall not include any cost increases due to events beyond the utility’s control. Further, a utility’s right to recover costs associated with a nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant may not be raised in any other forum or in the review of proceedings in such other forum. Costs incurred prior to commercial operation shall be recovered pursuant to chapter 366.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 80-65; s. 24, ch. 90-331; s. 43, ch. 2006-230; s. 3, ch. 2007-117; s. 85, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>