<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.085" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sanitary sewage disposal units; advanced and secondary waste treatment; industrial waste treatment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the Department of Health nor any other state agency, county, special district, or municipality shall approve construction of any disposal well for sanitary sewage disposal which does not provide for secondary waste treatment and, in addition thereto, advanced waste treatment as deemed necessary and ordered by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sanitary sewage disposal treatment plants which discharge effluent through disposal wells shall provide for secondary waste treatment and, in addition thereto, advanced waste treatment as deemed necessary and ordered by the Department of Environmental Protection. Failure to conform shall be punishable by a fine of $500 for each 24-hour day or fraction thereof that such failure is allowed to continue thereafter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the Department of Health nor any other state agency, county, special district, or municipality shall approve construction of any ocean outfall, inland outfall, or disposal well for the discharge of industrial waste of any kind which does not provide for secondary waste treatment or such other treatment as is deemed necessary and ordered by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Industrial plants or facilities which discharge industrial waste of any kind through ocean outfalls, inland outfalls, or disposal wells shall provide for secondary waste treatment or such other waste treatment as deemed necessary and ordered by the former Department of Environmental Regulation. Failure to conform shall be punishable as provided in s. 403.161(2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-82; s. 2, ch. 71-137; s. 1, ch. 71-274; s. 270, ch. 77-147; s. 74, ch. 79-65; s. 360, ch. 94-356; s. 157, ch. 99-8; s. 11, ch. 2000-211; s. 5, ch. 2008-232.</History></Section>