<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.506" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Applicability, thresholds, and certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this act shall apply to any electrical power plant as defined herein, except that the provisions of this act shall not apply to any electrical power plant of less than 75 megawatts in gross capacity, including its associated facilities, unless the applicant has elected to apply for certification of such electrical power plant under this act. The provisions of this act shall not apply to capacity expansions of 75 megawatts or less, in the aggregate, of an existing exothermic reaction cogeneration electrical generating facility that was exempt from this act when it was originally built; however, this exemption shall not apply if the unit uses oil or natural gas for purposes other than unit startup. No construction of any new electrical power plant or expansion in steam generating capacity as measured by an increase in the maximum electrical generator rating of any existing electrical power plant may be undertaken after October 1, 1973, without first obtaining certification in the manner as herein provided, except that this act shall not apply to any such electrical power plant which is presently operating or under construction or which has, upon the effective date of chapter 73-33, Laws of Florida, applied for a permit or certification under requirements in force prior to the effective date of such act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in the certification, modification of nonnuclear fuels, internal related hardware, including increases in steam turbine efficiency, or operating conditions not in conflict with certification which increase the electrical output of a unit to no greater capacity than the maximum electrical generator rating of the existing generator shall not constitute an alteration or addition to generating capacity which requires certification pursuant to this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An electric utility may obtain separate licenses, permits, and approvals for the construction of facilities necessary to construct an electrical power plant without first obtaining certification under this act if the utility intends to locate, license, and construct a proposed or expanded electrical power plant that uses nuclear materials as fuel. Such facilities may include, but are not limited to, access and onsite roads, rail lines, electrical transmission facilities to support construction, and facilities necessary for waterborne delivery of construction materials and project components. This exemption applies to such facilities regardless of whether the facilities are used for operation of the power plant. The applicant shall file with the department a statement that declares that the construction of such facilities is necessary for the timely construction of the proposed electrical power plant and identifies those facilities that the applicant intends to seek licenses for and construct prior to or separate from certification of the project. The facilities may be located within or off the site for the proposed electrical power plant. The filing of an application under this act shall not affect other applications for separate licenses which are pending at the time of filing the application. Furthermore, the filing of an application shall not prevent an electric utility from seeking separate licenses for facilities that are necessary to construct the electrical power plant. Licenses, permits, or approvals issued by any state, regional, or local agency for such facilities shall be incorporated by the department into a final certification upon completion of construction. Any facilities necessary for construction of the electrical power plant shall become part of the certified electrical power plant upon completion of the electrical power plant’s construction. The exemption in this subsection shall not require or authorize agency rulemaking, and any action taken under this subsection shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 120. This subsection shall be given retroactive effect and shall apply to applications filed after May 1, 2008.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-33; s. 3, ch. 76-76; s. 2, ch. 79-76; s. 5, ch. 81-131; s. 15, ch. 86-173; s. 24, ch. 86-186; s. 5, ch. 90-331; s. 80, ch. 93-213; s. 23, ch. 2006-230; s. 69, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>