<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.1832" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department to accept federal aid; Grants and Donations Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is designated as the administrative agency of the state to apply for and accept any funds or other aid and to cooperate and enter into contracts and agreements with the Federal Government relating to the planning, design, construction, operation, maintenance, and enforcement activities of the program to provide clean air and water and pollution abatement of the air and waters of the state, including solid waste management, hazardous waste management, and ecosystem management and restoration, or to any other related environmental purposes authorized by the Congress of the United States. The department may, in the name of the state, make such applications, sign such documents, give such assurances, and do such other things as are necessary to obtain such aid from or cooperate with the United States Government or any agency thereof. The department may consent to enter into contracts and agreements and cooperate with any other state agency, local governmental agency, person, or other state when it is necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Grants and Donations Trust Fund is to be administered by the Department of Environmental Protection. The fund is intended to serve as the depository for federal grants and funds received by the department and to assist in tracking and monitoring the use of federal funds that are not otherwise deposited directly into a separate trust fund. The Grants and Donations Trust Fund is intended to be a broad-based fund from which moneys can be used for various environmental and natural resource program purposes for which the federal funds were intended. Funds may be expended for purposes including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water quality improvement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management of solid and hazardous wastes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stormwater management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Air quality improvement and management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wetland protection and management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marine research.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marine habitat restoration and management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aquatic weed control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Environmental regulatory compliance and enforcement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local or state recreational projects.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 70-251; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 53, ch. 83-310; s. 63, ch. 96-321; s. 14, ch. 2001-270.</History></Section>