<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.718" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Waste tire fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the privilege of engaging in business, a fee for each new motor vehicle tire sold at retail, including those sold to any governmental entity, is imposed on any person engaging in the business of making retail sales of new motor vehicle tires within this state. The fee imposed under this section shall be stated separately on the invoice to the purchaser. Such fee shall be imposed at the rate of $1 for each new tire sold. The fee imposed shall be paid to the Department of Revenue on or before the 20th day of the month following the month in which the sale occurs. For purposes of this section, a motor vehicle tire sold at retail includes such tires when sold as a component part of a motor vehicle. The terms “sold at retail” and “retail sales” do not include the sale of new motor vehicle tires to a person solely for the purpose of resale provided the subsequent retail sale in this state is subject to the fee. This fee does not apply to recapped tires. Such fee shall be subject to all applicable taxes imposed in chapter 212.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee imposed by this section shall be reported to the Department of Revenue. The payment shall be accompanied by such form as the Department of Revenue may prescribe. The proceeds of the waste tire fee, less administrative costs, shall be transferred by the Department of Revenue into the Solid Waste Management Trust Fund. For the purposes of this section, “proceeds” of the fee means all funds collected and received by the department hereunder, including interest and penalties on delinquent fees. The amount deducted for the costs of administration must not exceed 3 percent of the total revenues collected hereunder and may include only those costs reasonably attributable to the fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall administer, collect, and enforce the fee authorized under this section pursuant to the same procedures used in the administration, collection, and enforcement of the general state sales tax imposed under chapter 212, except as provided in this section. The provisions of this section regarding the authority to audit and make assessments, keeping of books and records, and interest and penalties on delinquent fees apply. The fee shall not be included in the computation of estimated taxes pursuant to s. 212.11 nor shall the dealer’s credit for collecting taxes or fees in s. 212.12 apply to this fee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue is authorized to employ persons and incur other expenses for which funds are appropriated by the Legislature. The department is empowered to adopt such rules and shall prescribe and publish such forms as are necessary to effectuate the purposes of this section. The department is authorized to establish audit procedures and to assess delinquent fees.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 42, ch. 88-130; s. 7, ch. 89-171; s. 17, ch. 89-324; s. 33, ch. 90-132; s. 121, ch. 91-112; s. 19, ch. 93-233; s. 12, ch. 97-99; s. 35, ch. 2000-153; s. 44, ch. 2001-62; s. 10, ch. 2002-291; s. 1, ch. 2005-174.</History></Section>