<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.9325" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of ss. 403.9321-403.9333, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alter” means anything other than trimming of mangroves.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local government” means a county or municipality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mangrove” means any specimen of the species <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Laguncularia racemosa</Font> (white mangrove), <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Rhizophora mangle</Font> (red mangrove), or <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Avicennia germinans</Font> (black mangrove).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mangroves on lands that have been set aside as mitigation” means mangrove areas on public or private land which have been created, enhanced, restored, or preserved as mitigation under a dredge and fill permit issued under ss. 403.91-403.929, Florida Statutes (1984 Supplement, as amended), or a dredge and fill permit, management and storage of surface waters permit, or environmental resource permit issued under part IV of chapter 373, applicable dredge and fill licenses or permits issued by a local government, a resolution of an enforcement action, or a conservation easement that does not provide for trimming.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Professional mangrove trimmer” means a person who meets the qualifications set forth in s. 403.9329.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public lands set aside for conservation or preservation” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conservation and recreation lands under chapter 259;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and national parks;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and national reserves and preserves, except as provided in s. 403.9326(3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and national wilderness areas;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">National wildlife refuges (only those lands under Federal Government ownership);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands acquired through the Water Management Lands Trust Fund, Save Our Rivers Program;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands acquired under the Save Our Coast program;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands acquired under the environmentally endangered lands bond program;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public lands designated as conservation or preservation under a local government comprehensive plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands purchased by a water management district, the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, or any other state agency for conservation or preservation purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public lands encumbered by a conservation easement that does not provide for the trimming of mangroves; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public lands designated as critical wildlife areas by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Riparian mangrove fringe” means mangroves growing along the shoreline on private property, property owned by a governmental entity, or sovereign submerged land, the depth of which does not exceed 50 feet as measured waterward from the trunk of the most landward mangrove tree in a direction perpendicular to the shoreline to the trunk of the most waterward mangrove tree. Riparian mangrove fringe does not include mangroves on uninhabited islands, or public lands that have been set aside for conservation or preservation, or mangroves on lands that have been set aside as mitigation, if the permit, enforcement instrument, or conservation easement establishing the mitigation area did not include provisions for the trimming of mangroves.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trim” means to cut mangrove branches, twigs, limbs, and foliage, but does not mean to remove, defoliate, or destroy the mangroves.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 95-299; s. 4, ch. 96-206; s. 215, ch. 99-245.</History></Section>