<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.816" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permits for maintenance dredging of deepwater ports and beach restoration projects.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a permit system under this chapter and chapter 253 which provides for the performance, for up to 25 years from the issuance of the original permit, of maintenance dredging of permitted navigation channels, port harbors, turning basins, harbor berths, and beach restoration projects approved pursuant to chapter 161. However, permits issued for dredging river channels which are not a part of a deepwater port shall be valid for no more than five years. No charge shall be exacted by the state for material removed during such maintenance dredging by a public port authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 253.77 do not apply to a permit for maintenance dredging and spoil site approval when there is no change in the size or location of the spoil disposal site and when the applicant provides documentation to the department that the appropriate lease, easement, or consent of use for the project site issued pursuant to chapter 253 is recorded in the county where the project is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section relating to ports apply only to the port waters, spoil disposal sites, port harbors, navigation channels, turning basins, and harbor berths used for deepwater commercial navigation in the ports of Jacksonville, Tampa, Port Everglades, Miami, Port Canaveral, Ft. Pierce, Palm Beach, Port Manatee, Port St. Joe, Panama City, St. Petersburg, Port Bartow, Florida Power Corporation’s Crystal River Canal, Boca Grande, Green Cove Springs, and Pensacola.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 5, ch. 81-228; s. 8, ch. 84-79; s. 2, ch. 85-296; s. 13, ch. 86-138; s. 20, ch. 89-175; s. 4, ch. 89-324.</History></Section>