<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.5251" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application; schedules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The formal date of the filing of the application for certification and commencement of the review process for certification is the date on which the applicant submits:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of the application for certification in a quantity and format, electronic or otherwise as prescribed by rule, to the department and other agencies identified in s. 403.526(2).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application fee as specified under s. 403.5365 to the department.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department shall provide to the applicant and the Division of Administrative Hearings the names and addresses of any additional agencies or persons entitled to notice and copies of the application and amendments, if any, within 7 days after receiving the application for certification and the application fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the application, the starting point and ending point of a transmission line must be specifically defined by the applicant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 days after the formal date of the application filing, the department shall prepare a proposed schedule of dates for determination of completeness, submission of statements of issues, submittal of final reports, and other significant dates to be followed during the certification process, including dates for filing notices of appearances to be a party under s. 403.527(2). This schedule shall be provided by the department to the applicant, the administrative law judge, and the agencies identified under subsection (1). Within 7 days after the filing of this proposed schedule, the administrative law judge shall issue an order establishing a schedule for the matters addressed in the department’s proposed schedule and other appropriate matters, if any.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of changes and amendments to the application shall be timely distributed by the applicant to all agencies and parties who have received a copy of the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the filing of the application shall be made in accordance with the requirements of s. 403.5363.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 90-331; s. 146, ch. 96-410; s. 51, ch. 2006-230.</History></Section>