<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.7215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax on gross receipts of commercial hazardous waste facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or operator of each privately owned, permitted, commercial hazardous waste transfer, storage, treatment, or disposal facility shall, on or before January 25 of each year, file with the chief fiscal officer of the primary host local government a certified, notarized statement. The statement shall indicate the gross receipts from all charges imposed during the preceding calendar year for the storage, treatment, or disposal of hazardous waste at the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 3-percent tax is hereby levied on the annual gross receipts of a privately owned, permitted, commercial hazardous waste transfer, storage, treatment, or disposal facility, which tax is payable annually on or before July 1 by the owner of the facility to the primary host local government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys received by the appropriate local government pursuant to subsection (2) shall be appropriated and used to pay for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs of collecting the tax;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any local inspection costs incurred by the local government to ensure that the facility is operated pursuant to the provisions of this part and any rule adopted pursuant thereto;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additional security costs incurred as a result of operating the facility, including monitoring, fire protection, and police protection;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hazardous waste contingency planning implementation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Road construction or repair costs for public roads adjacent to and within 1,000 feet of the facility;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other cost incurred by the local government as a result of the operation of the facility, if all other costs specified in paragraphs (a)-(e) have been paid; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other purposes relating to environmental protection within the jurisdiction of the local government, including, but not limited to, the establishment of a system for the collection and disposal of household, agricultural and other types of hazardous waste, the protection or improvement of the quality of the air or water, or the acquisition of environmentally sensitive lands, provided all other costs specified in this section have been paid.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary host local government is responsible for regulating, controlling, administering, and enforcing the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 83-310; s. 24, ch. 88-130; s. 33, ch. 88-393; s. 1, ch. 89-285; s. 36, ch. 91-305.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 203.10.</Text></Note></Section>