<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.7225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local hazardous waste management assessments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that there is a need for identifying the amount, type, sources, and management of hazardous waste generated by small quantity generators in the state. There is also a need for facilitating responsible waste storage, transportation, volume reduction, recycling treatment, disposal, and the introduction of waste reduction opportunities to small quantity generators of hazardous waste. Responsible management of these wastes is imperative in order to protect the public health, safety, and welfare and the environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish guidelines for local hazardous waste management assessments and shall specify a standard format. The local hazardous waste management assessments shall include, but not be limited to, the identification of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All small quantity generators of hazardous waste within a county as defined pursuant to federal regulations under 40 C.F.R. part 260.10.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The types and quantities of hazardous waste generated by small quantity generators within a county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current hazardous waste management practices of small quantity generators within a county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective waste management practices for small quantity generators of hazardous waste.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county or regional planning council shall coordinate the local hazardous waste management assessments within its jurisdiction according to guidelines established under s. 403.7226. If a county declines to perform the local hazardous waste management assessment, the county shall make arrangements with its regional planning council to perform the assessment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County-designated areas under the original assessments in which hazardous waste storage facilities have been located are recognized by the Legislature. However, this section does not prohibit a county from amending its comprehensive plan to designate other areas for this purpose, nor does this section prohibit construction of a facility on any other locally approved or state-approved site.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No county may amend its comprehensive plan or undertake rezoning actions in order to prevent areas designated pursuant to subsection (4) from being used as hazardous waste storage facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless performed by the county pursuant to subsection (3), the regional planning councils shall upon successful arrangements with a county:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform local hazardous waste management assessments;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide any technical expertise needed by the counties in developing the assessments.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selection of a regional storage facility site during the original assessment will not preclude the siting of a storage facility at some other site which is locally or state approved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall assemble the data collected from the local hazardous waste management assessments and determine if the needs of small quantity generators of hazardous waste will be met by in-state commercial hazardous waste facilities or if additional storage, treatment, or disposal facilities are needed in the state and which regions have the greatest need.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Storage facility area selections, or regional storage facility site selections from the original assessments shall not prevent siting of storage or treatment facilities in any area of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this part, no local government law, ordinance, or rule pertaining to the subject of hazardous waste regulation may be more stringent than department rules adopted under the authority of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local hazardous waste management assessments shall be renewed every 5 years, based on the schedule determined by the department. More frequent assessments shall not be required by the state. However, at their option, counties may update such assessments at more frequent intervals. The assessment rolls shall be brought up to date annually before the end of the 5-year interval by including the applicable names from department sources, occupational licenses, building permits, and from not less than one complete survey of the business pages of the county local telephone systems. The roll shall be updated continuously thereafter in the same manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes the expense incurred by county governments in the proper identification, notification, and verification of small quantity generators of hazardous waste within their jurisdictions. When required to support the local hazardous waste assessments required by this section, the small quantity generator notification and verification program required pursuant to s. 403.7234, and the reporting requirements of s. 403.7236, a county may impose a small quantity generator notification and verification surcharge of up to $50 on the business or occupational license or renewal of any firm that is classified as a small quantity generator of hazardous wastes. A county may contract with or otherwise enter into an agreement with the county tax collector to collect the annual surcharge.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 83-310; s. 34, ch. 84-338; s. 3, ch. 85-269; s. 11, ch. 87-374; s. 37, ch. 91-305; s. 40, ch. 93-207.</History></Section>