<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Variances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application, the department in its discretion may grant a variance from the provisions of this act or the rules and regulations adopted pursuant hereto. Variances and renewals thereof may be granted for any one of the following reasons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is no practicable means known or available for the adequate control of the pollution involved.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with the particular requirement or requirements from which a variance is sought will necessitate the taking of measures which, because of their extent or cost, must be spread over a considerable period of time. A variance granted for this reason shall prescribe a timetable for the taking of the measures required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To relieve or prevent hardship of a kind other than those provided for in paragraphs (a) and (b). Variances and renewals thereof granted under authority of this paragraph shall each be limited to a period of 24 months, except that variances granted pursuant to part II may extend for the life of the permit or certification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No variance shall be granted from any provision or requirement concerning discharges of waste into waters of the state or hazardous waste management which would result in the provision or requirement being less stringent than a comparable federal provision or requirement, except as provided in s. 403.70715.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall publish notice, or shall require a petitioner for a variance to publish notice, in the Florida Administrative Weekly and in a newspaper of general circulation in the area affected, of proposed agency action; and the department shall afford interested persons an opportunity for a hearing on each application for a variance. If no request for hearing is filed with the department within 14 days of published notice, the department may proceed to final agency action without a hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require by rule a processing fee for and may prescribe such time limits and other conditions to the granting of a variance as it deems appropriate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 67-436; ss. 26, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 74-170; s. 14, ch. 78-95; s. 7, ch. 82-27; s. 21, ch. 86-186; s. 78, ch. 93-213; s. 106, ch. 2008-4.</History></Section>