<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.5066" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of completeness.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after the filing of an application, affected agencies shall file a statement with the department containing each agency’s recommendations on the completeness of the application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 40 days after the filing of an application, the department shall file a statement with the Division of Administrative Hearings, with the applicant, and with all parties declaring its position with regard to the completeness of the application. The department’s statement shall be based upon consultation with the affected agencies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department declares the application to be incomplete, the applicant, within 15 days after the filing of the statement by the department, shall file with the Division of Administrative Hearings, with the department, and all parties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A withdrawal of the application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement agreeing to supply the additional information necessary to make the application complete. Such additional information shall be provided within 30 days after the issuance of the department’s statement on completeness of the application. The time schedules under this act shall not be tolled if the applicant makes the application complete within 30 days after the issuance of the department’s statement on completeness of the application. A subsequent finding by the department that the application remains incomplete, based upon the additional information submitted by the applicant or upon the failure of the applicant to timely submit the additional information, tolls the time schedules under this act until the application is determined complete;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement contesting the department’s determination of incompleteness; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement agreeing with the department and requesting additional time beyond 30 days to provide the information necessary to make the application complete. If the applicant exercises this option, the time schedules under this act are tolled until the application is determined complete.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant contests the determination by the department that an application is incomplete, the administrative law judge shall schedule a hearing on the statement of completeness. The hearing shall be held as expeditiously as possible, but not later than 21 days after the filing of the statement by the department. The administrative law judge shall render a decision within 7 days after the hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parties to a hearing on the issue of completeness shall include the applicant, the department, and any agency that has jurisdiction over the matter in dispute.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge determines that the application was not complete, the applicant shall withdraw the application or make such additional submittals as necessary to complete it. The time schedules referencing a complete application under this act shall not commence until the application is determined complete.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge determines that the application was complete at the time it was declared incomplete, the time schedules referencing a complete application under this act shall commence upon such determination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant provides additional information to address the issues identified in the determination of incompleteness, each affected agency may submit to the department, no later than 15 days after the applicant files the additional information, a recommendation on whether the agency believes the application is complete. Within 22 days after receipt of the additional information from the applicant submitted under paragraph (2)(b), paragraph (2)(d), or paragraph (3)(c), the department shall determine whether the additional information supplied by an applicant makes the application complete. If the department finds that the application is still incomplete, the applicant may exercise any of the options specified in subsection (2) as often as is necessary to resolve the dispute.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 90-331; s. 137, ch. 96-410; s. 26, ch. 2006-230.</History></Section>