<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspections.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized representative of the department may at any reasonable time enter and inspect, for the purpose of ascertaining the state of compliance with the law or rules and regulations of the department, any property, premises, or place, except a building which is used exclusively for a private residence, on or at which:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hazardous waste generator, transporter, or facility or other air or water contaminant source;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A discharger, including any nondomestic discharger which introduces any pollutant into a publicly owned treatment works;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility, as defined in s. 376.301; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resource recovery and management facility</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is located or is being constructed or installed or where records which are required under this chapter, ss. 376.30-376.317, or department rule are kept.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized representative may at reasonable times have access to and copy any records required under this chapter or ss. 376.30-376.317; inspect any monitoring equipment or method; sample for any pollutants as defined in s. 376.301, effluents, or wastes which the owner or operator of such source may be discharging or which may otherwise be located on or underlying the owner’s or operator’s property; and obtain any other information necessary to determine compliance with permit conditions or other requirements of this chapter, ss. 376.30-376.317, or department rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall refuse reasonable entry or access to any authorized representative of the department who requests entry for purposes of inspection and who presents appropriate credentials; nor shall any person obstruct, hamper, or interfere with any such inspection. The owner or operator of the premises shall receive a report, if requested, setting forth all facts found which relate to compliance status.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inspection pursuant to subsection (1) may be conducted only after:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent for the inspection is received from the owner, operator, or person in charge; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate inspection warrant as provided in this section is obtained.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inspection warrant as authorized by this chapter may be issued by a judge of any county court or circuit court of this state which has jurisdiction of the place or thing to be searched.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proper affidavit being made, an inspection warrant may be issued under the provisions of this chapter or ss. 376.30-376.317:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When it appears that the properties to be inspected may be connected with or contain evidence of the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter or ss. 376.30-376.317 or any rule properly promulgated thereunder; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the inspection sought is an integral part of a larger scheme of systematic routine inspections which are necessary to, and consistent with, the continuing efforts of the department to ensure compliance with the provisions of this chapter or ss. 376.30-376.317 and any rules adopted thereunder.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judge shall, before issuing the warrant, have the application for the warrant duly sworn to and subscribed by a representative of the department; and may receive further testimony from witnesses, supporting affidavits, or depositions in writing to support the application. The affidavit and further proof, if had or required, shall set forth the facts tending to establish the grounds specified in paragraph (b) or the reasons for believing that such grounds exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon examination of the application and proofs submitted and if satisfied that cause exists for the issuing of the inspection warrant, the judge shall thereupon issue a warrant, signed by him or her with the name of his or her office, to any department representative, which warrant will authorize the representative forthwith to inspect the property described in the warrant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 67-436; ss. 26, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 80-302; s. 6, ch. 82-27; s. 26, ch. 84-338; s. 25, ch. 86-159; s. 9, ch. 89-188; s. 69, ch. 91-221; s. 3, ch. 97-103; s. 81, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>