<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.0615" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Water resources restoration and preservation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Water Resources Restoration and Preservation Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a program to assist in the restoration and preservation of bodies of water and to enhance existing public access when deemed necessary for the enhancement of the restoration effort. This program shall be funded from the General Revenue Fund, from funds available from the Ecosystem Management and Restoration Trust Fund, and from available federal moneys.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt, by rule, criteria for the allocation of restoration and preservation funds. Such criteria shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The degree of water quality degradation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The degree to which sources of pollution which have contributed to the need for restoration or preservation have been abated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public uses which can be made of the subject waters;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ecological value of the subject waters in relation to other waters proposed for restoration and preservation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The implementation by local government of regulatory or management programs to prevent further and subsequent degradation of the subject waters; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commitment of local government resources to assist in the proposed restoration and preservation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this act are for the benefit of the public and shall be liberally construed to accomplish the purposes set forth in this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 4, 5, ch. 77-369; s. 2, ch. 79-130; s. 25, ch. 93-120; s. 357, ch. 94-356; s. 59, ch. 96-321.</History></Section>