<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.9404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Environmental Protection; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection shall have the following powers and duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt procedural rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of ss. 403.9401-403.9425 and to adopt rules to implement the provisions of subsection (8).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prescribe the form and content of the public notices and the form, content, and necessary supporting documentation, and any required studies, for certification applications. All such data and studies shall be related to the jurisdiction of the agencies relevant to the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive applications for natural gas transmission pipeline and corridor certifications and initially determine the completeness and sufficiency thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make or contract for studies of certification applications. All such studies shall be related to the jurisdiction of the agencies relevant to the application. For studies in areas outside the jurisdiction of the department and in the jurisdiction of another agency, the department may initiate such studies, but only with the consent of such agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To administer the processing of applications for certification and ensure that the applications are processed as expeditiously as possible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require such fees as allowed by ss. 403.9401-403.9425.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prepare a report and written analysis as required by s. 403.941.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prescribe the means for monitoring the effects arising from the construction, operation, and maintenance of the natural gas transmission pipelines to assure continued compliance with the terms of the certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make a determination of acceptability of any alternate corridor proposed for consideration pursuant to s. 403.9412.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act as clerk for the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enforce compliance with the provisions of ss. 403.9401-403.9425.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To function as staff to the board, when appropriate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-284; s. 432, ch. 94-356; s. 109, ch. 98-200.</History></Section>