<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.9418" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Modification of certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification may be modified after issuance in any one of the following ways:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may delegate to the department the authority to modify specific conditions in the certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may modify the terms and conditions of the certification if no party objects in writing to such modification within 45 days after notice by mail to the last address of record in the certification proceeding, and, if no other person whose substantial interests will be affected by the modification objects in writing within 30 days after issuance of public notice. If objections are raised, the applicant or department may file a petition for modification with the department and the Division of Administrative Hearings setting forth:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed modification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The factual reasons asserted for the modification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The anticipated additional environmental effects of the proposed modification.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petitions filed pursuant to paragraph (1)(b) shall be disposed of in the same manner as an application but within the times established by the administrative law judge commensurate with the significance of the modification requested.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that any of the terms and conditions of any permit issued pursuant to a federally delegated or approved permit program are modified under the requirements of the program and the modified permit conflicts with the terms and conditions of the site certification, the terms and conditions of the permit shall control and the site certification shall be deemed modified to incorporate the permit requirements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-284; s. 14, ch. 94-321; s. 181, ch. 96-410.</History></Section>