<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.9421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees; disposition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall charge the applicant the following fees, as appropriate, which shall be paid into the Florida Permit Fee Trust Fund:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application fee of $240,000, plus $500 per mile for each mile of natural gas transmission pipeline corridor proposed to be located in an existing electrical transmission line right-of-way or in existing rights-of-way for roads, highways, railroads, gas, water, oil, sewer, or any other public purpose, and $1,000 per mile for each mile of natural gas transmission pipeline proposed to be located outside existing rights-of-way, not to exceed a total fee of $890,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A postcertification fee determined as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For pipelines of 50 miles or less in total length, the fee shall be $75,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For pipelines of between 50 and 150 miles in total length, the fee shall be $125,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For pipelines of a total length greater than 150 miles, the fee shall be $175,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application amendment fee which shall apply only when a corridor alignment change is proposed by an applicant prior to the issuance of the department’s written analysis as to a proposed corridor.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee shall be $5,000 plus $500 for each mile of natural gas transmission pipeline corridor proposed to be located in an existing electrical transmission line right-of-way or in existing rights-of-way for roads, highways, railroads, gas, water, oil, sewer, or any other public purpose, and $1,000 per mile for each mile of natural gas transmission pipeline proposed to be located outside existing rights-of-way.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No fee shall be required if an applicant adopts an alternate corridor alignment which is timely proposed under s. 403.9412.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification modification fee determined as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no corridor alignment change is involved, the fee shall be $10,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a corridor alignment change is proposed, the fee shall be $10,000 plus $500 for each mile of natural gas transmission pipeline corridor proposed to be located in an existing electrical transmission line right-of-way or in existing rights-of-way for roads, highways, railroads, gas, water, oil, sewer, or any other public purpose, and $1,000 per mile for each mile of natural gas transmission pipeline proposed to be located outside existing rights-of-way.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In administering fee revenues received under this section, the department shall allocate the funds as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall retain fee revenues to be utilized as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent of the fees specified under this section, except for postcertification fees, shall be retained by the department to cover its costs associated with reviewing and acting upon applications and requests for modification of certification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sixty percent of postcertification fees shall be retained by the department exclusively to cover its costs associated with postcertification review of natural gas transmission pipeline rights-of-way which are established, constructed, and maintained under certification issued under ss. 403.9401-403.9425.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sixteen percent of the fees specified under this section, except for postcertification fees, shall be transferred to the Operating Trust Fund of the Division of Administrative Hearings to cover its costs associated with reviewing and hearing applications, amendments, modifications, and disputes related to ss. 403.9401-403.9425.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The balance of fees remaining shall be used by the department to reimburse affected agencies included in s. 403.941(2)(a) for costs incurred in application and postcertification review, respectively.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For application processing costs, upon presentation by an affected agency of a proper itemized accounting within 90 days after the date of the board’s order approving certification or the date on which a pending application is otherwise disposed of, the department shall reimburse the agencies for authorized costs from the fee balances remaining. Such reimbursement shall be authorized for studies and the preparation of any reports required of the agencies by ss. 403.9401-403.9425, for agency travel and per diem to attend any hearing held, and for participation in the proceedings. In the event the amount available for allocation is insufficient to provide for complete reimbursement to the agencies, reimbursement shall be on a prorated basis. If any sums are remaining, the department shall retain them for use in the same manner as is otherwise authorized by this section; however, if the certification application is withdrawn, the remaining sums shall be refunded to the applicant within 120 days after withdrawal.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For postcertification costs, an invoice may be submitted on an annual basis, commencing from the date of certification, for expenses incurred by affected agencies conducting postcertification review work pursuant to the conditions of certification. In the event the amount available for allocation is insufficient to provide for complete reimbursement to the agencies, reimbursement shall be on a prorated basis.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-284; s. 70, ch. 96-321; s. 15, ch. 2006-79.</History></Section>