<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.704" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of the department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have responsibility for the implementation and enforcement of this act. In addition to other powers and duties, the department shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and implement, in consultation with local governments, a state solid waste management program, as defined in s. 403.705.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide technical assistance to counties, municipalities, and other persons, and cooperate with appropriate federal agencies and private organizations in carrying out this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote the planning and application of recycling and resource recovery systems which preserve and enhance the quality of the air, water, and other natural resources of the state and assist in and encourage, where appropriate, the development of regional solid waste management facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as the official state representative for all purposes of the federal Solid Waste Disposal Act, as amended by Pub. L. No. 91-512, or as subsequently amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use private industry or the State University System through contractual arrangements for implementation of some or all of the requirements of the state solid waste management program and for such other activities as may be considered necessary, desirable, or convenient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage recycling and resource recovery as a source of energy and materials.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist in and encourage, as much as possible, the development within the state of industries and commercial enterprises which are based upon resource recovery, recycling, and reuse of solid waste.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine by rule the facilities, equipment, personnel, and number of monitoring wells to be provided at each solid waste disposal facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement and enforce this act, including requirements for the classification, construction, operation, maintenance, and closure of solid waste management facilities and requirements for, and conditions on, solid waste disposal in this state, whether such solid waste is generated within this state or outside this state as long as such requirements and conditions are not based on the out-of-state origin of the waste and are consistent with applicable law. When classifying solid waste management facilities, the department shall consider the hydrogeology of the site for the facility, the types of wastes to be handled by the facility, and methods used to control the types of waste to be handled by the facility and shall seek to minimize the adverse effects of solid waste management on the environment. Whenever the department adopts any rule stricter or more stringent than one that has been set by the United States Environmental Protection Agency, the procedures set forth in s. 403.804(2) shall be followed. The department shall not, however, adopt hazardous waste rules for solid waste for which special studies were required prior to October 1, 1988, under s. 8002 of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, 42 U.S.C. s. 6982, as amended, until the studies are completed by the United States Environmental Protection Agency and the information is available to the department for consideration in adopting its own rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue or modify permits on such conditions as are necessary to effect the intent and purposes of this act, and may deny or revoke permits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and implement or contract for services to develop information on recovered materials markets and strategies for market development and expansion for use of these materials. Additionally, the department shall maintain a directory of recycling businesses operating in the state and shall serve as a coordinator to match recovered materials with markets. Such directory shall be made available to the public and to local governments to assist with their solid waste management activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish accounts and deposit to the Solid Waste Management Trust Fund and control and administer moneys it may withdraw from the fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manage a program of grants, using funds from the Solid Waste Management Trust Fund and funds provided by the Legislature for solid waste management, for programs for recycling, composting, litter control, and special waste management and for programs that provide for the safe and proper management of solid waste.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Budget and receive appropriated funds and accept, receive, and administer grants or other funds or gifts from public or private agencies, including the state and the Federal Government, for the purpose of carrying out this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegate its powers, enter into contracts, or take such other actions as may be necessary to implement this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive and administer funds appropriated for county hazardous waste management assessments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide technical assistance to local governments and regional agencies to ensure consistency between county hazardous waste management assessments; coordinate the development of such assessments with the assistance of the appropriate regional planning councils; and review and make recommendations to the Legislature relative to the sufficiency of the assessments to meet state hazardous waste management needs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Increase public education and public awareness of solid and hazardous waste issues by developing and promoting statewide programs of litter control, recycling, volume reduction, and proper methods of solid waste and hazardous waste management.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist the hazardous waste storage, treatment, or disposal industry by providing to the industry any data produced on the types and quantities of hazardous waste generated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Institute a hazardous waste emergency response program which would include emergency telecommunication capabilities and coordination with appropriate agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules necessary to accept delegation of the hazardous waste management program from the Environmental Protection Agency under the Hazardous and Solid Waste Amendments of 1984, Pub. L. No. 98-616.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules, if necessary, to address the incineration and disposal of biomedical waste and the management of biological waste within the state, whether such waste is generated within this state or outside this state, as long as such requirements and conditions are not based on the out-of-state origin of the waste and are consistent with applicable provisions of law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-342; s. 1, ch. 75-54; s. 2, ch. 78-387; s. 5, ch. 80-302; ss. 21, 32, ch. 83-310; s. 31, ch. 84-338; s. 32, ch. 86-186; s. 6, ch. 88-130; s. 10, ch. 93-207; s. 3, ch. 96-284; s. 67, ch. 96-321; s. 104, ch. 98-200; s. 7, ch. 2007-184.</History></Section>