<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.9408" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of completeness.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 days after receipt of an application, the department shall file a statement with the Division of Administrative Hearings and with the applicant declaring its position with regard to the completeness, not the sufficiency, of the application.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department declares the application to be incomplete, the applicant, within 15 days after the filing of the statement by the department, shall file with the Division of Administrative Hearings and with the department a statement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agreeing with the statement of the department and withdrawing the application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agreeing with the statement of the department and agreeing to amend the application without withdrawing it. The time schedules referencing a complete application under ss. 403.9401-403.9425 shall not commence until the application is determined complete; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contesting the statement of the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant contests the determination by the department that an application is incomplete, the administrative law judge shall schedule a hearing on the statement of completeness. The hearing shall be held as expeditiously as possible, but not later than 30 days after the filing of the statement by the department. The administrative law judge shall render a decision within 10 days after the hearing.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge determines that the application was not complete as filed, the applicant shall withdraw the application or make such additional submittals as necessary to complete it. The time schedules referencing a complete application under ss. 403.9401-403.9425 shall not commence until the application is determined complete.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the administrative law judge determines that the application was complete at the time it was filed, the time schedules referencing a complete application under ss. 403.9401-403.9425 shall commence upon such determination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-284; s. 173, ch. 96-410.</History></Section>