<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Environmental Protection; powers and duties enumerated.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the following powers and duties in relation to this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this act, including rules setting forth environmental precautions to be followed in relation to the location, construction, and operation of electrical power plants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prescribe the form and content of the public notices and the notice of intent and the form, content, and necessary supporting documentation and studies to be prepared by the applicant for electrical power plant certification applications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive applications for electrical power plant certifications and to determine the completeness and sufficiency thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make, or contract for, studies of electrical power plant certification applications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To administer the processing of applications for electric power plant certifications and to ensure that the applications are processed as expeditiously as possible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require such fees as allowed by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conduct studies and prepare a project analysis under s. 403.507.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prescribe the means for monitoring the effects arising from the construction and operation of electrical power plants to assure continued compliance with terms of the certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To determine whether an alternate corridor proposed for consideration under s. 403.5064(4) is acceptable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act as clerk for the siting board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To administer and manage the terms and conditions of the certification order and supporting documents and records for the life of the electrical power plant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To issue emergency orders on behalf of the board for facilities licensed under this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-33; s. 1, ch. 76-76; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 132, ch. 79-190; s. 4, ch. 81-131; s. 35, ch. 81-167; s. 35, ch. 83-55; s. 23, ch. 86-186; s. 4, ch. 90-331; s. 7, ch. 93-94; s. 384, ch. 94-356; s. 102, ch. 98-200; s. 21, ch. 2006-230; s. 68, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>