<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.8055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department adoption of federal standards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 120.54 and 403.804, the secretary is empowered to adopt rules substantively identical to regulations adopted in the Federal Register by the United States Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to federal law, in accordance with the following procedures:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary shall publish notice of intent to adopt a rule pursuant to this section in the Florida Administrative Weekly at least 21 days prior to filing the rule with the Department of State. The secretary shall mail a copy of the notice of intent to adopt a rule to the Administrative Procedures Committee at least 21 days prior to the date of filing with the Department of State. Prior to filing the rule with the Department of State, the secretary shall consider any written comments received within 21 days after the date of publication of the notice of intent to adopt a rule. The rule shall be adopted upon filing with the Department of State. Substantive changes from the rules as noticed shall require republishing of notice as required in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any rule adopted pursuant to this section shall become effective upon the date designated in the rule by the secretary; however, no such rule shall become effective earlier than the effective date of the substantively identical United States Environmental Protection Agency regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary shall stay any terms or conditions of a permit implementing department rules adopted pursuant to this section if the substantively identical provisions of a United States Environmental Protection Agency regulation have been stayed under federal judicial review. A stay issued pursuant to this subsection shall terminate upon completion of federal judicial review.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any domestic for-profit or nonprofit corporation or association formed, in whole or in part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote conservation or natural beauty;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To protect the environment, personal health, or other biological values;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To preserve historical sites;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote consumer interests;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To represent labor, commercial, or industrial groups; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote orderly development;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and any other substantially affected person may, within 14 days after the date of publication of the notice of intent to adopt a rule, file an objection to rulemaking with the Environmental Regulation Commission. The objection shall specify the portions of the proposed rule to which the person objects and the reasons for the objection. The secretary shall not have the authority under this section to adopt those portions of a proposed rule specified in such objection. Objections which are frivolous shall not be considered sufficient to prohibit the secretary from adopting rules under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever all or part of any rule proposed for adoption by the department is substantively identical to a regulation adopted in the Federal Register by the United States Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to federal law, such rule shall be written in a manner so that the rule specifically references such regulation whenever possible.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 80-66; s. 11, ch. 82-27; s. 38, ch. 88-130.</History></Section>