<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.864" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public water supply accounting program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to require a yearly accounting of funds, overhead, personnel, and property used by the department and the Department of Health and its units, including each of the county health departments, in conducting their respective responsibilities for the state public water supply program. Such accounting shall be presented to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by the department and the Department of Health no later than February 1 of each year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In furtherance of this intent, the Department of Health and the department shall jointly develop an accounting program for use by the department and the Department of Health and its units, including the county health departments, to determine the funds, overhead, personnel, and property used by each of the departments in conducting its respective public water supply functions and responsibilities for each fiscal year. The accounting program shall provide information sufficient to satisfy state auditing and federal grant and aid reporting requirements and shall include provisions requiring the Department of Health to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Segregate, from an accounting standpoint, funds distributed to county health departments for public water supply functions from other county health department trust funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Segregate, from an accounting standpoint, funds distributed to the central and branch laboratories of the Department of Health for public water supply functions from other laboratory funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require each county health department, the central and each branch laboratory of the Department of Health, and any other entity of the Department of Health involved in and carrying out public water supply functions to account to the Department of Health on a semiannual basis for the funds received, from whatever source, and used for public water supply functions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require each county health department, the central and each branch laboratory of the Department of Health, and any other entity of the Department of Health involved in carrying out public water supply functions either wholly or partially with funds, either federal or state, received from the department through an interagency agreement or other means to account to the department on a semiannual basis for such funds received and used for public water supply functions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 77-337; s. 100, ch. 79-164; s. 5, ch. 95-144; s. 173, ch. 99-8; s. 113, ch. 2001-266.</History></Section>