<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.5315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Modification of certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certification may be modified after issuance in any one of the following ways:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may delegate to the department the authority to modify specific conditions in the certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee may file a petition for modification with the department, or the department may initiate the modification upon its own initiative.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for modification must set forth:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed modification;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The factual reasons asserted for the modification; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The anticipated additional environmental effects of the proposed modification.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may modify the terms and conditions of the certification if no party objects in writing to the modification within 45 days after notice by mail to the last address of record in the certification proceeding, and if no other person whose substantial interests will be affected by the modification objects in writing within 30 days after issuance of public notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If objections are raised or the department denies the proposed modification, the licensee may file a request for hearing on the modification with the department. Such a request shall be handled pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request for hearing referred to the Division of Administrative Hearings shall be disposed of in the same manner as an application but with time periods established by the administrative law judge commensurate with the significance of the modification requested.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-65; s. 15, ch. 83-222; s. 41, ch. 90-331; s. 155, ch. 96-410; s. 62, ch. 2006-230.</History></Section>