<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.5115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following notices are to be published by the applicant for all applications:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the filing of a notice of intent under s. 403.5063, which shall be published within 21 days after the filing of the notice. The notice shall be published as specified by subsection (2), except that the newspaper notice shall be one-fourth page in size in a standard size newspaper or one-half page in size in a tabloid size newspaper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of filing of the application, which shall include a description of the proceedings required by this act, within 21 days after the date of the application filing. Such notice shall give notice of the provisions of s. 403.511(1) and (2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, notice of the land use determination made pursuant to s. 403.50665(2) within 21 days after the deadline for the filing of the determination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, notice of the land use hearing, which shall be published as specified in subsection (2), no later than 15 days before the hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the certification hearing and notice of the deadline for filing notice of intent to be a party, which shall be published as specified in subsection (2), at least 65 days before the date set for the certification hearing. If one or more alternate corridors have been accepted for consideration, the notice of the certification hearing shall include a map of all corridors proposed for certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of revised deadline for filing alternate corridors if the certification hearing is rescheduled to a date other than as published in the notice of filing of the application. This notice shall be published at least 185 days before the rescheduled certification hearing and as specified in subsection (2), except no map is required and the size of the notice shall be no smaller than 6 square inches.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the cancellation of the certification hearing, if applicable, no later than 3 days before the date of the originally scheduled certification hearing. The newspaper notice shall be one-fourth page in size in a standard size newspaper or one-half page in size in a tabloid size newspaper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of modification when required by the department, based on whether the requested modification of certification will significantly increase impacts to the environment or the public. Such notice shall be published as specified under subsection (2):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 21 days after receipt of a request for modification. The newspaper notice shall be of a size as directed by the department commensurate with the scope of the modification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a hearing is to be conducted in response to the request for modification, then notice shall be published no later than 30 days before the hearing.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notices provided by the applicant shall be published in newspapers of general circulation within the county or counties in which the proposed electrical power plant will be located. The newspaper notices, unless otherwise specified, shall be at least one-half page in size in a standard size newspaper or a full page in a tabloid size newspaper. These notices shall include a map generally depicting the project and all associated facilities corridors. A newspaper of general circulation shall be the newspaper which has the largest daily circulation in that county and has its principal office in that county. If the newspaper with the largest daily circulation has its principal office outside the county, the notices shall appear in both the newspaper having the largest circulation in that county and in a newspaper authorized to publish legal notices in that county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All notices published by the applicant shall be paid for by the applicant and shall be in addition to the application fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall arrange for publication of the following notices in the manner specified by chapter 120 and provide copies of those notices to any persons who have requested to be placed on the departmental mailing list for this purpose:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the filing of the notice of intent within 15 days after receipt of the notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the filing of the application, no later than 21 days after the application filing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the land use determination made pursuant to s. 403.50665(2) within 21 days after the determination is filed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the land use hearing before the administrative law judge, if applicable, no later than 15 days before the hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the land use hearing before the board, if applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the certification hearing at least 45 days before the date set for the certification hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the revised deadline for filing alternate corridors if the certification hearing is rescheduled to a date other than as published in the notice of filing of the application. This notice shall be published at least 185 days before the rescheduled certification hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the cancellation of the certification hearing, if applicable, no later than 3 days prior to the date of the originally scheduled certification hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the hearing before the board, if applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of stipulations, proposed agency action, or petitions for modification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government or regional planning council that proposes to conduct an informational public meeting pursuant to s. 403.50663 must publish notice of the meeting in a newspaper of general circulation within the county or counties in which the proposed electrical power plant will be located no later than 7 days prior to the meeting. A newspaper of general circulation shall be the newspaper that has the largest daily circulation in that county and has its principal office in that county. If the newspaper with the largest daily circulation has its principal office outside the county, the notices shall appear in both the newspaper having the largest circulation in that county and in a newspaper authorized to publish legal notices in that county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A good faith effort shall be made by the applicant to provide direct written notice of the filing of an application for certification by United States mail or hand delivery no later than 45 days after filing of the application to all local landowners whose property, as noted in the most recent local government tax records, and residences are located within the following distances of the proposed project:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three miles of the proposed main site boundaries of the proposed electrical power plant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One-quarter mile for a transmission line corridor that only includes a transmission line as defined by s. 403.522(22).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One-quarter mile for all other linear associated facilities extending away from the main site boundary except for a transmission line corridor that includes a transmission line that operates below those defined by s. 403.522(22).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 60 days from the filing of an application for certification, the applicant shall file a list with the department’s Siting Coordination Office of landowners and residences that were notified.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A good faith effort shall be made by the proponent of an alternate corridor that includes a transmission line, as defined by s. 403.522(22), to provide direct written notice of the filing of an alternate corridor for certification by United States mail or hand delivery of the filing no later than 30 days after filing of the alternate corridor to all local landowners whose property, as noted in the most recent local government tax records, and residences, are located within one-quarter mile of the proposed boundaries of a transmission line corridor that includes a transmission line as defined by s. 403.522(22).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 45 days from the filing of an alternate corridor for certification, the proponent of an alternate corridor shall file a list with the department’s Siting Coordination Office of landowners and residences that were notified.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 90-331; s. 12, ch. 93-94; s. 36, ch. 2006-230; s. 80, ch. 2008-227; s. 49, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>