<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.721" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards, requirements, and procedures for generators and transporters of hazardous waste and owners and operators of hazardous waste facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who generate or transport hazardous waste, or who own or operate a hazardous waste facility, shall comply with the applicable standards, requirements, and procedures of this act and the rules adopted pursuant to it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish by rule such standards, requirements, and procedures as are needed to protect human health and the environment, which standards, requirements, and procedures shall apply to persons who generate or transport hazardous waste; to persons who own or operate hazardous waste disposal, storage, or treatment facilities; and to hazardous waste disposal facilities. The department may establish standards, requirements, and procedures which may vary based on differences in amounts of, types of, concentrations of, and methods of handling hazardous waste and on differences in the size and location of hazardous waste facilities and which may take into account standards, requirements, and procedures imposed by other laws not in conflict with this act. Solid waste determined to be special wastes by the United States Environmental Protection Agency shall be regulated pursuant to this act consistent with federal regulations for special wastes under Subtitle C of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, with respect to generators of hazardous waste identified or listed pursuant to this act, shall adopt rules governing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recordkeeping practices that accurately identify the quantities of such hazardous waste generated, the constituents thereof which are significant in quantity or in potential harm to human health or the environment, and the method of disposal of such wastes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Labeling practices for any containers used for the disposal, storage, or transport of such hazardous waste which accurately identify such waste;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of appropriate containers for such hazardous waste;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The furnishing of information on the general elemental and chemical composition of such hazardous waste to persons transporting, treating, storing, or disposing of such wastes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of a manifest system to assure that all such hazardous waste generated is designated for treatment, storage, or disposal in treatment, storage, or disposal facilities, other than facilities on the premises where the waste is generated, for which a permit has been issued; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission of reports and inspection of manifests to describe the quantities of hazardous waste which are identified or listed pursuant to this act and which have been generated or transported during a particular time period to show their disposition and certification of the generator’s efforts to reduce their amount and toxicity.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, with respect to transporters of hazardous waste identified or listed pursuant to this act, shall adopt rules governing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Liability and financial responsibility for any liability which may be incurred in the transport of hazardous waste;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recordkeeping concerning the source, transport, and delivery of hazardous waste;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transportation of hazardous waste, requiring that such waste be properly labeled;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with the manifest system required in paragraph (3)(e);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transportation of all such hazardous waste only to the hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facilities designated by the shipper on the manifest form, which facility shall be a facility holding a permit; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of appropriate containers for transporting such hazardous waste.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any hazardous waste and transporters of hazardous waste, which also meet the definitions and criteria for hazardous materials and transporters of hazardous materials regulated by the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act, 88 Stat. 2156, 49 U.S.C. ss. 1801 et seq., the department shall consider and adopt, as appropriate, rules which are consistent with such act and the rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, with respect to owners and operators of hazardous waste disposal, storage, or treatment facilities, and with respect to such facilities, shall adopt rules governing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintenance of records concerning all hazardous wastes which are identified or listed pursuant to this act and which are treated, stored, or disposed of and the manner of treatment, storage, or disposal;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfactory reporting, monitoring, and inspection for compliance with the manifest system required in paragraph (3)(e);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The treatment, storage, or disposal of all hazardous waste received by the facility pursuant to operating methods, techniques, and practices approved by the department;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location, design, and construction of such hazardous waste treatment, disposal, or storage facilities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingency plans for effective action to minimize unanticipated damage resulting from any accident occurring during the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintenance or operation of such facilities and the requirement of such additional qualifications as to ownership, continuity of operation, training for personnel, and financial responsibility as may be necessary or desirable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with s. 403.722.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corrective action at a hazardous waste facility which shall be taken beyond a facility boundary where necessary to protect human health and the environment, unless the owner or operator demonstrates that despite her or his best efforts she or he was unable to obtain the necessary permission to undertake such action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conditions on a permit which require cleanup of releases of hazardous waste and hazardous constituents from any solid waste management unit, regardless of when the waste was placed in the unit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Groundwater monitoring, unsaturated zone monitoring, and corrective action requirements for land disposal facilities accepting hazardous waste after July 26, 1982.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prohibition of the land disposal and storage of certain hazardous waste based on the requirements and criteria set forth in s. 201(g)-(j) of the Hazardous and Solid Waste Amendments of 1984, Pub. L. No. 98-616.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules governing the production, burning, marketing, sale, and distribution of hazardous waste fuel. The department may provide for exemptions to such rules so long as the exemptions are no less stringent than those provided by federal law or regulation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 80-302; s. 22, ch. 83-310; s. 33, ch. 86-186; s. 66, ch. 90-331; s. 17, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>