<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.854" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Variances, exemptions, and waivers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may authorize variances or exemptions from the regulations issued pursuant to s. 403.853 under conditions and in such manner as it deems necessary and desirable, provided that such variances or exemptions are authorized under such conditions and in such manner as are no less stringent than the conditions under which and the manner in which variances and exemptions may be granted under the federal act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall exempt public water systems from any requirements respecting a maximum contaminant level or any treatment technique requirement, or both, when:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Due to compelling factors (which may include economic factors), the public water system is unable to comply with such contaminant level or treatment technique requirement;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public water system was in operation on the effective date of such contaminant level or treatment technique requirement; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The granting of the exemption will not result in an unreasonable risk to health.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proposed additions to existing treatment plants not under contract for construction on July 1, 1977, shall not be automatically exempt.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department receives an application for exemption, it shall act upon such application within a time period under Pub. L. No. 93-523, s. 1416(g), or the Florida Administrative Procedure Act, whichever is earlier.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prescribe a compliance schedule for the exempted system and shall notify the Environmental Protection Agency Administrator personally by certified mail pursuant to Pub. L. No. 93-523, s. 1416(b) and (c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, except upon a showing of good cause, waive on a case-by-case basis any disinfection requirement applicable to transient noncommunity water systems using groundwater as a source of supply upon an affirmative showing by the supplier of water that no hazard to health will result. This showing shall be based upon the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The completion of a satisfactory sanitary survey;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The history of the quality of water provided by the system and monthly monitoring tests for bacteriological contamination;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation of the well and the site on which it is located, including geology, depth of well, casing, grouting, and other relevant factors which have an impact on the quality of water supplied; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of connections and size of the distribution system.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may as a condition of waiver require a monitoring program of sufficient frequency to assure that safe drinking water standards are being met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, except upon a showing of good cause, waive on a case-by-case basis any requirement for a certified operator for a transient noncommunity water system using groundwater as a source of supply upon an affirmative showing by the supplier of water that the system can be properly maintained without a certified operator. The department shall consider:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The results of a sanitary survey if deemed necessary;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation and maintenance records for the year preceding an application for waiver;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adequacy of monitoring procedures for maximum contaminant levels included in primary drinking water regulations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The feasibility of the supplier of water becoming a certified operator; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any threat to public health that could result from nonattendance of the system by a certified operator.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A waiver shall be granted for 3 years and shall be renewable upon application to the department pursuant to subsection (4) or subsection (5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may revoke any waiver to protect the public health, provided the department finds, on the basis of technical evidence, that revocation is necessary to achieve compliance with state quality standards for safe drinking water or that the supplier of water fails to comply with any conditions of the waiver. The department may proceed under s. 403.855 or s. 403.860.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the department nor any of its employees shall be held liable for money damages for any injury, sickness, or death sustained by any person as a result of drinking water from any transient noncommunity water system granted a waiver under subsection (4) or subsection (5).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 77-337; s. 1, ch. 80-417; s. 70, ch. 90-331; s. 39, ch. 91-305; s. 4, ch. 2001-270.</History></Section>