<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In construing this chapter, or rules and regulations adopted pursuant hereto, the following words, phrases, or terms, unless the context otherwise indicates, have the following meanings:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contaminant” is any substance which is harmful to plant, animal, or human life.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Effluent limitations” means any restriction established by the department on quantities, rates, or concentrations of chemical, physical, biological, or other constituents which are discharged from sources into waters of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Installation” is any structure, equipment, or facility, or appurtenances thereto, or operation which may emit air or water contaminants in quantities prohibited by rules of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means the state or any agency or institution thereof, the United States or any agency or institution thereof, or any municipality, political subdivision, public or private corporation, individual, partnership, association, or other entity and includes any officer or governing or managing body of the state, the United States, any agency, any municipality, political subdivision, or public or private corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plant” is any unit operation, complex, area, or multiple of unit operations that produce, process, or cause to be processed any materials, the processing of which can, or may, cause air or water pollution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pollution” is the presence in the outdoor atmosphere or waters of the state of any substances, contaminants, noise, or manmade or human-induced impairment of air or waters or alteration of the chemical, physical, biological, or radiological integrity of air or water in quantities or at levels which are or may be potentially harmful or injurious to human health or welfare, animal or plant life, or property or which unreasonably interfere with the enjoyment of life or property, including outdoor recreation unless authorized by applicable law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pollution prevention” means the steps taken by a potential generator of contamination or pollution to eliminate or reduce the contamination or pollution before it is discharged into the environment. The term includes nonmandatory steps taken to use alternative forms of energy, conserve or reduce the use of energy, substitute nontoxic materials for toxic materials, conserve or reduce the use of toxic materials and raw materials, reformulate products, modify manufacturing or other processes, improve in-plant maintenance and operations, implement environmental planning before expanding a facility, and recycle toxic or other raw materials.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sewerage system” means pipelines or conduits, pumping stations, and force mains and all other structures, devices, appurtenances, and facilities used for collecting or conducting wastes to an ultimate point for treatment or disposal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Source” is any and all points of origin of the item defined in subsection (1), whether privately or publicly owned or operated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Treatment works” and “disposal systems” mean any plant or other works used for the purpose of treating, stabilizing, or holding wastes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wastes” means sewage, industrial wastes, and all other liquid, gaseous, solid, radioactive, or other substances which may pollute or tend to pollute any waters of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Waters” include, but are not limited to, rivers, lakes, streams, springs, impoundments, wetlands, and all other waters or bodies of water, including fresh, brackish, saline, tidal, surface, or underground waters. Waters owned entirely by one person other than the state are included only in regard to possible discharge on other property or water. Underground waters include, but are not limited to, all underground waters passing through pores of rock or soils or flowing through in channels, whether manmade or natural. Solely for purposes of s. 403.0885, waters of the state also include navigable waters or waters of the contiguous zone as used in s. 502 of the Clean Water Act, as amended, 33 U.S.C. ss. 1251 et seq., as in existence on January 1, 1993, except for those navigable waters seaward of the boundaries of the state set forth in s. 1, Art. II of the State Constitution. Solely for purposes of this chapter, waters of the state also include the area bounded by the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commence at the intersection of State Road (SRD) 5 (U.S. 1) and the county line dividing Miami-Dade and Monroe Counties, said point also being the mean high-water line of Florida Bay, located in section 4, township 60 south, range 39 east of the Tallahassee Meridian for the point of beginning. From said point of beginning, thence run northwesterly along said SRD 5 to an intersection with the north line of section 18, township 58 south, range 39 east; thence run westerly to a point marking the southeast corner of section 12, township 58 south, range 37 east, said point also lying on the east boundary of the Everglades National Park; thence run north along the east boundary of the aforementioned Everglades National Park to a point marking the northeast corner of section 1, township 58 south, range 37 east; thence run west along said park to a point marking the northwest corner of said section 1; thence run northerly along said park to a point marking the northwest corner of section 24, township 57 south, range 37 east; thence run westerly along the south lines of sections 14, 15, and 16 to the southwest corner of section 16; thence leaving the Everglades National Park boundary run northerly along the west line of section 16 to the northwest corner of section 16; thence east along the northerly line of section 16 to a point at the intersection of the east one-half and west one-half of section 9; thence northerly along the line separating the east one-half and the west one-half of sections 9, 4, 33, and 28; thence run easterly along the north line of section 28 to the northeast corner of section 28; thence run northerly along the west line of section 22 to the northwest corner of section 22; thence easterly along the north line of section 22 to a point at the intersection of the east one-half and west one-half of section 15; thence run northerly along said line to the point of intersection with the north line of section 15; thence easterly along the north line of section 15 to the northeast corner of section 15; thence run northerly along the west lines of sections 11 and 2 to the northwest corner of section 2; thence run easterly along the north lines of sections 2 and 1 to the northeast corner of section 1, township 56 south, range 37 east; thence run north along the east line of section 36, township 55 south, range 37 east to the northeast corner of section 36; thence run west along the north line of section 36 to the northwest corner of section 36; thence run north along the west line of section 25 to the northwest corner of section 25; thence run west along the north line of section 26 to the northwest corner of section 26; thence run north along the west line of section 23 to the northwest corner of section 23; thence run easterly along the north line of section 23 to the northeast corner of section 23; thence run north along the west line of section 13 to the northwest corner of section 13; thence run east along the north line of section 13 to a point of intersection with the west line of the southeast one-quarter of section 12; thence run north along the west line of the southeast one-quarter of section 12 to the northwest corner of the southeast one-quarter of section 12; thence run east along the north line of the southeast one-quarter of section 12 to the point of intersection with the east line of section 12; thence run east along the south line of the northwest one-quarter of section 7 to the southeast corner of the northwest one-quarter of section 7; thence run north along the east line of the northwest one-quarter of section 7 to the point of intersection with the north line of section 7; thence run northerly along the west line of the southeast one-quarter of section 6 to the northwest corner of the southeast one-quarter of section 6; thence run east along the north lines of the southeast one-quarter of section 6 and the southwest one-quarter of section 5 to the northeast corner of the southwest one-quarter of section 5; thence run northerly along the east line of the northwest one-quarter of section 5 to the point of intersection with the north line of section 5; thence run northerly along the line dividing the east one-half and the west one-half of Lot 5 to a point intersecting the north line of Lot 5; thence run east along the north line of Lot 5 to the northeast corner of Lot 5, township 54<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> south, range 38 east; thence run north along the west line of section 33, township 54 south, range 38 east to a point intersecting the northwest corner of the southwest one-quarter of section 33; thence run easterly along the north line of the southwest one-quarter of section 33 to the northeast corner of the southwest one-quarter of section 33; thence run north along the west line of the northeast one-quarter of section 33 to a point intersecting the north line of section 33; thence run easterly along the north line of section 33 to the northeast corner of section 33; thence run northerly along the west line of section 27 to a point intersecting the northwest corner of the southwest one-quarter of section 27; thence run easterly to the northeast corner of the southwest one-quarter of section 27; thence run northerly along the west line of the northeast one-quarter of section 27 to a point intersecting the north line of section 27; thence run west along the north line of section 27 to the northwest corner of section 27; thence run north along the west lines of sections 22 and 15 to the northwest corner of section 15; thence run easterly along the north lines of sections 15 and 14 to the point of intersection with the L-31N Levee, said intersection located near the southeast corner of section 11, township 54 south, range 38 east; thence run northerly along Levee L-31N crossing SRD 90 (U.S. 41 Tamiami Trail) to an intersection common to Levees L-31N, L-29, and L-30, said intersection located near the southeast corner of section 2, township 54 south, range 38 east; thence run northeasterly, northerly, and northeasterly along Levee L-30 to a point of intersection with the Miami-Dade/Broward Levee, said intersection located near the northeast corner of section 17, township 52 south, range 39 east; thence run due east to a point of intersection with SRD 27 (Krome Ave.); thence run northeasterly along SRD 27 to an intersection with SRD 25 (U.S. 27), said intersection located in section 3, township 52 south, range 39 east; thence run northerly along said SRD 25, entering into Broward County, to an intersection with SRD 84 at Andytown; thence run southeasterly along the aforementioned SRD 84 to an intersection with the southwesterly prolongation of Levee L-35A, said intersection being located in the northeast one-quarter of section 5, township 50 south, range 40 east; thence run northeasterly along Levee L-35A to an intersection of Levee L-36, said intersection located near the southeast corner of section 12, township 49 south, range 40 east; thence run northerly along Levee L-36, entering into Palm Beach County, to an intersection common to said Levees L-36, L-39, and L-40, said intersection located near the west quarter corner of section 19, township 47 south, range 41 east; thence run northeasterly, easterly, and northerly along Levee L-40, said Levee L-40 being the easterly boundary of the Loxahatchee National Wildlife Refuge, to an intersection with SRD 80 (U.S. 441), said intersection located near the southeast corner of section 32, township 43 south, range 40 east; thence run westerly along the aforementioned SRD 80 to a point marking the intersection of said road and the northeasterly prolongation of Levee L-7, said Levee L-7 being the westerly boundary of the Loxahatchee National Wildlife Refuge; thence run southwesterly and southerly along said Levee L-7 to an intersection common to Levees L-7, L-15 (Hillsborough Canal), and L-6; thence run southwesterly along Levee L-6 to an intersection common to Levee L-6, SRD 25 (U.S. 27), and Levee L-5, said intersection being located near the northwest corner of section 27, township 47 south, range 38 east; thence run westerly along the aforementioned Levee L-5 to a point intersecting the east line of range 36 east; thence run northerly along said range line to a point marking the northeast corner of section 1, township 47 south, range 36 east; thence run westerly along the north line of township 47 south, to an intersection with Levee L-23/24 (Miami Canal); thence run northwesterly along the Miami Canal Levee to a point intersecting the north line of section 22, township 46 south, range 35 east; thence run westerly to a point marking the northwest corner of section 21, township 46 south, range 35 east; thence run southerly to the southwest corner of said section 21; thence run westerly to a point marking the northwest corner of section 30, township 46 south, range 35 east, said point also being on the line dividing Palm Beach and Hendry Counties; from said point, thence run southerly along said county line to a point marking the intersection of Broward, Hendry, and Collier Counties, said point also being the northeast corner of section 1, township 49 south, range 34 east; thence run westerly along the line dividing Hendry and Collier Counties and continuing along the prolongation thereof to a point marking the southwest corner of section 36, township 48 south, range 29 east; thence run southerly to a point marking the southwest corner of section 12, township 49 south, range 29 east; thence run westerly to a point marking the southwest corner of section 10, township 49 south, range 29 east; thence run southerly to a point marking the southwest corner of section 15, township 49 south, range 29 east; thence run westerly to a point marking the northwest corner of section 24, township 49 south, range 28 east, said point lying on the west boundary of the Big Cypress Area of Critical State Concern as described in rule 28-25.001, Florida Administrative Code; thence run southerly along said boundary crossing SRD 84 (Alligator Alley) to a point marking the southwest corner of section 24, township 50 south, range 28 east; thence leaving the aforementioned west boundary of the Big Cypress Area of Critical State Concern run easterly to a point marking the northeast corner of section 25, township 50 south, range 28 east; thence run southerly along the east line of range 28 east to a point lying approximately 0.15 miles south of the northeast corner of section 1, township 52 south, range 28 east; thence run southwesterly 2.4 miles more or less to an intersection with SRD 90 (U.S. 41 Tamiami Trail), said intersection lying 1.1 miles more or less west of the east line of range 28 east; thence run northwesterly and westerly along SRD 90 to an intersection with the west line of section 10, township 52 south, range 28 east; thence leaving SRD 90 run southerly to a point marking the southwest corner of section 15, township 52 south, range 28 east; thence run westerly crossing the Faka Union Canal 0.6 miles more or less to a point; thence run southerly and parallel to the Faka Union Canal to a point located on the mean high-water line of Faka Union Bay; thence run southeasterly along the mean high-water line of the various bays, rivers, inlets, and streams to the point of beginning.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The area bounded by the line described in paragraph (a) generally includes those waters to be known as waters of the state. The landward extent of these waters shall be determined by the delineation methodology ratified in s. 373.4211. Any waters which are outside the general boundary line described in paragraph (a) but which are contiguous thereto by virtue of the presence of a wetland, watercourse, or other surface water, as determined by the delineation methodology ratified in s. 373.4211, shall be a part of this water body. Any areas within the line described in paragraph (a) which are neither a wetland nor surface water, as determined by the delineation methodology ratified in s. 373.4211, shall be excluded therefrom. If the Florida Environmental Regulation Commission designates the waters within the boundaries an Outstanding Florida Water, waters outside the boundaries shall not be included as part of such designation unless a hearing is held pursuant to notice in each appropriate county and the boundaries of such lands are specifically considered and described for such designation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State water resource implementation rule” means the rule authorized by s. 373.036, which sets forth goals, objectives, and guidance for the development and review of programs, rules, and plans relating to water resources, based on statutory policies and directives. The waters of the state are among its most basic resources. Such waters should be managed to conserve and protect water resources and to realize the full beneficial use of these resources.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stormwater management program” means the institutional strategy for stormwater management, including urban, agricultural, and other stormwater.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stormwater management system” means a system which is designed and constructed or implemented to control discharges which are necessitated by rainfall events, incorporating methods to collect, convey, store, absorb, inhibit, treat, use, or reuse water to prevent or reduce flooding, overdrainage, environmental degradation and water pollution or otherwise affect the quantity and quality of discharges from the system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stormwater utility” means the funding of a stormwater management program by assessing the cost of the program to the beneficiaries based on their relative contribution to its need. It is operated as a typical utility which bills services regularly, similar to water and wastewater services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Watershed” means the land area which contributes to the flow of water into a receiving body of water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Regulated air pollutant” means any pollutant regulated under the federal Clean Air Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electrical power plant” means, for purposes of this part of this chapter, any electrical generating facility that uses any process or fuel and that is owned or operated by an electric utility, as defined in s. 403.503(14), and includes any associated facility that directly supports the operation of the electrical power plant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Total maximum daily load” is defined as the sum of the individual wasteload allocations for point sources and the load allocations for nonpoint sources and natural background. Prior to determining individual wasteload allocations and load allocations, the maximum amount of a pollutant that a water body or water segment can assimilate from all sources without exceeding water quality standards must first be calculated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 67-436; ss. 26, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 71-36; s. 2, ch. 71-137; s. 153, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 73-46; s. 112, ch. 73-333; ss. 1, 2, ch. 74-133; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 72, ch. 79-65; s. 13, ch. 84-79; s. 1, ch. 89-143; s. 30, ch. 89-279; s. 22, ch. 91-305; s. 1, ch. 92-132; s. 1, ch. 93-94; ss. 35, 69, ch. 93-213; ss. 12, 13, ch. 94-122; s. 355, ch. 94-356; s. 7, ch. 96-370; s. 1005, ch. 97-103; s. 24, ch. 97-160; s. 2, ch. 99-223; s. 9, ch. 99-353; s. 42, ch. 2001-62; s. 105, ch. 2008-4; s. 15, ch. 2008-150; s. 64, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>