<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0403.74" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Management of hazardous materials by governmental agencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, “hazardous materials” are those substances which are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Listed as constituents of waste streams F001, F002, F003, F004, and F005 in 40 C.F.R. s. 261.31, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Listed in 40 C.F.R. s. 261.33, including those substances which are “pesticides” as defined by s. 487.021.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every local, state, or other governmental agency and every institution of the State University System that disposes of hazardous materials shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the department of the type and approximate annual quantity of each hazardous material that is generated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the department of the management practices used for disposal of its hazardous materials.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each such agency shall develop written plans for the management of the disposal of hazardous material.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each such agency shall develop plans for spill prevention control and countermeasures for hazardous materials incidents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hazardous materials which are used by governmental agencies in annual quantities of less than 1 kilogram, except for those hazardous materials which are listed because of reactivity, are exempt from this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 83-310; s. 39, ch. 84-338; s. 56, ch. 85-81; s. 35, ch. 92-115; s. 415, ch. 94-356.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 501.118.</Text></Note></Section>