<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.008" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before any entity may operate a prepaid limited health service organization, it must obtain a certificate of authority from the office. An application for a certificate of authority to operate a prepaid limited health service organization must be filed with the office on a form prescribed by the commission. Such application must be sworn to by an officer or authorized representative of the applicant and be accompanied by the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the applicant’s basic organizational document, including the articles of incorporation, articles of association, partnership agreements, trust agreement, or other applicable documents and all amendments to such documents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of all bylaws, rules, and regulations, or similar documents, if any, regulating the conduct of the applicant’s internal affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of the names, addresses, official positions, and biographical information of the individuals who are responsible for conducting the applicant’s affairs, including, but not limited to, all members of the board of directors, board of trustees, executive committee, or other governing board or committee, the officers, contracted management company personnel, and any person or entity owning or having the right to acquire 10 percent or more of the voting securities of the applicant. Such listing must fully disclose the extent and nature of any contracts or arrangements between any individual who is responsible for conducting the applicant’s affairs and the prepaid limited health service organization, including any possible conflicts of interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A complete biographical statement, on forms prescribed by the commission, an independent investigation report, and a set of fingerprints, as provided in chapter 624, with respect to each individual identified under subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement generally describing the applicant, its facilities and personnel, and the limited health service or services to be offered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the form of all contracts made or to be made between the applicant and any providers regarding the provision of limited health services to enrollees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the form of any contract made or arrangement to be made between the applicant and any person listed in subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the form of any contract made or to be made between the applicant and any person, corporation, partnership, or other entity for the performance on the applicant’s behalf of any function, including, but not limited to, marketing, administration, enrollment, investment management, and subcontracting for the provision of limited health services to enrollees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the form of any prepaid limited health service contract which is to be issued to employers, unions, trustees, individuals, or other organizations and a copy of any form of evidence of coverage to be issued to subscribers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the applicant’s most recent financial statements audited by an independent certified public accountant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the applicant’s financial plan, including a 3-year projection of anticipated operating results, a statement of the sources of funding, and provisions for contingencies, for which projection all material assumptions shall be disclosed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A schedule of rates and charges for each contract to be used which contains an opinion from a qualified independent actuary or a qualified employee that the rates are not inadequate, excessive, or discriminatory. If a prepaid limited health service organization does not employ or otherwise retain the services of an independent actuary, the chief executive officer of the prepaid limited health service organization must review and sign the certification indicating her or his agreement with its conclusions. If the office determines that, based upon documents filed with the office, the qualified employee is not qualified, the organization shall retain the services of a qualified independent actuary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the proposed method of marketing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the subscriber complaint procedures to be established and maintained as required under s. 636.038.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of how the applicant will comply with s. 636.046.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for issuance of a certificate of authority as provided in s. 636.057.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other information as the commission or office may reasonably require to make the determinations required by this act.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The office shall issue a certificate of authority which shall expire on June 1 each year and which the office shall renew if the applicant pays the license fees provided in s. 636.057 and if the office is satisfied that the organization is in compliance with this act.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 93-148; s. 484, ch. 97-102; s. 1526, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>