<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Provider arrangements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a contract exists between a prepaid limited health service organization and a provider, and the organization fails to meet its obligations to pay fees for services already rendered to a subscriber who is in good standing, the prepaid limited health service organization is liable for such fee or fees rather than the subscriber, and the contract must so state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No subscriber, who is in good standing, of a prepaid limited health service organization is liable to any provider of health care services for any services covered by the prepaid limited health service organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provider of prepaid limited health care services or any representative of such provider may collect or attempt to collect from a subscriber any money for services covered by a prepaid limited health service organization, and no provider or representative of such provider may maintain any action against a subscriber of a prepaid limited health service organization to collect money owed to such provider by a prepaid limited health service organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every contract between a prepaid limited health service organization and a provider of health care services must be in writing and must contain a provision that the subscriber is not liable to the provider for any services covered by the subscriber’s or enrollee’s contract with the prepaid limited health service organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section do not apply to the amount of any deductible or copayment which is not covered by the contract, or for services not authorized by the prepaid limited health service organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all provider contracts executed after October 1, 1993, and within 180 days after October 1, 1993, for contracts in existence as of October 1, 1993:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contracts must provide that the provider will provide no less than 90 days’ advance written notice to the prepaid limited health service organization before canceling the contract with the prepaid limited health service organization for any reason.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract must also provide that nonpayment for goods or services rendered by the provider to the prepaid limited health service organization shall not be a valid reason for avoiding the 90-day advance notice of cancellation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all provider contracts in force on October 1, 1993, the organization shall be responsible for notifying all providers of the provisions of this section and their responsibilities under this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt by the prepaid limited health service organization of a 90-day cancellation notice, the prepaid limited health service organization may, if requested by the provider, terminate the contract in less than 90 days if the prepaid limited health service organization is not financially impaired or insolvent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provider contracts executed after October 1, 1997, and within 180 days after October 1, 1997, for all contracts in existence on October 1, 1997, must provide that the prepaid limited health service organization will provide 90 days’ advance written notice to the provider before canceling, without cause, the contract with the provider, except where a patient’s health is subject to imminent danger or a provider’s ability to practice is effectively impaired by an action by the Board of Dentistry or another governmental agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every contract between a prepaid limited health service organization and a provider of health care services must contain a provision that if any provision of the agreement is held to be unenforceable or otherwise contrary to any applicable laws, regulations, or rules, such provision shall have no effect and shall be severable without affecting the validity or enforceability of the remaining provisions of this agreement. This subsection applies to policies issued or renewed after October 1, 1997.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract between a prepaid limited health service organization and a provider of limited health care services may not contain any provision restricting the provider’s ability to communicate information to the provider’s patient regarding care or treatment options for the patient when the provider deems knowledge of such information by the patient to be in the best interest of the health of the patient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract between a prepaid limited health service organization and a provider of limited health services may not contain any provision that in any way prohibits or restricts the limited health service provider from entering into or renewing a contract with any other prepaid limited health service organization. This subsection applies to all contracts entered into or renewed on or after July 1, 2009.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prepaid limited health service organization may not require, as a condition of continuation or renewal of a contract, a contracted limited health service provider to accept the terms of other health care practitioner contracts with the prepaid limited health service organization or any insurer or other limited health service organization under common management and control with the prepaid limited health service organization, including, but not limited to, Medicare and Medicaid practitioner contracts and those authorized by s. 627.6471, s. 627.6472, s. 641.315, or this section, except for a practitioner in a group practice as defined in s. 456.053 who must accept the terms of a contract negotiated for the practitioner by the group. Any contract provision that violates this subsection is void. A violation of this subsection is not subject to the criminal penalty specified in s. 624.15. This subsection applies to all contracts entered into or renewed on or after July 1, 2009.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 93-148; s. 3, ch. 97-65; s. 2, ch. 2009-41.</History></Section>