<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.064" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidentiality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information pertaining to the diagnosis, treatment, or health of any enrollee of a prepaid limited health service organization is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution and shall only be available pursuant to specific written consent of the enrollee, or as otherwise provided by law. With respect to any information pertaining to the diagnosis, treatment, or health of any enrollee or applicant, a prepaid limited health service organization is entitled to claim any statutory privileges against disclosure which the provider who furnished such information to the prepaid limited health service organization is entitled to claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proprietary financial information contained in contracts entered into with providers by prepaid limited health service organizations is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information obtained or produced by the department or office pursuant to an examination or investigation is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution until the examination report has been filed pursuant to s. 624.319 or until such investigation is completed or ceases to be active. For purposes of this subsection, an investigation is considered “active” while such investigation is being conducted by the department or office with a reasonable, good faith belief that it may lead to the filing of administrative, civil, or criminal proceedings. An investigation does not cease to be active if the department or office is proceeding with reasonable dispatch and there is a good faith belief that action may be initiated by the department or office or other administrative or law enforcement agency. Except for active criminal intelligence or criminal investigative information, as defined in s. 119.011; personal financial and medical information; information that would defame or cause unwarranted damage to the good name or reputation of an individual; information that would impair the safety and financial soundness of the licensee or affiliated party; proprietary financial information; or information that would reveal the identity of a confidential source, all information obtained by the department or office pursuant to an examination or investigation shall be available after the examination report has been filed or the investigation is completed or ceases to be active.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 51, ch. 93-148; s. 1, ch. 95-134; s. 398, ch. 96-406; s. 1552, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>