<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.222" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension or revocation of license; suspension of enrollment of new members; terms of suspension.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may suspend the authority of a discount medical plan organization to enroll new members, revoke any license issued to a discount medical plan organization, or order compliance if the office finds that any of the following conditions exist:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization is not operating in compliance with this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization does not have the minimum net worth as required by this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization has advertised, merchandised, or attempted to merchandise its services in such a manner as to misrepresent its services or capacity for service or has engaged in deceptive, misleading, or unfair practices with respect to advertising or merchandising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization is not fulfilling its obligations as a medical discount medical plan organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The continued operation of the organization would be hazardous to its members.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the office has cause to believe that grounds for the suspension or revocation of a license exist, the office shall notify the discount medical plan organization in writing specifically stating the grounds for suspension or revocation and shall pursue a hearing on the matter in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the license of a discount medical plan organization is surrendered or revoked, such organization must proceed, immediately following the effective date of the order of revocation, to wind up its affairs transacted under the license. The organization may not engage in any further advertising, solicitation, collecting of fees, or renewal of contracts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall, in its order suspending the authority of a discount medical plan organization to enroll new members, specify the period during which the suspension is to be in effect and the conditions, if any, which must be met by the discount medical plan organization prior to reinstatement of its license to enroll new members. The order of suspension is subject to rescission or modification by further order of the office prior to the expiration of the suspension period. Reinstatement may not be made unless requested by the discount medical plan organization; however, the office may not grant reinstatement if it finds that the circumstances for which the suspension occurred still exist or are likely to recur.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 2004-297.</History></Section>