<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.018" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Changes in rates and benefits; material modifications; addition of limited health services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No prepaid limited health services contract, certificate of coverage, application, enrollment form, rider, endorsement, and applicable rates to be charged may be delivered in this state unless the forms and rates have been filed with the office by or on behalf of the prepaid limited health service organization and have been approved by the office. Every form filed shall be identified by a unique form number placed in the lower left corner of each form. If a prepaid limited health service organization desires to amend any contract with its subscribers or any certificate or member handbook, or desires to change any rate charged for the contract or to change any basic prepaid limited health services contract, certificate, grievance procedure, or member handbook form, or application form where written application is required and is to be made a part of the contract, or printed amendment, addendum, rider, or endorsement form or form renewal certificate, it must file such changes 30 days prior to the effective date of the proposed change. At least 30 days’ written notice must be provided to the subscriber before application of any approved change in rates. In the case of a group enrollee, there may be a contractual agreement with the prepaid limited health service organization to have the contract holder provide the required notice to the individual enrollees of the group. Any proposed change must contain information as required by s. 636.017.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prepaid limited health service organization’s certification must be prepared by an independent actuary or a qualified employee. The chief executive officer of the prepaid limited health service organization must review and sign the certification indicating her or his agreement with its conclusions. Following receipt of notice of any disapproval or withdrawal of approval, no prepaid limited health service organization may issue or use any form disapproved by the office or as to which the office has withdrawn approval.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such filings are disapproved, the office shall notify the prepaid limited health service organization and shall specify the reasons for disapproval in the notice. The prepaid limited health service organization has 21 days from the date of receipt of notice to request a hearing before the office pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 93-148; s. 486, ch. 97-102; s. 1531, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>