<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.048" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension or revocation of certificate of authority; suspension of enrollment of new subscribers; terms of suspension.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may suspend the authority of a prepaid limited health service organization to enroll new subscribers or revoke any certificate issued to a prepaid limited health service organization or order compliance within 30 days, if it finds that any of the following conditions exist:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization is not operating in compliance with this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan is no longer actuarially sound or the organization does not have the minimum surplus as required by this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization has advertised, merchandised, or attempted to merchandise its services in such a manner as to misrepresent its services or capacity for service or has engaged in deceptive, misleading, or unfair practices with respect to advertising or merchandising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization is insolvent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prepaid limited health service organization is operating significantly in contravention of its basic organizational document or in a manner contrary to that described in and reasonably inferred from any other information submitted pursuant to ss. 636.008 and 636.009, unless amendments to such submissions have been filed with and approved by the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prepaid limited health service organization is unable to fulfill its obligations to furnish limited health services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prepaid limited health service organization has no subscribers 12 months after the issuance of the certificate of authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The continued operation of the prepaid limited health service organization would be hazardous to its enrollees.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the office has cause to believe that grounds for the suspension or revocation of a certificate of authority exist, it shall notify the prepaid limited health service organization in writing specifically stating the grounds for suspension or revocation and shall pursue a hearing on the matter in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the certificate of authority of a prepaid limited health service organization is surrendered or revoked, such organization must proceed, immediately following the effective date of the order of revocation, to wind up its affairs transacted under the certificate of authority. It may not engage in any further advertising, solicitation, or renewal of contracts. The office may, by written order, permit such further operation of the organization as it finds to be in the best interest of enrollees, so that enrollees will be afforded the greatest practical opportunity to obtain continuing limited health services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall, in its order suspending the authority of a prepaid limited health service organization to enroll new subscribers, specify the period during which the suspension is to be in effect and the conditions, if any, which must be met by the prepaid limited health service organization prior to reinstatement of its authority to enroll new subscribers. The order of suspension is subject to rescission or modification by further order of the office prior to the expiration of the suspension period. Reinstatement may not be made unless requested by the prepaid limited health service organization; however, the office may not grant reinstatement if it finds that the circumstances for which the suspension occurred still exist or are likely to recur.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 39, ch. 93-148; s. 1542, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>