<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.046" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insolvency protection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as required in subsection (2), each prepaid limited health service organization must deposit with the department cash or securities of the type eligible under s. 641.35 which must have at all times a market value in the amount set forth in this subsection. The amount of the deposit shall be reviewed annually or more often as the office deems necessary. The market value of the deposit must be $50,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If securities or assets deposited by a prepaid limited health service organization under this act are subject to material fluctuations in market value, the office may in its discretion require the organization to deposit and maintain on deposit additional securities or assets in an amount as may be reasonably necessary to assure that the deposit will at all times have a market value of not less than the amount specified under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If for any reason the market value of assets and securities of a prepaid limited health service organization held on deposit under this act falls below the amount required, the organization must promptly deposit other or additional assets or securities eligible for deposit sufficient to cure the deficiency. If the prepaid limited health service organization has failed to cure the deficiency within 30 days after receipt of notice by certified mail from the office, the office may revoke the certificate of authority of the prepaid limited health service organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prepaid limited health service organization may, at its option, deposit assets or securities in an amount exceeding its deposit required or otherwise permitted under this act for the purpose of absorbing fluctuations in the value of securities and assets deposited and to facilitate the exchange and substitution of securities and assets. During the solvency of the prepaid limited health service organization any excess must be released to the organization upon its request. During the insolvency of the prepaid limited health service organization, any excess deposit may be released only as provided in s. 625.62.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All income from deposits belongs to the depositing prepaid limited health service organization and must be paid to it as it becomes available.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 93-148; s. 1540, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>