<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0636.003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Capitation” means the fixed amount paid by a prepaid limited health service organization to a health care provider under contract with the prepaid limited health service organization in exchange for the rendering of covered limited health services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enrollee” means an individual, including dependents, who is entitled to limited health services pursuant to a contract, or any other evidence of coverage, with an entity authorized to provide or arrange for such services under this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Evidence of coverage” means the certificate, agreement, membership card, or contract issued pursuant to this act setting forth the coverage to which an enrollee is entitled.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Insolvent” means that all the statutory assets of the prepaid limited health service organization, if made immediately available, would not be sufficient to discharge all of its statutory liabilities or that the prepaid limited health service organization is unable to pay its debts as they become due in the usual course of business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited health service” means ambulance services, dental care services, vision care services, mental health services, substance abuse services, chiropractic services, podiatric care services, and pharmaceutical services. “Limited health service” does not include inpatient, hospital surgical services, or emergency services except as such services are provided incident to the limited health services set forth in this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prepaid limited health service contract” means any contract entered into by a prepaid limited health service organization with a subscriber or group of subscribers to provide limited health services in exchange for a prepaid per capita or prepaid aggregate fixed sum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prepaid limited health service organization” means any person, corporation, partnership, or any other entity which, in return for a prepayment, undertakes to provide or arrange for, or provide access to, the provision of a limited health service to enrollees through an exclusive panel of providers. Prepaid limited health service organization does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An entity otherwise authorized pursuant to the laws of this state to indemnify for any limited health service;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider or entity when providing limited health services pursuant to a contract with a prepaid limited health service organization, a health maintenance organization, a health insurer, or a self-insurance plan; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is licensed pursuant to part II as a discount medical plan organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Provider” means, but is not limited to, any physician, dentist, health facility, or other person or institution which is duly licensed in this state to deliver limited health services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified independent actuary” means an actuary who is a member of the American Academy of Actuaries or the Society of Actuaries and has experience in establishing rates for limited health services and who has no financial or employment interest in the prepaid limited health service organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reporting period” means the annual accounting period or fiscal year, or any part thereof, of the prepaid limited health service organization. The calendar year shall be the fiscal year for each such organization other than those holding an existing certificate of authority as of October 1, 1993.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Subscriber” means an individual who has contracted, or arranged, or on whose behalf a contract or arrangement has been entered into, with a prepaid limited health service organization for health care services or other persons who also receive health care services as a result of the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surplus” means total statutory assets in excess of total liabilities, except that assets pledged to secure debts not reflected on the books of the prepaid limited health service organization shall not be included in surplus. Surplus includes capital stock, capital in excess of par, other contributed capital, retained earnings, and surplus notes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surplus notes” means debt which has been subordinated to all claims of subscribers and general creditors of the organization and the debt instrument shall so state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Statutory accounting principles” means generally accepted accounting principles, except as modified by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified employee” means an employee of the organization:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has a minimum of 5 years of experience in rate determinations for prepaid health services, and who demonstrates through filings with the office that the person is in fact qualified under the terms of this act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is a member of the American Academy of Actuaries or the Society of Actuaries and has experience in establishing rates for limited health service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 93-148; s. 1, ch. 97-159; s. 1523, ch. 2003-261; s. 30, ch. 2004-297.</History></Section>