<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.0025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited practices.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act as a loan originator in this state without a current, active license issued by the office pursuant to part II of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act as a mortgage broker in this state without a current, active license issued by the office pursuant to part II of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To act as a mortgage lender in this state without a current, active license issued by the office pursuant to part III of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any practice or transaction or course of business relating to the sale, purchase, negotiation, promotion, advertisement, or hypothecation of mortgage loan transactions, directly or indirectly:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To knowingly or willingly employ any device, scheme, or artifice to defraud;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To engage in any transaction, practice, or course of business which operates as a fraud upon any person in connection with the purchase or sale of any mortgage loan; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To obtain property by fraud, willful misrepresentation of a future act, or false promise.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any matter within the jurisdiction of the office, to knowingly and willfully falsify, conceal, or cover up by a trick, scheme, or device a material fact, make any false or fraudulent statement or representation, or make or use any false writing or document, knowing the same to contain any false or fraudulent statement or entry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To violate s. 655.922(2), subject to ss. 494.001-494.0077.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay a fee or commission in any mortgage loan transaction to any person or entity other than a licensed mortgage broker or mortgage lender, or a person exempt from licensure under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To record a mortgage broker agreement or any other document, not rendered by a court of competent jurisdiction, which purports to enforce the terms of the agreement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To use the name or logo of a financial institution, as defined in s. 655.005(1), or its affiliates or subsidiaries when marketing or soliciting existing or prospective customers if such marketing materials are used without the written consent of the financial institution and in a manner that would lead a reasonable person to believe that the material or solicitation originated from, was endorsed by, or is related to or the responsibility of the financial institution or its affiliates or subsidiaries.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to investigation or examination under this chapter, to knowingly alter, withhold, conceal, or destroy any books, records, computer records, or other information relating to a person’s activities which subject the person to the jurisdiction of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 16, 50, ch. 91-245; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 4, ch. 95-313; s. 7, ch. 99-213; s. 523, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2004-340; s. 84, ch. 2004-390; s. 14, ch. 2009-241.</History>
</Section>