<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0494.0075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for selling loans to noninstitutional investors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mortgage lender, when selling a mortgage loan to a noninstitutional investor, shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before any payment of money by a noninstitutional investor, provide an opinion of value from an appraiser stating the value of the security property unless the opinion is waived in writing. The opinion must state the value of the property as it exists on the date of the opinion. If any relationship exists between the lender and the appraiser, that relationship must be disclosed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to the noninstitutional investor a mortgagee’s title insurance policy or an opinion of title by an attorney licensed to practice law in this state, or a copy thereof:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a title insurance policy is issued, it must insure the noninstitutional investor against the unmarketability of the mortgagee’s interest in such title. It must also specify any superior liens that exist against the property. If an opinion of title is issued by an attorney, the opinion must include a statement as to the marketability of the title to the property described in the mortgage and specify the priority of the mortgage being purchased.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the title insurance policy or opinion of title is not available at the time of purchase, the licensee shall provide a binder of the title insurance or conditional opinion of title. This binder or opinion must include any conditions or requirements needed to be corrected before the issuance of the final title policy or opinion of title. The binder or opinion must also include information concerning the requirements specified in subparagraph 1. Any conditions must be eliminated or waived in writing by the investor before delivery to the noninstitutional investor. The policy or opinion, or a copy thereof, shall be delivered to the investor within a reasonable period of time, not exceeding 6 months, after purchase.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of this paragraph may be waived in writing. If the requirements are waived by the noninstitutional investor, the waiver must include the following wording: “The noninstitutional investor acknowledges that the mortgage lender selling this mortgage loan is not providing a title insurance policy or opinion of title issued by an attorney who is licensed to practice law in the State of Florida. Any requirement for title insurance or for a legal opinion of title is the sole responsibility of the noninstitutional mortgage purchaser.”</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, if the loan is other than a first mortgage, a statement showing the balance owed by the mortgagor on any existing mortgages prior to this investment and the status of such existing mortgages.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a disclosure if the licensee is directly or indirectly acting as a borrower or principal in the transaction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each mortgage, or other instrument securing a note or assignment thereof, must be recorded before being delivered to the noninstitutional investor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each mortgage and assignment shall be recorded as soon as practical, but within 30 business days after the date of purchase.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the loan is to be serviced by a licensee under this part for a noninstitutional investor, there shall be a written servicing agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mortgage lender shall cause the original note to be properly endorsed showing the assignment of the note to the noninstitutional investor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 47, 50, ch. 91-245; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 59, ch. 2009-241.</History></Section>