<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.00125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public records exemptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTIGATIONS OR EXAMINATIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by this subsection, information relative to an investigation or examination by the office pursuant to this chapter, including any consumer complaint received by the office or the Department of Financial Services, is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) until the investigation or examination is completed or ceases to be active. For purposes of this subsection, an investigation or examination is considered active if the office or any law enforcement or administrative agency is proceeding with reasonable dispatch and has a reasonable good faith belief that the investigation or examination may lead to the filing of an administrative, civil, or criminal proceeding or to the denial or conditional grant of a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not prohibit the disclosure of information that is filed with the office as a normal condition of licensure and which, but for the investigation or examination, would be subject to s. 119.07(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as necessary for the office to enforce the provisions of this chapter, a consumer complaint and other information relative to an investigation or examination shall remain confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) after the investigation or examination is completed or ceases to be active to the extent disclosure would:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Jeopardize the integrity of another active investigation or examination.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reveal the name, address, telephone number, social security number, or any other identifying number or information of any complainant, customer, or account holder.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclose the identity of a confidential source.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclose investigative techniques or procedures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reveal a trade secret as defined in s. 688.002.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If office personnel are or have been involved in an investigation or examination of such nature as to endanger their lives or physical safety or that of their families, the home addresses, telephone numbers, places of employment, and photographs of such personnel, together with the home addresses, telephone numbers, photographs, and places of employment of spouses and children of such personnel and the names and locations of schools and day care facilities attended by the children of such personnel are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> This subsection does not prohibit the office from providing confidential and exempt information to any law enforcement or administrative agency. Any law enforcement or administrative agency receiving confidential and exempt information in connection with its official duties shall maintain the confidentiality of the information if it would otherwise be confidential.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All information obtained by the office from any person which is only made available to the office on a confidential or similarly restricted basis shall be confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If information subject to this subsection is offered in evidence in any administrative, civil, or criminal proceeding, the presiding officer may prevent the disclosure of information that would be confidential pursuant to paragraph (c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A privilege against civil liability is granted to a person who furnishes information or evidence to the office, unless such person acts in bad faith or with malice in providing such information or evidence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FINANCIAL STATEMENTS.<EmDash />All audited financial statements submitted pursuant to ss. 494.001-494.0077 are confidential and exempt from the requirements of s. 119.07(1), except that office employees may have access to such information in the administration and enforcement of ss. 494.001-494.0077 and such information may be used by office personnel in the prosecution of violations under ss. 494.001-494.0077.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CREDIT INFORMATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit history information and credit scores held by the office and related to licensing under ss. 494.001-494.0077 are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit history information and credit scores made confidential and exempt pursuant to paragraph (a) may be provided by the office to another governmental entity having oversight or regulatory or law enforcement authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to information that is otherwise publicly available.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15 and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2015, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 50, ch. 91-245; s. 4, ch. 91-429;  s. 2, ch. 92-9; s. 1, ch. 95-131; ss. 328, 329, ch. 96-406; s. 1140, ch. 97-103; s. 4, ch. 99-213; ss. 516, 522, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2010-169.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (2) former s. 494.0021.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>