<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.0011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of the commission and office.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall be responsible for the administration and enforcement of ss. 494.001-494.0077.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules to administer parts I, II, and III of this chapter, including rules:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring electronic submission of any forms, documents, or fees required by this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relating to compliance with the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008, including rules to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require loan originators, mortgage brokers, mortgage lenders, and branch offices to register through the registry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the use of uniform forms that have been approved by the registry, and any subsequent amendments to such forms if the forms are substantially in compliance with the provisions of this chapter. Uniform forms that the commission may adopt include, but are not limited to:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uniform Mortgage Lender/Mortgage Broker Form, MU1.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uniform Mortgage Biographical Statement &amp; Consent Form, MU2.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uniform Mortgage Branch Office Form, MU3.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uniform Individual Mortgage License/Registration &amp; Consent Form, MU4.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the filing of forms, documents, and fees in accordance with the requirements of the registry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribe requirements for amending or surrendering a license or other activities as the commission deems necessary for the office’s participation in the registry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribe procedures that allow a licensee to challenge information contained in the registry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribe procedures for reporting violations of this chapter and disciplinary actions on licensees to the registry.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing time periods during which a loan originator, mortgage broker, or mortgage lender license applicant under part II or part III is barred from licensure due to prior criminal convictions of, or guilty or nolo contendere pleas by, any of the applicant’s control persons, regardless of adjudication.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules must provide:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permanent bars for felonies involving fraud, dishonesty, breach of trust, or money laundering;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 15-year disqualifying period for felonies involving moral turpitude;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 7-year disqualifying period for all other felonies; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 5-year disqualifying period for misdemeanors involving fraud, dishonesty, or any other act of moral turpitude.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules may provide for an additional waiting period due to dates of imprisonment or community supervision, the commitment of multiple crimes, and other factors reasonably related to the applicant’s criminal history.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules may provide for mitigating factors for crimes identified in sub-subparagraph 1.b. However, the mitigation may not result in a period of disqualification less than 7 years. The rule may not mitigate the disqualifying periods in sub-subparagraphs 1.a., 1.c., and 1.d.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant is not eligible for licensure until the expiration of the disqualifying period set by rule.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 112.011 is not applicable to eligibility for licensure under this part.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 494.00172, all fees, charges, and fines collected pursuant to ss. 494.001-494.0077 shall be deposited in the Regulatory Trust Fund of the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall participate in the registry and shall regularly report to the registry violations of this chapter, disciplinary actions, and other information deemed relevant by the office under this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 50, ch. 91-245; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 165, ch. 98-200; s. 20, ch. 99-155; s. 2, ch. 99-213; s. 514, ch. 2003-261; s. 2, ch. 2006-213; s. 3, ch. 2009-241; s. 2, ch. 2011-71.</History>
</Section>