<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.00331" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Loan originator and loan processor employment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOAN ORIGINATORS.<EmDash />An individual may not act as a loan originator unless he or she is an employee of, or an independent contractor for, a mortgage broker or a mortgage lender, and may not be employed by or contract with more than one mortgage broker or mortgage lender, or either simultaneously.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTRACT LOAN PROCESSORS.<EmDash />Subsection (1) does not apply to a contract loan processor who has a declaration of intent to act solely as a contract loan processor on file with the office. The declaration of intent must be on a form as prescribed by commission rule.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A loan originator may withdraw his or her declaration of intent. The withdrawal of declaration of intent must be on such form as prescribed by commission rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A declaration of intent or a withdrawal of declaration of intent is effective upon receipt by the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee earned by a contract loan processor may be paid to the company that employs the loan processor without violating the restriction in s. 494.0025(7) requiring fees or commissions to be paid to a licensed mortgage broker or mortgage lender or a person exempt from licensure under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IN-HOUSE LOAN PROCESSORS.<EmDash />An individual may not act as an in-house loan processor unless he or she is an employee of a mortgage broker or a mortgage lender and may not be employed by more than one mortgage broker or mortgage lender, or either, simultaneously. An in-house loan processor must work at the direction of and be subject to the supervision and instruction of a loan originator licensed under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 95-313; s. 11, ch. 99-213; s. 30, ch. 2009-241; s. 2, ch. 2010-67; s. 39, ch. 2011-4; s. 5, ch. 2011-71.</History>
</Section>