<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0494.0026" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition of insurance proceeds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following provisions apply to mortgage loans held by a mortgagee or assignee that is subject to part II or part III of this chapter.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mortgagee or assignee must promptly endorse a check, draft, or other negotiable instrument payable jointly to the mortgagee or assignee and the insured by the insurance company. However, the mortgagee or assignee is not required to endorse such instrument if the insured or a payee who is not subject to part II or part III of this chapter refuses to endorse the instrument.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance proceeds received by a mortgagee or assignee that relate to compensation for damage to property or contents insurance coverage in which the mortgagee or assignee has a security interest must be promptly deposited into a segregated account of a federally insured financial institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance proceeds received by a mortgagee or assignee that relate to contents insurance coverage in which the mortgagee or assignee does not have a security interest in the contents must be promptly distributed to the insured.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance proceeds received by a mortgagee or assignee that relate to additional living expenses must be promptly distributed to the insured.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mortgagee or assignee is not required to remit the portion of the proceeds relating to additional living expenses and contents insurance if the mortgagee or assignee is not able to determine which part of the proceeds relates to additional living expenses and contents insurance.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This section may not be construed to prevent an insurance company from paying the insured directly for additional living expenses or paying the insured directly for contents insurance coverage if the mortgagee or assignee does not have a security interest in the contents.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 95-313; s. 16, ch. 2009-241.</History></Section>