<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0494.00794" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right to cure high-cost home loans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RIGHT TO REINSTATE.<EmDash />For a high-cost home loan, if a lender asserts that grounds for acceleration exist and requires the payment in full of all sums secured by the security instrument, the borrower, or anyone authorized to act on the borrower’s behalf, shall have the right, during the 45-day period set forth in subsection (2), to cure the default and reinstate the home loan by tendering the amount or performance as specified in this section. However, once a lender has provided two such notices as required by this section, for two separate incidents, a lender is not thereafter required to provide the notice required by this section, and the borrower is not entitled by this section to cure the default, for a third or subsequent incident for which the lender asserts that grounds exist for acceleration of the loan and repayment in full. Cure of default as provided in this section shall reinstate the borrower to the same position as if the default had not occurred and shall nullify, as of the date of the cure, any acceleration of any obligation under the security instrument or note arising from the default.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GROUNDS FOR REINSTATEMENT.<EmDash />Before any action filed to foreclose upon the home or other action is taken to seize or transfer ownership of the home, a notice of the right to cure the default must be delivered to the borrower at the address of the property upon which any security exists for the home loan by postage prepaid certified United States mail, return receipt requested, which notice is effective upon deposit in the United States mail, and shall inform the borrower:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the nature of default claimed on the home loan and of the borrower’s right to cure the default by paying the sum of money required to cure the default. If the amount necessary to cure the default will change during the 45-day period after the effective date of the notice due to the application of a daily interest rate or the addition of late payment fees, as allowed by this act, the notice shall give sufficient information to enable the borrower to calculate the amount at any point during the 45-day period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the date by which the borrower shall cure the default to avoid acceleration and initiation of foreclosure or other action to seize the home, which date shall not be less than 45 days after the date the notice is effective, and the name and address and telephone number of a person to whom the payment or tender shall be made.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That if the borrower does not cure the default by the date specified, the creditor may take steps to terminate the borrower’s ownership of the property by requiring payment in full of the home loan and commencing a foreclosure proceeding or other action to seize the home.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the name and address of the creditor and the telephone number of a representative of the creditor whom the borrower may contact if the borrower disagrees with the creditor’s assertion that a default has occurred or the correctness of the creditor’s calculation of the amount required to cure the default.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FEES.<EmDash />To cure a default under this section, a borrower shall not be required to pay any charge, fee, or penalty attributable to the exercise of the right to cure a default as provided for in this section, other than the fees specifically allowed by this act. The borrower shall not be liable for any attorney’s fees or costs relating to the borrower’s default that are incurred by the creditor prior to or during the 45-day period set forth in paragraph (2)(b).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2002-57.</History></Section>