<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.0035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Principal loan originator and branch manager for mortgage broker.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each mortgage broker must be operated by a principal loan originator who shall have full charge, control, and supervision of the mortgage broker. The principal loan originator must have been licensed as a loan originator for at least 1 year before being designated as the principal loan originator, or must demonstrate to the satisfaction of the office that he or she has been actively engaged in a mortgage-related business for at least 1 year before being designated as a principal loan originator. Each mortgage broker must keep the office informed of the person designated as the principal loan originator as prescribed by commission rule. If the designation is inaccurate, the mortgage broker shall be deemed to be operated under the full charge, control, and supervision of each officer, director, or ultimate equitable owner of a 10-percent or greater interest in the mortgage broker, or any other person in a similar capacity. A loan originator may not be a principal loan originator for more than one mortgage broker at any given time.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each branch office of a mortgage broker must be operated by a branch manager who shall have full charge, control, and supervision of the branch office. The designated branch manager must be a licensed loan originator pursuant to s. 494.00312. Each branch office must keep the office informed of the person designated as the branch manager as prescribed by commission rule, which includes documentation of the individual’s acceptance of such responsibility. If the designation is inaccurate, the branch office shall be deemed to be operated under the full charge, control, and supervision of each officer, director, or ultimate equitable owner of a 10-percent or greater interest in the mortgage broker, or any other person in a similar capacity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 22, 50, ch. 91-245; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 2001-228; s. 531, ch. 2003-261; s. 32, ch. 2009-241; s. 6, ch. 2011-71.</History>
</Section>