<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0494.00797" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General rule.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All counties and municipalities of this state are prohibited from enacting and enforcing ordinances, resolutions, and rules regulating financial or lending activities, including ordinances, resolutions, and rules disqualifying persons from doing business with a city, county, or municipality based upon lending interest rates or imposing reporting requirements or any other obligations upon persons regarding financial services or lending practices of persons or entities, and any subsidiaries or affiliates thereof, who:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are subject to the jurisdiction of the office, including for activities subject to this chapter, except entities licensed under s. 537.004;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are subject to the jurisdiction of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Trade Commission, or the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Originate, purchase, sell, assign, secure, or service property interests or obligations created by financial transactions or loans made, executed, or originated by persons referred to in subsection (1) or subsection (2) to assist or facilitate such transactions;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are chartered by the United States Congress to engage in secondary market mortgage transactions; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are created by the Florida Housing Finance Corporation.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Proof of noncompliance with this act can be used by a city, county, or municipality of this state to disqualify a vendor or contractor from doing business with a city, county, or municipality of this state.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2002-57; s. 549, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>