<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.00115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from regulation under this part and parts II and III of this chapter.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person operating exclusively as a registered loan originator in accordance with the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A depository institution; subsidiaries that are owned and controlled by a depository institution and regulated by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the National Credit Union Administration, or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; or institutions regulated by the Farm Credit Administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Federal National Mortgage Association; the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation; any agency of the Federal Government; any state, county, or municipal government; or any quasi-governmental agency that acts in such capacity under the specific authority of the laws of any state or the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An attorney licensed in this state who negotiates the terms of a mortgage loan on behalf of a client as an ancillary matter to the attorney’s representation of the client.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person involved solely in the extension of credit relating to the purchase of a timeshare plan, as that term is defined in 11 U.S.C. s. 101(53D).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who performs only real estate brokerage activities and is licensed or registered in this state under part I of chapter 475, unless the person is compensated by a lender, a mortgage broker, or other loan originator or by an agent of such lender, mortgage broker, or other loan originator. The term “real estate brokerage activity” has the same meaning as in the federal Secure and Fair Enforcement for Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons are exempt from regulation under part III of this chapter:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person acting in a fiduciary capacity conferred by the authority of a court.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who, as a seller of his or her own real property, receives one or more mortgages in a purchase money transaction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who acts solely under contract and as an agent for federal, state, or municipal agencies for the purpose of servicing mortgage loans.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who makes only nonresidential mortgage loans and sells loans only to institutional investors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual making or acquiring a mortgage loan using his or her own funds for his or her own investment, and who does not hold himself or herself out to the public as being in the mortgage lending business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual selling a mortgage that was made or purchased with that individual’s funds for his or her own investment, and who does not hold himself or herself out to the public as being in the mortgage lending business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is not necessary to negate any of the exemptions provided in this section in any complaint, information, indictment, or other writ or proceeding brought under ss. 494.001-494.0077. The burden of establishing the right to an exemption is on the party claiming the benefit of the exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2009-241; s. 3, ch. 2011-71.</History>
</Section>