<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0494.007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Commitment process.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a commitment is issued, the mortgage lender shall disclose in writing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expiration date of the commitment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mortgage amount, meaning the face amount of credit provided to the borrower or in the borrower’s behalf;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the interest rate or other terms are subject to change before expiration of the commitment:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The basis, index, or method, if any, which will be used to determine the rate at closing. Such basis, index, or method shall be established and disclosed with direct reference to the movement of an interest rate index or of a national or regional index that is available to and verifiable by the borrower and beyond the control of the lender; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement, in at least 10-point bold type: “The interest rate will be the rate established by the lender in its discretion as its prevailing rate . . . days before closing.”;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the commitment fee, if any, and whether and under what circumstances the commitment fee is refundable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time, if any, within which the commitment must be accepted by the borrower.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of a commitment cannot be changed prior to expiration of the specified period within which the borrower must accept it. If any information necessary for an accurate disclosure required by subsection (1) is unknown to the mortgage lender at the time disclosure is required, the lender shall make the disclosure based upon the best information reasonably available to it and shall state that the disclosure is an estimate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commitment fee is refundable if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commitment is contingent upon approval by parties to whom the mortgage lender seeks to sell the loan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The loan purchaser’s requirements are not met due to circumstances beyond the borrower’s control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The borrower is willing but unable to comply with the loan purchaser’s requirements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 41, 50, ch. 91-245; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 54, ch. 2009-241.</History></Section>