<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.00612" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mortgage lender license renewal.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to renew a mortgage lender license, a mortgage lender must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a completed license renewal form as prescribed by commission rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a nonrefundable renewal fee of $475, the $100 nonrefundable fee if required by s. 494.00172, and nonrefundable fees to cover the cost of further fingerprint processing and retention as set forth in commission rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit fingerprints in accordance with s. 494.00611(2)(d) for any new control persons who have not been screened.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide proof that the mortgage lender continues to meet the applicable net worth requirement in a form prescribed by commission rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorize the registry to obtain an independent credit report on each of the mortgage lender’s control persons from a consumer reporting agency, and transmit or provide access to the report to the office. The cost of the credit report shall be borne by the licensee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit any additional information or documentation requested by the office and required by rule concerning the licensee. Additional information may include documentation of pending and prior disciplinary and criminal history events, including arrest reports and certified copies of charging documents, plea agreements, judgments and sentencing documents, documents relating to pretrial intervention, orders terminating probation or supervised release, final administrative agency orders, or other comparable documents that may provide the office with the appropriate information to determine eligibility for renewal of licensure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may not renew a mortgage lender license unless the mortgage lender continues to meet the minimum requirements for initial licensure pursuant to s. 494.00611 and adopted rule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 2009-241; s. 9, ch. 2011-71.</History>
</Section>