<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0494.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements of licensees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee under this part shall report to the office:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In writing, any conviction of, or plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, any felony or any crime or administrative violation that involves fraud, dishonesty, breach of trust, money laundering, or any other act of moral turpitude, in any jurisdiction, by the licensee or any control person within 30 days after the date of conviction, entry of a plea of nolo contendere, or final administrative action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a form prescribed by rule of the commission, any conviction of, or plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, any felony committed by the licensee or any control person within 30 days after the date of conviction or the date the plea of nolo contendere is entered.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action in bankruptcy, voluntary or involuntary, within 30 days after the action is instituted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a form prescribed by rule of the commission, any change to the information contained in any initial application form or any amendment to the application within 30 days after the change is effective.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change in the principal loan originator, any addition or subtraction of a control person, or any change in the form of business organization, by written amendment in the form and at the time the commission specifies by rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any addition of a control person who has not previously filed a Uniform Mortgage Biographical Statement &amp; Consent Form, MU2, or has not previously complied with the fingerprinting and credit report requirements of ss. 494.00321 and 494.00322, is subject to the provisions of these sections. If, after the addition of a control person, the office finds that the licensee does not continue to meet licensure requirements, the office may bring an administrative action in accordance with s. 494.00255 to enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In every mortgage loan transaction, each licensee under this part must notify a borrower of any material changes in the terms of a mortgage loan previously offered to the borrower within 3 business days after being made aware of such changes by the mortgage lender but at least 3 business days before the signing of the settlement or closing statement. The licensee bears the burden of proving such notification was provided and accepted by the borrower. A borrower may waive the right to receive notice of a material change if the borrower determines that the extension of credit is needed to meet a bona fide personal financial emergency and the right to receive notice would delay the closing of the mortgage loan. The imminent sale of the borrower’s home at foreclosure during the 3-day period before the signing of the settlement or closing statement is an example of a bona fide personal financial emergency. In order to waive the borrower’s right to receive notice, the borrower must provide the licensee with a dated written statement that describes the personal financial emergency, waives the right to receive the notice, bears the borrower’s signature, and is not on a printed form prepared by the licensee for the purpose of such a waiver.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each mortgage broker shall submit to the registry reports of condition, which must be in such form and shall contain such information as the registry may require.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license issued under this part is not transferable or assignable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 27, 50, ch. 91-245; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 16, 17, ch. 99-213; s. 534, ch. 2003-261; s. 12, ch. 2006-213; s. 7, ch. 2007-182; s. 36, ch. 2009-241.</History>
</Section>