<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of scanning device or reencoder to defraud; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Scanning device” means a scanner, reader, or any other electronic device that is used to access, read, scan, obtain, memorize, or store, temporarily or permanently, information encoded on the magnetic strip or stripe of a payment card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reencoder” means an electronic device that places encoded information from the magnetic strip or stripe of a payment card onto the magnetic strip or stripe of a different payment card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Payment card” means a credit card, charge card, debit card, or any other card that is issued to an authorized card user and that allows the user to obtain, purchase, or receive goods, services, money, or anything else of value from a merchant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Merchant” means a person who receives from an authorized user of a payment card, or someone the person believes to be an authorized user, a payment card or information from a payment card, or what the person believes to be a payment card or information from a payment card, as the instrument for obtaining, purchasing, or receiving goods, services, money, or anything else of value from the person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, for a person to use:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A scanning device to access, read, obtain, memorize, or store, temporarily or permanently, information encoded on the magnetic strip or stripe of a payment card without the permission of the authorized user of the payment card and with the intent to defraud the authorized user, the issuer of the authorized user’s payment card, or a merchant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reencoder to place information encoded on the magnetic strip or stripe of a payment card onto the magnetic strip or stripe of a different card without the permission of the authorized user of the card from which the information is being reencoded and with the intent to defraud the authorized user, the issuer of the authorized user’s payment card, or a merchant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subparagraph (a)1. or subparagraph (a)2. a second or subsequent time commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subparagraph (a)1. or subparagraph (a)2. shall also be subject to the provisions of ss. 932.701-932.706.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2001-115; s. 163, ch. 2008-4.</History></Section>