<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.481" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Credit cards; obtaining goods by use of false, expired, etc.; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person knowingly to obtain or attempt to obtain credit, or to purchase or attempt to purchase any goods, property or service, by the use of any false, fictitious, counterfeit, or expired credit card, telephone number, credit number, or other credit device, or by the use of any credit card, telephone number, credit number, or other credit device of another without the authority of the person to whom such card, number or device was issued, or by the use of any credit card, telephone number, credit number, or other credit device in any case where such card, number or device has been revoked and notice of revocation has been given to the person to whom issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person to avoid or attempt to avoid or to cause another to avoid payment of the lawful charges, in whole or in part, for any telephone or telegraph service or for the transmission of a message, signal or other communication by telephone or telegraph or over telephone or telegraph facilities by the use of any fraudulent scheme, means or method, or any mechanical, electric, or electronic device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property, goods, or services obtained or which are sought to be obtained in violation of this section is $300 or more, the offender shall be guilty of grand larceny.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property, goods, or services obtained or which are sought to be obtained in violation of this section is less than $300 the offender shall be guilty of petit larceny.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 61-83; s. 1, ch. 65-245; s. 1, ch. 65-128; s. 873, ch. 71-136; s. 4, ch. 86-161.</History></Section>