<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.545" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mortgage fraud.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of the section, the term “mortgage lending process” means the process through which a person seeks or obtains a residential mortgage loan, including, but not limited to, the solicitation, application or origination, negotiation of terms, third-party provider services, underwriting, signing and closing, and funding of the loan. Documents involved in the mortgage lending process include, but are not limited to, mortgages, deeds, surveys, inspection reports, uniform residential loan applications, or other loan applications; appraisal reports; HUD-1 settlement statements; supporting personal documentation for loan applications such as W-2 forms, verifications of income and employment, credit reports, bank statements, tax returns, and payroll stubs; and any required disclosures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person commits the offense of mortgage fraud if, with the intent to defraud, the person knowingly:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes any material misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission during the mortgage lending process with the intention that the misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission will be relied on by a mortgage lender, borrower, or any other person or entity involved in the mortgage lending process; however, omissions on a loan application regarding employment, income, or assets for a loan which does not require this information are not considered a material omission for purposes of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses or facilitates the use of any material misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission during the mortgage lending process with the intention that the material misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission will be relied on by a mortgage lender, borrower, or any other person or entity involved in the mortgage lending process; however, omissions on a loan application regarding employment, income, or assets for a loan which does not require this information are not considered a material omission for purposes of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receives any proceeds or any other funds in connection with the mortgage lending process that the person knew resulted from a violation of paragraph (a) or paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Files or causes to be filed with the clerk of the circuit court for any county of this state a document involved in the mortgage lending process which contains a material misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offense of mortgage fraud may not be predicated solely upon information lawfully disclosed under federal disclosure laws, regulations, or interpretations related to the mortgage lending process.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of venue under this section, any violation of this section is considered to have been committed:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the county in which the real property is located; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any county in which a material act was performed in furtherance of the violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subsection (2) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subsection (2), and the loan value stated on documents used in the mortgage lending process exceeds $100,000, commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 2007-182; s. 2, ch. 2008-80.</History></Section>