<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.7001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Buyer” means any individual who is solicited to purchase, or who purchases, the services of a credit service organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Credit service organization” means any person who, with respect to the extension of credit by others, sells, provides, performs, or represents that he or she can or will sell, provide, or perform, in return for the payment of money or other valuable consideration, any of the following services:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improving a buyer’s credit record, history, or rating;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining an extension of credit for a buyer; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing advice or assistance to a buyer with regard to the services described in either subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Credit service organization” does not include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person authorized to make loans or extensions of credit under the laws of this state or the United States who is subject to regulation and supervision by this state or the United States or a lender approved by the United States Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for participation in any mortgage insurance program under the National Housing Act;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bank, savings bank, or savings and loan association whose deposits or accounts are eligible for insurance by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, or a subsidiary of such bank, savings bank, or savings and loan association;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any credit union, federal credit union, or out-of-state credit union doing business in this state;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nonprofit organization exempt from taxation under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person licensed as a real estate broker by this state if the person is acting within the course and scope of that license;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person collecting consumer claims pursuant to s. 559.72;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person licensed to practice law in this state if the person renders services within the course and scope of his or her practice as an attorney and does not engage in the credit service business on a regular and continuing basis;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any broker-dealer registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission or the Commodity Futures Trading Commission if the broker-dealer is acting within the course and scope of that regulation; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any consumer reporting agency as defined in the Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1681-1681t.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Extension of credit” means the right to defer payment of debt or to incur debt and defer its payment offered or granted primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-204.</History></Section>