<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.562" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fraud involving a security interest.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the terms “proceeds,” “security agreement,” “security interest,” and “secured party” shall be given the meanings prescribed for them in chapter 679.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is guilty of fraud involving a security interest when, having executed a security agreement creating a security interest in personal property, including accounts receivable, which security interest secures a monetary obligation owed to a secured party, and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having under the security agreement both the right of sale or other disposition of the property and the duty to account to the secured party for the proceeds of disposition, he or she sells or otherwise disposes of the property and wrongfully and willfully fails to account to the secured party for the proceeds of disposition; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having under the security agreement no right of sale or other disposition of the property, he or she knowingly secretes, withholds, or disposes of such property in violation of the security agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly violates this section shall be punished as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property sold, secreted, withheld, or disposed of or the proceeds from the sale or disposition of the property is $300 or more, such person is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the property sold, secreted, withheld, or disposed of or the proceeds obtained from the sale or disposition of the property is less than $300, such person is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-113; s. 5, ch. 86-161; s. 196, ch. 91-224; s. 1265, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>