<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.2341" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">False or misleading statements or supporting documents; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully files with the department or office, or who willfully signs for filing with the department or office, a materially false or materially misleading financial statement or document in support of such statement required by law or rule, with intent to deceive and with knowledge that the statement or document is materially false or materially misleading, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who makes a false entry of a material fact in any book, report, or statement relating to a transaction of an insurer or entity organized pursuant to chapter 624 or chapter 641, intending to deceive any person about the financial condition or solvency of the insurer or entity, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the false entry of a material fact is made with the intent to deceive any person as to the impairment of capital, as defined in s. 631.011(12), of the insurer or entity or is the significant cause of the insurer or entity being placed in conservation, rehabilitation, or liquidation by a court, the person commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly makes a material false statement or report to the department or office or any agent of the department or office, or knowingly and materially overvalues any property in any document or report prepared to be presented to the department or office or any agent of the department or office, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the material false statement or report or the material overvaluation is made with the intent to deceive any person as to the impairment of capital, as defined in s. 631.011(12), of an insurer or entity organized pursuant to chapter 624 or chapter 641, or is the significant cause of the insurer or entity being placed in receivership by a court, the person commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Financial Services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Office” means the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2002-25; s. 1910, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>