<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.4821" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cellular telephone counterfeiting offenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Possess” means to have physical possession or otherwise to exercise dominion or control over tangible property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intercept” means to electronically capture, record, reveal, or otherwise access, the signals emitted or received during the operation of a cellular telephone without the consent of the sender or receiver thereof, by means of any instrument, device, or equipment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electronic serial number” means the unique numerical algorithm that is programmed into the microchip of each cellular telephone by the manufacturer and is vital to the successful operation and billing of the telephone.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mobile identification number” means the cellular telephone number assigned to the cellular telephone by the cellular telephone carrier.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cellular telephone” means a communication device containing a unique electronic serial number that is programmed into its computer chip by its manufacturer and whose operation is dependent on the transmission of that electronic serial number along with a mobile identification number, which is assigned by the cellular telephone carrier, in the form of radio signals through cell sites and mobile switching stations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cloned cellular telephone” or “counterfeit cellular telephone” means a cellular telephone whose electronic serial number has been altered from the electronic serial number that was programmed in the phone by the manufacturer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cloning paraphernalia” means materials that, when possessed in combination, are necessary and capable of the creation of a cloned cellular telephone. These materials include scanners to intercept the electronic serial number and mobile identification number, cellular telephones, cables, EPROM chips, EPROM burners, software for programming the microchip of the cloned cellular telephone with a false electronic serial number and mobile identification number combination, a computer containing such software, and lists of electronic serial number and mobile identification number combinations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly possesses a cloned cellular telephone commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly possesses an instrument capable of intercepting electronic serial number and mobile identification number combinations under circumstances evidencing an intent to clone a cellular telephone commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly sells a cloned cellular telephone commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly possesses cloning paraphernalia with intent to use it to create cloned cellular telephones commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing herein shall make unlawful the possession or use of cloning paraphernalia, a cloned cellular telephone, or any intercept by a law enforcement officer or persons acting under the direction of a law enforcement officer in the course of a criminal investigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall make unlawful the possession or use of cloning paraphernalia or a cloned cellular telephone by a cellular telephone carrier.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 95-403; s. 1, ch. 96-264.</History></Section>