<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.4115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">False, deceptive, or misleading advertisement of live musical performances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Performing person or group” means a vocal or instrumental performer using or attempting to use the name of a recording person or group.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recording person or group” means a vocal or instrumental performer that has previously produced or released, or both, a commercial recording.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not advertise a live musical performance or production in this state using a false, deceptive, or misleading statement of an affiliation, connection, or association between a performing person or group and a recording person or group.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not conduct a live musical performance or production in this state using a false, deceptive, or misleading statement of an affiliation, connection, or association between a performing person or group and a recording person or group.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advertisement or the conducting of a live musical performance or production does not violate subsection (2) if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performing person or at least one member of the performing group was a member of the recording group and retains the legal right to use the name of the recording group by not having abandoned the affiliation with the recording group or its name;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performing person or group is the authorized registrant and owner of a federal service mark for that person or group which is registered with the United States Patent and Trademark Office;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The live musical performance or production is identified as a “salute” or “tribute” to, and is otherwise unaffiliated with, the recording person or group;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advertising does not relate to a live musical performance taking place in this state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance is expressly authorized in the advertising by the recording person or group.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subsection (2) commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Upon a second or subsequent violation of subsection (2), the person commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or by a fine not to exceed $5,000, or both.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Legal Affairs or a state attorney may file a civil action on behalf of the people of this state for injunctive relief against any person or group violating subsection (2) to restrain the prohibited activity. The court may award court costs and reasonable attorney’s fees to the prevailing party. The court may also impose a civil penalty not to exceed $5,000 for each violation of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-137.</History></Section>