<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.487" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Telephone caller identification systems.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Call” means any type of telephone call made using a public switched telephone network, wireless cellular telephone service, or voice-over-Internet protocol (VoIP) service that has the capability of accessing users on the public switched telephone network or a successor network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Caller” means a person who places a call, whether by telephone, over a telephone line, or on a computer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enter” means to input data by whatever means into a computer or telephone system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“False information” means data that misrepresents the identity of the caller to the recipient of a call or to the network itself; however, when a person making an authorized call on behalf of another person inserts the name, telephone number, or name and telephone number of the person on whose behalf the call is being made, such information shall not be deemed false information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Telephone caller identification system” means a listing of a caller’s name, telephone number, or name and telephone number that is shown to a recipient of a call when it is received.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not enter or cause to be entered false information into a telephone caller identification system with the intent to deceive, defraud, or mislead the recipient of a call.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not place a call knowing that false information was entered into the telephone caller identification system with the intent to deceive, defraud, or mislead the recipient of the call.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The blocking of caller identification information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement agency of the federal, state, county, or municipal government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any intelligence or security agency of the Federal Government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A telecommunications, broadband, or voice-over-Internet service provider that is acting solely as an intermediary for the transmission of telephone service between the caller and the recipient.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subsection (2) or subsection (3) commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of subsection (2) or subsection (3) constitutes an unlawful trade practice under part II of chapter 501 and, in addition to any remedies or penalties set forth in this section, is subject to any remedies or penalties available for a violation of that part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The felony or misdemeanor degree of any criminal offense shall be reclassified by the court to the next higher degree as provided in this subsection if the offender violated subsection (2) or subsection (3) during the commission of the criminal offense or if a violation by the offender of subsection (2) or subsection (3) facilitated or furthered the criminal offense. The reclassification shall be as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a misdemeanor of the second degree, the offense is reclassified as a misdemeanor of the first degree.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a misdemeanor of the first degree, the offense is reclassified as a felony of the third degree.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the third degree, the offense is reclassified as a felony of the second degree.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the second degree, the offense is reclassified as a felony of the first degree.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a felony of the first degree or a felony of the first degree punishable by a term of imprisonment not exceeding life, the offense is reclassified as a life felony.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of sentencing under chapter 921, the following offense severity ranking levels apply:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offense that is a misdemeanor of the first degree and that is reclassified under this subsection as a felony of the third degree is ranked in level 2 of the offense severity ranking chart.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony offense that is reclassified under this subsection is ranked one level above the ranking specified in s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023 for the offense committed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2008-185.</History></Section>