<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.558" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Water-treatment devices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Water-treatment device” means any product, device, or system designed for personal, family, or household use and for which any claim is made that it will improve the quality of water by reducing one or more contaminants through mechanical, physical, chemical, or biological processes or a combination thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Advertisement” means any representation of fact or opinion disseminated to the public in any manner or by any means which is designed to induce, directly or indirectly, any person to enter into any obligation to acquire any title or interest in or to use any water-treatment device.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Misleading” means any direct or indirect misrepresentation or omission of any material fact or circumstance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to make or disseminate any false or misleading advertisement regarding any water-treatment device.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person who solicits the sale, rental, lease, or order of any water-treatment device to make any false or misleading statement or claim:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regarding contamination problems in tap water;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stating or implying scientific certainty regarding the relationship between acute or chronic illnesses and water quality;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regarding the type and degree of problems caused by water treated in public water-treatment systems;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stating that the water flowing from a water-treatment device is “pure,” unless such word is reasonably defined;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making undocumented claims about the performance or benefits of a water-treatment device; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using unauthorized endorsements or testimonials.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of or before the order, sale, rental, or lease of any water-treatment device to a consumer, the person soliciting the order, sale, rental, or lease must notify the consumer in clear and conspicuous writing in at least 10-point boldfaced type that operational, maintenance, and replacement requirements are essential for the water-treatment device to perform as represented. In addition to the notification requirement, each water-treatment device must have a label or tag affixed to it or the container in which it is sold or delivered which notifies the consumer that operational, maintenance, and replacement requirements are essential for the water-treatment device to perform as sold.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 91-41; s. 9, ch. 91-68; s. 1, ch. 93-43.</History></Section>