<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.484" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obtaining telephone calling records by fraudulent means prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Calling record” means a record held by a telecommunications company of the telephone calls made or text messages sent or received by a customer of that company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Customer” means a person who has received telephone service from a telecommunications company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law enforcement agency” has the same meaning as in s. 23.1225(1)(d).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Telecommunications company” has the same meaning as in s. 364.02, except that the term includes VoIP service and commercial mobile radio service providers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a violation of this section for a person to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtain or attempt to obtain the calling record of another person without the permission of that person by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to an officer, employee, or agent of a telecommunications company;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to a customer of a telecommunications company; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing any document to an officer, employee, or agent of a telecommunications company, knowing that the document is forged, is counterfeit, was lost or stolen, was fraudulently obtained, or contains a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ask another person to obtain a calling record, knowing that the other person will obtain, or attempt to obtain, the calling record from the telecommunications company in any manner described in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell or offer to sell a calling record obtained in any manner described in paragraph (a) or paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section for the first time commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. A second or subsequent violation constitutes a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is not a violation of this section for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A law enforcement agency to obtain a calling record in connection with the performance of the official duties of that agency in accordance with other applicable laws.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A telecommunications company, or an officer, employee, or agent of a telecommunications company, to obtain a calling record of that company in the course of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Testing the security procedures or systems of the telecommunications company for maintaining the confidentiality of customer information;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigating an allegation of misconduct or negligence on the part of an officer, employee, or agent of the telecommunications company; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recovering a calling record that was obtained or received by another person in any manner described in subsection (2).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2006-141.</History></Section>