<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.62" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fraud by person authorized to provide goods or services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ILLEGALLY OBTAINED OR ILLEGALLY POSSESSED CREDIT CARD; FORGED, REVOKED, OR EXPIRED CREDIT CARD.<EmDash />A person who is authorized by an acquirer to furnish money, goods, services, or anything else of value upon presentation of a credit card by the cardholder, or any agent or employee of such person, who, with intent to defraud the issuer, the acquirer, or the cardholder, furnishes money, goods, services, or anything else of value upon presentation of a credit card obtained or retained in violation of this part or a credit card which he or she knows is forged, expired, or revoked violates this subsection and is subject to the penalties set forth in s. 817.67(1), if the value of all money, goods, services, and other things of value furnished in violation of this subsection does not exceed $300 in any 6-month period. The violator is subject to the penalties set forth in s. 817.67(2) if such value does exceed $300 in any 6-month period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISREPRESENTATION TO ISSUER OR ACQUIRER.<EmDash />A person who is authorized by an acquirer to furnish money, goods, services, or anything else of value upon presentation of a credit card by the cardholder, or any agent or employee of such person, who, with intent to defraud the issuer, the acquirer, or the cardholder, fails to furnish money, goods, services, or anything else of value which he or she represents in writing to the issuer or the acquirer that he or she has furnished violates this subsection and is subject to the penalties set forth in s. 817.67(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ILLEGALLY FACTORING CREDIT CARD TRANSACTIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is authorized by an acquirer to furnish money, goods, services, or anything else of value upon presentation of a credit card or a credit card account number by a cardholder, or any agent or employee of such person, who, with intent to defraud the issuer, the acquirer, or the cardholder, presents to the issuer or acquirer, for payment, a credit card transaction record of a sale, which sale was not made by such person or his or her agent or employee, violates this paragraph and is subject to the penalties set forth in s. 817.67(2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who, without the acquirer’s authorization, employs, solicits, or otherwise causes a person who is authorized by an acquirer to furnish money, goods, services, or anything else of value upon presentation of a credit card or a credit card account number by a cardholder, or employs, solicits, or otherwise causes an agent or employee of such authorized person, to remit to the acquirer a credit card transaction record of a sale that was not made by such authorized person or his or her agent or employee violates this paragraph and is subject to the penalties set forth in s. 817.67(2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of this subsection constitutes an unfair or deceptive act or practice within the meaning of s. 501.204 and thus the basis for a civil or administrative action by an enforcing authority pursuant to part II of chapter 501.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 67-340; s. 5, ch. 84-297; s. 6, ch. 86-161; s. 2, ch. 88-198; s. 1, ch. 89-27; s. 1272, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>