<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0817.415" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Free Gift Advertising Law.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature of the State of Florida recognizes that the deceptive misuse of the term “free” and words of similar meaning and intent in advertising by the unscrupulous has resulted in deception of consumers, leading them unknowingly to assume contractual obligations which were initially concealed by the deception.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to prevent such deception by requiring disclosure of all contingent conditions, obligations, or considerations in any form in connection with the advertising of goods or services using the term “free” or words of similar meaning and intent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is not the intent of the Legislature to prohibit the use of gifts in legitimate promotions of trade so long as the advertising of such gifts and promotions makes full disclosure of any requirement for purchase or contractual obligations to be assumed in order to qualify for the gift.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This act may be cited as the “Florida Free Gift Advertising Law.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this act:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” includes an individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other entity doing business in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Free” includes the use of terms such as “awarded,” “prize,” “absolutely without charge,” “free of charge,” and words or groups of words of similar intent which reasonably lead a person to believe that he or she may receive, or has been selected to receive, something of value, entirely or in part without a requirement of compensation in any form from the recipient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Item” means goods, services, or any tangible or intangible thing of value and the rights therein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Advertisement” and “advertising” includes every form of communication which offers for sale, or attempts to induce the creation of obligations in exchange for, any item or rights therein.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESTRICTIONS ON USE OF WORD “FREE.”<EmDash />Any item or portion of an item unconditionally offered as “free” shall in fact be free, without obligation or requirement of consideration in any form, when accepted in writing within the time limit set forth in the advertisement or within a reasonable time, if no time limit is so set. However, any person so receiving and accepting such offer may be required to pay any necessary transportation or delivery charges directly to the United States Postal Service or other regulated public carrier.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REQUIREMENTS FOR ADVERTISEMENTS.<EmDash />Advertising in which items are offered as free with conditions or obligations necessary to acceptance shall include a clear and conspicuous statement of any such conditions or obligations and advertising in compliance herewith shall not be considered deceptive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VIOLATIONS.<EmDash />Any violation of this section is declared to be a deceptive trade practice and unlawful.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INJUNCTIONS.<EmDash />The Commissioner of Agriculture or the Attorney General may bring an action for injunction to prohibit practices in violation of this law, and any such injunction shall be issued without bond. Such suit may be brought in any circuit court of this state having jurisdiction over the party or parties defendant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, ch. 70-164; s. 1, ch. 70-439; ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, ch. 72-4; s. 1259, ch. 97-102; s. 11, ch. 98-299.</History></Section>