<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.08135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trust accountings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trust accounting must be a reasonably understandable report from the date of the last accounting or, if none, from the date on which the trustee became accountable, that adequately discloses the information required in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accounting must begin with a statement identifying the trust, the trustee furnishing the accounting, and the time period covered by the accounting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accounting must show all cash and property transactions and all significant transactions affecting administration during the accounting period, including compensation paid to the trustee and the trustee’s agents. Gains and losses realized during the accounting period and all receipts and disbursements must be shown.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent feasible, the accounting must identify and value trust assets on hand at the close of the accounting period. For each asset or class of assets reasonably capable of valuation, the accounting shall contain two values, the asset acquisition value or carrying value and the estimated current value. The accounting must identify each known noncontingent liability with an estimated current amount of the liability if known.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent feasible, the accounting must show significant transactions that do not affect the amount for which the trustee is accountable, including name changes in investment holdings, adjustments to carrying value, a change of custodial institutions, and stock splits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accounting must reflect the allocation of receipts, disbursements, accruals, or allowances between income and principal when the allocation affects the interest of any beneficiary of the trust.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trustee shall include in the final accounting a plan of distribution for any undistributed assets shown on the final accounting.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to all trust accountings rendered for any accounting periods beginning on or after January 1, 2003.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2006-217.</History></Section>