<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.1204" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of trustee of a private foundation trust or a split interest trust.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the exercise of a trustee’s powers, including the powers granted by this part, a trustee has a duty to act with due regard to the trustee’s obligation as a fiduciary, including a duty not to exercise any power in such a way as to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deprive the trust of an otherwise available tax exemption, deduction, or credit for tax purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deprive a donor of a trust asset or tax deduction or credit; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operate to impose a tax on a donor, trust, or other person.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of this subsection, the term “tax” includes, but is not limited to, any federal, state, or local excise, income, gift, estate, or inheritance tax.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 736.1205, a trustee of a private foundation trust shall make distributions at such time and in such manner as not to subject the trust to tax under s. 4942 of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (4) and in s. 736.1205, a trustee of a private foundation trust, or a split interest trust to the extent that the split interest trust is subject to the provisions of s. 4947(a)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code, in the exercise of the trustee’s powers shall not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage in any act of self-dealing as defined in s. 4941(d) of the Internal Revenue Code;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retain any excess business holdings as defined in s. 4943(c) of the Internal Revenue Code;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any investments in a manner that subjects the foundation to tax under s. 4944 of the Internal Revenue Code; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any taxable expenditures as defined in s. 4945(d) of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraphs (3)(b) and (c) shall not apply to a split interest trust if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All the income interest, and none of the remainder interest, of the trust is devoted solely to one or more of the purposes described in s. 170(c)(2)(B) of the Internal Revenue Code, and all amounts in the trust for which a deduction was allowed under s. 170, s. 545(b)(2), s. 556(b)(2), s. 642(c), s. 2055, s. 2106(a)(2), or s. 2522 of the Internal Revenue Code have an aggregate fair market value of not more than 60 percent of the aggregate fair market value of all amounts in the trust; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A deduction was allowed under s. 170, s. 545(b)(2), s. 556(b)(2), s. 642(c), s. 2055, s. 2106(a)(2), or s. 2522 of the Internal Revenue Code for amounts payable under the terms of the trust to every remainder beneficiary but not to any income beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2006-217; s. 17, ch. 2007-153.</History></Section>