<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0736.04114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited judicial construction of irrevocable trust with federal tax provisions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the application of a trustee or any qualified beneficiary of a trust, a court at any time may construe the terms of a trust that is not then revocable to define the respective shares or determine beneficiaries, in accordance with the intention of the settlor, if a disposition occurs during the applicable period and the trust contains a provision that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Includes a formula disposition referring to the “unified credit,” “estate tax exemption,” “applicable exemption amount,” “applicable credit amount,” “applicable exclusion amount,” “generation-skipping transfer tax exemption,” “GST exemption,” “marital deduction,” “maximum marital deduction,” “unlimited marital deduction,” or “maximum charitable deduction”;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Measures a share of a trust based on the amount that can pass free of federal estate tax or the amount that can pass free of federal generation-skipping transfer tax;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Otherwise makes a disposition referring to a charitable deduction, marital deduction, or another provision of federal estate tax or generation-skipping transfer tax law; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appears to be intended to reduce or minimize federal estate tax or generation-skipping transfer tax.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this section:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicable period” means a period beginning January 1, 2010, and ending on the end of the day on the earlier of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">December 31, 2010; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The day before the date that an act becomes law which repeals or otherwise modifies or has the effect of repealing or modifying s. 901 of the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “disposition occurs” when an interest takes effect in possession or enjoyment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In construing the trust, the court shall consider the terms and purposes of the trust, the facts and circumstances surrounding the creation of the trust, and the settlor’s probable intent. In determining the settlor’s probable intent, the court may consider evidence relevant to the settlor’s intent even though the evidence contradicts an apparent plain meaning of the trust instrument.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a disposition that is specifically conditioned upon no federal estate or generation-skipping transfer tax being imposed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise ordered by the court, during the applicable period and without court order, the trustee administering a trust containing one or more provisions described in subsection (1) may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delay or refrain from making any distribution;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incur and pay fees and costs reasonably necessary to determine its duties and obligations, including compliance with provisions of existing and reasonably anticipated future federal tax laws; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and maintain reserves for the payment of these fees and costs and federal taxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The trustee is not liable for its actions as provided in this subsection which are made or taken in good faith.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are in addition to, and not in derogation of, rights under this code or the common law to construe a trust.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is remedial in order to provide a new or modified legal remedy. This section applies retroactively and is effective as of January 1, 2010.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2010-122.</History>
</Section>