<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.0403" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trusts created in other jurisdictions; formalities required for revocable trusts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trust not created by will is validly created if the creation of the trust complies with the law of the jurisdiction in which the trust instrument was executed or the law of the jurisdiction in which, at the time of creation, the settlor was domiciled.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No trust or confidence of or in any messuages, lands, tenements, or hereditaments shall arise or result unless the trust complies with the provisions of s. 689.05.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The testamentary aspects of a revocable trust, executed by a settlor who is a domiciliary of this state at the time of execution, are invalid unless the trust instrument is executed by the settlor with the formalities required for the execution of a will in this state. For purposes of this subsection, the term “testamentary aspects” means those provisions of the trust instrument that dispose of the trust property on or after the death of the settlor other than to the settlor’s estate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (2)(b) does not apply to trusts established as part of an employee annuity described in s. 403 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, an individual retirement account as described in s. 408 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, a Keogh (HR-10) Plan, or a retirement or other plan that is qualified under s. 401 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (2)(b) applies to trusts created on or after the effective date of this code. Section 737.111, as in effect prior to the effective date of this code, continues to apply to trusts created before the effective date of this code.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2006-217.</History></Section>