<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.04115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Judicial modification of irrevocable trust when modification is in best interests of beneficiaries.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without regard to the reasons for modification provided in s. 736.04113, if compliance with the terms of a trust is not in the best interests of the beneficiaries, upon the application of a trustee or any qualified beneficiary, a court may at any time modify a trust that is not then revocable as provided in s. 736.04113(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In exercising discretion to modify a trust under this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall exercise discretion in a manner that conforms to the extent possible with the intent of the settlor, taking into account the current circumstances and best interests of the beneficiaries.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall consider the terms and purposes of the trust, the facts and circumstances surrounding the creation of the trust, and extrinsic evidence relevant to the proposed modification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall consider spendthrift provisions as a factor in making a decision, but the court is not precluded from modifying a trust because the trust contains spendthrift provisions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any trust created prior to January 1, 2001.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any trust created after December 31, 2000, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the terms of the trust, all beneficial interests in the trust must vest or terminate within the period prescribed by the rule against perpetuities in s. 689.225(2), notwithstanding s. 689.225(2)(f).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms of the trust expressly prohibit judicial modification.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of subsection (3), a revocable trust shall be treated as created when the right of revocation terminates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are in addition to, and not in derogation of, rights under the common law to modify, amend, terminate, or revoke trusts.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2006-217.</History></Section>