<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0736.0201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Role of court in trust proceedings.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsections (5) and (6) and s. 736.0206, judicial proceedings concerning trusts shall be commenced by filing a complaint and shall be governed by the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may intervene in the administration of a trust to the extent the court’s jurisdiction is invoked by an interested person or as provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trust is not subject to continuing judicial supervision unless ordered by the court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A judicial proceeding involving a trust may relate to the validity, administration, or distribution of a trust, including proceedings to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the validity of all or part of a trust;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint or remove a trustee;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review trustees’ fees;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and settle interim or final accounts;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ascertain beneficiaries; determine any question arising in the administration or distribution of any trust, including questions of construction of trust instruments; instruct trustees; and determine the existence or nonexistence of any immunity, power, privilege, duty, or right;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtain a declaration of rights; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine any other matters involving trustees and beneficiaries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proceeding for the construction of a testamentary trust may be filed in the probate proceeding for the testator’s estate. The proceeding shall be governed by the Florida Probate Rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rule 1.525, Florida Rules of Civil Procedure, shall apply to judicial proceedings concerning trusts, except that the following do not constitute taxation of costs or attorney’s fees even if the payment is for services rendered or costs incurred in a judicial proceeding:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trustee’s payment of compensation or reimbursement of costs to persons employed by the trustee from assets of the trust.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination by the court directing from what part of the trust fees or costs shall be paid, unless the determination is made under s. 736.1004 in an action for breach of fiduciary duty or challenging the exercise of, or failure to exercise, a trustee’s powers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2006-217; s. 13, ch. 2011-183.</History>
</Section>