<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.1001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Remedies for breach of trust.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation by a trustee of a duty the trustee owes to a beneficiary is a breach of trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To remedy a breach of trust that has occurred or may occur, the court may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compel the trustee to perform the trustee’s duties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enjoin the trustee from committing a breach of trust;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compel the trustee to redress a breach of trust by paying money or restoring property or by other means;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order a trustee to account;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a special fiduciary to take possession of the trust property and administer the trust;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suspend the trustee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remove the trustee as provided in s. 736.0706;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reduce or deny compensation to the trustee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to s. 736.1016, void an act of the trustee, impose a lien or a constructive trust on trust property, or trace trust property wrongfully disposed of and recover the property or its proceeds; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order any other appropriate relief.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an illustration of the remedies available to the court and without limiting the court’s discretion as provided in subsection (2), if a breach of trust results in the favoring of any beneficiary to the detriment of any other beneficiary or consists of an abuse of the trustee’s discretion:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent the breach of trust has resulted in no distribution to a beneficiary or a distribution that is too small, the court may require the trustee to pay from the trust to the beneficiary an amount the court determines will restore the beneficiary, in whole or in part, to his or her appropriate position.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent the breach of trust has resulted in a distribution to a beneficiary that is too large, the court may restore the beneficiaries, the trust, or both, in whole or in part, to their appropriate positions by requiring the trustee to withhold an amount from one or more future distributions to the beneficiary who received the distribution that was too large or by requiring that beneficiary to return some or all of the distribution to the trust.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 2006-217; s. 147, ch. 2007-5; s. 19, ch. 2007-153.</History></Section>