<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.0802" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duty of loyalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As between a trustee and the beneficiaries, a trustee shall administer the trust solely in the interests of the beneficiaries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the rights of persons dealing with or assisting the trustee as provided in s. 736.1016, a sale, encumbrance, or other transaction involving the investment or management of trust property entered into by the trustee for the trustee’s own personal account or which is otherwise affected by a conflict between the trustee’s fiduciary and personal interests is voidable by a beneficiary affected by the transaction unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction was authorized by the terms of the trust;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction was approved by the court;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary did not commence a judicial proceeding within the time allowed by s. 736.1008;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary consented to the trustee’s conduct, ratified the transaction, or released the trustee in compliance with s. 736.1012;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction involves a contract entered into or claim acquired by the trustee when that person had not become or contemplated becoming trustee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction was consented to in writing by a settlor of the trust while the trust was revocable; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transaction is one by a corporate trustee that involves a money market mutual fund, mutual fund, or a common trust fund described in s. 736.0816(3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sale, encumbrance, or other transaction involving the investment or management of trust property is presumed to be affected by a conflict between personal and fiduciary interests if the sale, encumbrance, or other transaction is entered into by the trustee with:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trustee’s spouse;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trustee’s descendants, siblings, parents, or their spouses;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer, director, employee, agent, or attorney of the trustee; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation or other person or enterprise in which the trustee, or a person that owns a significant interest in the trustee, has an interest that might affect the trustee’s best judgment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transaction not concerning trust property in which the trustee engages in the trustee’s individual capacity involves a conflict between personal and fiduciary interests if the transaction concerns an opportunity properly belonging to the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investment by a trustee authorized by lawful authority to engage in trust business, as defined in s. 658.12(20), in investment instruments, as defined in s. 660.25(6), that are owned or controlled by the trustee or its affiliate, or from which the trustee or its affiliate receives compensation for providing services in a capacity other than as trustee, is not presumed to be affected by a conflict between personal and fiduciary interests provided the investment otherwise complies with chapters 518 and 660 and the trustee complies with the requirements of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trustee who, pursuant to this subsection, invests trust funds in investment instruments that are owned or controlled by the trustee or its affiliate shall disclose the following to all qualified beneficiaries:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice that the trustee has invested trust funds in investment instruments owned or controlled by the trustee or its affiliate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of the investment instruments.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity and relationship to the trustee of any affiliate that owns or controls the investment instruments.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trustee who, pursuant to this subsection, invests trust funds in investment instruments with respect to which the trustee or its affiliate receives compensation for providing services in a capacity other than as trustee shall disclose to all qualified beneficiaries, the nature of the services provided by the trustee or its affiliate, and all compensation, including, but not limited to, fees or commissions paid or to be paid by the account and received or to be received by an affiliate arising from such affiliated investment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosure required by this subsection shall be made at least annually unless there has been no change in the method or increase in the rate at which such compensation is calculated since the most recent disclosure. The disclosure may be given in a trust disclosure document as defined in s. 736.1008, in a copy of the prospectus for the investment instrument, in any other written disclosure prepared for the investment instrument under applicable federal or state law, or in a written summary that includes all compensation received or to be received by the trustee and any affiliate of the trustee and an explanation of the manner in which such compensation is calculated, either as a percentage of the assets invested or by some other method.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall apply as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to qualified investment instruments or to a trust for which a right of revocation exists.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For investment instruments other than qualified investment instruments, paragraphs (a), (b), (c), and (d) shall apply to irrevocable trusts created on or after July 1, 2007, which expressly authorize the trustee, by specific reference to this subsection, to invest in investment instruments owned or controlled by the trustee or its affiliate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For investment instruments other than qualified investment instruments, paragraphs (a), (b), (c), and (d) shall apply to irrevocable trusts created on or after July 1, 2007, that are not described in subparagraph 2. and to irrevocable trusts created prior to July 1, 2007, only as follows:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such paragraphs shall not apply until the statement required in paragraph (f) is provided and a majority of the qualified beneficiaries have provided written consent. All consents must be obtained within 90 days after the date of delivery of the written request. Once given, consent shall be valid as to all investment instruments acquired pursuant to the consent prior to the date of any withdrawal of the consent.</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any qualified beneficiary may petition the court for an order to prohibit, limit, or restrict a trustee’s authority to make investments under this subsection. The burden shall be upon the petitioning beneficiary to show good cause for the relief sought.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may award costs and attorney’s fees relating to any petition under this subparagraph in the same manner as in chancery actions. When costs and attorney’s fees are to be paid out of the trust, the court, in its discretion, may direct from which part of the trust such costs and fees shall be paid.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The consent of a majority of the qualified beneficiaries under this subparagraph may be withdrawn prospectively by written notice of a majority of any one of the class or classes of the qualified beneficiaries.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trustee of a trust as defined in s. 731.201 may request authority to invest in investment instruments described in this subsection other than a qualified investment instrument, by providing to all qualified beneficiaries a written request containing the following:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, telephone number, street address, and mailing address of the trustee and of any individuals who may be contacted for further information.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the investment or investments cannot be made without the consent of a majority of each class of the qualified beneficiaries.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that, if a majority of each class of qualified beneficiaries consent, the trustee will have the right to make investments in investment instruments, as defined in s. 660.25(6), which are owned or controlled by the trustee or its affiliate, or from which the trustee or its affiliate receives compensation for providing services in a capacity other than as trustee, that such investment instruments may include investment instruments sold primarily to trust accounts, and that the trustee or its affiliate may receive fees in addition to the trustee’s compensation for administering the trust.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the consent may be withdrawn prospectively at any time by written notice given by a majority of any class of the qualified beneficiaries.</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A statement by the trustee is not delivered if the statement is accompanied by another written communication other than a written communication by the trustee that refers only to the statement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of paragraph (e) and this paragraph:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Majority of the qualified beneficiaries” means:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If at the time the determination is made there are one or more beneficiaries as described in s. 736.0103(14)(c), at least a majority in interest of the beneficiaries described in s. 736.0103(14)(a), at least a majority in interest of the beneficiaries described in s. 736.0103(14)(b), and at least a majority in interest of the beneficiaries described in s. 736.0103(14)(c), if the interests of the beneficiaries are reasonably ascertainable; otherwise, a majority in number of each such class; or</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there is no beneficiary as described in s. 736.0103(14)(c), at least a majority in interest of the beneficiaries described in s. 736.0103(14)(a) and at least a majority in interest of the beneficiaries described in s. 736.0103(14)(b), if the interests of the beneficiaries are reasonably ascertainable; otherwise, a majority in number of each such class.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified investment instrument” means a mutual fund, common trust fund, or money market fund described in and governed by s. 736.0816(3).</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An irrevocable trust is created upon execution of the trust instrument. If a trust that was revocable when created thereafter becomes irrevocable, the irrevocable trust is created when the right of revocation terminates.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this chapter is intended to create or imply a duty for the trustee to seek the application of this subsection to invest in investment instruments described in paragraph (a), and no inference of impropriety may be made as a result of a trustee electing not to invest trust assets in investment instruments described in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is not the exclusive authority under this code for investing in investment instruments described in paragraph (a). A trustee who invests trust funds in investment instruments described in paragraph (a) is not required to comply with paragraph (b), paragraph (c), or paragraph (f) if the trustee is permitted to invest in such investment instruments pursuant to subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In voting shares of stock or in exercising powers of control over similar interests in other forms of enterprise, the trustee shall act in the best interests of the beneficiaries. If the trust is the sole owner of a corporation or other form of enterprise, the trustee shall elect or appoint directors or other managers who will manage the corporation or enterprise in the best interests of the beneficiaries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not preclude the following transactions, if fair to the beneficiaries:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agreement between a trustee and a beneficiary relating to the appointment or compensation of the trustee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A payment of reasonable compensation to the trustee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transaction between a trust and another trust, the decedent’s estate, or a guardian of the property of which the trustee is a fiduciary or in which a beneficiary has an interest;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A deposit of trust money in a regulated financial service institution operated by the trustee; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advance by the trustee of money for the protection of the trust.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not preclude the employment of persons, including, but not limited to, attorneys, accountants, investment advisers, or agents, even if they are the trustee, an affiliate of the trustee, or otherwise associated with the trustee, to advise or assist the trustee in the exercise of any of the trustee’s powers and to pay reasonable compensation and costs incurred in connection with such employment from the assets of the trust; to act without independent investigation on their recommendations; and, instead of acting personally, to employ one or more agents to perform any act of administration, whether or not discretionary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may appoint a special fiduciary to act with respect to any proposed transaction that might violate this section if entered into by the trustee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of costs or attorney’s fees incurred in any proceeding from the assets of the trust may be made by the trustee without the approval of any person and without court authorization, unless the court orders otherwise as provided in paragraph (b).</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a claim or defense based upon a breach of trust is made against a trustee in a proceeding, the trustee shall provide written notice to each qualified beneficiary of the trust whose share of the trust may be affected by the payment of attorney’s fees and costs of the intention to pay costs or attorney’s fees incurred in the proceeding from the trust prior to making payment. The written notice shall be delivered by sending a copy by any commercial delivery service requiring a signed receipt, by any form of mail requiring a signed receipt, or as provided in the Florida Rules of Civil Procedure for service of process. The written notice shall inform each qualified beneficiary of the trust whose share of the trust may be affected by the payment of attorney’s fees and costs of the right to apply to the court for an order prohibiting the trustee from paying attorney’s fees or costs from trust assets. If a trustee is served with a motion for an order prohibiting the trustee from paying attorney’s fees or costs in the proceeding and the trustee pays attorney’s fees or costs before an order is entered on the motion, the trustee and the trustee’s attorneys who have been paid attorney’s fees or costs from trust assets to defend against the claim or defense are subject to the remedies in paragraphs (b) and (c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a claim or defense based upon breach of trust is made against a trustee in a proceeding, a party must obtain a court order to prohibit the trustee from paying costs or attorney’s fees from trust assets. To obtain an order prohibiting payment of costs or attorney’s fees from trust assets, a party must make a reasonable showing by evidence in the record or by proffering evidence that provides a reasonable basis for a court to conclude that there has been a breach of trust. The trustee may proffer evidence to rebut the evidence submitted by a party. The court in its discretion may defer ruling on the motion, pending discovery to be taken by the parties. If the court finds that there is a reasonable basis to conclude that there has been a breach of trust, unless the court finds good cause, the court shall enter an order prohibiting the payment of further attorney’s fees and costs from the assets of the trust and shall order attorney’s fees or costs previously paid from assets of the trust to be refunded. An order entered under this paragraph shall not limit a trustee’s right to seek an order permitting the payment of some or all of the attorney’s fees or costs incurred in the proceeding from trust assets, including any fees required to be refunded, after the claim or defense is finally determined by the court. If a claim or defense based upon a breach of trust is withdrawn, dismissed, or resolved without a determination by the court that the trustee committed a breach of trust after the entry of an order prohibiting payment of attorney’s fees and costs pursuant to this paragraph, the trustee may pay costs or attorney’s fees incurred in the proceeding from the assets of the trust without further court authorization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court orders a refund under paragraph (b), the court may enter such sanctions as are appropriate if a refund is not made as directed by the court, including, but not limited to, striking defenses or pleadings filed by the trustee. Nothing in this subsection limits other remedies and sanctions the court may employ for the failure to refund timely.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this subsection limits the power of the court to review fees and costs or the right of any interested persons to challenge fees and costs after payment, after an accounting, or after conclusion of the litigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice under paragraph (a) is not required if the action or defense is later withdrawn or dismissed by the party that is alleging a breach of trust or resolved without a determination by the court that the trustee has committed a breach of trust.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2006-217; s. 3, ch. 2007-153; s. 159, ch. 2008-4; s. 2, ch. 2008-76; s. 20, ch. 2009-115.</History></Section>