<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.08125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Protection of successor trustees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A successor trustee is not personally liable for actions taken by any prior trustee, nor does any successor trustee have a duty to institute any proceeding against any prior trustee, or file any claim against any prior trustee’s estate, for any of the prior trustee’s actions as trustee under any of the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to a successor trustee who succeeds a trustee who was also the settlor of a trust that was revocable during the time that the settlor served as trustee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to any beneficiary who has waived any accounting required by s. 736.0813, but only as to the periods included in the waiver;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to any beneficiary who has released the successor trustee from the duty to institute any proceeding or file any claim;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to any person who is not an eligible beneficiary; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to any eligible beneficiary:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a super majority of the eligible beneficiaries have released the successor trustee;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the eligible beneficiary has not delivered a written request to the successor trustee to institute an action or file a claim against the prior trustee within 6 months after the date of the successor trustee’s acceptance of the trust, if the successor trustee has notified the eligible beneficiary in writing of acceptance by the successor trustee in accordance with s. 736.0813(1)(a) and that writing advises the beneficiary that, unless the beneficiary delivers the written request within 6 months after the date of acceptance, the right to proceed against the successor trustee will be barred pursuant to this section; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any action or claim that the eligible beneficiary is barred from bringing against the prior trustee.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible beneficiaries” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the determination is made, if there are one or more beneficiaries as described in s. 736.0103(14)(c), the beneficiaries described in s. 736.0103(14)(a) and (c); or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there is no beneficiary as described in s. 736.0103(14)(c), the beneficiaries described in s. 736.0103(14)(a) and (b).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Super majority of eligible beneficiaries” means at least two-thirds in interest of the eligible beneficiaries if the interests of the eligible beneficiaries are reasonably ascertainable, otherwise, at least two-thirds in number of the eligible beneficiaries.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section affects any liability of the prior trustee or the right of the successor trustee or any beneficiary to pursue an action or claim against the prior trustee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2006-217.</History></Section>