<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.0703" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cotrustees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cotrustees who are unable to reach a unanimous decision may act by majority decision.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a vacancy occurs in a cotrusteeship, the remaining cotrustees or a majority of the remaining cotrustees may act for the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cotrustee must participate in the performance of a trustee’s function unless the cotrustee is unavailable to perform the function because of absence, illness, disqualification under other provision of law, or other temporary incapacity or the cotrustee has properly delegated the performance of the function to another cotrustee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a cotrustee is unavailable to perform duties because of absence, illness, disqualification under other law, or other temporary incapacity, and prompt action is necessary to achieve the purposes of the trust or to avoid injury to the trust property, the remaining cotrustee or a majority of the remaining cotrustees may act for the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cotrustee may not delegate to another cotrustee the performance of a function the settlor reasonably expected the cotrustees to perform jointly, except that a cotrustee may delegate investment functions to a cotrustee pursuant to and in compliance with s. 518.112. A cotrustee may revoke a delegation previously made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (7), a cotrustee who does not join in an action of another cotrustee is not liable for the action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (9), each cotrustee shall exercise reasonable care to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevent a cotrustee from committing a breach of trust.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compel a cotrustee to redress a breach of trust.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissenting cotrustee who joins in an action at the direction of the majority of the cotrustees and who notifies any cotrustee of the dissent at or before the time of the action is not liable for the action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the terms of a trust instrument provide for the appointment of more than one trustee but confer upon one or more of the trustees, to the exclusion of the others, the power to direct or prevent specified actions of the trustees, the excluded trustees shall act in accordance with the exercise of the power. Except in cases of willful misconduct on the part of the trustee with the authority to direct or prevent actions of the trustees of which the excluded trustee has actual knowledge, an excluded trustee is not liable, individually or as a fiduciary, for any consequence that results from compliance with the exercise of the power, regardless of the information available to the excluded trustees. The excluded trustees are relieved of any obligation to review, inquire, investigate, or make recommendations or evaluations with respect to the exercise of the power. The trustee or trustees having the power to direct or prevent actions of the trustees shall be liable to the beneficiaries with respect to the exercise of the power as if the excluded trustees were not in office and shall have the exclusive obligation to account to and to defend any action brought by the beneficiaries with respect to the exercise of the power.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2006-217; s. 1, ch. 2008-76; s. 5, ch. 2009-117.</History></Section>