<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.0816" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Specific powers of trustee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as limited or restricted by this code, a trustee may:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect trust property and accept or reject additions to the trust property from a settlor, including an asset in which the trustee is personally interested, and hold property in the name of a nominee or in other form without disclosure of the trust so that title to the property may pass by delivery but the trustee is liable for any act of the nominee in connection with the property so held.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire or sell property, for cash or on credit, at public or private sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire an undivided interest in a trust asset, including, but not limited to, a money market mutual fund, mutual fund, or common trust fund, in which asset the trustee holds an undivided interest in any trust capacity, including any money market or other mutual fund from which the trustee or any affiliate or associate of the trustee is entitled to receive reasonable compensation for providing necessary services as an investment adviser, portfolio manager, or servicing agent. A trustee or affiliate or associate of the trustee may receive compensation for such services in addition to fees received for administering the trust provided such compensation is fully disclosed in writing to all qualified beneficiaries. As used in this subsection, the term “mutual fund” includes an open-end or closed-end management investment company or investment trust registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940, 15 U.S.C. ss. 80a-1 et seq., as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exchange, partition, or otherwise change the character of trust property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deposit trust money in an account in a regulated financial service institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Borrow money, with or without security, and mortgage or pledge trust property for a period within or extending beyond the duration of the trust and advance money for the protection of the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an interest in a proprietorship, partnership, limited liability company, business trust, corporation, or other form of business or enterprise, continue the business or other enterprise and take any action that may be taken by shareholders, members, or property owners, including, but not limited to, merging, dissolving, or otherwise changing the form of business organization or contributing additional capital.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to stocks or other securities, exercise the rights of an absolute owner, including, but not limited to, the right to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vote, or give proxies to vote, with or without power of substitution, or enter into or continue a voting trust agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold a security in the name of a nominee or in other form without disclosure of the trust so that title may pass by delivery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay calls, assessments, and other sums chargeable or accruing against the securities, and sell or exercise stock subscription or conversion rights.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deposit the securities with a depositary or other regulated financial service institution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an interest in real property, construct, or make ordinary or extraordinary repairs to, alterations to, or improvements in, buildings or other structures, demolish improvements, raze existing or erect new party walls or buildings, subdivide or develop land, dedicate land to public use or grant public or private easements, and make or vacate plats and adjust boundaries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into a lease for any purpose as lessor or lessee, including a lease or other arrangement for exploration and removal of natural resources, with or without the option to purchase or renew, for a period within or extending beyond the duration of the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grant an option involving a sale, lease, or other disposition of trust property or acquire an option for the acquisition of property, including an option exercisable beyond the duration of the trust, and exercise an option so acquired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insure the property of the trust against damage or loss and insure the trustee, trustee’s agents, and beneficiaries against liability arising from the administration of the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abandon or decline to administer property of no value or of insufficient value to justify the collection or continued administration of such property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay or contest any claim, settle a claim by or against the trust, and release, in whole or in part, a claim belonging to the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay taxes, assessments, compensation of the trustee and of employees and agents of the trust, and other expenses incurred in the administration of the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allocate items of income or expense to trust income or principal, as provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise elections with respect to federal, state, and local taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Select a mode of payment under any employee benefit or retirement plan, annuity, or life insurance payable to the trustee, exercise rights under such plan, annuity, or insurance, including exercise of the right to indemnification for expenses and against liabilities, and take appropriate action to collect the proceeds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make loans out of trust property, including, but not limited to, loans to a beneficiary on terms and conditions that are fair and reasonable under the circumstances, and the trustee has a lien on future distributions for repayment of those loans.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ persons, including, but not limited to, attorneys, accountants, investment advisers, or agents, even if they are the trustee, an affiliate of the trustee, or otherwise associated with the trustee, to advise or assist the trustee in the exercise of any of the trustee’s powers and pay reasonable compensation and costs incurred in connection with such employment from the assets of the trust and act without independent investigation on the recommendations of such persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay an amount distributable to a beneficiary who is under a legal disability or who the trustee reasonably believes is incapacitated, by paying the amount directly to the beneficiary or applying the amount for the beneficiary’s benefit, or by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying the amount to the beneficiary’s guardian of the property or, if the beneficiary does not have a guardian of the property, the beneficiary’s guardian of the person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying the amount to the beneficiary’s custodian under a Uniform Transfers to Minors Act or custodial trustee under a Uniform Custodial Trust Act, and, for that purpose, creating a custodianship or custodial trust;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying the amount to an adult relative or other person having legal or physical care or custody of the beneficiary, to be expended on the beneficiary’s behalf, if the trustee does not know of a guardian of the property, guardian of the person, custodian, or custodial trustee; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managing the amount as a separate fund on the beneficiary’s behalf, subject to the beneficiary’s continuing right to withdraw the distribution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On distribution of trust property or the division or termination of a trust, make distributions in divided or undivided interests, allocate particular assets in proportionate or disproportionate shares, value the trust property for those purposes, and adjust for resulting differences in valuation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prosecute or defend, including appeals, an action, claim, or judicial proceeding in any jurisdiction to protect trust property or the trustee in the performance of the trustee’s duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sign and deliver contracts and other instruments that are useful to achieve or facilitate the exercise of the trustee’s powers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On termination of the trust, exercise the powers appropriate to wind up the administration of the trust and distribute the trust property to the persons entitled to the property, subject to the right of the trustee to retain a reasonable reserve for the payment of debts, expenses, and taxes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2006-217; s. 4, ch. 2007-153.</History></Section>