<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0736.0504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discretionary trusts; effect of standard.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “discretionary distribution” means a distribution that is subject to the trustee’s discretion whether or not the discretion is expressed in the form of a standard of distribution and whether or not the trustee has abused the discretion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether or not a trust contains a spendthrift provision, if a trustee may make discretionary distributions to or for the benefit of a beneficiary, a creditor of the beneficiary, including a creditor as described in s. 736.0503(2), may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compel a distribution that is subject to the trustee’s discretion; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attach or otherwise reach the interest, if any, which the beneficiary might have as a result of the trustee’s authority to make discretionary distributions to or for the benefit of the beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the trustee’s discretion to make distributions for the trustee’s own benefit is limited by an ascertainable standard, a creditor may not reach or compel distribution of the beneficial interest except to the extent the interest would be subject to the creditor’s claim were the beneficiary not acting as trustee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not limit the right of a beneficiary to maintain a judicial proceeding against a trustee for an abuse of discretion or failure to comply with a standard for distribution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-217; s. 14, ch. 2007-153.</History></Section>