<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0112.665" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of Department of Management Services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gather, catalog, and maintain complete, computerized data information on all public employee retirement systems or plans in the state, based upon a review of audits, reports, and other data pertaining to the systems or plans;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive and comment upon all actuarial reviews of retirement systems or plans maintained by units of local government;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with local retirement systems or plans on matters of mutual concern and provide technical assistance to units of local government in the assessment and revision of retirement systems or plans;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue, by January 1 annually, a report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, which report details division activities, findings, and recommendations concerning all governmental retirement systems. The report may include legislation proposed to carry out such recommendations;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a fact sheet for each participating local government defined benefit pension plan summarizing the plan’s actuarial status. The fact sheet should provide a summary of the plan’s most current actuarial data, minimum funding requirements as a percentage of pay, and a 5-year history of funded ratios. The fact sheet must include a brief explanation of each element in order to maximize the transparency of the local government plans. These documents shall be posted on the department’s website. Plan sponsors that have websites must provide a link to the department’s website;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue, by January 1 annually, a report to the Special District Information Program of the Department of Economic Opportunity that includes the participation in and compliance of special districts with the local government retirement system provisions in s. 112.63 and the state-administered retirement system provisions as specified in part I of chapter 121; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt reasonable rules to administer the provisions of this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may subpoena actuarial witnesses, review books and records, hold hearings, and take testimony. A witness shall have the right to be accompanied by counsel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 79-183; s. 7, ch. 84-254; s. 34, ch. 89-169; s. 49, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 24, ch. 94-249; s. 24, ch. 99-255; s. 14, ch. 2000-169; s. 46, ch. 2011-142; s. 3, ch. 2011-216.</History>
</Section>