<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.063" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reimbursement of county employees for educational expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County constitutional officers and county commissioners are authorized to reimburse employees for educational expenses, subject to the following conditions:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coursework must be designed to enhance the knowledge, skills, and abilities relating to official duties which the employees perform.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reimbursement of educational expenses in no way obligates the officer or commissioner to grant time off or leave for the taking or completion of such course or program of instruction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee shall not be permitted to utilize any space, personnel, equipment, or supplies of the office by which he or she is employed in the process of fulfilling any of the requirements imposed by the coursework for which he or she is being reimbursed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limitations contained in subsections (1)-(3) shall not be construed to apply to any courses offered by or as a part of an educational program sponsored by any state agency for which the constitutional officer or commissioner is obligated to perform duties prescribed by law, or any educational program conducted in furtherance of s. 195.002, if such limitations did not exist prior to July 1, 1990.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting employees from receiving otherwise authorized per diem expenses provided for by s. 112.061, nor shall it be construed as prohibiting the payment of wages otherwise due under the provisions of state or federal law.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-80; s. 686, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>