<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.81" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Firefighter” means any person who is certified in compliance with s. 633.35 and who is employed solely within the fire department or public safety department of an employing agency as a full-time firefighter whose primary responsibility is the prevention and extinguishment of fires; the protection of life and property; and the enforcement of municipal, county, and state fire prevention codes and laws pertaining to the prevention and control of fires.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employing agency” means any municipality or the state or any political subdivision thereof, including authorities and special districts, which employs firefighters.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Informal inquiry” means a meeting by supervisory or management personnel with a firefighter about whom an allegation of misconduct has come to the attention of such supervisory or management personnel, the purpose of which meeting is to mediate a complaint or discuss the facts to determine whether a formal investigation should be commenced.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Formal investigation” means the process of investigation ordered by supervisory personnel, after the supervisory personnel have previously determined that the firefighter shall be reprimanded, suspended, or removed, during which the questioning of a firefighter is conducted for the purpose of gathering evidence of misconduct.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrative proceeding” means any nonjudicial hearing which may result in the recommendation, approval, or order of disciplinary action against, or suspension or discharge of, a firefighter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Interrogation” means the questioning of a firefighter by an employing agency in connection with a formal investigation or an administrative proceeding but shall not include arbitration or civil service proceedings. Questioning pursuant to an informal inquiry shall not be deemed to be an interrogation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-6.</History></Section>