<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.193" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Law enforcement, correctional, and correctional probation officers’ commemorative service awards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employer” means a state board, commission, department, division, bureau, or agency or a county or municipality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law enforcement, correctional, or correctional probation officer” means any full-time, part-time, or auxiliary officer as defined in s. 943.10(14).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employer that employs or appoints law enforcement, correctional, or correctional probation officers may present to each such employee who retires under any provision of a state or municipal retirement system, including medical disability retirement, or who is eligible to retire under any such provision but, instead, resigns from one employer to accept an elected public office, one complete uniform including the badge worn by that officer, the officer’s service handgun, if one was issued as part of the officer’s equipment, and an identification card clearly marked “RETIRED.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the death of a law enforcement, correctional, or correctional probation officer, the employer may present to the spouse or other beneficiary of the officer, upon request, one complete uniform, including the badge worn by the officer. However, if a law enforcement, correctional, or correctional probation officer is killed in the line of duty, the employer may present, upon request, to the spouse or other beneficiary of the officer the officer’s service-issued handgun, if one was issued as part of the officer’s equipment. If the employer is not in possession of the service-issued handgun, the employer may, within its discretion, and upon written request of the spouse or other beneficiary, present a similar handgun. The provisions of this section shall also apply in that instance to a law enforcement or correctional officer who died before May 1, 1993. In addition, the officer’s service handgun may be presented by the employer for any such officer who was killed in the line of duty prior to this act becoming a law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each uniform, badge, service handgun, and identification card presented under this section is to commemorate prior service and must be used only in such manner as the employer prescribes by rule. The provisions of this section shall also apply in that instance to a law enforcement officer who died before May 1, 1993.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-335; s. 3, ch. 89-22; s. 1, ch. 93-32; s. 4, ch. 93-149.</History></Section>