<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.661" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investment policies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investment of the assets of any local retirement system or plan must be consistent with a written investment policy adopted by the board. Such policies shall be structured to maximize the financial return to the retirement system or plan consistent with the risks incumbent in each investment and shall be structured to establish and maintain an appropriate diversification of the retirement system or plan’s assets.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCOPE.<EmDash />The investment policy shall apply to funds under the control of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES.<EmDash />The investment policy shall describe the investment objectives of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERFORMANCE MEASUREMENT.<EmDash />The investment policy shall specify performance measures as are appropriate for the nature and size of the assets within the board’s custody.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT AND FIDUCIARY STANDARDS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall describe the level of prudence and ethical standards to be followed by the board in carrying out its investment activities with respect to funds described in this section. The board in performing its investment duties shall comply with the fiduciary standards set forth in the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 at 29 U.S.C. s. 1104(a)(1)(A)-(C). In case of conflict with other provisions of law authorizing investments, the investment and fiduciary standards set forth in this section shall prevail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHORIZED INVESTMENTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The investment policy shall list investments authorized by the board. Investments not listed in the investment policy are prohibited. Unless otherwise authorized by law or ordinance, the investment of the assets of any local retirement system or plan covered by this part shall be subject to the limitations and conditions set forth in s. 215.47(1)-(6), (8), (9), (11) and (17).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local retirement system or plan has investments that, on October 1, 2000, either exceed the applicable limit or do not satisfy the applicable investment standard, such excess or investment not in compliance with the policy may be continued until such time as it is economically feasible to dispose of such investment. However, no additional investment may be made in the investment category which exceeds the applicable limit, unless authorized by law or ordinance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MATURITY AND LIQUIDITY REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall require that the investment portfolio be structured in such manner as to provide sufficient liquidity to pay obligations as they come due. To that end, the investment policy should direct that, to the extent possible, an attempt will be made to match investment maturities with known cash needs and anticipated cash-flow requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PORTFOLIO COMPOSITION.<EmDash />The investment policy shall establish guidelines for investments and limits on security issues, issuers, and maturities. Such guidelines shall be commensurate with the nature and size of the funds within the custody of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RISK AND DIVERSIFICATION.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for appropriate diversification of the investment portfolio. Investments held should be diversified to the extent practicable to control the risk of loss resulting from overconcentration of assets in a specific maturity, issuer, instrument, dealer, or bank through which financial instruments are bought and sold. Diversification strategies within the established guidelines shall be reviewed and revised periodically, as deemed necessary by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXPECTED ANNUAL RATE OF RETURN.<EmDash />The investment policy shall require that, for each actuarial valuation, the board determine the total expected annual rate of return for the current year, for each of the next several years, and for the long term thereafter. This determination must be filed promptly with the Department of Management Services and with the plan’s sponsor and the consulting actuary. The department shall use this determination only to notify the board, the plan’s sponsor, and consulting actuary of material differences between the total expected annual rate of return and the actuarial assumed rate of return.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THIRD-PARTY CUSTODIAL AGREEMENTS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide appropriate arrangements for the holding of assets of the board. Securities should be held with a third party, and all securities purchased by, and all collateral obtained by, the board should be properly designated as an asset of the board. No withdrawal of securities, in whole or in part, shall be made from safekeeping except by an authorized member of the board or the board’s designee. Securities transactions between a broker-dealer and the custodian involving purchase or sale of securities by transfer of money or securities must be made on a “delivery vs. payment” basis, if applicable, to ensure that the custodian will have the security or money, as appropriate, in hand at the conclusion of the transaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MASTER REPURCHASE AGREEMENT.<EmDash />The investment policy shall require all approved institutions and dealers transacting repurchase agreements to execute and perform as stated in the Master Repurchase Agreement. All repurchase agreement transactions shall adhere to the requirements of the Master Repurchase Agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BID REQUIREMENT.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide that the board determine the approximate maturity date based on cash-flow needs and market conditions, analyze and select one or more optimal types of investment, and competitively bid the security in question when feasible and appropriate. Except as otherwise required by law, the most economically advantageous bid must be selected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTERNAL CONTROLS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for a system of internal controls and operational procedures. The board shall establish a system of internal controls which shall be in writing and made a part of the board’s operational procedures. The policy shall provide for review of such controls by independent certified public accountants as part of any financial audit periodically required of the board’s unit of local government. The internal controls should be designed to prevent losses of funds which might arise from fraud, error, misrepresentation by third parties, or imprudent actions by the board or employees of the unit of local government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTINUING EDUCATION.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for the continuing education of the board members in matters relating to investments and the board’s responsibilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORTING.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for appropriate annual or more frequent reporting of investment activities. To that end, the board shall prepare periodic reports for submission to the governing body of the unit of local government which shall include investments in the portfolio by class or type, book value, income earned, and market value as of the report date. Such reports shall be available to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FILING OF INVESTMENT POLICY.<EmDash />Upon adoption by the board, the investment policy shall be promptly filed with the Department of Management Services and the plan’s sponsor and consulting actuary. The effective date of the investment policy, and any amendment thereto, shall be the 31st calendar day following the filing date with the plan sponsor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VALUATION OF ILLIQUID INVESTMENTS.<EmDash />The investment policy shall provide for the valuation of illiquid investments for which a generally recognized market is not available or for which there is no consistent or generally accepted pricing mechanism. If those investments are utilized, the investment policy must include the criteria set forth in s. 215.47(6), except that submission to the Investment Advisory Council is not required. The investment policy shall require that, for each actuarial valuation, the board must verify the determination of the fair market value for those investments and ascertain that the determination complies with all applicable state and federal requirements. The investment policy shall require that the board disclose to the Department of Management Services and the plan’s sponsor each such investment for which the fair market value is not provided.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2000-264; s. 6, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>