<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.31901" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigatory records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If certified pursuant to subsection (2), an investigatory record of the Chief Inspector General within the Executive Office of the Governor or of the employee designated by an agency head as the agency inspector general under s. 112.3189 is exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution until the investigation ceases to be active, or a report detailing the investigation is provided to the Governor or the agency head, or 60 days from the inception of the investigation for which the record was made or received, whichever first occurs. Investigatory records are those records that are related to the investigation of an alleged, specific act or omission or other wrongdoing, with respect to an identifiable person or group of persons, based on information compiled by the Chief Inspector General or by an agency inspector general, as named under the provisions of s. 112.3189, in the course of an investigation. An investigation is active if it is continuing with a reasonable, good faith anticipation of resolution and with reasonable dispatch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor, in the case of the Chief Inspector General, or agency head, in the case of an employee designated as the agency inspector general under s. 112.3189, may certify that such investigatory records require an exemption to protect the integrity of the investigation or avoid unwarranted damage to an individual’s good name or reputation. The certification must specify the nature and purpose of the investigation and shall be kept with the exempt records and made public when the records are made public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to whistle-blower investigations conducted pursuant to ss. 112.3187, 112.3188, 112.3189, and 112.31895.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 93-405; s. 35, ch. 95-398; s. 38, ch. 2005-251; s. 13, ch. 2006-1.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 119.07(6)(w).</Text></Note></Section>