<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.042" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discrimination in county and municipal employment; relief.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is against the public policy of this state for the governing body of any county or municipal agency, board, commission, department, or office, solely because of the race, color, national origin, sex, handicap, or religious creed of any individual, to refuse to hire or employ, to bar, or to discharge from employment such individuals or to otherwise discriminate against such individuals with respect to compensation, hire, tenure, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment, if the individual is the most competent and able to perform the services required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, corporation, association, or other group or body, jointly or severally, who is aggrieved by any decision, regulation, restriction, or resolution adopted by the governing body of any county or municipal agency, board, commission, or department which is an unlawful employment practice under this section may apply to such agency, board, commission, or department at any time for a modification or rescission thereof. If such modification or rescission is refused, any such person, firm, corporation, association or other group or body may, within 30 days after such refusal, but not thereafter, institute original proceedings for relief in the circuit court of the county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is no right to apply to the court for relief on account of any order, requirement, decision, determination, or action of any county or municipal officer pursuant to this section unless there has first been an appeal therefrom to the governing agency, board, commission, or department to which such officer is responsible.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit alternative relief through local civil service systems and boards provided for in s. 14, Art. III of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-334; s. 2, ch. 84-125.</History></Section>