<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retirement; cost-of-living adjustment; employment after retirement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any state official or state employee has attained the age of 70 years or more and has served the state as either an official or employee, or both, for as much as 20 consecutive years or more or for an aggregate time of 30 years or more, or whenever any state official or employee, irrespective of age, has served the state as either an official or employee, or both, for 30 consecutive years or more, or for as much as an aggregate of 35 years or more, such official or employee may retire from office as such official or employee with the right to be paid, and shall be paid monthly on his or her own requisition during the remainder of his or her natural life one-half the amount of the average monthly salary received during the last 10 years of such service; and sufficient money to meet the requirements of this section is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the State Treasury not otherwise appropriated. Provided, that military service in the Armed Forces of the United States shall be computed as a part of the time specified hereinabove as entitling a state official or employee to the benefits of this section. This section shall apply only to persons retired or persons who are on a state payroll June 30, 1953, and remain continuously on a state payroll until eligible to retire. This section shall not affect any state official or employee who has already retired under any retirement act, except that no Cabinet officer qualifying shall receive less than $4,500 per year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any state official or state employee who, as of January 1, 1976, has served the state as either an official or employee, or both, for 29 consecutive years, irrespective of age, and who has a terminal or critical illness, which illness is certified by two physicians licensed in this state as terminal or critical, shall be eligible for early retirement. The benefits accruing to any such person under this section shall be reduced by five-twelfths of 1 percent for each complete month by which such retirement precedes the 30 years of service required under paragraph (a).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any state official or employee eligible to retire pursuant to the provisions of this paragraph may retire from office as such official or employee with the right to be paid, and shall be paid monthly on his or her own requisition, during the remainder of his or her natural life, one-half the amount of the average monthly salary received during the last 10 years of service, less the actuarial reduction provided for in subparagraph 1.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the death of a retired state officer or employee receiving monthly benefits under this section, the monthly benefits shall be paid through the last day of the month of death and shall terminate on that date.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual cost-of-living adjustment shall be made to the monthly benefit payable to retirees who are retired under this section pursuant to the provisions of s. 121.101.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is retired under this section may be employed by an employer who does not participate in a state-administered retirement system and may receive compensation from such employment without limiting or restricting in any way the retirement benefits payable to such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is retired under this section may be reemployed by any private or public employer after retirement and receive retirement benefits and compensation from his or her employer without limitation, except that no person may receive both a salary from reemployment with any agency participating in the Florida Retirement System and retirement benefits under this chapter for a period of 12 months immediately subsequent to the date of retirement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person to whom the limitation in paragraph (a) applies who violates such reemployment limitation and is reemployed with any agency participating in the Florida Retirement System prior to completion of the 12-month limitation period shall give timely notice of this fact in writing to the employer and to the division; and the person’s retirement benefits shall be suspended for the balance of the 12-month limitation period. Any person employed in violation of this subsection and any employing agency which knowingly employs or appoints such person without notifying the Department of Management Services to suspend retirement benefits shall be jointly and severally liable for reimbursement to the retirement trust fund of any benefits paid during the reemployment limitation period. To avoid liability, such employing agency shall have a written statement from the retiree that he or she is not retired from a state-administered retirement system. Any retirement benefits received by such person while reemployed during this limitation period shall be repaid to the retirement trust fund, and the retirement benefits shall remain suspended until such repayment has been made. Any benefits suspended beyond the reemployment limitation period shall apply toward the repayment of benefits received in violation of the reemployment limitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employer, upon employment of any person who has been retired under a state-administered retirement program, shall pay retirement contributions in an amount equal to the unfunded actuarial accrued liability portion of the employer contribution which would be required for a regular member of the Florida Retirement System.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limitations of this subsection apply to reemployment in any capacity with an employer as defined in s. 121.021(10), irrespective of the category of funds from which the person is compensated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 12293, 1927; CGL 242; s. 1, ch. 17274, 1935; s. 1, ch. 20499, 1941; s. 1, ch. 22828, 1945; ss. 1, chs. 28147, 28148, 1953; s. 1, ch. 74-303; s. 1, ch. 76-212; s. 1, ch. 80-126; s. 2, ch. 80-130; s. 1, ch. 81-307; s. 31, ch. 83-217; s. 19, ch. 84-266; s. 1, ch. 90-274; s. 3, ch. 95-146; s. 683, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 96-368; s. 12, ch. 99-255.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 121.001.</Text></Note></Section>