<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of funds; amortization of unfunded liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employee contributions shall be deposited in the retirement system or plan at least monthly. Employer contributions shall be deposited at least quarterly; however, any revenues received from any source by an employer which are specifically collected for the purpose of allocation for deposit into a retirement system or plan shall be so deposited within 30 days of receipt by the employer. All employers and employees participating in the Florida Retirement System and other existing retirement systems which are administered by the Department of Management Services shall continue to make contributions at least monthly.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From and after October 1, 1980, for those plans in existence on October 1, 1980, the total contributions to the retirement system or plan shall be sufficient to meet the normal cost of the retirement system or plan and to amortize the unfunded liability, if any, within 40 years; however, nothing contained in this subsection permits any retirement system or plan to amortize its unfunded liabilities over a period longer than that which remains under its current amortization schedule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a retirement system or plan which comes into existence after October 1, 1980, the unfunded liability, if any, shall be amortized within 40 years of the first plan year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The net increase, if any, in unfunded liability under the plan arising from significant plan amendments adopted, changes in actuarial assumptions, changes in funding methods, or actuarial gains or losses shall be amortized within 30 plan years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the amortization schedule for unfunded liability is to be based on a contribution derived in whole or in part from a percentage of the payroll of the system or plan membership, the assumption as to payroll growth shall not exceed the average payroll growth for the 10 years prior to the latest actuarial valuation of the system or plan unless a transfer, merger, or consolidation of government functions or services occurs, in which case the assumptions for payroll growth may be adjusted and may be based on the membership of the retirement plan or system subsequent to such transfer, merger, or consolidation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An unfunded liability amortization schedule that includes a payroll growth assumption and is in existence on September 30, 1996, or is established thereafter, may be continued using the same payroll growth assumption, or one not exceeding the payroll growth assumption established at the start of the schedule, regardless of the actual 10-year average payroll growth rate, provided that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assumptions underlying the payroll growth rate are consistent with the actuarial assumptions used to determine unfunded liabilities, including, but not limited to, the inflation assumption; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payroll growth rate is reasonable and consistent with future expectations of payroll growth.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An unfunded liability amortization schedule that does not include a payroll growth assumption and is in existence on September 30, 1996, or is established thereafter, may be continued or modified to include a payroll growth assumption, provided that such assumption does not exceed the 10-year average payroll growth rate as of the actuarial valuation date such change in the amortization schedule commences. Such schedule may be continued thereafter, subject to the reasonable and consistent requirements in paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this section shall result in the allocation of chapter 175 or chapter 185 premium tax funds to any other retirement system or plan or for any other use than the exclusive purpose of providing retirement benefits for firefighters or police officers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-170; s. 16, ch. 79-183; s. 2, ch. 84-266; s. 2, ch. 96-368; s. 22, ch. 99-255.</History></Section>