<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0112.3185" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional standards for state agency employees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contractual services” shall be defined as set forth in chapter 287.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means any state officer, department, board, commission, or council of the executive or judicial branch of state government and includes the Public Service Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency employee who participates through decision, approval, disapproval, recommendation, preparation of any part of a purchase request, influencing the content of any specification or procurement standard, rendering of advice, investigation, or auditing or in any other advisory capacity in the procurement of contractual services may not become or be, while an agency employee, the employee of a person contracting with the agency by whom the employee is employed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency employee may not, after retirement or termination, have or hold any employment or contractual relationship with any business entity other than an agency in connection with any contract in which the agency employee participated personally and substantially through decision, approval, disapproval, recommendation, rendering of advice, or investigation while an officer or employee. When the agency employee’s position is eliminated and his or her duties are performed by the business entity, this subsection does not prohibit him or her from employment or contractual relationship with the business entity if the employee’s participation in the contract was limited to recommendation, rendering of advice, or investigation and if the agency head determines that the best interests of the state will be served thereby and provides prior written approval for the particular employee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency employee may not, within 2 years after retirement or termination, have or hold any employment or contractual relationship with any business entity other than an agency in connection with any contract for contractual services which was within his or her responsibility while an employee. If the agency employee’s position is eliminated and his or her duties are performed by the business entity, this subsection may be waived by the agency head through prior written approval for a particular employee if the agency head determines that the best interests of the state will be served thereby.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sum of money paid to a former agency employee during the first year after the cessation of his or her responsibilities, by the agency with whom he or she was employed, for contractual services provided to the agency, shall not exceed the annual salary received on the date of cessation of his or her responsibilities. This subsection may be waived by the agency head for a particular contract if the agency head determines that such waiver will result in significant time or cost savings for the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agency employee acting in an official capacity may not directly or indirectly procure contractual services for his or her own agency from any business entity of which a relative is an officer, partner, director, or proprietor or in which the officer or employee or his or her spouse or child, or any combination of them, has a material interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of any provision of this section is punishable in accordance with s. 112.317.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is not applicable to any employee of the Public Service Commission who was so employed on or before December 31, 1994.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 82-196; s. 32, ch. 83-217; s. 2, ch. 90-268; s. 11, ch. 90-502; s. 9, ch. 94-277; s. 1415, ch. 95-147; s. 9, ch. 2006-275.</History></Section>