<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.2511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Urban infill and redevelopment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 163.2511-163.2520 may be cited as the “Growth Policy Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is declared that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fiscally strong urban centers are beneficial to regional and state economies and resources, are a method for reduction of future urban sprawl, and should be promoted by state, regional, and local governments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health and vibrancy of the urban cores benefit their respective regions and the state; conversely, the deterioration of those urban cores negatively impacts the surrounding area and the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In recognition of the interwoven destiny between the urban center, the suburbs, the region, and the state, the respective governments need to establish a framework and work in partnership with communities and the private sector to revitalize urban centers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State urban policies should guide the state, regional agencies, local governments, and the private sector in preserving and redeveloping existing urban cores and promoting the adequate provision of infrastructure, human services, safe neighborhoods, educational facilities, and economic development to sustain these cores into the future.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Successfully revitalizing and sustaining the urban cores is dependent on addressing, through an integrated and coordinated community effort, a range of varied components essential to a healthy urban environment, including cultural, educational, recreational, economic, transportation, and social service components.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Infill development and redevelopment are recognized to be important components and useful mechanisms for promoting and sustaining urban cores. State and regional entities and local governments should provide incentives to promote urban infill and redevelopment. Existing programs and incentives should be integrated to the extent possible to promote urban infill and redevelopment and to achieve the goals of the state urban policy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-378; s. 186, ch. 2010-102; s. 3, ch. 2012-90.</History>
</Section>