<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Interlocal Cooperation Act of 1969.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be known and may be cited as the “Florida Interlocal Cooperation Act of 1969.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the purpose of this section to permit local governmental units to make the most efficient use of their powers by enabling them to cooperate with other localities on a basis of mutual advantage and thereby to provide services and facilities in a manner and pursuant to forms of governmental organization that will accord best with geographic, economic, population, and other factors influencing the needs and development of local communities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Interlocal agreement” means an agreement entered into pursuant to this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public agency” means a political subdivision, agency, or officer of this state or of any state of the United States, including, but not limited to, state government, county, city, school district, single and multipurpose special district, single and multipurpose public authority, metropolitan or consolidated government, a separate legal entity or administrative entity created under subsection (7), an independently elected county officer, any agency of the United States Government, a federally recognized Native American tribe, and any similar entity of any other state of the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” means a state of the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electric project” means:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any plant, works, system, facilities, and real property and personal property of any nature whatsoever, together with all parts thereof and appurtenances thereto, which is located within or without the state and which is used or useful in the generation, production, transmission, purchase, sale, exchange, or interchange of electric capacity and energy, including facilities and property for the acquisition, extraction, conversion, transportation, storage, reprocessing, or disposal of fuel and other materials of any kind for any such purposes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interest in, or right to, the use, services, output, or capacity of any such plant, works, system, or facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any study to determine the feasibility or costs of any of the foregoing, including, but not limited to, engineering, legal, financial, and other services necessary or appropriate to determine the legality and financial and engineering feasibility of any project referred to in subparagraph 1. or subparagraph 2.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any natural person;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States; any state; any municipality, political subdivision, or municipal corporation created by or pursuant to the laws of the United States or any state; or any board, corporation, or other entity or body declared by or pursuant to the laws of the United States or any state to be a department, agency, or instrumentality thereof;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporation, not-for-profit corporation, firm, partnership, cooperative association, electric cooperative, or business trust of any nature whatsoever which is organized and existing under the laws of the United States or any state; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any foreign country; any political subdivision or governmental unit of a foreign country; or any corporation, not-for-profit corporation, firm, partnership, cooperative association, electric cooperative, or business trust of any nature whatsoever which is organized and existing under the laws of a foreign country or of a political subdivision or governmental unit thereof.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electric utility” has the same meaning as in s. 361.11(2). The term also includes those municipalities, authorities, commissions, special districts, or other public bodies that own, maintain, or operate an electrical generation, transmission, or distribution system within the state on June 25, 2008.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign public utility” means any person whose principal location or principal place of business is not located within this state; who owns, maintains, or operates facilities for the generation, transmission, or distribution of electrical energy; and who supplies electricity to retail or wholesale customers, or both, on a continuous, reliable, and dependable basis. “Foreign public utility” also means any affiliate or subsidiary of such person, the business of which is limited to the generation or transmission, or both, of electrical energy and activities reasonably incidental thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local government liability pool” means a reciprocal insurer as defined in s. 629.021 or any self-insurance program created pursuant to s. 768.28(16), formed and controlled by counties or municipalities of this state to provide liability insurance coverage for counties, municipalities, or other public agencies of this state, which pool may contract with other parties for the purpose of providing claims administration, processing, accounting, and other administrative facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public agency of this state may exercise jointly with any other public agency of the state, of any other state, or of the United States Government any power, privilege, or authority which such agencies share in common and which each might exercise separately.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A joint exercise of power pursuant to this section shall be made by contract in the form of an interlocal agreement, which may provide for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of such interlocal agreement or the power to be exercised and the method by which the purpose will be accomplished or the manner in which the power will be exercised.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration of the interlocal agreement and the method by which it may be rescinded or terminated by any participating public agency prior to the stated date of termination.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The precise organization, composition, and nature of any separate legal or administrative entity created thereby with the powers designated thereto, if such entity may be legally created.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which the parties to an interlocal agreement will provide from their treasuries the financial support for the purpose set forth in the interlocal agreement; payments of public funds that may be made to defray the cost of such purpose; advances of public funds that may be made for the purposes set forth in the interlocal agreements and repayment thereof; and the personnel, equipment, or property of one or more of the parties to the agreement that may be used in lieu of other contributions or advances.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which funds may be paid to and disbursed by any separate legal or administrative entity created pursuant to the interlocal agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method or formula for equitably providing for and allocating and financing the capital and operating costs, including payments to reserve funds authorized by law and payments of principal and interest on obligations. The method or formula shall be established by the participating parties to the interlocal agreement on a ratio of full valuation of real property, on the basis of the amount of services rendered or to be rendered or benefits received or conferred or to be received or conferred, or on any other equitable basis, including the levying of taxes or assessments to pay such costs on the entire area serviced by the parties to the interlocal agreement, subject to such limitations as may be contained in the constitution and statutes of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner of employing, engaging, compensating, transferring, or discharging necessary personnel, subject to the provisions of applicable civil service and merit systems.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fixing and collecting of charges, rates, rents, or fees, where appropriate, and the making and promulgation of necessary rules and regulations and their enforcement by or with the assistance of the participating parties to the interlocal agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which purchases shall be made and contracts entered into.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition, ownership, custody, operation, maintenance, lease, or sale of real or personal property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disposition, diversion, or distribution of any property acquired through the execution of such interlocal agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which, after the completion of the purpose of the interlocal agreement, any surplus money shall be returned in proportion to the contributions made by the participating parties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acceptance of gifts, grants, assistance funds, or bequests.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The making of claims for federal or state aid payable to the individual or several participants on account of the execution of the interlocal agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner of responding for any liabilities that might be incurred through performance of the interlocal agreement and insuring against any such liability.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adjudication of disputes or disagreements, the effects of failure of participating parties to pay their shares of the costs and expenses, and the rights of the other participants in such cases.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which strict accountability of all funds shall be provided for and the manner in which reports, including an annual independent audit, of all receipts and disbursements shall be prepared and presented to each participating party to the interlocal agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other necessary and proper matters agreed upon by the participating public agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An interlocal agreement may provide for one or more parties to the agreement to administer or execute the agreement. One or more parties to the agreement may agree to provide all or a part of the services set forth in the agreement in the manner provided in the agreement. The parties may provide for the mutual exchange of services without payment of any contribution other than such services. The parties may provide for the use or maintenance of facilities or equipment of another party on a cost-reimbursement basis.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An interlocal agreement may provide for a separate legal or administrative entity to administer or execute the agreement, which may be a commission, board, or council constituted pursuant to the agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate legal or administrative entity created by an interlocal agreement shall possess the common power specified in the agreement and may exercise it in the manner or according to the method provided in the agreement. The entity may, in addition to its other powers, be authorized in its own name to make and enter into contracts; to employ agencies or employees; to acquire, construct, manage, maintain, or operate buildings, works, or improvements; to acquire, hold, or dispose of property; and to incur debts, liabilities, or obligations which do not constitute the debts, liabilities, or obligations of any of the parties to the agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No separate legal or administrative entity created by an interlocal agreement shall possess the power or authority to levy any type of tax within the boundaries of any governmental unit participating in the interlocal agreement, to issue any type of bond in its own name, or in any way to obligate financially a governmental unit participating in the interlocal agreement. However, any separate legal entity, the membership of which consists only of electric utilities as defined in s. 361.11(2) and which is created for the purpose of exercising the powers granted by part II of chapter 361, the Joint Power Act, may, for the purpose of financing or refinancing the costs of an electric project, exercise all powers in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of bonds as are conferred by parts I, II, and III of chapter 159 or part II of chapter 166, or both. Any such entity may also issue bond anticipation notes, as provided by s. 215.431, in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of such bonds. All of the privileges, benefits, powers, and terms of parts I, II, and III of chapter 159 and part II of chapter 166, notwithstanding any limitations provided above, shall be fully applicable to such entity. In addition, the governing body of such legal entity may also authorize bonds to be issued and sold from time to time and delegate, to such officer, official, or agent of such legal entity as the governing body of such legal entity shall select, the power to determine the time; manner of sale, public or private; maturities; rate or rates of interest, which may be fixed or may vary at such time or times and in accordance with a specified formula or method of determination; and other terms and conditions as may be deemed appropriate by the officer, official, or agent so designated by the governing body of such legal entity. However, the amounts and maturities of such bonds and the interest rate or rates on such bonds shall be within the limits prescribed by the governing body of such legal entity in its resolution delegating to such officer, official, or agent the power to authorize the issuance and sale of such bonds. Bonds issued pursuant to this section may be validated as provided in chapter 75 and paragraph (15)(f). However, the complaint in any action to validate such bonds shall be filed only in the Circuit Court for Leon County. The notice required to be published by s. 75.06 shall be published only in Leon County, and the complaint and order of the circuit court shall be served only on the State Attorney of the Second Judicial Circuit and on the state attorney of each circuit in which a public agency participating in the electric project lies. Notice of such proceedings shall be published in the manner and at the time required by s. 75.06 in Leon County and in each county in which any portion of any public agency participating in the electric project lies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (c), any separate legal entity created pursuant to this section and controlled by the municipalities or counties of this state or by one or more municipality and one or more county of this state, the membership of which consists or is to consist of municipalities only, counties only, or one or more municipality and one or more county, may, for the purpose of financing or refinancing any capital projects, exercise all powers in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of bonds. Notwithstanding any limitations provided in this section, all of the privileges, benefits, powers, and terms of part I of chapter 125, part II of chapter 166, and part I of chapter 159 shall be fully applicable to such entity. Bonds issued by such entity shall be deemed issued on behalf of the counties or municipalities which enter into loan agreements with such entity as provided in this paragraph. Any loan agreement executed pursuant to a program of such entity shall be governed by the provisions of part I of chapter 159 or, in the case of counties, part I of chapter 125, or in the case of municipalities and charter counties, part II of chapter 166. Proceeds of bonds issued by such entity may be loaned to counties or municipalities of this state or a combination of municipalities and counties, whether or not such counties or municipalities are also members of the entity issuing the bonds. The issuance of bonds by such entity to fund a loan program to make loans to municipalities or counties or a combination of municipalities and counties with one another for capital projects to be identified subsequent to the issuance of the bonds to fund such loan programs is deemed to be a paramount public purpose. Any entity so created may also issue bond anticipation notes, as provided by s. 215.431, in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of such bonds. In addition, the governing body of such legal entity may also authorize bonds to be issued and sold from time to time and may delegate, to such officer, official, or agent of such legal entity as the governing body of such legal entity may select, the power to determine the time; manner of sale, public or private; maturities; rate or rates of interest, which may be fixed or may vary at such time or times and in accordance with a specified formula or method of determination; and other terms and conditions as may be deemed appropriate by the officer, official, or agent so designated by the governing body of such legal entity. However, the amounts and maturities of such bonds and the interest rate or rates of such bonds shall be within the limits prescribed by the governing body of such legal entity and its resolution delegating to such officer, official, or agent the power to authorize the issuance and sale of such bonds. A local government self-insurance fund established under this section may financially guarantee bonds or bond anticipation notes issued or loans made under this subsection. Bonds issued pursuant to this paragraph may be validated as provided in chapter 75. The complaint in any action to validate such bonds shall be filed only in the Circuit Court for Leon County. The notice required to be published by s. 75.06 shall be published only in Leon County, and the complaint and order of the circuit court shall be served only on the State Attorney of the Second Judicial Circuit and on the state attorney of each circuit in each county where the public agencies which were initially a party to the agreement are located. Notice of such proceedings shall be published in the manner and the time required by s. 75.06 in Leon County and in each county where the public agencies which were initially a party to the agreement are located. Obligations of any county or municipality pursuant to a loan agreement as described in this paragraph may be validated as provided in chapter 75.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (c), any separate legal entity, created pursuant to the provisions of this section and controlled by counties or municipalities of this state, the membership of which consists or is to consist only of public agencies of this state, may, for the purpose of financing the provision or acquisition of liability or property coverage contracts for or from one or more local government liability or property pools to provide liability or property coverage for counties, municipalities, or other public agencies of this state, exercise all powers in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of bonds. All of the privileges, benefits, powers, and terms of s. 125.01 relating to counties and s. 166.021 relating to municipalities shall be fully applicable to such entity and such entity shall be considered a unit of local government for all of the privileges, benefits, powers, and terms of part I of chapter 159. Bonds issued by such entity shall be deemed issued on behalf of counties, municipalities, or public agencies which enter into loan agreements with such entity as provided in this paragraph. Proceeds of bonds issued by such entity may be loaned to counties, municipalities, or other public agencies of this state, whether or not such counties, municipalities, or other public agencies are also members of the entity issuing the bonds, and such counties, municipalities, or other public agencies may in turn deposit such loan proceeds with a separate local government liability or property pool for purposes of providing or acquiring liability or property coverage contracts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Counties or municipalities of this state are authorized pursuant to this section, in addition to the authority provided by s. 125.01, part II of chapter 166, and other applicable law, to issue bonds for the purpose of acquiring liability coverage contracts from a local government liability pool. Any individual county or municipality may, by entering into interlocal agreements with other counties, municipalities, or public agencies of this state, issue bonds on behalf of itself and other counties, municipalities, or other public agencies, for purposes of acquiring a liability coverage contract or contracts from a local government liability pool. Counties, municipalities, or other public agencies are also authorized to enter into loan agreements with any entity created pursuant to subparagraph 1., or with any county or municipality issuing bonds pursuant to this subparagraph, for the purpose of obtaining bond proceeds with which to acquire liability coverage contracts from a local government liability pool. No county, municipality, or other public agency shall at any time have more than one loan agreement outstanding for the purpose of obtaining bond proceeds with which to acquire liability coverage contracts from a local government liability pool. Obligations of any county, municipality, or other public agency of this state pursuant to a loan agreement as described above may be validated as provided in chapter 75. Prior to the issuance of any bonds pursuant to subparagraph 1. or this subparagraph for the purpose of acquiring liability coverage contracts from a local government liability pool, the reciprocal insurer or the manager of any self-insurance program shall demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission that excess liability coverage for counties, municipalities, or other public agencies is reasonably unobtainable in the amounts provided by such pool or that the liability coverage obtained through acquiring contracts from a local government liability pool, after taking into account costs of issuance of bonds and any other administrative fees, is less expensive to counties, municipalities, or special districts than similar commercial coverage then reasonably available.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity created pursuant to this section or any county or municipality may also issue bond anticipation notes, as provided by s. 215.431, in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of such bonds. In addition, the governing body of such legal entity or the governing body of such county or municipality may also authorize bonds to be issued and sold from time to time and may delegate, to such officer, official, or agent of such legal entity as the governing body of such legal entity may select, the power to determine the time; manner of sale, public or private; maturities; rate or rates of interest, which may be fixed or may vary at such time or times and in accordance with a specified formula or method of determination; and other terms and conditions as may be deemed appropriate by the officer, official, or agent so designated by the governing body of such legal entity. However, the amounts and maturities of such bonds and the interest rate or rates of such bonds shall be within the limits prescribed by the governing body of such legal entity and its resolution delegating to such officer, official, or agent the power to authorize the issuance and sale of such bonds. Any series of bonds issued pursuant to this paragraph for liability coverage shall mature no later than 7 years following the date of issuance. A series of bonds issued pursuant to this paragraph for property coverage shall mature no later than 30 years following the date of issuance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds issued pursuant to subparagraph 1. may be validated as provided in chapter 75. The complaint in any action to validate such bonds shall be filed only in the Circuit Court for Leon County. The notice required to be published by s. 75.06 shall be published in Leon County and in each county which is an owner of the entity issuing the bonds, or in which a member of the entity is located, and the complaint and order of the circuit court shall be served only on the State Attorney of the Second Judicial Circuit and on the state attorney of each circuit in each county or municipality which is an owner of the entity issuing the bonds or in which a member of the entity is located.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds issued pursuant to subparagraph 2. may be validated as provided in chapter 75. The complaint in any action to validate such bonds shall be filed in the circuit court of the county or municipality which will issue the bonds. The notice required to be published by s. 75.06 shall be published only in the county where the complaint is filed, and the complaint and order of the circuit court shall be served only on the state attorney of the circuit in the county or municipality which will issue the bonds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The participation by any county, municipality, or other public agency of this state in a local government liability pool shall not be deemed a waiver of immunity to the extent of liability coverage, nor shall any contract entered regarding such a local government liability pool be required to contain any provision for waiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, any separate legal entity, created pursuant to the provisions of this section, wholly owned by the municipalities or counties of this state, the membership of which consists or is to consist only of municipalities or counties of this state, may exercise the right and power of eminent domain, including the procedural powers under chapters 73 and 74, if such right and power is granted to such entity by the interlocal agreement creating the entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, any separate legal entity created under this section, the membership of which is limited to municipalities and counties of the state, and which may include a special district in addition to a municipality or county or both, may acquire, own, construct, improve, operate, and manage public facilities, or finance facilities on behalf of any person, relating to a governmental function or purpose, including, but not limited to, wastewater facilities, water or alternative water supply facilities, and water reuse facilities, which may serve populations within or outside of the members of the entity. Notwithstanding s. 367.171(7), any separate legal entity created under this paragraph is not subject to Public Service Commission jurisdiction. The separate legal entity may not provide utility services within the service area of an existing utility system unless it has received the consent of the utility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this paragraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Host government” means the governing body of the county, if the largest number of equivalent residential connections currently served by a system of the utility is located in the unincorporated area, or the governing body of a municipality, if the largest number of equivalent residential connections currently served by a system of the utility is located within that municipality’s boundaries.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Separate legal entity” means any entity created by interlocal agreement the membership of which is limited to two or more special districts, municipalities, or counties of the state, but which entity is legally separate and apart from any of its member governments.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“System” means a water or wastewater facility or group of such facilities owned by one entity or affiliate entities.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Utility” means a water or wastewater utility and includes every person, separate legal entity, lessee, trustee, or receiver owning, operating, managing, or controlling a system, or proposing construction of a system, who is providing, or proposes to provide, water or wastewater service to the public for compensation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate legal entity that seeks to acquire any utility shall notify the host government in writing by certified mail about the contemplated acquisition not less than 30 days before any proposed transfer of ownership, use, or possession of any utility assets by such separate legal entity. The potential acquisition notice shall be provided to the legislative head of the governing body of the host government and to its chief administrative officer and shall provide the name and address of a contact person for the separate legal entity and information identified in s. 367.071(4)(a) concerning the contemplated acquisition.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days following receipt of the notice, the host government may adopt a resolution to become a member of the separate legal entity, adopt a resolution to approve the utility acquisition, or adopt a resolution to prohibit the utility acquisition by the separate legal entity if the host government determines that the proposed acquisition is not in the public interest. A resolution adopted by the host government which prohibits the acquisition may include conditions that would make the proposal acceptable to the host government.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a host government adopts a membership resolution, the separate legal entity shall accept the host government as a member on the same basis as its existing members before any transfer of ownership, use, or possession of the utility or the utility facilities. If a host government adopts a resolution to approve the utility acquisition, the separate legal entity may complete the acquisition. If a host government adopts a prohibition resolution, the separate legal entity may not acquire the utility within that host government’s territory without the specific consent of the host government by future resolution. If a host government does not adopt a prohibition resolution or an approval resolution, the separate legal entity may proceed to acquire the utility after the 30-day notice period without further notice.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the acquisition or construction of any utility systems by a separate legal entity created under this paragraph, revenues or any other income may not be transferred or paid to a member of a separate legal entity, or to any other special district, county, or municipality, from user fees or other charges or revenues generated from customers that are not physically located within the jurisdictional or service delivery boundaries of the member, special district, county, or municipality receiving the transfer or payment. Any transfer or payment to a member, special district, or other local government must be solely from user fees or other charges or revenues generated from customers that are physically located within the jurisdictional or service delivery boundaries of the member, special district, or local government receiving the transfer of payment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is an alternative provision otherwise provided by law as authorized in s. 4, Art. VIII of the State Constitution for any transfer of power as a result of an acquisition of a utility by a separate legal entity from a municipality, county, or special district.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The entity may finance or refinance the acquisition, construction, expansion, and improvement of such facilities relating to a governmental function or purpose through the issuance of its bonds, notes, or other obligations under this section or as otherwise authorized by law. The entity has all the powers provided by the interlocal agreement under which it is created or which are necessary to finance, own, operate, or manage the public facility, including, without limitation, the power to establish rates, charges, and fees for products or services provided by it, the power to levy special assessments, the power to sell or finance all or a portion of such facility, and the power to contract with a public or private entity to manage and operate such facilities or to provide or receive facilities, services, or products. Except as may be limited by the interlocal agreement under which the entity is created, all of the privileges, benefits, powers, and terms of s. 125.01, relating to counties, and s. 166.021, relating to municipalities, are fully applicable to the entity. However, neither the entity nor any of its members on behalf of the entity may exercise the power of eminent domain over the facilities or property of any existing water or wastewater plant utility system, nor may the entity acquire title to any water or wastewater plant utility facilities, other facilities, or property which was acquired by the use of eminent domain after the effective date of this act. Bonds, notes, and other obligations issued by the entity are issued on behalf of the public agencies that are members of the entity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity created under this section may also issue bond anticipation notes in connection with the authorization, issuance, and sale of bonds. The bonds may be issued as serial bonds or as term bonds or both. Any entity may issue capital appreciation bonds or variable rate bonds. Any bonds, notes, or other obligations must be authorized by resolution of the governing body of the entity and bear the date or dates; mature at the time or times, not exceeding 40 years from their respective dates; bear interest at the rate or rates; be payable at the time or times; be in the denomination; be in the form; carry the registration privileges; be executed in the manner; be payable from the sources and in the medium or payment and at the place; and be subject to the terms of redemption, including redemption prior to maturity, as the resolution may provide. If any officer whose signature, or a facsimile of whose signature, appears on any bonds, notes, or other obligations ceases to be an officer before the delivery of the bonds, notes, or other obligations, the signature or facsimile is valid and sufficient for all purposes as if he or she had remained in office until the delivery. The bonds, notes, or other obligations may be sold at public or private sale for such price as the governing body of the entity shall determine. Pending preparation of the definitive bonds, the entity may issue interim certificates, which shall be exchanged for the definitive bonds. The bonds may be secured by a form of credit enhancement, if any, as the entity deems appropriate. The bonds may be secured by an indenture of trust or trust agreement. In addition, the governing body of the legal entity may delegate, to an officer, official, or agent of the legal entity as the governing body of the legal entity may select, the power to determine the time; manner of sale, public or private; maturities; rate of interest, which may be fixed or may vary at the time and in accordance with a specified formula or method of determination; and other terms and conditions as may be deemed appropriate by the officer, official, or agent so designated by the governing body of the legal entity. However, the amount and maturity of the bonds, notes, or other obligations and the interest rate of the bonds, notes, or other obligations must be within the limits prescribed by the governing body of the legal entity and its resolution delegating to an officer, official, or agent the power to authorize the issuance and sale of the bonds, notes, or other obligations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds, notes, or other obligations issued under this paragraph may be validated as provided in chapter 75. The complaint in any action to validate the bonds, notes, or other obligations must be filed only in the Circuit Court for Leon County. The notice required to be published by s. 75.06 must be published in Leon County and in each county that is a member of the entity issuing the bonds, notes, or other obligations, or in which a member of the entity is located, and the complaint and order of the circuit court must be served only on the State Attorney of the Second Judicial Circuit and on the state attorney of each circuit in each county that is a member of the entity issuing the bonds, notes, or other obligations or in which a member of the entity is located. Section 75.04(2) does not apply to a complaint for validation brought by the legal entity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accomplishment of the authorized purposes of a legal entity created under this paragraph is in all respects for the benefit of the people of the state, for the increase of their commerce and prosperity, and for the improvement of their health and living conditions. Since the legal entity will perform essential governmental functions in accomplishing its purposes, the legal entity is not required to pay any taxes or assessments of any kind whatsoever upon any property acquired or used by it for such purposes or upon any revenues at any time received by it. The bonds, notes, and other obligations of an entity, their transfer, and the income therefrom, including any profits made on the sale thereof, are at all times free from taxation of any kind by the state or by any political subdivision or other agency or instrumentality thereof. The exemption granted in this subparagraph is not applicable to any tax imposed by chapter 220 on interest, income, or profits on debt obligations owned by corporations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (c), any separate legal entity consisting of an alliance, as defined in s. 395.106(2)(a), created pursuant to this paragraph and controlled by and whose members consist of eligible entities comprised of special districts created pursuant to a special act and having the authority to own or operate one or more hospitals licensed in this state or hospitals licensed in this state that are owned, operated, or funded by a county or municipality, for the purpose of providing property insurance coverage as defined in s. 395.106(2)(b), for such eligible entities, may exercise all powers under this subsection in connection with borrowing funds for such purposes, including, without limitation, the authorization, issuance, and sale of bonds, notes, or other obligations of indebtedness. Borrowed funds, including, but not limited to, bonds issued by such alliance shall be deemed issued on behalf of such eligible entities that enter into loan agreements with such separate legal entity as provided in this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such separate legal entity shall have all the powers that are provided by the interlocal agreement under which the entity is created or that are necessary to finance, operate, or manage the alliance’s property insurance coverage program. Proceeds of bonds, notes, or other obligations issued by such an entity may be loaned to any one or more eligible entities. Such eligible entities are authorized to enter into loan agreements with any separate legal entity created pursuant to this paragraph for the purpose of obtaining moneys with which to finance property insurance coverage or claims. Obligations of any eligible entity pursuant to a loan agreement as described in this paragraph may be validated as provided in chapter 75.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bonds, notes, or other obligations to be issued or incurred by a separate legal entity created pursuant to this paragraph shall be authorized by resolution of the governing body of such entity and bear the date or dates; mature at the time or times, not exceeding 30 years from their respective dates; bear interest at the rate or rates, which may be fixed or vary at such time or times and in accordance with a specified formula or method of determination; be payable at the time or times; be in the denomination; be in the form; carry the registration privileges; be executed in the manner; be payable from the sources and in the medium of payment and at the place; and be subject to redemption, including redemption prior to maturity, as the resolution may provide. The bonds, notes, or other obligations may be sold at public or private sale for such price as the governing body of the separate legal entity shall determine. The bonds may be secured by such credit enhancement, if any, as the governing body of the separate legal entity deems appropriate. The bonds may be secured by an indenture of trust or trust agreement. In addition, the governing body of the separate legal entity may delegate, to such officer or official of such entity as the governing body may select, the power to determine the time; manner of sale, public or private; maturities; rate or rates of interest, which may be fixed or may vary at such time or times and in accordance with a specified formula or method of determination; and other terms and conditions as may be deemed appropriate by the officer or official so designated by the governing body of such separate legal entity. However, the amounts and maturities of such bonds, the interest rate or rates, and the purchase price of such bonds shall be within the limits prescribed by the governing body of such separate legal entity in its resolution delegating to such officer or official the power to authorize the issuance and sale of such bonds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds issued pursuant to this paragraph may be validated as provided in chapter 75. The complaint in any action to validate such bonds shall be filed only in the Circuit Court for Leon County. The notice required to be published by s. 75.06 shall be published in Leon County and in each county in which an eligible entity that is a member of an alliance is located. The complaint and order of the circuit court shall be served only on the State Attorney of the Second Judicial Circuit and on the state attorney of each circuit in each county in which an eligible entity receiving bond proceeds is located.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accomplishment of the authorized purposes of a separate legal entity created under this paragraph is deemed in all respects for the benefit, increase of the commerce and prosperity, and improvement of the health and living conditions of the people of this state. Inasmuch as the separate legal entity performs essential public functions in accomplishing its purposes, the separate legal entity is not required to pay any taxes or assessments of any kind upon any property acquired or used by the entity for such purposes or upon any revenues at any time received by the entity. The bonds, notes, and other obligations of such separate legal entity, the transfer of and income from such bonds, notes, and other obligations, including any profits made on the sale of such bonds, notes, and other obligations, are at all times free from taxation of any kind of the state or by any political subdivision or other agency or instrumentality of the state. The exemption granted in this paragraph does not apply to any tax imposed by chapter 220 on interest, income, or profits on debt obligations owned by corporations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The participation by any eligible entity in an alliance or a separate legal entity created pursuant to this paragraph may not be deemed a waiver of immunity to the extent of liability or any other coverage, and a contract entered regarding such alliance is not required to contain any provision for waiver.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the purpose set forth in an interlocal agreement is the acquisition, construction, or operation of a revenue-producing facility, the agreement may provide for the repayment or return to the parties of all or any part of the contributions, payments, or advances made by the parties pursuant to subsection (5) and for payment to the parties of any sum derived from the revenues of such facility. Payments, repayments, or returns shall be made at any time and in the manner specified in the agreement and may be made at any time on or prior to the rescission or termination of the agreement or completion of the purposes of the agreement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All of the privileges and immunities from liability; exemptions from laws, ordinances, and rules; and pensions and relief, disability, workers’ compensation, and other benefits which apply to the activity of officers, agents, or employees of any public agents or employees of any public agency when performing their respective functions within the territorial limits for their respective agencies shall apply to the same degree and extent to the performance of such functions and duties of such officers, agents, or employees extraterritorially under the provisions of any such interlocal agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An interlocal agreement does not relieve a public agency of any obligation or responsibility imposed upon it by law except to the extent of actual and timely performance thereof by one or more of the parties to the agreement or any legal or administrative entity created by the agreement, in which case the performance may be offered in satisfaction of the obligation or responsibility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All of the privileges and immunities from liability and exemptions from laws, ordinances, and rules which apply to the municipalities and counties of this state apply to the same degree and extent to any separate legal entity, created pursuant to the provisions of this section, wholly owned by the municipalities or counties of this state, the membership of which consists or is to consist only of municipalities or counties of this state, unless the interlocal agreement creating such entity provides to the contrary. All of the privileges and immunities from liability; exemptions from laws, ordinances, and rules; and pension and relief, disability, and worker’s compensation, and other benefits which apply to the activity of officers, agents, employees, or employees of agents of counties and municipalities of this state which are parties to an interlocal agreement creating a separate legal entity pursuant to the provisions of this section shall apply to the same degree and extent to the officers, agents, or employees of such entity unless the interlocal agreement creating such entity provides to the contrary.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public agency entering into an interlocal agreement may appropriate funds and sell, give, or otherwise supply any party designated to operate the joint or cooperative undertaking such personnel, services, facilities, property, franchises, or funds thereof as may be within its legal power to furnish.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public agency entering into an interlocal agreement may receive grants-in-aid or other assistance funds from the United States Government or this state for use in carrying out the purposes of the interlocal agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to its effectiveness, an interlocal agreement and subsequent amendments thereto shall be filed with the clerk of the circuit court of each county where a party to the agreement is located. However, if the parties to the agreement are located in multiple counties and the agreement under subsection (7) provides for a separate legal entity or administrative entity to administer the agreement, the interlocal agreement and any amendments thereto may be filed with the clerk of the circuit court in the county where the legal or administrative entity maintains its principal place of business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any public agency entering into an agreement pursuant to this section may appropriate funds and may sell, lease, give, or otherwise supply the administrative joint board or other legal or administrative entity created to operate the joint or cooperative undertaking by providing such personnel or services therefor as may be within its legal power to furnish.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers and authority granted by this section shall be in addition and supplemental to those granted by any other general, local, or special law. Nothing contained herein shall be deemed to interfere with the application of any other law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is intended to authorize the entry into contracts for the performance of service functions of public agencies, but shall not be deemed to authorize the delegation of the constitutional or statutory duties of state, county, or city officers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or of any other law except s. 361.14, any public agency of this state which is an electric utility, or any separate legal entity created pursuant to the provisions of this section, the membership of which consists only of electric utilities, and which exercises or proposes to exercise the powers granted by part II of chapter 361, the Joint Power Act, may exercise any or all of the following powers:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such public agency or legal entity, or both, may plan, finance, acquire, construct, reconstruct, own, lease, operate, maintain, repair, improve, extend, or otherwise participate jointly in one or more electric projects, which are proposed, existing, or under construction and which are located or to be located within or without this state, with any one or more of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such legal entity;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more electric utilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more foreign public utilities; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other person,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">if the right to full possession and to all of the use, services, output, and capacity of any such electric project during the original estimated useful life thereof is vested, subject to creditors’ rights, in any one or more of such legal entities, electric utilities, or foreign public utilities, or in any combination thereof. Any such public agency or legal entity, or both, may act as agent or designate one or more persons, whether or not participating in an electric project, to act as its agent in connection with the planning, design, engineering, licensing, acquisition, construction, completion, management, control, operation, maintenance, repair, renewal, addition, replacement, improvement, modification, insuring, decommissioning, cleanup, retirement, or disposal, or all of the foregoing, of such electric project or electric projects.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case in which any such public agency or legal entity, or both, participate in an electric project with any one or more of the following:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such legal entity;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more electric utilities;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more foreign public utilities; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other person,</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and if the right to full possession and to all of the use, services, output, and capacity of any such electric project during the original estimated useful life thereof is vested, subject to creditors’ rights, in any one or more of such legal entities, electric utilities, or foreign public utilities, or in any combination thereof, such public agency or legal entity, or both, may enter into an agreement or agreements with respect to such electric project with the other person or persons participating therein, and such legal entity may enter into an agreement or agreements with one or more public agencies who are parties to the interlocal agreement creating such legal entity. Any such agreement may be for such period, including, but not limited to, an unspecified period, and may contain such other terms, conditions, and provisions, consistent with the provisions of this section, as the parties thereto shall determine. In connection with entry into and performance pursuant to any such agreement, with the selection of any person or persons with which any such public agency or legal entity, or both, may enter into any such agreement, and with the selection of any electric project to which such agreement may relate, no such public agency or legal entity shall be required to comply with any general, local, or special statute, including, but not limited to, the provisions of s. 287.055, or with any charter provision of any public agency, which would otherwise require public bidding, competitive negotiation, or both.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such agreement may include, but need not be limited to, any or all of the following:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions defining what constitutes a default thereunder and providing for the rights and remedies of the parties thereto upon the occurrence of such a default, including, without limitation, the right to discontinue the delivery of products or services to a defaulting party and requirements that the remaining parties not in default who are entitled to receive products or services from the same electric project may be required to pay for and use or otherwise dispose of, on a proportionate or other basis, all or some portion of the products and services which were to be purchased by the defaulting party.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions granting one or more of the parties the option to purchase the interest or interests of one or more other parties in the electric project upon such occurrences, and at such times and pursuant to such terms and conditions, as the parties may agree, notwithstanding the limitations on options in the provisions of any law to the contrary.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions setting forth restraints on alienation of the interests of the parties in the electric project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for the planning, design, engineering, licensing, acquisition, construction, completion, management, control, operation, maintenance, repair, renewal, addition, replacement, improvement, modification, insuring, decommissioning, cleanup, retirement, or disposal, or all of the foregoing of such electric project by any one or more of the parties to such agreement, which party or parties may be designated in or pursuant to such agreement as agent or agents on behalf of itself and one or more of the other parties thereto or by such other means as may be determined by the parties thereto.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for a method or methods of determining and allocating among or between the parties the costs of planning, design, engineering, licensing, acquisition, construction, completion, management, control, operation, maintenance, repair, renewal, addition, replacement, improvement, modification, insuring, decommissioning, cleanup, retirement, or disposal, or all of the foregoing with respect to such electric project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions that any such public agency or legal entity, or both, will not rescind, terminate, or amend any contract or agreement relating to such electric project without the consent of one or more persons with which such public agency or legal entity, or both, have entered into an agreement pursuant to this section or without the consent of one or more persons with whom any such public agency or legal entity, or both, have made a covenant or who are third-party beneficiaries of any such covenant.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions whereby any such public agency or legal entity, or both, are obligated to pay for the products and services of such electric project and the support of such electric project, including, without limitation, those activities set forth in sub-subparagraph d., without setoff or counterclaim and irrespective of whether such products or services are furnished, made available, or delivered to such public agency or legal entity, or both, or whether any electric project contemplated by such contract or agreement is completed, operable, or operating, and notwithstanding suspension, interruption, interference, reduction, or curtailment of the products and services of such electric project and notwithstanding the quality, or failure, of performance of any one or more of the activities set forth in sub-subparagraph d. with respect to such electric project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions that in the event of the failure or refusal of any such public agency or legal entity, or both, to perform punctually any specified covenant or obligation contained in or undertaken pursuant to any such agreement, any one or more parties to such agreement or any one or more persons who have been designated in such agreement as third-party beneficiaries of such covenant or obligation may enforce the performance of such public agency or legal entity by an action at law or in equity, including, but not limited to, specific performance or mandamus.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions obligating any such public agency or legal entity, or both, to indemnify, including, without limitation, indemnification against the imposition or collection of local, state, or federal taxes and interest or penalties related thereto, or payments made in lieu thereof, to hold harmless, or to waive claims or rights for recovery, including claims or rights for recovery based on sole negligence, gross negligence, any other type of negligence, or any other act or omission, intentional or otherwise, against one or more of the other parties to such agreement. Such provisions may define the class or classes of persons for whose acts, intentional or otherwise, a party shall not be responsible; and all of such provisions may be upon such terms and conditions as the parties thereto shall determine.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="j">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions obligating any such public agency or legal entity, or both, not to dissolve until all principal and interest payments for all bonds and other evidences of indebtedness issued by such public agency or legal entity, or both, have been paid or otherwise provided for and until all contractual obligations and duties of such public agency or legal entity have been fully performed or discharged, or both.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="k">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions obligating any such public agency or legal entity, or both, to establish, levy, and collect rents, rates, and other charges for the products and services provided by such legal entity or provided by the electric or other integrated utility system of such public agency, which rents, rates, and other charges shall be at least sufficient to meet the operation and maintenance expenses of such electric or integrated utility system; to comply with all covenants pertaining thereto contained in, and all other provisions of, any resolution, trust indenture, or other security agreement relating to any bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued or to be issued by any such public agency or legal entity; to generate funds sufficient to fulfill the terms of all other contracts and agreements made by such public agency or legal entity, or both; and to pay all other amounts payable from or constituting a lien or charge on the revenues derived from the products and services of such legal entity or constituting a lien or charge on the revenues of the electric or other integrated utility system of such public agency.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="l">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions obligating such legal entity to enforce the covenants and obligations of each such public agency with which such legal entity has entered into a contract or agreement with respect to such electric project.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="m">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions obligating such legal entity not to permit any such public agency to withdraw from such legal entity until all contractual obligations and duties of such legal entity and of each such public agency with which it has entered into a contract or agreement with respect to such electric project have been fully performed, discharged, or both.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="n">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions obligating each such public agency which has entered into a contract or agreement with such legal entity with respect to an electric project not to withdraw from, or cause or participate in the dissolution of, such legal entity until all duties and obligations of such legal entity and of each such public agency arising from all contracts and agreements entered into by such public agency or legal entity, or both, have been fully performed, discharged, or both.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="o">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions obligating each such public agency which has entered into a contract or agreement with such legal entity or which has entered into a contract or agreement with any other person or persons with respect to such electric project to maintain its electric or other integrated utility system in good repair and operating condition until all duties and obligations of each such public agency and of each such legal entity arising out of all contracts and agreements with respect to such electric project entered into by each such public agency or legal entity, or both, have been fully performed, discharged, or both.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All actions taken by an agent designated in accordance with the provisions of any such agreement may, if so provided in the agreement, be made binding upon such public agency or legal entity, or both, without further action or approval by such public agency or legal entity, or both. Any agent or agents designated in any such agreement shall be governed by the laws and rules applicable to such agent as a separate entity and not by any laws or rules which may be applicable to any of the other participating parties and not otherwise applicable to the agent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such legal entity may acquire services, output, capacity, energy, or any combination thereof only from:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An electric project in which it has an ownership interest; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other source:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent of replacing the services, output, capacity, energy, or combination thereof of its share of an electric project when the output or capacity of such electric project is reduced or unavailable; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time and in any amount for resale to any of its members as necessary to meet their retail load requirements.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, under sub-subparagraph 2.b., such legal entity may not purchase wholesale power for resale to any of its members from any electric utility as a result of any legal proceeding commenced by the legal entity or any of its members after January 1, 1982, before any state or federal court or administrative body, to the extent that such purchase or proceeding would involuntarily expand the responsibility of the electric utility to provide such wholesale power.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such legal entity may sell services, output, capacity, energy, or any combination thereof only to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its members to meet their retail load requirements;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other electric utilities or foreign public utilities which have ownership interests in, or contractual arrangements which impose on such electric utilities or foreign public utilities obligations which are the economic equivalents of ownership interests in, the electric project from which such services, output, capacity, energy, or combination thereof is to be acquired;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other electric utility or foreign public utility to dispose of services, output, capacity, energy, or any combination thereof that is surplus to the requirements of such legal entity:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such surplus results from default by one or more of the members of such legal entity under a contract or contracts for the purchase of such services, output, capacity, energy, or combination thereof; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the revenues from such contract or contracts are pledged as security for payment of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued by such legal entity or if such revenues are required by such legal entity to meet its obligations under any contract or agreement entered into by such legal entity pursuant to paragraph (b);</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other electric utility or foreign public utility for a period not to exceed 5 years from the later to occur of the date of commercial operation of, or the date of acquisition by such legal entity of any ownership interest in or right to acquire services, output, capacity, energy, or any combination thereof from, the electric project from which such services, output, capacity, energy, or combination thereof is to be acquired, if:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more members of such legal entity have contracted to purchase such services, output, capacity, energy, or combination thereof from such legal entity commencing upon the expiration of such period; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such services, output, capacity, energy, or combination thereof, if acquired commencing at an earlier time, could have been reasonably predicted to create a surplus or surpluses in the electric system or systems of such member or members during such period, when added to services, output, capacity, energy, or any combination thereof available to such member or members during such period from facilities owned by such member or members or pursuant to one or more then-existing firm contractual obligations which are not terminable prior to the end of such period without payment of a penalty, or both; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any combination of the above.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Nothing contained in this paragraph shall prevent such legal entity from selling the output of its ownership interest in any such electric project to any electric utility or foreign public utility as emergency, scheduled maintenance, or economy interchange service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All obligations and covenants of any such public agency or legal entity, or both, contained in any contract or agreement, which contract or agreement and obligations and covenants are authorized, permitted, or contemplated by this section, shall be the legal, valid, and binding obligations and covenants of the public agency or legal entity undertaking such obligations or making such covenants; and each such obligation or covenant shall be enforceable in accordance with its terms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When contract payments by any such public agency contracting with any such legal entity or revenues of any such public agency contracting with any other person or persons with respect to an electric project are to be pledged as security for the payment of bonds or other evidences of indebtedness sought to be validated, the complaint for validation may make parties defendant to such action, in addition to the state and the taxpayers, property owners, and citizens of the county in which the complaint for validation is filed, including nonresidents owning property or subject to taxation therein:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every public agency the contract payments of which are to be so pledged.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other person contracting with such public agency or legal entity, or both, in any manner relating to such electric project, and particularly with relation to any ownership or operation of any electric project; the supplying of electrical energy to such public agency or legal entity, or both; or the taking or purchase of electrical energy from the electric project.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxpayers, property owners, and citizens of each county or municipality in which each such public agency is located, including nonresidents owning property or subject to taxation therein, and the holders of any outstanding debt obligations of any such public agency or legal entity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All such parties who are made defendants and over whom the court acquires jurisdiction in such validation proceedings shall be required to show cause, if any exists, why such contract or agreement and the terms and conditions thereof should not be inquired into by the court, the validity of the terms thereof determined, and the matters and conditions which are imposed on the parties to such contract or agreement and all such undertakings thereof adjudicated to be valid and binding on the parties thereto. Notice of such proceedings shall be included in the notice of validation hearing required to be issued and published pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (7)(c); and a copy of the complaint in such proceedings, together with a copy of such notice, shall be served on each party defendant referred to in subparagraphs 1. and 2. who is made a defendant and over whom the court acquires jurisdiction in such validation proceedings. Any person resident of this state or any person not a resident of, or located within, this state, whether or not authorized to transact business in this state, who contracts with any such public agency or legal entity, or both, in any manner relating to such electric project, may intervene in the validation proceedings at or before the time set for the validation hearing and assert any ground or objection to the validity and binding effect of such contract or agreement on his or her own behalf and on behalf of any such public agency and of all citizens, residents, and property owners of the state. No appeal may be taken by any person who was not a party of record in such proceedings at the time the judgment appealed from was rendered. An adjudication as to the validity of any such contract or agreement from which no appeal has been taken within the time permitted by law from the date of entry of the judgment of validation or, if an appeal is filed, which is confirmed on appeal shall be forever conclusive and binding upon such legal entity and all such parties who are made defendants and over whom the court acquires jurisdiction in such validation proceedings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each such public agency or legal entity, or both, which contracts with any other person or persons with respect to the ownership or operation of any electric project, and each such public agency which contracts with any legal entity for the support of, or supply of, power from an electric project, is authorized to pledge to such other person or persons or such legal entity, or both, for the benefit of such electric project all or any portion of the revenues derived or to be derived:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of any such public agency, from the ownership and operation of its electric or other integrated utility system; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a legal entity, from the provision of products and services by it;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and to pledge to such other person or persons or such legal entity, or both, for the benefit of such electric project any securities, contract rights, and other property. Each such legal entity is also authorized to pledge to, or for the benefit of, the holders of any bonds, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness issued by such legal entity, as security for the payment thereof, any revenues, securities, contract rights, or other property. Any such pledge shall specify the priority and ranking of such pledge in respect of other pledges, if any, of the same revenues, securities, contract rights, or other property by such public agency or legal entity. Any pledge of revenues, securities, contract rights, or other property made by any such public agency or legal entity, or both, pursuant to this section shall be valid and binding from the date the pledge is made. The revenues, securities, contract rights, or other property so pledged and then held or thereafter received by such public agency or legal entity, or any fiduciary, or such other person or persons shall immediately be subject to the lien of the pledge without any physical delivery thereof or further act; and the lien of the pledge shall be valid and binding as against all parties having claims of any kind in tort, in contract, or otherwise against the public agency or legal entity making such pledge, without regard to whether such parties have notice thereof. The resolution, trust indenture, security agreement, or other instrument by which a pledge is created need not be filed or recorded in any manner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such legal entity is authorized and empowered to sue and be sued in its own name. In the event that any such public agency or legal entity enters into a contract or an agreement with respect to an electric project located in another state, or owns an interest in an electric project located in another state, an action against such public agency or legal entity may be brought in the federal or state courts located in such state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this subsection shall be liberally construed to effect the purposes hereof. The powers conferred by the provisions of this subsection shall be in addition and supplementary to the powers conferred by the other provisions of this section, by any other general, local, or special law, or by any charter of any public agency. When the exercise of any power conferred on any public agency or any legal entity by the provisions of this subsection would conflict with any limitation or requirement upon such public agency or such legal entity contained in the other provisions of this section, in any other general, local, or special law, except s. 361.14, or in the charter of such public agency, such limitation or requirement shall be superseded by the provisions of this subsection for the purposes of the exercise of such power pursuant to the provisions of this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While any bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued by any such public agency or any such legal entity pursuant to the authority granted by paragraph (7)(c) or other applicable law remain outstanding, or while any such public agency or any such legal entity has any undischarged duties or obligations under any contract or agreement, including, but not limited to, obligations to any operator or joint owner of any electric project, the powers, duties, or existence of such public agency or such legal entity or of its officers, employees, or agents shall not be diminished, impaired, or affected in any manner which will affect materially and adversely the interests and rights of the owners of such bonds or other evidences of indebtedness or the persons to whom such duties or obligations are owed under such contract or agreement. The provisions of this subsection shall be for the benefit of the state, each such public agency, each such legal entity, every owner of the bonds of each such legal entity or public agency, and every other person to whom such public agency or such legal entity owes a duty or is obligated by contract or agreement; and, upon and after the earlier of the execution and delivery by any public agency or legal entity, pursuant to this section, of any contract or agreement to any person with respect to an electric project, or the issuance of such bonds or other evidences of indebtedness, the provisions of this subsection shall constitute an irrevocable contract by the state with the owners of the bonds or other evidences of indebtedness issued by such public agency or legal entity and with the other person or persons to whom any such public agency or legal entity owes a duty or is obligated by any such contract or agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limitations on waiver in the provisions of s. 768.28 or any other law to the contrary notwithstanding, the Legislature, in accordance with s. 13, Art. X of the State Constitution, hereby declares that any such legal entity or any public agency of this state that participates in any electric project waives its sovereign immunity to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other persons participating therein; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person in any manner contracting with a legal entity of which any such public agency is a member, with relation to:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ownership, operation, or any other activity set forth in sub-subparagraph (b)2.d. with relation to any electric project; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supplying or purchasing of services, output, capacity, energy, or any combination thereof.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the definition of “electric project” contained in paragraph (3)(d), or any other provision of this subsection or of part II of chapter 361 limiting the parties which may participate jointly in electric projects, any public agency of this state which is an electric utility, or any separate legal entity created pursuant to the provisions of this section, the membership of which consists only of electric utilities, and which exercises or proposes to exercise the powers granted by part II of chapter 361, may exercise any or all of the powers provided in this subsection jointly with any other person with respect to the acquisition, extraction, conversion, use, transportation, storage, reprocessing, disposal, or any combination thereof of any primary fuel or source thereof, as well as any other materials resulting therefrom, only when such primary fuel or source thereof is to be used for the generation of electrical energy in one or more electric projects by such legal entity, any member thereof, or any combination thereof; and, in connection therewith, any such public agency or legal entity shall be deemed to have all the additional powers, privileges, and rights provided in this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that any public agency or any such legal entity, or both, should receive, in connection with its joint ownership or right to the services, output, capacity, or energy of an electric project, as defined in paragraph (3)(d), any material which is designated by the person supplying such material as proprietary confidential business information or which a court of competent jurisdiction has designated as confidential or secret shall be kept confidential and shall be exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). As used in this paragraph, “proprietary confidential business information” includes, but is not limited to, trade secrets; internal auditing controls and reports of internal auditors; security measures, systems, or procedures; information concerning bids or other contractual data, the disclosure of which would impair the efforts of the utility to contract for services on favorable terms; employee personnel information unrelated to compensation, duties, qualifications, or responsibilities; and formulas, patterns, devices, combinations of devices, contract costs, or other information the disclosure of which would injure the affected entity in the marketplace.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All of the additional powers and authority granted by chapter 82-53, Laws of Florida, to a public agency as defined in paragraph (3)(b), a legal entity created pursuant to the provisions of this section, or both, respecting agreements for participation in electric projects shall apply to any agreement in existence as of March 25, 1982, as well as to any such agreement entered into thereafter; but no additional limitation provided in chapter 82-53 upon any power or authority of any such public agency or legal entity, or both, respecting agreements for participation in electric projects shall apply to any such agreement entered into prior to March 25, 1982.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 82-53, Laws of Florida, shall be deemed to be enacted for the purpose of further implementing the provisions of s. 10(d), Art. VII of the State Constitution, as amended.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any agreement entered into pursuant to this section, any public agency or separate legal entity created by interlocal agreement may, in its discretion, grant, sell, donate, dedicate, lease or otherwise convey, title, easements or use rights in real property, including tax-reverted real property, title to which is in such public agency or separate legal entity, to any other public agency or separate legal entity created by interlocal agreement. Any public agency or separate legal entity created by interlocal agreement is authorized to grant such interests in real property or use rights without consideration when in its discretion it is determined to be in the public interest. Real property and interests in real property granted or conveyed to such public agency or separate legal entity shall be for the public purposes contemplated in the interlocal agreement and may be made subject to the condition that in the event that said real property or interest in real property is not so used, or if used and subsequently its use for such purpose is abandoned, the interest granted shall cease as to such public agency or separate legal entity and shall automatically revert to the granting public agency or separate legal entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any separate legal entity created under subsection (7) which has member public agencies located in at least five counties, of which at least three are not contiguous, may conduct public meetings and workshops by means of communications media technology. The notice for any such public meeting or workshop shall state that the meeting or workshop will be conducted through the use of communications media technology; specify how persons interested in attending may do so; and provide a location where communications media technology facilities are available. The participation by an officer, board member, or other representative of a member public agency in a meeting or workshop conducted through communications media technology constitutes that individual’s presence at such meeting or workshop. As used in this subsection, the term “communications media technology” means conference telephone, video conference, or other communications technology by which all persons attending a public meeting or workshop may audibly communicate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-42; ss. 11, 18, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 79-24; ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-31; s. 61, ch. 79-40; s. 68, ch. 81-259; ss. 1, 7, 8, ch. 82-53; s. 45, ch. 83-217; s. 21, ch. 85-55; s. 1, ch. 87-9; s. 6, ch. 87-237; s. 46, ch. 88-130; ss. 33, 34, ch. 90-360; s. 83, ch. 91-45; s. 11, ch. 93-51; s. 896, ch. 95-147; s. 45, ch. 96-406; s. 19, ch. 97-236; s. 61, ch. 99-2; s. 23, ch. 99-251; s. 1, ch. 2001-201; s. 72, ch. 2002-295; s. 156, ch. 2003-261; s. 10, ch. 2004-5; s. 1, ch. 2004-336; s. 6, ch. 2006-218; s. 1, ch. 2006-220; s. 1, ch. 2007-1; s. 1, ch. 2007-90; s. 1, ch. 2008-43; s. 1, ch. 2012-164.</History>
</Section>