<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.3233" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local laws and policies governing a development agreement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government’s laws and policies governing the development of the land at the time of the execution of the development agreement shall govern the development of the land for the duration of the development agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government may apply subsequently adopted laws and policies to a development that is subject to a development agreement only if the local government has held a public hearing and determined:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">They are not in conflict with the laws and policies governing the development agreement and do not prevent development of the land uses, intensities, or densities in the development agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">They are essential to the public health, safety, or welfare, and expressly state that they shall apply to a development that is subject to a development agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">They are specifically anticipated and provided for in the development agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government demonstrates that substantial changes have occurred in pertinent conditions existing at the time of approval of the development agreement; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development agreement is based on substantially inaccurate information supplied by the developer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not abrogate any rights that may vest pursuant to common law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 86-191.</History></Section>