<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3220" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Short title; legislative intent.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 163.3220-163.3243 may be cited as the “Florida Local Government Development Agreement Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lack of certainty in the approval of development can result in a waste of economic and land resources, discourage sound capital improvement planning and financing, escalate the cost of housing and development, and discourage commitment to comprehensive planning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assurance to a developer that upon receipt of his or her development permit or brownfield designation he or she may proceed in accordance with existing laws and policies, subject to the conditions of a development agreement, strengthens the public planning process, encourages sound capital improvement planning and financing, assists in assuring there are adequate capital facilities for the development, encourages private participation in comprehensive planning, and reduces the economic costs of development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conformity with, in furtherance of, and to implement the Community Planning Act and the Florida State Comprehensive Planning Act of 1972, it is the intent of the Legislature to encourage a stronger commitment to comprehensive and capital facilities planning, ensure the provision of adequate public facilities for development, encourage the efficient use of resources, and reduce the economic cost of development.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This intent is effected by authorizing local governments to enter into development agreements with developers, subject to the procedures and requirements of ss. 163.3220-163.3243.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 163.3220-163.3243 shall be regarded as supplemental and additional to the powers conferred upon local governments by other laws and shall not be regarded as in derogation of any powers now existing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 86-191; s. 902, ch. 95-147; s. 8, ch. 99-378; s. 22, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>