<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.365" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Neighborhood and communitywide plans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any municipality or county or any public body authorized to perform planning work may prepare a general neighborhood redevelopment plan for a community redevelopment area or areas, together with any adjoining areas having specially related problems, which may be of such scope that redevelopment activities may have to be carried out in stages. Such plans may include, but not be limited to, a preliminary plan which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Outlines the community redevelopment activities proposed for the area involved;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides a framework for the preparation of community redevelopment plans; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Indicates generally the land uses, population density, building coverage, prospective requirements for rehabilitation and improvement of property and portions of the area contemplated for clearance and redevelopment.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A general neighborhood redevelopment plan shall, in the determination of the governing body, conform to the general plan of the locality as a whole and the workable program of the county or municipality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or municipality or any public body authorized to perform planning work may prepare or complete a communitywide plan or program for community redevelopment which shall conform to the general plan for the development of the county or municipality as a whole and may include, but not be limited to, identification of slum or blighted areas, measurement of blight, determination of resources needed and available to renew such areas, identification of potential project areas and types of action contemplated, including the development of affordable housing if needed and appropriate for the area, and scheduling of community redevelopment activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authority is hereby vested in every county and municipality to prepare, adopt, and revise from time to time a general plan for the physical development of the county or municipality as a whole (giving due regard to the environs and metropolitan surroundings), to establish and maintain a planning commission for such purpose and related county or municipal planning activities, and to make available and to appropriate necessary funds therefor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 69-305; s. 7, ch. 94-236.</History></Section>