<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.362" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contents of community redevelopment plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every community redevelopment plan shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain a legal description of the boundaries of the community redevelopment area and the reasons for establishing such boundaries shown in the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Show by diagram and in general terms:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The approximate amount of open space to be provided and the street layout.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the type, size, height, number, and proposed use of buildings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The approximate number of dwelling units.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such property as is intended for use as public parks, recreation areas, streets, public utilities, and public improvements of any nature.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the redevelopment area contains low or moderate income housing, contain a neighborhood impact element which describes in detail the impact of the redevelopment upon the residents of the redevelopment area and the surrounding areas in terms of relocation, traffic circulation, environmental quality, availability of community facilities and services, effect on school population, and other matters affecting the physical and social quality of the neighborhood.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify specifically any publicly funded capital projects to be undertaken within the community redevelopment area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain adequate safeguards that the work of redevelopment will be carried out pursuant to the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the retention of controls and the establishment of any restrictions or covenants running with land sold or leased for private use for such periods of time and under such conditions as the governing body deems necessary to effectuate the purposes of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide assurances that there will be replacement housing for the relocation of persons temporarily or permanently displaced from housing facilities within the community redevelopment area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide an element of residential use in the redevelopment area if such use exists in the area prior to the adoption of the plan or if the plan is intended to remedy a shortage of housing affordable to residents of low or moderate income, including the elderly, or if the plan is not intended to remedy such shortage, the reasons therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain a detailed statement of the projected costs of the redevelopment, including the amount to be expended on publicly funded capital projects in the community redevelopment area and any indebtedness of the community redevelopment agency, the county, or the municipality proposed to be incurred for such redevelopment if such indebtedness is to be repaid with increment revenues.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a time certain for completing all redevelopment financed by increment revenues. Such time certain shall occur no later than 30 years after the fiscal year in which the plan is approved, adopted, or amended pursuant to s. 163.361(1). However, for any agency created after July 1, 2002, the time certain for completing all redevelopment financed by increment revenues must occur within 40 years after the fiscal year in which the plan is approved or adopted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1), (3), (4), and (8), as amended by s. 10, chapter 84-356, Laws of Florida, and subsections (9) and (10) do not apply to any governing body of a county or municipality or to a community redevelopment agency if such governing body has approved and adopted a community redevelopment plan pursuant to s. 163.360 before chapter 84-356 became a law; nor do they apply to any governing body of a county or municipality or to a community redevelopment agency if such governing body or agency has adopted an ordinance or resolution authorizing the issuance of any bonds, notes, or other forms of indebtedness to which is pledged increment revenues pursuant only to a community redevelopment plan as approved and adopted before chapter 84-356 became a law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 77-391; s. 7, ch. 83-231; ss. 10, 22, ch. 84-356; s. 5, ch. 93-286; s. 6, ch. 94-236; s. 6, ch. 2002-294.</History></Section>