<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Local Government Development Agreement Act; definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 163.3220-163.3243:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Brownfield designation” means a resolution adopted by a local government pursuant to the Brownfields Redevelopment Act, ss. 376.77-376.85.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Comprehensive plan” means a plan adopted pursuant to the Community Planning Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Developer” means any person, including a governmental agency, undertaking any development.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Development” means the carrying out of any building activity or mining operation, the making of any material change in the use or appearance of any structure or land, or the dividing of land into three or more parcels.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following activities or uses shall be taken for the purposes of this act to involve “development”:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reconstruction, alteration of the size, or material change in the external appearance of a structure on land.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A change in the intensity of use of land, such as an increase in the number of dwelling units in a structure or on land or a material increase in the number of businesses, manufacturing establishments, offices, or dwelling units in a structure or on land.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alteration of a shore or bank of a seacoast, river, stream, lake, pond, or canal, including any “coastal construction” as defined in s. 161.021.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commencement of drilling, except to obtain soil samples, mining, or excavation on a parcel of land.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demolition of a structure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clearing of land as an adjunct of construction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deposit of refuse, solid or liquid waste, or fill on a parcel of land.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following operations or uses shall not be taken for the purpose of this act to involve “development”:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work by a highway or road agency or railroad company for the maintenance or improvement of a road or railroad track, if the work is carried out on land within the boundaries of the right-of-way.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work by any utility and other persons engaged in the distribution or transmission of gas or water, for the purpose of inspecting, repairing, renewing, or constructing on established rights-of-way any sewers, mains, pipes, cables, utility tunnels, power lines, towers, poles, tracks, or the like.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work for the maintenance, renewal, improvement, or alteration of any structure, if the work affects only the interior or the color of the structure or the decoration of the exterior of the structure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of any structure or land devoted to dwelling uses for any purpose customarily incidental to enjoyment of the dwelling.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of any land for the purpose of growing plants, crops, trees, and other agricultural or forestry products; raising livestock; or for other agricultural purposes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A change in use of land or structure from a use within a class specified in an ordinance or rule to another use in the same class.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A change in the ownership or form of ownership of any parcel or structure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The creation or termination of rights of access, riparian rights, easements, covenants concerning development of land, or other rights in land.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Development,” as designated in an ordinance, rule, or development permit includes all other development customarily associated with it unless otherwise specified. When appropriate to the context, “development” refers to the act of developing or to the result of development. Reference to any specific operation is not intended to mean that the operation or activity, when part of other operations or activities, is not development. Reference to particular operations is not intended to limit the generality of this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Development permit” includes any building permit, zoning permit, subdivision approval, rezoning, certification, special exception, variance, or any other official action of local government having the effect of permitting the development of land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Governing body” means the board of county commissioners of a county, the commission or council of an incorporated municipality, or any other chief governing body of a unit of local government, however designated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land” means the earth, water, and air, above, below, or on the surface, and includes any improvements or structures customarily regarded as land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land development regulations” means ordinances enacted by governing bodies for the regulation of any aspect of development and includes any local government zoning, rezoning, subdivision, building construction, or sign regulations or any other regulations controlling the development of land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Laws” means all ordinances, resolutions, regulations, comprehensive plans, land development regulations, and rules adopted by a local government affecting the development of land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local government” means any county or municipality or any special district or local governmental entity established pursuant to law which exercises regulatory authority over, and grants development permits for, land development.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local planning agency” means the agency designated to prepare a comprehensive plan or plan amendment pursuant to the Community Planning Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, corporation, business or land trust, estate, trust, partnership, association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, state agency, or any legal entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public facilities” means major capital improvements, including, but not limited to, transportation, sanitary sewer, solid waste, drainage, potable water, educational, parks and recreational, and health systems and facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State land planning agency” means the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 86-191; s. 4, ch. 92-129; s. 9, ch. 99-378; s. 23, ch. 2011-139; s. 10, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>