<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Miami River Commission.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Miami River Commission is hereby established as the official coordinating clearinghouse for all public policy and projects related to the Miami River to unite all governmental agencies, businesses, and residents in the area to speak with one voice on river issues; to develop coordinated plans, priorities, programs, projects, and budgets that might substantially improve the river area; and to act as the principal advocate and watchdog to ensure that river projects are funded and implemented in a proper and timely manner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may seek and receive funding to further its coordinating functions regarding river improvement projects of the commission. Nothing in this act affects or supersedes the regulatory authority of any governmental agency or any local government, and any responsibilities of any governmental entity relating to the Miami River shall remain with such respective governmental entity. However, the commission may accept any specifically defined coordinating authority or functions delegated to the commission by any governmental entity, through a memorandum of understanding or other legal instrument. The commission shall use powers of persuasion to achieve its objectives through the process of building a consensus work plan and through widespread publication of regular progress reports.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Miami River Commission shall consist of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A policy committee comprised of the Governor, the chair of the Miami-Dade County delegation, the chair of the governing board of the South Florida Water Management District, the Miami-Dade County State Attorney, the Mayor of Miami, the Mayor of Miami-Dade County, a commissioner of the City of Miami Commission, a commissioner of the Miami-Dade County Commission, the chair of the Miami River Marine Group, the chair of the Marine Council, the Executive Director of the Downtown Development Authority, and the chair of the Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce; two neighborhood representatives, selected from the Spring Garden Neighborhood Association, the Grove Park Neighborhood Association, and the Miami River Neighborhood Enhancement Corporation, one neighborhood representative to be appointed by the city commission and one neighborhood representative to be appointed by the county commission, each selected from a list of three names submitted by each such organization; one representative from an environmental or civic association, appointed by the Governor; and three members-at-large, who shall be persons who have a demonstrated history of involvement on the Miami River through business, residence, or volunteer activity, one appointed by the Governor, one appointed by the city commission, and one appointed by the county commission. All members shall be voting members. The committee shall also include a member of the United States Congressional delegation and the Captain of the Port of Miami as a representative of the United States Coast Guard, as nonvoting, ex officio members. The policy committee may meet monthly, but shall meet at least quarterly.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A managing director who has the responsibility to implement plans and programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A working group consisting of all governmental agencies that have jurisdiction in the Miami River area, as well as representatives from business and civic associations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy committee shall have the following powers and duties:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidate existing plans, programs, and proposals into a coordinated strategic plan for improvement of the Miami River and surrounding areas, addressing environmental, economic, social, recreational, and aesthetic issues. The committee shall monitor the progress on each element of such plan and shall revise the plan regularly.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare an integrated financial plan using the different jurisdictional agencies available for projected financial resources. The committee shall monitor the progress on each element of such plan and revise the plan regularly.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide technical assistance and political support as needed to help implement each element of the strategic and financial plans.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept any specifically defined coordinating authority or function delegated to the committee by any level of government through a memorandum of understanding or other legal instrument.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publicize a semiannual report describing accomplishments of the commission and each member agency, as well as the status of each pending task. The committee shall distribute the report to the city and county commissions and mayors, the Governor, chair of the Miami-Dade County delegation, stakeholders, and the local media.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek grants from public and private sources and receive grant funds to provide for the enhancement of its coordinating functions and activities and administer contracts that achieve these goals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a forum for exchange of information and facilitate the resolution of conflicts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Act as a clearinghouse for public information and conduct public education programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the Miami River working group, appoint members to the group, and organize subcommittees, delegate tasks, and seek counsel from members of the working group as necessary to carry out the powers and duties listed in this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Elect officers and adopt rules of procedure as necessary to carry out the powers and duties listed above and solicit appointing authorities to name replacements for policy committee members who do not participate on a regular basis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hire the managing director, who shall be authorized to represent the commission and to implement all policies, plans, and programs of the commission. The committee shall employ any additional staff necessary to assist the managing director.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 7, ch. 98-402; s. 1, ch. 2003-123; s. 26, ch. 2008-4; s. 2, ch. 2011-139; s. 14, ch. 2012-5.</History>
	
</Section>