<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3217" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Municipal overlay for municipal incorporation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />In order to assist in the planning for future municipal incorporation of a specific geographic area, a county may adopt a municipal overlay as an amendment to its comprehensive plan. A municipal overlay will allow a county, in cooperation with the public, to address the future possible municipal incorporation of a specific geographic area and the impact of municipal incorporation on the provision of public services to serve the area.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PREPARATION, ADOPTION, AND AMENDMENT OF THE MUNICIPAL OVERLAY.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies only in those jurisdictions in which the county has authorized, by resolution or local ordinance, the development of a municipal overlay pursuant to the provisions of this section. A county governing body, or a citizens’ organization that represents property owners in the area affected, may sponsor the preparation of the municipal overlay.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the responsibility of the county to prepare the municipal overlay for an area under its jurisdiction; however, if the sponsor of the municipal overlay is other than the county, the county may by written agreement authorize the sponsor to prepare some or all of a proposed municipal overlay.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipal overlay shall be adopted as an amendment to the local government comprehensive plan as prescribed by s. 163.3184.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTENTS OF A MUNICIPAL OVERLAY.<EmDash />A municipal overlay must contain:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boundary options for the creation of the new municipality.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A feasibility study as outlined in chapter 165.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A map of existing and proposed land uses in the area by type and density.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Population projections for the area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Data and analysis relating to the provision of public facilities for the area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNDING OF THE MUNICIPAL OVERLAY.<EmDash />The development of the municipal overlay shall be funded by the county unless there is written agreement between the county and another entity to fund it.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 96-416; s. 21, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>