<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.506" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local government neighborhood improvement districts; creation; advisory council; dissolution.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a local planning ordinance has been adopted authorizing the creation of local government neighborhood improvement districts, the local governing body of a municipality or county may create local government neighborhood improvement districts by the enactment of a separate ordinance for each district, which ordinance:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifies the boundaries, size, and name of the district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizes the district to receive a planning grant from the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizes the local government neighborhood improvement district to levy an ad valorem tax on real and personal property of up to 2 mills annually.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizes the use of special assessments to support planning and implementation of district improvements pursuant to the provisions of s. 163.514(16), including community policing innovations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designates the local governing body as the board of directors of the district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishes an advisory council to the board of directors comprised of property owners or residents of the district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May prohibit the use of any district power authorized by s. 163.514.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requires the district to notify the Department of Legal Affairs and the Department of Economic Opportunity in writing of its establishment within 30 days thereof pursuant to s. 163.5055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory council shall perform such duties as may be prescribed by the governing body and shall submit within the time period specified by the governing body, acting as the board of directors, a report on the district’s activities and a proposed budget to accomplish its objectives. In formulating a plan for services or improvements the advisory board shall consult in public session with the appropriate staff or consultants of the local governing body responsible for the district’s plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an alternative to designating the local governing body as the board of directors, a majority of the local governing body of a city or county may appoint a board of three to seven directors for the district who shall be residents of the proposed area and who are subject to ad valorem taxation in the residential neighborhood improvement district or who are property owners in a commercial neighborhood improvement district. The directors shall be appointed for staggered terms of 3 years. The initial appointments shall be as follows: one director for a 1-year term; one director for a 2-year term; and one director for a 3-year term. If more than three directors are to be appointed, the additional members shall initially be appointed for 3-year terms. Vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired portion of a term in the same manner as the initial appointments were made. Each director shall hold office until his or her successor is appointed and qualified unless the director ceases to be qualified or is removed from office. Upon appointment and qualification and in January of each year, the directors shall organize by electing from their number a chair and a secretary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A district may be dissolved by the governing body by rescinding the ordinance creating the district. The governing body shall consider rescinding the ordinance if presented with a petition containing the signatures of 60 percent of the residents of a district.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 59, ch. 87-243; s. 26, ch. 88-381; s. 7, ch. 91-86; s. 907, ch. 95-147; s. 13, ch. 98-314; s. 19, ch. 2012-96.</History>
</Section>