<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3167" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Scope of act.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The several incorporated municipalities and counties shall have power and responsibility:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To plan for their future development and growth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt and amend comprehensive plans, or elements or portions thereof, to guide their future development and growth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To implement adopted or amended comprehensive plans by the adoption of appropriate land development regulations or elements thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish, support, and maintain administrative instruments and procedures to carry out the provisions and purposes of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The powers and authority set out in this act may be employed by municipalities and counties individually or jointly by mutual agreement in accord with this act and in such combinations as their common interests may dictate and require.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local government shall maintain a comprehensive plan of the type and in the manner set out in this part or prepare amendments to its existing comprehensive plan to conform it to the requirements of this part and in the manner set out in this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality established after the effective date of this act shall, within 1 year after incorporation, establish a local planning agency, pursuant to s. 163.3174, and prepare and adopt a comprehensive plan of the type and in the manner set out in this act within 3 years after the date of such incorporation. A county comprehensive plan shall be deemed controlling until the municipality adopts a comprehensive plan in accord with this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any comprehensive plan, or element or portion thereof, adopted pursuant to this act, which but for its adoption after the deadlines established pursuant to previous versions of this act would have been valid, shall be valid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this act shall limit or modify the rights of any person to complete any development that has been authorized as a development of regional impact pursuant to chapter 380 or who has been issued a final local development order and development has commenced and is continuing in good faith.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Reedy Creek Improvement District shall exercise the authority of this part as it applies to municipalities, consistent with the legislative act under which it was established, for the total area under its jurisdiction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part shall supersede any provision of ss. 341.8201-341.842.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An initiative or referendum process in regard to any development order or in regard to any local comprehensive plan amendment or map amendment is prohibited. However, any local government charter provision that was in effect as of June 1, 2011, for an initiative or referendum process in regard to development orders or in regard to local comprehensive plan amendments or map amendments may be retained and implemented.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each local government shall address in its comprehensive plan, as enumerated in this chapter, the water supply sources necessary to meet and achieve the existing and projected water use demand for the established planning period, considering the applicable plan developed pursuant to s. 373.709.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local government grants a development order pursuant to its adopted land development regulations and the order is not the subject of a pending appeal and the timeframe for filing an appeal has expired, the development order may not be invalidated by a subsequent judicial determination that such land development regulations, or any portion thereof that is relevant to the development order, are invalid because of a deficiency in the approval standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not preclude or affect the timely institution of any other remedy available at law or equity, including a common law writ of certiorari proceeding pursuant to Rule 9.190, Florida Rules of Appellate Procedure, or an original proceeding pursuant to s. 163.3215, as applicable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 75-257; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 3, ch. 85-55; s. 6, ch. 86-191; s. 1, ch. 87-338; s. 1, ch. 92-129; s. 5, ch. 93-206; s. 1, ch. 95-322; s. 23, ch. 96-410; s. 158, ch. 2003-261; s. 11, ch. 2004-5; s. 1, ch. 2004-37; s. 3, ch. 2004-372; s. 1, ch. 2004-381; s. 42, ch. 2010-102; s. 3, ch. 2010-205; s. 7, ch. 2011-139; s. 1, ch. 2012-99.</History>
</Section>