<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.568" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purposes and powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority created and established by this part is granted the authority to purchase, own, or operate, or provide for the operation of, transportation facilities; to contract for transit services; to exercise power of eminent domain limited to right-of-way and contiguous transportation facility acquisition and subject to any further limitations set forth in the authority charter; to conduct studies; and to contract with other governmental agencies, private companies and individuals. However, no public transportation system shall be purchased, owned, or operated that would be in the continued business of competing with existing private charter transportation companies for charter business, nor shall a new system be implemented where an existing transportation system of the same mode is operating a comparable service without first purchasing said existing system through negotiation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority is granted the authority to exercise all powers necessary, appurtenant, convenient, or incidental to the carrying out of the aforesaid purposes, including, but not limited to, the following rights and powers:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and be sued, implead and be impleaded, complain and defend in all courts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt, use, and alter at will a corporate seal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire, purchase, hold, lease as a lessee, and use any franchise or property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, or any interest therein, necessary or desirable for carrying out the purposes of the authority, and to sell, lease as lessor, transfer and dispose of any property or interest therein acquired by it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fix, alter, charge, and establish rates, fares, and other charges for the services and facilities within the area, which rates, fees, and charges shall be equitable and just.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire and operate, or provide for the operation of, local transportation systems, public or private, within the area, the acquisition of such system to be by negotiation and agreement between the authority and the owner of the system to be acquired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make contracts of every name and nature and to execute all instruments necessary or convenient for the carrying on of its business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter into management contracts with any person or persons for the management of a public transportation system owned or controlled by the authority for such period or periods of time, and under such compensation and other terms and conditions, as shall be deemed advisable by the authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without limitation, to borrow money and issue evidence of indebtedness and to accept gifts or grants or loans of money or other property and to enter into contracts, leases, or other transactions with any federal agency, the state, any agency of the state, or any other public body of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop transportation plans, and to coordinate its planning and programs with those of appropriate municipal, county, and state agencies and other political subdivisions of the state. All transportation plans are subject to review and approval by the Department of Transportation and by the regional planning agency, if any, for consistency with programs or planning for the area and region.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To do all acts and things necessary or convenient for the conduct of its business and the general welfare of the authority in order to carry out the powers granted to it by this part or any other law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prescribe and promulgate necessary rules and regulations consistent with the provisions of this part and the requirements of chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 71-373; s. 1, ch. 73-278.</History></Section>