<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.400" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation by public bodies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of aiding in the planning, undertaking, or carrying out of community redevelopment and related activities authorized by this part, any public body may, upon such terms, with or without consideration, as it may determine:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dedicate, sell, convey, or lease any of its interest in any property or grant easements, licenses, or other rights or privileges therein to a county or municipality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incur the entire expense of any public improvements made by such public body in exercising the powers granted in this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Do any and all things necessary to aid or cooperate in the planning or carrying out of a community redevelopment plan and related activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lend, grant, or contribute funds to a county or municipality; borrow money; and apply for and accept advances, loans, grants, contributions, or any other form of financial assistance from the Federal Government, the state, the county, another public body, or any other source.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements, which may extend over any period, notwithstanding any provision or rule of law to the contrary, with the Federal Government, a county, a municipality, or another public body respecting action to be taken pursuant to any of the powers granted by this part, including the furnishing of funds or other assistance in connection with community redevelopment and related activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause public buildings and public facilities, including parks, playgrounds, recreational, community, educational, water, sewer, or drainage facilities, or any other works which it is otherwise empowered to undertake to be furnished; furnish, dedicate, close, vacate, pave, install, grade, regrade, plan, or replan streets, roads, sidewalks, ways, or other places; plan or replan or zone or rezone any part of the public body or make exceptions from building regulations; and cause administrative and other services to be furnished to the county or municipality.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If at any time title to or possession of any property in a community redevelopment area is held by any public body or governmental agency, other than the county or municipality, but including any agency or instrumentality of the United States, which is authorized by law to engage in the undertaking, carrying out, or administration of community redevelopment and related activities, the provisions of the agreements referred to in this section shall inure to the benefit of and may be enforced by such public body or governmental agency. As used in this subsection, the term “county or municipality” also includes a community redevelopment agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any sale, conveyance, lease, or agreement provided for in this section may be made by a public body without appraisal, public notice, advertisement, or public bidding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of aiding in the planning, undertaking, or carrying out of any community redevelopment and related activities of a community redevelopment agency or a housing authority hereunder, any county or municipality may, in addition to its other powers and upon such terms, with or without consideration, as it determines, do and perform any or all of the actions or things which, by the provisions of subsection (1), a public body is authorized to do or perform, including the furnishing of financial and other assistance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, or for the purpose of aiding in the planning, undertaking, or carrying out of community redevelopment and related activities of a county or municipality, such county or municipality may, in addition to any authority to issue bonds pursuant to s. 163.385, issue and sell its general obligation bonds. Any bonds issued by the county or municipality pursuant to this section shall be issued in the manner and within the limitations prescribed by the applicable laws of this state for the issuance and authorization of general obligation bonds by such county or municipality. Nothing in this section shall limit or otherwise adversely affect any other section of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 69-305; s. 14, ch. 77-391; s. 79, ch. 79-400; s. 18, ch. 84-356.</History></Section>