<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.63" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Steering committee; security policy information sharing agreements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The counties involved in the creation and administration of a collaborative client information system shall form a steering committee, consisting of representatives of all agencies and organizations participating in the system, to govern the organization and administration of the collaborative system. Each steering committee shall determine its procedures for governance of the organization, participation in the collaborative information system, and administration of the data in the system. Each steering committee also must develop a security policy to be followed by all agencies participating in the collaborative system to ensure the integrity of the data in the collaborative information system and to guarantee the privacy, to the extent possible, of all clients served by an agency that participates in the collaborative system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before sharing confidential information with other members of the information collaborative, each member of the steering committee shall sign an agreement specifying, at a minimum, the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What information each agency will share with the collaborative;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How the information will be shared;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How clients will be notified that an agency participates in the collaborative;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who in each agency will have access to the information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes to be served by sharing the information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assurances from each agency that it will maintain the confidentiality of the information as required by law; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other information decided upon by members of the information cooperative.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 45, ch. 97-286.</History></Section>