<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.356" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of community redevelopment agency.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a finding of necessity as set forth in s. 163.355, and upon a further finding that there is a need for a community redevelopment agency to function in the county or municipality to carry out the community redevelopment purposes of this part, any county or municipality may create a public body corporate and politic to be known as a “community redevelopment agency.” A charter county having a population less than or equal to 1.6 million may create, by a vote of at least a majority plus one of the entire governing body of the charter county, more than one community redevelopment agency. Each such agency shall be constituted as a public instrumentality, and the exercise by a community redevelopment agency of the powers conferred by this part shall be deemed and held to be the performance of an essential public function. Community redevelopment agencies of a county have the power to function within the corporate limits of a municipality only as, if, and when the governing body of the municipality has by resolution concurred in the community redevelopment plan or plans proposed by the governing body of the county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the governing body adopts a resolution declaring the need for a community redevelopment agency, that body shall, by ordinance, appoint a board of commissioners of the community redevelopment agency, which shall consist of not fewer than five or more than nine commissioners. The terms of office of the commissioners shall be for 4 years, except that three of the members first appointed shall be designated to serve terms of 1, 2, and 3 years, respectively, from the date of their appointments, and all other members shall be designated to serve for terms of 4 years from the date of their appointments. A vacancy occurring during a term shall be filled for the unexpired term. As provided in an interlocal agreement between the governing body that created the agency and one or more taxing authorities, one or more members of the board of commissioners of the agency may be representatives of a taxing authority, including members of that taxing authority’s governing body, whose membership on the board of commissioners of the agency would be considered an additional duty of office as a member of the taxing authority governing body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commissioner shall receive no compensation for services, but is entitled to the necessary expenses, including travel expenses, incurred in the discharge of duties. Each commissioner shall hold office until his or her successor has been appointed and has qualified. A certificate of the appointment or reappointment of any commissioner shall be filed with the clerk of the county or municipality, and such certificate is conclusive evidence of the due and proper appointment of such commissioner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers of a community redevelopment agency shall be exercised by the commissioners thereof. A majority of the commissioners constitutes a quorum for the purpose of conducting business and exercising the powers of the agency and for all other purposes. Action may be taken by the agency upon a vote of a majority of the commissioners present, unless in any case the bylaws require a larger number. Any person may be appointed as commissioner if he or she resides or is engaged in business, which means owning a business, practicing a profession, or performing a service for compensation, or serving as an officer or director of a corporation or other business entity so engaged, within the area of operation of the agency, which shall be coterminous with the area of operation of the county or municipality, and is otherwise eligible for such appointment under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of the county or municipality shall designate a chair and vice chair from among the commissioners. An agency may employ an executive director, technical experts, and such other agents and employees, permanent and temporary, as it requires, and determine their qualifications, duties, and compensation. For such legal service as it requires, an agency may employ or retain its own counsel and legal staff. An agency authorized to transact business and exercise powers under this part shall file with the governing body, on or before March 31 of each year, a report of its activities for the preceding fiscal year, which report shall include a complete financial statement setting forth its assets, liabilities, income, and operating expenses as of the end of such fiscal year. At the time of filing the report, the agency shall publish in a newspaper of general circulation in the community a notice to the effect that such report has been filed with the county or municipality and that the report is available for inspection during business hours in the office of the clerk of the city or county commission and in the office of the agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time after the creation of a community redevelopment agency, the governing body of the county or municipality may appropriate to the agency such amounts as the governing body deems necessary for the administrative expenses and overhead of the agency, including the development and implementation of community policing innovations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body may remove a commissioner for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or misconduct in office only after a hearing and only if he or she has been given a copy of the charges at least 10 days prior to such hearing and has had an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 77-391; s. 1, ch. 83-231; s. 6, ch. 84-356; s. 903, ch. 95-147; s. 4, ch. 98-314; s. 41, ch. 2001-266; s. 4, ch. 2002-294; s. 2, ch. 2006-307.</History></Section>