<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.526" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Neighborhood Councils and local government designated agency; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Neighborhood Councils shall have all of the following powers and duties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All those specified in ss. 163.514 and 163.5151.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To record all complaints of alleged violations of the standards and codes specified within the Neighborhood Enhancement Plan brought by any resident of the district.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To identify plan violations and problem areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the alleged complaint or problem is found to be valid, to notify that property owner of noncompliance with the plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the property owner does not adequately respond to the notification of the plan violation within a reasonable amount of time, to negotiate informally with the property owner to reach an agreement to bring the property owner into compliance with the plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the negotiation process fails to remedy the alleged violation of the plan, to report the alleged violation to the designated agency of the local government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If after 30 days the council is dissatisfied with the response of the designated agency of the local government, to request written notification from the designated agency of the steps taken to remedy the alleged violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the council is still dissatisfied 30 days after receipt of written notification, to request an audience before the local governing body to resolve its differences with the designated agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To hold public meetings at least once quarterly to: solicit and listen to suggestions and complaints regarding alleged violations of the Neighborhood Enhancement Plan; discuss alleged violations and issues of concern in the neighborhood; and listen and respond to complaints regarding the activity or inactivity of the Neighborhood Council. At least three members must be present at the public meeting to constitute a quorum. No resident or property owner in the district shall be prohibited from addressing the council.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designated agency of the local government shall have all of the following powers and duties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of an alleged plan violation from the Neighborhood Council, the designated agency of the local government shall provide the Neighborhood Council with written acknowledgment of receipt of the alleged violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designated agency of the local government shall notify the property owner that the owner may be in violation of the requirements and standards of the Neighborhood Enhancement Plan. The designated agency is entitled to exercise all the powers under chapter 162 to enforce any alleged plan violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The designated agency shall, at the request of the Neighborhood Council, provide written notification of the steps taken to remedy the alleged violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If requested, the local governing body shall, pursuant to this section, grant the Neighborhood Council an audience to resolve the council’s differences or dissatisfaction with the designated agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 95-289.</History></Section>