<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Short title; intent and purpose.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part shall be known and may be cited as the “Community Planning Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the purpose of this act to utilize and strengthen the existing role, processes, and powers of local governments in the establishment and implementation of comprehensive planning programs to guide and manage future development consistent with the proper role of local government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this act to focus the state role in managing growth under this act to protecting the functions of important state resources and facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this act that local governments have the ability to preserve and enhance present advantages; encourage the most appropriate use of land, water, and resources, consistent with the public interest; overcome present handicaps; and deal effectively with future problems that may result from the use and development of land within their jurisdictions. Through the process of comprehensive planning, it is intended that units of local government can preserve, promote, protect, and improve the public health, safety, comfort, good order, appearance, convenience, law enforcement and fire prevention, and general welfare; facilitate the adequate and efficient provision of transportation, water, sewerage, schools, parks, recreational facilities, housing, and other requirements and services; and conserve, develop, utilize, and protect natural resources within their jurisdictions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this act to encourage and ensure cooperation between and among municipalities and counties and to encourage and ensure coordination of planning and development activities of units of local government with the planning activities of regional agencies and state government in accord with applicable provisions of law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this act that adopted comprehensive plans shall have the legal status set out in this act and that no public or private development shall be permitted except in conformity with comprehensive plans, or elements or portions thereof, prepared and adopted in conformity with this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this act that the activities of units of local government in the preparation and adoption of comprehensive plans, or elements or portions therefor, shall be conducted in conformity with this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this act in their interpretation and application are declared to be the minimum requirements necessary to accomplish the stated intent, purposes, and objectives of this act; to protect human, environmental, social, and economic resources; and to maintain, through orderly growth and development, the character and stability of present and future land use and development in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the repeal of ss. 163.160 through 163.315 by s. 19 of chapter 85-55, Laws of Florida, and amendments to this part by this chapter law, not be interpreted to limit or restrict the powers of municipal or county officials, but be interpreted as a recognition of their broad statutory and constitutional powers to plan for and regulate the use of land. It is, further, the intent of the Legislature to reconfirm that ss. 163.3161-163.3248 have provided and do provide the necessary statutory direction and basis for municipal and county officials to carry out their comprehensive planning and land development regulation powers, duties, and responsibilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that all governmental entities in this state recognize and respect judicially acknowledged or constitutionally protected private property rights. It is the intent of the Legislature that all rules, ordinances, regulations, comprehensive plans and amendments thereto, and programs adopted under the authority of this act must be developed, promulgated, implemented, and applied with sensitivity for private property rights and not be unduly restrictive, and property owners must be free from actions by others which would harm their property or which would constitute an inordinate burden on property rights as those terms are defined in s. 70.001(3)(e) and (f). Full and just compensation or other appropriate relief must be provided to any property owner for a governmental action that is determined to be an invalid exercise of the police power which constitutes a taking, as provided by law. Any such relief must ultimately be determined in a judicial action.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this part that the traditional economic base of this state, agriculture, tourism, and military presence, be recognized and protected. Further, it is the intent of this part to encourage economic diversification, workforce development, and community planning.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of this part that new statutory requirements created by the Legislature will not require a local government whose plan has been found to be in compliance with this part to adopt amendments implementing the new statutory requirements until the evaluation and appraisal period provided in s. 163.3191, unless otherwise specified in law. However, any new amendments must comply with the requirements of this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 75-257; ss. 1, 20, ch. 85-55; s. 1, ch. 93-206; s. 4, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>