<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Land development regulations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 1 year after submission of its revised comprehensive plan for review pursuant to s. 163.3167(2), each county and each municipality shall adopt or amend and enforce land development regulations that are consistent with and implement their adopted comprehensive plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local land development regulations shall contain specific and detailed provisions necessary or desirable to implement the adopted comprehensive plan and shall at a minimum:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulate the subdivision of land.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulate the use of land and water for those land use categories included in the land use element and ensure the compatibility of adjacent uses and provide for open space.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for protection of potable water wellfields.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulate areas subject to seasonal and periodic flooding and provide for drainage and stormwater management.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure the protection of environmentally sensitive lands designated in the comprehensive plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regulate signage.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide that public facilities and services meet or exceed the standards established in the capital improvements element required by s. 163.3177 and are available when needed for the development, or that development orders and permits are conditioned on the availability of these public facilities and services necessary to serve the proposed development. A local government may not issue a development order or permit that results in a reduction in the level of services for the affected public facilities below the level of services provided in the local government’s comprehensive plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure safe and convenient onsite traffic flow, considering needed vehicle parking.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain the existing density of residential properties or recreational vehicle parks if the properties are intended for residential use and are located in the unincorporated areas that have sufficient infrastructure, as determined by a local governing authority, and are not located within a coastal high-hazard area under s. 163.3178.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be construed to encourage the use of innovative land development regulations which include provisions such as transfer of development rights, incentive and inclusionary zoning, planned-unit development, impact fees, and performance zoning. These and all other such regulations shall be combined and compiled into a single land development code for the jurisdiction. A general zoning code shall not be required if a local government’s adopted land development regulations meet the requirements of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency may require a local government to submit one or more land development regulations if it has reasonable grounds to believe that a local government has totally failed to adopt any one or more of the land development regulations required by this section. Once the state land planning agency determines after review and consultation with local government whether the local government has adopted regulations required by this section, the state land planning agency shall notify the local government in writing within 30 calendar days after receipt of the regulations from the local government. If the state land planning agency determines that the local government has failed to adopt regulations required by this section, it may institute an action in circuit court to require adoption of these regulations. This action shall not review compliance of adopted regulations with this section or consistency with locally adopted plans.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall adopt rules for review and schedules for adoption of land development regulations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 85-55; s. 12, ch. 86-191; s. 14, ch. 93-206; s. 7, ch. 95-322; s. 6, ch. 96-416; s. 5, ch. 98-146; s. 20, ch. 2009-96; s. 188, ch. 2010-102; s. 6, ch. 2011-4; s. 6, ch. 2011-15.</History>
</Section>