<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.410" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exercise of powers in counties with home rule charters.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any county which has adopted a home rule charter, the powers conferred by this part shall be exercised exclusively by the governing body of such county. However, the governing body of any such county which has adopted a home rule charter may, in its discretion, by resolution delegate the exercise of the powers conferred upon the county by this part within the boundaries of a municipality to the governing body of such a municipality. Such a delegation to a municipality shall confer only such powers upon a municipality as shall be specifically enumerated in the delegating resolution. Any power not specifically delegated shall be reserved exclusively to the governing body of the county. This section does not affect any community redevelopment agency created by a municipality prior to the adoption of a county home rule charter. Unless otherwise provided by an existing ordinance, resolution, or interlocal agreement between any such county and a municipality, the governing body of the county that has adopted a home rule charter shall grant in whole or in part or deny any request from a municipality for a delegation of powers or a change in an existing delegation of powers within 120 days after the receipt of all required documentation, or such request shall be deemed granted unless this period is extended by mutual consent in writing by the municipality and county. Within 30 days after receipt of the request, the county shall notify the municipality by registered mail whether the request is complete or if additional information is required. Any request by the county for additional documentation shall specify the deficiencies in the submitted documentation, if any. The county shall notify the municipality by registered mail within 30 days after receiving the additional information whether such additional documentation is complete. If the meeting of the county commission at which the request for a delegation of powers or a change in an existing delegation of powers is unable to be held due to events beyond the control of the county, the request shall be acted upon at the next regularly scheduled meeting of the county commission without regard to the 120-day limitation. If the county does not act upon the request at the next regularly scheduled meeting, the request shall be deemed granted.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 69-305; s. 1, ch. 83-29; s. 9, ch. 2002-294; s. 8, ch. 2006-307.</History></Section>