<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.3227" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements of a development agreement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A development agreement shall include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legal description of the land subject to the agreement, and the names of its legal and equitable owners;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration of the agreement;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development uses permitted on the land, including population densities, and building intensities and height;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of public facilities that will service the development, including who shall provide such facilities; the date any new facilities, if needed, will be constructed; and a schedule to assure public facilities are available concurrent with the impacts of the development;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any reservation or dedication of land for public purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of all local development permits approved or needed to be approved for the development of the land;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A finding that the development permitted or proposed is consistent with the local government’s comprehensive plan and land development regulations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any conditions, terms, restrictions, or other requirements determined to be necessary by the local government for the public health, safety, or welfare of its citizens; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement indicating that the failure of the agreement to address a particular permit, condition, term, or restriction shall not relieve the developer of the necessity of complying with the law governing said permitting requirements, conditions, term, or restriction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A development agreement may provide that the entire development or any phase thereof be commenced or completed within a specific period of time.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 86-191; s. 31, ch. 91-45.</History></Section>