<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.361" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Modification of community redevelopment plans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If at any time after the approval of a community redevelopment plan by the governing body it becomes necessary or desirable to amend or modify such plan, the governing body may amend such plan upon the recommendation of the agency. The agency recommendation to amend or modify a redevelopment plan may include a change in the boundaries of the redevelopment area to add land to or exclude land from the redevelopment area, or may include the development and implementation of community policing innovations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body shall hold a public hearing on a proposed modification of any community redevelopment plan after public notice thereof by publication in a newspaper having a general circulation in the area of operation of the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of s. 163.346, and prior to the adoption of any modification to a community redevelopment plan that expands the boundaries of the community redevelopment area or extends the time certain set forth in the redevelopment plan as required by s. 163.362(10), the agency shall report such proposed modification to each taxing authority in writing or by an oral presentation, or both, regarding such proposed modification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any community redevelopment agency that was not created pursuant to a delegation of authority under s. 163.410 by a county that has adopted a home rule charter and that modifies its adopted community redevelopment plan in a manner that expands the boundaries of the redevelopment area after October 1, 2006, the following additional procedures are required prior to adoption by the governing body of a modified community redevelopment plan:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after receipt of any report of a proposed modification that expands the boundaries of the redevelopment area, the county may provide notice by registered mail to the governing body of the municipality and the community redevelopment agency that the county has competing policy goals and plans for the public funds the county would be required to deposit to the community redevelopment trust fund under the proposed modification to the community redevelopment plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the notice required in subparagraph 1. is timely provided, the governing body of the county and the governing body of the municipality that created the community redevelopment agency shall schedule and hold a joint hearing co-chaired by the chair of the governing body of the county and the mayor of the municipality, with the agenda to be set by the chair of the governing body of the county, at which the competing policy goals for the public funds shall be discussed. For those community redevelopment agencies for which the board of commissioners of the community redevelopment agency are comprised as specified in s. 163.356(2), a designee of the community redevelopment agency shall participate in the joint meeting as a nonvoting member. Any such hearing shall be held within 90 days after receipt by the county of the recommended modification of the adopted community redevelopment plan. Prior to the joint public hearing, the county may propose an alternative modified community redevelopment plan that meets the requirements of s. 163.360 to address the conditions identified in the resolution making a finding of necessity required under s. 163.355. If such an alternative modified redevelopment plan is proposed by the county, such plan shall be delivered to the governing body of the municipality that created the community redevelopment agency and the executive director or other officer of the community redevelopment agency by registered mail at least 30 days prior to holding the joint meeting.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the notice required in subparagraph 1. is timely provided, the municipality may not proceed with the adoption of a modified plan until 30 days after the joint hearing unless the governing body of the county has failed to schedule or a majority of the members of the governing body of the county have failed to attend the joint hearing within the required 90-day period.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the time requirements established in subparagraphs 2. and 3., the county and the municipality may at any time voluntarily use the dispute resolution process established in chapter 164 to attempt to resolve any competing policy goals between the county and municipality related to the community redevelopment agency. Nothing in this subparagraph grants the county or the municipality the authority to require the other local government to participate in the dispute resolution process.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A modification to a community redevelopment plan that includes a change in the boundaries of the redevelopment area to add land must be supported by a resolution as provided in s. 163.355.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a community redevelopment plan is modified by the county or municipality after the lease or sale of real property in the community redevelopment area, such modification may be conditioned upon such approval of the owner, lessee, or successor in interest as the county or municipality may deem advisable and, in any event, shall be subject to such rights at law or in equity as a lessee or purchaser, or his or her successor or successors in interest, may be entitled to assert.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 77-391; s. 6, ch. 83-231; s. 904, ch. 95-147; s. 7, ch. 98-314; s. 5, ch. 2002-294; s. 5, ch. 2006-307.</History></Section>