<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3191" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Evaluation and appraisal of comprehensive plan.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least once every 7 years, each local government shall evaluate its comprehensive plan to determine if plan amendments are necessary to reflect changes in state requirements in this part since the last update of the comprehensive plan, and notify the state land planning agency as to its determination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local government determines amendments to its comprehensive plan are necessary to reflect changes in state requirements, the local government shall prepare and transmit within 1 year such plan amendment or amendments for review pursuant to s. 163.3184.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local governments are encouraged to comprehensively evaluate and, as necessary, update comprehensive plans to reflect changes in local conditions. Plan amendments transmitted pursuant to this section shall be reviewed pursuant to s. 163.3184(4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a local government fails to submit its letter prescribed by subsection (1) or update its plan pursuant to subsection (2), it may not amend its comprehensive plan until such time as it complies with this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency may not adopt rules to implement this section, other than procedural rules or a schedule indicating when local governments must comply with the requirements of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 75-257; s. 10, ch. 85-55; s. 11, ch. 86-191; s. 10, ch. 92-129; s. 13, ch. 93-206; s. 6, ch. 95-322; s. 29, ch. 96-410; s. 5, ch. 96-416; s. 4, ch. 98-146; ss. 6, 14, ch. 98-176; s. 5, ch. 98-258; s. 17, ch. 2000-158; s. 9, ch. 2002-296; s. 905, ch. 2002-387; s. 4, ch. 2004-230; s. 8, ch. 2005-290; s. 12, ch. 2005-291; s. 13, ch. 2007-196; s. 5, ch. 2007-198; s. 4, ch. 2007-204; s. 5, ch. 2010-205; s. 20, ch. 2011-139; s. 8, ch. 2012-96; s. 9, ch. 2012-99.</History>
</Section>