<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0163.5151" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fiscal management; budget preparation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to agreement with the local governing body, all funds of the districts created pursuant to this part shall be received, held, and secured in the same manner as other public funds by the appropriate fiscal officers of the municipality in which the district is located, or the county if the district is located in the unincorporated portion of the county. The funds of the district shall be maintained under a separate account, shall be used for purposes authorized by this part, and shall be disbursed only by direction of or with approval of the district pursuant to requisitions signed by the manager or other designated chief fiscal officer of the district and countersigned by at least one other member of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district bylaws shall provide for maintenance of minutes and other official records of its proceedings and actions; for preparation and adoption of an annual budget for each ensuing fiscal year; for internal supervision and control of its accounts, which function the appropriate city or county fiscal officers may perform for the district at its request; and for an external audit at least annually by an independent certified public accountant who has no personal interest, direct or indirect, in the fiscal affairs of the district. A copy of the external audit shall be filed with the city clerk or the clerk of the court, whichever is appropriate, within 90 days after the end of each fiscal year. The bylaws shall specify the means by which each of these functions is to be performed and, as to those functions assigned to district personnel, the manner and schedule of performance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each special neighborhood improvement district shall establish its budget pursuant to the provisions of chapter 200. Prior to adoption of the final budget and setting of the millage rate to be levied by the board, the board shall submit a tentative budget and proposed millage rate of the district to the governing body of the municipality in which the district is located, or to the county if the district is located in the unincorporated portion of the county, for approval or disapproval. Such governing body shall have the power to modify the budget or millage submitted by the board. Subsequent to approval, the board shall adopt its final budget and millage rate in accordance with the requirements of chapter 200.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the option of the county property appraiser for the county within which the neighborhood improvement district is located, the assessments levied by the district shall be collected in the same manner as all ad valorem taxes if so requested by the local governing body pursuant to s. 197.363.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 64, ch. 87-243; s. 30, ch. 88-381; s. 13, ch. 91-86.</History></Section>