<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3163" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Applications for development permits; disclosure and acknowledgment  of contiguous sustainable agricultural land.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Agricultural Land Acknowledgment Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that nonagricultural land which neighbors agricultural land may adversely affect agricultural production and farm operations on the agricultural land and may lead to the agricultural land’s conversion to urban, suburban, or other nonagricultural uses. The Legislature intends to reduce the occurrence of conflicts between agricultural and nonagricultural land uses and encourage sustainable agricultural land use. The purpose of this section is to ensure that generally accepted agricultural practices will not be subject to interference by residential use of land contiguous to sustainable agricultural land.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Contiguous” means touching, bordering, or adjoining along a boundary. For purposes of this section, properties that would be contiguous if not separated by a roadway, railroad, or other public easement are considered contiguous.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Farm operation” has the same meaning as defined in s. 823.14.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sustainable agricultural land” means land classified as agricultural land pursuant to s. 193.461 which is used for a farm operation that uses current technology, based on science or research and demonstrated measurable increases in productivity, to meet future food, feed, fiber, and energy needs, while considering the environmental impacts and the social and economic benefits to the rural communities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before a political subdivision issues a local land use permit, building permit, or certificate of occupancy for nonagricultural land contiguous to sustainable agricultural land, the political subdivision shall require that, as a condition of issuing the permit or certificate, the applicant for the permit or certificate sign and submit to the political subdivision, in a format that is recordable in the official records of the county in which the political subdivision is located, a written acknowledgment of contiguous sustainable agricultural land in the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ACKNOWLEDGMENT OF CONTIGUOUS<NewLine />SUSTAINABLE AGRICULTURAL LAND</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">I, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of applicant)</Directions>, understand that my property located at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(address of nonagricultural land)</Directions>, as further described in the attached legal description, is contiguous to sustainable agricultural land located at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(address of agricultural land)</Directions>, as further described in the attached legal description.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">I acknowledge and understand that the farm operation on the contiguous sustainable agricultural land identified herein will be conducted according to generally accepted agricultural practices as provided in the Florida Right to Farm Act, s. 823.14, Florida Statutes.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">Signature: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(signature of applicant)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">Date: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(date)</Directions></Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro" SpaceAbove="true">An acknowledgment submitted to a political subdivision under paragraph (a) shall be recorded in the official records of the county in which the political subdivision is located.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, in cooperation with the Department of Revenue, may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 9, ch. 2011-7; HJR 7103, 2011 Regular Session; s. 14, ch. 2012-83.</History>
</Section>