<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0163.3168" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Planning innovations and technical assistance.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes the need for innovative planning and development strategies to promote a diverse economy and vibrant rural and urban communities, while protecting environmentally sensitive areas. The Legislature further recognizes the substantial advantages of innovative approaches to development directed to meet the needs of urban, rural, and suburban areas.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local governments are encouraged to apply innovative planning tools, including, but not limited to, visioning, sector planning, and rural land stewardship area designations to address future new development areas, urban service area designations, urban growth boundaries, and mixed-use, high-density development in urban areas.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall help communities find creative solutions to fostering vibrant, healthy communities, while protecting the functions of important state resources and facilities. The state land planning agency and all other appropriate state and regional agencies may use various means to provide direct and indirect technical assistance within available resources. If plan amendments may adversely impact important state resources or facilities, upon request by the local government, the state land planning agency shall coordinate multiagency assistance, if needed, in developing an amendment to minimize impacts on such resources or facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state land planning agency shall provide, on its website, guidance on the submittal and adoption of comprehensive plans, plan amendments, and land development regulations. Such guidance shall not be adopted as a rule and is exempt from s. 120.54(1)(a).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>