<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0083.595" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Choice of remedies upon breach or early termination by tenant.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the tenant breaches the rental agreement for the dwelling unit and the landlord has obtained a writ of possession, or the tenant has surrendered possession of the dwelling unit to the landlord, or the tenant has abandoned the dwelling unit, the landlord may:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Treat the rental agreement as terminated and retake possession for his or her own account, thereby terminating any further liability of the tenant;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retake possession of the dwelling unit for the account of the tenant, holding the tenant liable for the difference between the rent stipulated to be paid under the rental agreement and what the landlord is able to recover from a reletting. If the landlord retakes possession, the landlord has a duty to exercise good faith in attempting to relet the premises, and any rent received by the landlord as a result of the reletting must be deducted from the balance of rent due from the tenant. For purposes of this subsection, the term “good faith in attempting to relet the premises” means that the landlord uses at least the same efforts to relet the premises as were used in the initial rental or at least the same efforts as the landlord uses in attempting to rent other similar rental units but does not require the landlord to give a preference in renting the premises over other vacant dwelling units that the landlord owns or has the responsibility to rent;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stand by and do nothing, holding the lessee liable for the rent as it comes due; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Charge liquidated damages, as provided in the rental agreement, or an early termination fee to the tenant if the landlord and tenant have agreed to liquidated damages or an early termination fee, if the amount does not exceed 2 months’ rent, and if, in the case of an early termination fee, the tenant is required to give no more than 60 days’ notice, as provided in the rental agreement, prior to the proposed date of early termination. This remedy is available only if the tenant and the landlord, at the time the rental agreement was made, indicated acceptance of liquidated damages or an early termination fee. The tenant must indicate acceptance of liquidated damages or an early termination fee by signing a separate addendum to the rental agreement containing a provision in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">☐ I agree, as provided in the rental agreement, to pay $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> (an amount that does not exceed 2 months’ rent) as liquidated damages or an early termination fee if I elect to terminate the rental agreement, and the landlord waives the right to seek additional rent beyond the month in which the landlord retakes possession.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">☐ I do not agree to liquidated damages or an early termination fee, and I acknowledge that the landlord may seek damages as provided by law.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to liquidated damages or an early termination fee, the landlord is entitled to the rent and other charges accrued through the end of the month in which the landlord retakes possession of the dwelling unit and charges for damages to the dwelling unit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply if the breach is failure to give notice as provided in s. 83.575.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 87-369; s. 4, ch. 88-379; s. 448, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 2008-131.</History></Section>