<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0083.232" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rent paid into registry of court.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an action by the landlord which includes a claim for possession of real property, the tenant shall pay into the court registry the amount alleged in the complaint as unpaid, or if such amount is contested, such amount as is determined by the court, and any rent accruing during the pendency of the action, when due, unless the tenant has interposed the defense of payment or satisfaction of the rent in the amount the complaint alleges as unpaid. Unless the tenant disputes the amount of accrued rent, the tenant must pay the amount alleged in the complaint into the court registry on or before the date on which his or her answer to the claim for possession is due. If the tenant contests the amount of accrued rent, the tenant must pay the amount determined by the court into the court registry on the day that the court makes its determination. The court may, however, extend these time periods to allow for later payment, upon good cause shown. Even though the defense of payment or satisfaction has been asserted, the court, in its discretion, may order the tenant to pay into the court registry the rent that accrues during the pendency of the action, the time of accrual being as set forth in the lease. If the landlord is in actual danger of loss of the premises or other hardship resulting from the loss of rental income from the premises, the landlord may apply to the court for disbursement of all or part of the funds so held in the court registry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the tenant contests the amount of money to be placed into the court registry, any hearing regarding such dispute shall be limited to only the factual or legal issues concerning:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the tenant has been properly credited by the landlord with any and all rental payments made; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What properly constitutes rent under the provisions of the lease.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, on its own motion, shall notify the tenant of the requirement that rent be paid into the court registry by order, which shall be issued immediately upon filing of the tenant’s initial pleading, motion, or other paper.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a counterclaim for money damages does not relieve the tenant from depositing rent due into the registry of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the tenant to pay the rent into the court registry pursuant to court order shall be deemed an absolute waiver of the tenant’s defenses. In such case, the landlord is entitled to an immediate default for possession without further notice or hearing thereon.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 93-70; s. 442, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>