<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0083.59" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of action for possession.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the rental agreement is terminated and the tenant does not vacate the premises, the landlord may recover possession of the dwelling unit as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A landlord, the landlord’s attorney, or the landlord’s agent, applying for the removal of a tenant shall file in the county court of the county where the premises are situated a complaint describing the dwelling unit and stating the facts that authorize its recovery. A landlord’s agent is not permitted to take any action other than the initial filing of the complaint, unless the landlord’s agent is an attorney. The landlord is entitled to the summary procedure provided in s. 51.011 [F.S. 1971], and the court shall advance the cause on the calendar.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The landlord shall not recover possession of a dwelling unit except:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an action for possession under subsection (2) or other civil action in which the issue of right of possession is determined;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the tenant has surrendered possession of the dwelling unit to the landlord;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the tenant has abandoned the dwelling unit. In the absence of actual knowledge of abandonment, it shall be presumed that the tenant has abandoned the dwelling unit if he or she is absent from the premises for a period of time equal to one-half the time for periodic rental payments. However, this presumption does not apply if the rent is current or the tenant has notified the landlord, in writing, of an intended absence; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the last remaining tenant of a dwelling unit is deceased, personal property remains on the premises, rent is unpaid, at least 60 days have elapsed following the date of death, and the landlord has not been notified in writing of the existence of a probate estate or of the name and address of a personal representative. This paragraph does not apply to a dwelling unit used in connection with a federally administered or regulated housing program, including programs under s. 202, s. 221(d)(3) and (4), s. 236, or s. 8 of the National Housing Act, as amended.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prevailing party is entitled to have judgment for costs and execution therefor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 73-330; s. 1, ch. 74-146; s. 24, ch. 82-66; s. 1, ch. 92-36; s. 447, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 2007-136.</History></Section>