<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0083.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Landlord’s access to dwelling unit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tenant shall not unreasonably withhold consent to the landlord to enter the dwelling unit from time to time in order to inspect the premises; make necessary or agreed repairs, decorations, alterations, or improvements; supply agreed services; or exhibit the dwelling unit to prospective or actual purchasers, mortgagees, tenants, workers, or contractors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The landlord may enter the dwelling unit at any time for the protection or preservation of the premises. The landlord may enter the dwelling unit upon reasonable notice to the tenant and at a reasonable time for the purpose of repair of the premises. “Reasonable notice” for the purpose of repair is notice given at least 12 hours prior to the entry, and reasonable time for the purpose of repair shall be between the hours of 7:30 a.m. and 8:00 p.m. The landlord may enter the dwelling unit when necessary for the further purposes set forth in subsection (1) under any of the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the consent of the tenant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case of emergency;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the tenant unreasonably withholds consent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the tenant is absent from the premises for a period of time equal to one-half the time for periodic rental payments. If the rent is current and the tenant notifies the landlord of an intended absence, then the landlord may enter only with the consent of the tenant or for the protection or preservation of the premises.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The landlord shall not abuse the right of access nor use it to harass the tenant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 73-330; s. 5, ch. 87-195; s. 4, ch. 93-255; s. 446, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>