<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0083.51" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Landlord’s obligation to maintain premises.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The landlord at all times during the tenancy shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with the requirements of applicable building, housing, and health codes; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where there are no applicable building, housing, or health codes, maintain the roofs, windows, screens, doors, floors, steps, porches, exterior walls, foundations, and all other structural components in good repair and capable of resisting normal forces and loads and the plumbing in reasonable working condition. However, the landlord shall not be required to maintain a mobile home or other structure owned by the tenant.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The landlord’s obligations under this subsection may be altered or modified in writing with respect to a single-family home or duplex.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise agreed in writing, in addition to the requirements of subsection (1), the landlord of a dwelling unit other than a single-family home or duplex shall, at all times during the tenancy, make reasonable provisions for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extermination of rats, mice, roaches, ants, wood-destroying organisms, and bedbugs. When vacation of the premises is required for such extermination, the landlord shall not be liable for damages but shall abate the rent. The tenant shall be required to temporarily vacate the premises for a period of time not to exceed 4 days, on 7 days’ written notice, if necessary, for extermination pursuant to this subparagraph.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Locks and keys.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clean and safe condition of common areas.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Garbage removal and outside receptacles therefor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Functioning facilities for heat during winter, running water, and hot water.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise agreed in writing, at the commencement of the tenancy of a single-family home or duplex, the landlord shall install working smoke detection devices. As used in this paragraph, the term “smoke detection device” means an electrical or battery-operated device which detects visible or invisible particles of combustion and which is listed by Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., Factory Mutual Laboratories, Inc., or any other nationally recognized testing laboratory using nationally accepted testing standards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part authorizes the tenant to raise a noncompliance by the landlord with this subsection as a defense to an action for possession under s. 83.59.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall not apply to a mobile home owned by a tenant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this subsection prohibits the landlord from providing in the rental agreement that the tenant is obligated to pay costs or charges for garbage removal, water, fuel, or utilities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the duty imposed by subsection (1) is the same or greater than any duty imposed by subsection (2), the landlord’s duty is determined by subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The landlord is not responsible to the tenant under this section for conditions created or caused by the negligent or wrongful act or omission of the tenant, a member of the tenant’s family, or other person on the premises with the tenant’s consent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 73-330; s. 22, ch. 82-66; s. 4, ch. 87-195; s. 1, ch. 90-133; s. 3, ch. 93-255; s. 444, ch. 95-147; s. 8, ch. 97-95.</History></Section>