<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0083.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of possession upon default in rent; determination of right of possession in action or surrender or abandonment of premises.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person leasing or renting any land or premises other than a dwelling unit fails to pay the rent at the time it becomes due, the lessor has the right to obtain possession of the premises as provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The landlord shall recover possession of rented premises only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an action for possession under s. 83.20, or other civil action in which the issue of right of possession is determined;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the tenant has surrendered possession of the rented premises to the landlord; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the tenant has abandoned the rented premises.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of actual knowledge of abandonment, it shall be presumed for purposes of paragraph (2)(c) that the tenant has abandoned the rented premises if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The landlord reasonably believes that the tenant has been absent from the rented premises for a period of 30 consecutive days;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rent is not current; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notice pursuant to s. 83.20(2) has been served and 10 days have elapsed since service of such notice.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, this presumption does not apply if the rent is current or the tenant has notified the landlord in writing of an intended absence.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, Nov. 21, 1828; RS 1750; GS 2226; RGS 3534; CGL 5398; s. 34, ch. 67-254; s. 1, ch. 83-151.</History></Section>