<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Real Estate Commission Education and Research Foundation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established a Florida Real Estate Commission Education and Research Foundation, hereinafter referred to as the “foundation,” which shall be administered by the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes, objectives, and duties of the foundation are as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To create and promote educational projects to expand the knowledge of the public and real estate licensees in matters pertaining to Florida real estate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To augment the existing real estate programs by increasing the number of teaching personnel and real estate courses in the state in degree-granting programs in universities and colleges in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conduct studies in all areas that relate directly or indirectly to real estate or urban or rural economics and to publish and disseminate the findings and results of the studies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist the teaching program in real estate offered by the universities, colleges, and real estate schools registered pursuant to this chapter in the state, when requested to do so.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To develop and from time to time revise and update materials for use in the courses in real estate offered by the universities, colleges, and real estate schools registered pursuant to this chapter in the state, when requested to do so.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make studies of, and recommend changes in, state statutes and municipal ordinances; provided, however, that such studies are requested by the Governor or the presiding officers of the Legislature. The foundation shall maintain political nonadvocacy.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To periodically review the progress of persons conducting such research and studies. The results of any research project or study shall not be published or disseminated until it has been reviewed and approved in writing by the commission or its designated representative.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prepare information of consumer interest concerning Florida real estate and to make the information available to the public and appropriate state agencies.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foundation may make a charge for its publications and may receive gifts and grants from foundations, individuals, and other sources for the benefit of the foundation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report of the activities and accomplishments of the foundation shall be published annually.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before January 1 of each year, the commission shall file with the Governor, the presiding officer of each house of the Legislature, and the secretary of the department a complete and detailed written report accounting for all funds received and disbursed by the foundation during the preceding year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall solicit advice and information from real estate licensees, the commission, universities, colleges, real estate schools registered pursuant to this chapter and the general public for the purpose of submitting proposals for carrying out the purposes, objectives, and duties of the foundation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall select the proposals that shall be funded and shall give priority to projects with the greatest potential for direct or indirect benefit to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall select the university or college within the state or qualified full-time faculty member of a university or college within the state with the consent of the institution to perform the education study, research study, or other project in accordance with the purposes, objectives, and duties of the foundation. In those instances where no university or college within the state, or qualified full-time faculty member of a university or college within the state with the consent of the institution, submits an acceptable proposal, a qualified person or persons may be selected in accordance with law to perform the education study, research study, or other project in accordance with the purposes, objectives, and duties of the foundation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director of the Division of Real Estate of the department, hereinafter referred to as the “director,” or her or his designated representative shall submit to the commission, in advance of each fiscal year, a budget for expenditures of all funds provided for the foundation in a form that is related to the proposed schedule of activities for the review and approval of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director shall submit to the commission all proposals received for its review and approval in developing an educational and research agenda at the beginning of each fiscal year and shall continuously inform the commission of changes in its substance and scheduling.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall have the power and authority to adopt all rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foundation may not fund or offer educational courses designed to qualify persons for licensure or the renewal of licenses pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foundation may not expend any funds for the purpose of employing staff.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall invest $3 million from the portion of the Professional Regulation Trust Fund credited to the real estate profession, under the same limitations as applied to investments of other state funds, and the income earned thereon shall be available to the foundation to fund the activities and projects authorized under this section. However, any balance of such interest in excess of $1 million shall revert to the portion of the Professional Regulation Trust Fund credited to the real estate profession. In the event the foundation is abolished, the funds in the trust fund shall revert to such portion of the Professional Regulation Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-199; ss. 5, 29, 31, ch. 88-20; s. 12, ch. 90-228; s. 12, ch. 90-341; s. 15, ch. 90-345; s. 10, ch. 91-89; s. 3, ch. 91-289; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 93-261; s. 161, ch. 94-218; s. 65, ch. 95-144; s. 42, ch. 96-418; s. 1118, ch. 97-103; s. 25, ch. 99-333; s. 52, ch. 2000-356; s. 505, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>