<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0475.624" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discipline of appraisers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve">The board may deny an application for registration or certification of an appraiser; may investigate the actions of any appraiser registered, licensed, or certified under this part; may reprimand or impose an administrative fine not to exceed $5,000 for each count or separate offense against any such appraiser; and may revoke or suspend, for a period not to exceed 10 years, the registration, license, or certification of any such appraiser, or place any such appraiser on probation, if the board finds that the registered trainee, licensee, or certificateholder:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has violated any provision of this part or s. 455.227(1); however, any appraiser registered, licensed, or certified under this part is exempt from s. 455.227(1)(i).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been guilty of fraud, misrepresentation, concealment, false promises, false pretenses, dishonest conduct, culpable negligence, or breach of trust in any business transaction in this state or any other state, nation, or territory; has violated a duty imposed upon her or him by law or by the terms of a contract, whether written, oral, express, or implied, in an appraisal assignment; has aided, assisted, or conspired with any other person engaged in any such misconduct and in furtherance thereof; or has formed an intent, design, or scheme to engage in such misconduct and committed an overt act in furtherance of such intent, design, or scheme. It is immaterial to the guilt of the registered trainee appraiser or licensed or certified appraiser that the victim or intended victim of the misconduct has sustained no damage or loss; that the damage or loss has been settled and paid after discovery of the misconduct; or that such victim or intended victim was a customer or a person in confidential relation with the registered trainee appraiser or licensed or certified appraiser, or was an identified member of the general public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has advertised services in a manner that is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has violated any provision of this part or any lawful order or rule issued under this part or chapter 455.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been convicted or found guilty of, or entered a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction that directly relates to the activities of a registered trainee appraiser or licensed or certified appraiser or that involves moral turpitude or fraudulent or dishonest conduct. The record of a conviction certified or authenticated in such form as admissible in evidence under the laws of the state shall be admissible as prima facie evidence of such guilt.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has had a registration, license, or certification as an appraiser revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against; has been disbarred; has had her or his registration, license, or certificate to practice or conduct any regulated profession, business, or vocation revoked or suspended by this or any other state, any nation, or any possession or district of the United States; or has had an application for such registration, licensure, or certification to practice or conduct any regulated profession, business, or vocation denied by this or any other state, any nation, or any possession or district of the United States.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has become temporarily incapacitated from acting as an appraiser with safety to those in a fiduciary relationship with her or him because of drunkenness, use of drugs, or temporary mental derangement; however, suspension of a license, certification, or registration in such cases shall only be for the period of such incapacity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is confined in any county jail, postadjudication; is confined in any state or federal prison or mental institution; or, through mental disease or deterioration, can no longer safely be entrusted to deal with the public or in a confidential capacity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to inform the board in writing within 30 days after pleading guilty or nolo contendere to, or being convicted or found guilty of, any felony.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been found guilty, for a second time, of any misconduct that warrants disciplinary action, or has been found guilty of a course of conduct or practice that shows that she or he is incompetent, negligent, dishonest, or untruthful to an extent that those with whom she or he may sustain a confidential relationship may not safely do so.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made or filed a report or record, either written or oral, that the registered trainee appraiser or licensed or certified appraiser knows to be false; has willfully failed to file a report or record required by state or federal law; has willfully impeded or obstructed such filing; or has induced another person to impede or obstruct such filing. However, such reports or records shall include only those that are signed or presented in the capacity of a registered trainee appraiser or licensed or certified appraiser.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has obtained or attempted to obtain a registration, license, or certification by means of knowingly making a false statement, submitting false information, refusing to provide complete information in response to an application question, or engaging in fraud, misrepresentation, or concealment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has paid money or other valuable consideration, except as required by this section, to any member or employee of the board to obtain a registration, license, or certification under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has violated any standard of professional practice established by rule of the board, including standards for the development or communication of a real estate appraisal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed or refused to exercise reasonable diligence in developing an appraisal or preparing an appraisal report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to communicate an appraisal without good cause.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has accepted an appraisal assignment if the employment itself is contingent upon the appraiser reporting a predetermined result, analysis, or opinion or if the fee to be paid for the performance of the appraisal assignment is contingent upon the opinion, conclusion, or valuation reached upon the consequences resulting from the appraisal assignment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to timely notify the department of any change in business location, or has failed to fully disclose all business locations from which she or he operates as a registered trainee appraiser or licensed or certified appraiser.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 11, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 10, 149, ch. 94-119; s. 391, ch. 97-103; s. 124, ch. 98-166; s. 32, ch. 98-250; s. 184, ch. 2000-160; s. 16, ch. 2003-164; s. 10, ch. 2006-198; s. 57, ch. 2009-195; s. 6, ch. 2010-84; s. 48, ch. 2010-106; s. 19, ch. 2012-61.</History>
</Section>