<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.630" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary practice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall recognize, on a temporary basis, the license or certification of an appraiser issued by another state, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property to be appraised is part of a federally related transaction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appraiser’s business is of a temporary nature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appraiser registers with the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person requesting recognition of a license or certification as an appraiser issued by another state is a nonresident of Florida.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to register with the board, the appraiser must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay any required fee as established by rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, or cause the state where the applicant may be licensed or certified to furnish, proof of licensure or certification along with the copies of the records of any disciplinary actions taken against the applicant’s license or certification in that or other jurisdictions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agree in writing to cooperate with any investigation initiated under this part by promptly supplying such documents that any authorized representative of the department may request. If the department sends a notice by certified mail to the last known address of a nonresident appraiser to produce documents or to appear in conjunction with an investigation and the nonresident appraiser fails to comply with that request, the board may impose on that nonresident appraiser any disciplinary action or penalty authorized under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sign a notarized statement that the applicant has read this section and all applicable rules and agrees to abide by these provisions in all appraisal activities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 11, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 38, ch. 98-250.</History></Section>