<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.5017" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Injunctive relief; powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate civil action may be brought by the department in circuit court to enjoin a broker from engaging in, or continuing, a violation of this part or doing any act or acts in furtherance thereof. In any such action, an order or judgment may be entered awarding such temporary or permanent injunction as may be deemed proper. In addition to all other means provided by law for the enforcement of a restraining order or injunction, the court in which such action is brought shall have power and jurisdiction to impound and appoint one or more receivers for the property and business of the broker, including books, papers, documents, and records pertaining thereto, or as much thereof as the court may deem reasonably necessary to prevent violations of the law or injury to the public through, or by means of, the use of such property and business. Such receiver, when so appointed and qualified, shall have such powers and duties as to custody, collection, administration, winding up, and liquidation of such property and business as is, from time to time, conferred upon her or him by the court. In any such action, the court may issue an order staying all pending civil actions and the court, in its discretion, may require that all civil actions be assigned to the circuit court judge who appointed the receiver.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All expenses of the receiver shall be paid out of the assets of the brokerage firm upon application to and approval by the court. If the assets are not sufficient to pay all the expenses of the receiver, the court may order disbursement from the Real Estate Recovery Fund, which may not exceed $100,000 per receivership.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 90-228; s. 20, ch. 90-341; s. 24, ch. 90-345; s. 9, ch. 91-201; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 147, ch. 94-119; s. 382, ch. 97-103; s. 49, ch. 2003-164.</History></Section>