<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.711" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Interpleader or other proceedings; deposit of reserved proceeds in court registry; discharge of closing agent from further liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The closing agent shall, by interpleader action or other legal proceeding, seek adjudication of the rights of the parties with respect to disputed reserved proceeds by the county court or circuit court, whichever may have jurisdiction of controversies in the amount of the disputed reserved proceeds, in a county where all or a portion of the commercial real estate is located if, after the closing of a transaction for the disposition of the commercial real estate, all of the following conditions are met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The closing agent has reserved all or a portion of the owner’s net proceeds pursuant to s. 475.709 and the owner disputes the release to the broker of all or any portion of the reserved proceeds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner and the broker have not agreed in writing, within 5 days after the closing, regarding the closing agent’s release of the disputed reserved proceeds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the owner nor the broker have commenced a civil action to determine the rights of the parties with respect to the disputed reserved proceeds.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise agreed to by the owner and the broker in writing, the closing agent shall deposit the net amount of disputed reserved proceeds in the registry of the court having jurisdiction of any legal action or proceeding to determine the rights of the parties in the disputed reserved proceeds, whether commenced by the closing agent under subsection (1) or commenced by the owner or the broker under s. 475.713 or otherwise. The closing agent shall determine the net amount of disputed reserved proceeds deposited in the court registry by deducting from the disputed reserved proceeds:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any costs incurred by the closing agent to commence such action or proceeding, or to appear in any such action or proceeding commenced by the owner or the broker, including reasonable attorney’s fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs of recording the affidavit described in subsection (3) if any commission notice has been recorded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service charges of the clerk of court under s. 28.24 for receiving the net amount of such disputed reserved proceeds into the registry of the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a commission notice has been recorded in the public records of the county or counties where the commercial real estate is located, upon depositing the net disputed reserved proceeds with the clerk of court pursuant to subsection (2), the closing agent shall execute and record an affidavit referring to the recorded commission notice and stating that the net disputed reserved proceeds have been so deposited in accordance with this part. The recording of the affidavit shall operate to release the recorded commission notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a closing agent deposits the net disputed reserved proceeds with the clerk of court pursuant to subsection (2), the closing agent is discharged from any further liability or responsibility concerning the disputed reserved proceeds.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-275; s. 12, ch. 2006-210.</History></Section>