<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.801" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Automatic renewal commission” means a renewal commission for which the brokerage agreement does not expressly require the broker to perform any additional services in order to receive the renewal commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Broker” has the same meaning as in s. 475.01.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Brokerage agreement” means a written contract, entered into on or after the effective date of this act, between an owner of commercial real estate and a broker that obligates the owner to pay a commission to the broker for licensed services provided by the broker relating to the leasing of the commercial real estate as specified in the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial real estate” means a fee simple interest or other possessory estate in real property, except an interest in real property that is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improved with one single-family residential unit or one multifamily structure containing one to four residential units;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unimproved and the maximum permitted development is one to four residential units under any restrictive covenants, zoning regulations, or comprehensive plan applicable to that real property; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improved with single-family residential units such as condominiums, townhouses, timeshares, mobile homes, or houses in a subdivision that may be legally sold, leased, or otherwise conveyed on a unit-by-unit basis, regardless of whether these units may be a part of a larger building or parcel containing more than four residential units.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commission” means any fee or other compensation that an owner agrees to pay a broker for licensed services as specified in a brokerage agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Days” means calendar days, but if a period would end on a day other than a business day, the last day of that period shall instead be the next business day.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lease” means a written agreement creating a relationship of landlord and tenant with respect to commercial real estate, such that the tenant acquires from the landlord the right to possess the commercial real estate for a specified period of time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lien notice” means the written notice of lien made by a broker claiming a commission under s. 475.805.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means a person that is vested with fee simple title or a possessory estate, including a leasehold, in commercial real estate that is the subject of a lease. For purposes of this part, the owner obligated to pay a commission under a brokerage agreement may be a landlord or a tenant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Real property” means one or more parcels or tracts of land located in this state, including any appurtenances and improvements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Renewal commission” means an additional commission that may become payable to a broker under a brokerage agreement if a lease subject to that brokerage agreement is later renewed or is later modified to expand the leased premises or extend the lease term.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-275; s. 57, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>