<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications for practice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for licensure who is a natural person must be at least 18 years of age; hold a high school diploma or its equivalent; be honest, truthful, trustworthy, and of good character; and have a good reputation for fair dealing. An applicant for an active broker’s license or a sales associate’s license must be competent and qualified to make real estate transactions and conduct negotiations therefor with safety to investors and to those with whom the applicant may undertake a relationship of trust and confidence. If the applicant has been denied registration or a license or has been disbarred, or the applicant’s registration or license to practice or conduct any regulated profession, business, or vocation has been revoked or suspended, by this or any other state, any nation, or any possession or district of the United States, or any court or lawful agency thereof, because of any conduct or practices which would have warranted a like result under this chapter, or if the applicant has been guilty of conduct or practices in this state or elsewhere which would have been grounds for revoking or suspending her or his license under this chapter had the applicant then been registered, the applicant shall be deemed not to be qualified unless, because of lapse of time and subsequent good conduct and reputation, or other reason deemed sufficient, it appears to the commission that the interest of the public and investors will not likely be endangered by the granting of registration. The commission may adopt rules requiring an applicant for licensure to provide written information to the commission regarding the applicant’s good character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application may be disapproved if the applicant has acted or attempted to act, or has held herself or himself out as entitled to act, during the period of 1 year next prior to the filing of the application, as a real estate broker or sales associate in the state in violation of this chapter. This paragraph may be deemed to bar any person from licensure who has performed any of the acts or services described in s. 475.01(3), unless exempt pursuant to s. 475.011, during a period of 1 year next preceding the filing of the application, or during the pendency of the application, and until a valid current license has been duly issued to the person, regardless of whether the performance of the act or service was done for compensation or valuable consideration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to other requirements under this part, the commission may require the satisfactory completion of one or more of the educational courses or equivalent courses conducted, offered, sponsored, prescribed, or approved pursuant to s. 475.04, taken at an accredited college, university, or community college, at a career center, or at a registered real estate school, as a condition precedent for any person to become licensed or to renew her or his license as a broker, broker associate, or sales associate. The course or courses required for one to become initially licensed shall not exceed a total of 63 classroom hours of 50 minutes each, inclusive of examination, for a sales associate and 72 classroom hours of 50 minutes each, inclusive of examination, for a broker. The satisfactory completion of an examination administered by the accredited college, university, or community college, by a career center, or by the registered real estate school shall be the basis for determining satisfactory completion of the course. However, notice of satisfactory completion shall not be issued if the student has absences in excess of 8 classroom hours.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A distance learning course or courses shall be approved by the commission as an option to classroom hours as satisfactory completion of the course or courses as required by this section. The schools authorized by this section have the option of providing classroom courses, distance learning courses, or both. However, satisfactory completion of a distance learning course requires the satisfactory completion of a timed distance learning course examination. Such examination shall not be required to be monitored or given at a centralized location.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such required course or courses must be made available by correspondence or other suitable means to any person who, by reason of hardship, as defined by rule, cannot attend the place or places where the course or courses are regularly conducted or does not have access to the distance learning course or courses.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not be licensed as a real estate broker unless, in addition to the other requirements of law, the person has held:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An active real estate sales associate’s license for at least 24 months during the preceding 5 years in the office of one or more real estate brokers licensed in this state or any other state, territory, or jurisdiction of the United States or in any foreign national jurisdiction;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A current and valid real estate sales associate’s license for at least 24 months during the preceding 5 years in the employ of a governmental agency for a salary and performing the duties authorized in this part for real estate licensees; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A current and valid real estate broker’s license for at least 24 months during the preceding 5 years in any other state, territory, or jurisdiction of the United States or in any foreign national jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has been licensed as a real estate sales associate in Florida during the preceding 5 years may not be licensed as a real estate broker unless, in addition to the other requirements of law, she or he has completed the sales associate postlicensure educational requirements, if these requirements have been prescribed by the commission pursuant to paragraph (3)(a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may prescribe a postlicensure education requirement in order for a person to maintain a valid sales associate’s license, which shall not exceed 45 classroom hours of 50 minutes each, inclusive of examination, prior to the first renewal following initial licensure. If prescribed, this shall consist of one or more commission-approved courses which total at least 45 classroom hours on one or more subjects which include, but are not limited to, property management, appraisal, real estate finance, the economics of real estate management, marketing, technology, sales and listing of properties, business office management, courses teaching practical real estate application skills, development of business plans, marketing of property, and time management. Required postlicensure education courses must be provided by an accredited college, university, or community college, by a career center, by a registered real estate school, or by a commission-approved sponsor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfactory completion of the postlicensure education requirement is demonstrated by successfully meeting all standards established for the commission-prescribed or commission-approved institution or school. However, notice of satisfactory completion shall not be issued if the student has absences in excess of 10 percent of the required classroom hours or has not satisfactorily completed a timed distance learning course examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license of any sales associate who does not complete the postlicensure education requirement prior to the first renewal following initial licensure shall be considered null and void. Such person wishing to again operate as a real estate sales associate must requalify by satisfactorily completing the sales associate’s prelicensure course and passing the state examination for licensure as a sales associate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sales associate who is required to complete any postlicensure education requirement must complete any postlicensure education requirement and hold a current and valid license in order to be eligible for licensure as a broker.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may prescribe a postlicensure education requirement in order for a person to maintain a valid broker’s license, which shall not exceed 60 classroom hours of 50 minutes each, inclusive of examination, prior to the first renewal following initial licensure. If prescribed, this shall consist of one or more commission-approved courses which total at least 60 classroom hours on one or more subjects which include, but are not limited to, advanced appraisal, advanced property management, real estate marketing, business law, advanced real estate investment analyses, advanced legal aspects, general accounting, real estate economics, syndications, commercial brokerage, feasibility analyses, advanced real estate finance, residential brokerage, advanced marketing, technology, advanced business planning, time management, or real estate brokerage office operations. Required postlicensure education courses must be provided by an accredited college, university, or community college, by a career center, by a registered real estate school, or by a commission-approved sponsor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfactory completion of the postlicensure education requirement is demonstrated by successfully meeting all standards established for the commission-prescribed or commission-approved institution or school. However, notice of satisfactory completion shall not be issued if the student has absences in excess of 10 percent of the required classroom hours or has not satisfactorily completed a timed distance learning course examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license of any broker who does not complete the postlicensure education requirement prior to the first renewal following initial licensure shall be considered null and void. If the licensee wishes to operate as a sales associate, she or he may be issued a sales associate’s license after providing proof that she or he has satisfactorily completed the 14-hour continuing education course within the 6 months following expiration of her or his broker’s license. To operate as a broker, the licensee must requalify by satisfactorily completing the broker’s prelicensure course and passing the state examination for licensure as a broker.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may allow an additional 6-month period after the first renewal following initial licensure for completing the postlicensure education courses for sales associates and brokers who cannot, due to individual physical hardship, as defined by rule, complete the courses within the required time.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (4), sales associates and brokers are not required to meet the 14-hour continuing education requirement prior to the first renewal following initial licensure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A distance learning course or courses shall be approved by the commission as an option to classroom hours as satisfactory completion of the postlicensure education course or courses as required by this section. The schools or sponsors authorized by this section have the option of providing classroom courses, distance learning courses, or both. However, satisfactory completion of a distance learning postlicensure education course or courses requires the satisfactory completion of a timed distance learning course examination. Such examination shall not be required to be monitored or given at a centralized location.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall provide for postlicensure education courses to be made available by correspondence or other suitable means to any person who, by reason of hardship, as defined by rule, cannot attend the place or places where courses are regularly conducted or does not have access to the distance learning courses.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The postlicensure education requirements of this section, and the education course requirements for one to become initially licensed, do not apply to any applicant or licensee who has received a 4-year degree in real estate from an accredited institution of higher education.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may not approve prelicensure or postlicensure distance learning courses for brokers, broker associates, and sales associates by correspondence methods, except in instances of hardship pursuant to subparagraphs (2)(a)3. and (5)(c)2.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 12223, 1927; CGL 4079; s. 1, ch. 24090, 1947; s. 1, ch. 57-244; s. 2, ch. 59-200; ss. 2, 3, ch. 69-378; s. 1, ch. 74-343; s. 1, ch. 75-106; s. 1, ch. 75-117; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-116; s. 1, ch. 77-238; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 11, 42, 43, ch. 79-239; s. 206, ch. 79-400; ss. 2, 4, 5, ch. 80-405; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 13, 38, ch. 82-1; s. 57, ch. 83-329; ss. 8, 28, 30, ch. 88-20; s. 26, ch. 88-392; s. 1, ch. 89-76; s. 13, ch. 90-228; s. 13, ch. 90-341; s. 16, ch. 90-345; s. 10, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 93-62; s. 6, ch. 93-261; s. 137, ch. 94-119; s. 365, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 98-116; s. 4, ch. 98-250; s. 1, ch. 2002-9; s. 27, ch. 2003-164; s. 51, ch. 2004-357; s. 26, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>