<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.811" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer of lien to security.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lien claimed by a broker by recording a lien notice under this part may be transferred by any person having an interest in the commercial real estate upon which the lien is imposed from such commercial real estate to other security by either:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Depositing in the clerk’s office a sum of money; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing in the clerk’s office a bond executed as surety by a surety insurer licensed to do business in this state, either to be in an amount equal to the amount claimed in the lien notice, plus interest thereon at the legal rate for 3 years, plus $1,000 or 25 percent of the amount demanded in the lien notice, whichever is greater, to apply on any attorney’s fees and court costs that may be taxed in any proceeding to enforce said lien.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such deposit or bond shall be conditioned to pay any judgment or decree that may be rendered for the satisfaction of the lien for which such lien notice was recorded. Upon making such deposit or filing such bond, the clerk shall make and record a certificate showing the transfer of the lien from the commercial real estate to the security and shall mail a copy thereof by registered or certified mail to the broker named in the lien notice at the address stated therein. Upon filing the certificate of transfer, the commercial real estate shall thereupon be released from the lien claimed, and such lien shall be transferred to said security. Subject to any order of the court increasing the amount required for the lien transfer deposit or bond, no other judgment or decree to pay money may be entered by the court against the owner on account of the commission claimed in the lien notice. The clerk shall be entitled to a service charge for making and serving the certificate, in the amount of up to $15. If the transaction involves the transfer of multiple liens, an additional charge of up to $7.50 for each additional lien shall be charged. For recording the certificate and approving the bond, the clerk shall receive her or his usual statutory service charges as prescribed in s. 28.24. Any number of liens may be transferred to one such security.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any excess of the security over the aggregate amount of any judgments or decrees rendered plus costs actually taxed shall be repaid to the party filing the security or her or his successor in interest. Any deposit of money shall be considered as paid into court and shall be subject to the provisions of law relative to payments of money into court and the disposition of same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action pending under s. 475.809 to foreclose or discharge a lien, any party having an interest in such security or the commercial real estate from which the lien was transferred may at any time and any number of times file a motion for an order to require additional security, reduction of security, change or substitution of sureties, payment of discharge thereof, or any other matter affecting said security. If the court finds that the amount of the deposit or bond in excess of the amount claimed in the lien notice is insufficient to pay the fees of the broker’s attorney and court costs incurred in the action to enforce the lien, the court shall increase the amount of the cash deposit or lien transfer bond.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a proceeding to enforce a transferred lien is not commenced within the time specified in s. 475.809 or if it appears that the transferred lien has been satisfied of record, the clerk shall return said security upon request of the person depositing or filing the same, or the insurer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-275.</History></Section>