<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0475.6175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registered trainee appraiser; postlicensure education required.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall prescribe postlicensure educational requirements in order for a person to maintain a valid registration as a registered trainee appraiser. If prescribed, the postlicensure educational requirements consist of one or more courses which total no more than the total educational hours required to qualify as a state certified residential appraiser. Such courses must be in subjects related to real estate appraisal and must include coverage of the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice, or its equivalent, as established by rule of the board. Such courses are provided by a nationally or state-recognized appraisal organization, career center, accredited community college, college, or university, state or federal agency or commission, or proprietary real estate school that holds a permit pursuant to s. 475.451.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registration of any registered trainee appraiser who does not complete the board-prescribed postlicensure educational requirements prior to the second renewal following initial registration is void without further administrative action. Such person may requalify to practice as a registered trainee appraiser only by retaking the required education and complying with all other requirements of law to be registered as a registered trainee appraiser. Any registered trainee appraiser registered prior to July 1, 2003, shall comply with the board-prescribed postlicensure educational requirements within the next two biennial renewal cycles following July 1, 2003.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may allow an additional 6-month period after the second renewal following initial licensure or the effective date of this act for completing the postlicensure education courses for registered trainee appraisers who have not completed or cannot complete, due to individual hardship, the courses within the required time.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2003-164; s. 54, ch. 2004-357; s. 6, ch. 2007-86; s. 17, ch. 2012-61.</History>
</Section>