<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.627" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appraisal course instructors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the course or courses to be taught are prescribed by the board or approved precedent to registration, licensure, certification, or renewal as a registered trainee appraiser, licensed appraiser, or certified residential appraiser, before commencing to instruct noncredit college courses in a college, university, or community college, or courses in a career center or proprietary real estate school, a person must certify her or his competency by meeting one of the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold a valid certification as a residential real estate appraiser in this or any other state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pass an appraiser instructor’s examination which shall test knowledge of residential appraisal topics.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the course or courses to be taught are prescribed by the board or approved precedent to registration, licensure, certification, or renewal as a registered trainee appraiser, licensed appraiser, or certified appraiser, before commencing to instruct noncredit college courses in a college, university, or community college, or courses in a career center or proprietary real estate school, a person must certify her or his competency by meeting one of the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold a valid certification as a general real estate appraiser in this or any other state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pass an appraiser instructor’s examination which shall test knowledge of residential and nonresidential appraisal topics.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possession of a permit to teach prescribed or approved appraisal courses does not entitle the permitholder to teach any courses outside the scope of the permit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 11, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 153, ch. 92-149; s. 393, ch. 97-103; s. 34, ch. 98-250; s. 18, ch. 2003-164; s. 56, ch. 2004-357.</History></Section>