<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.631" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonresident licenses and certifications.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the requirements for certification set forth in ss. 475.615 and 475.616, the board may enter into written agreements with similar licensing or certification authorities of other states, territories, or jurisdictions of the United States to ensure for state-certified appraisers nonresident licensure or certification opportunities comparable to those afforded to nonresidents by this section. Whenever the board determines that another jurisdiction does not offer nonresident licensure or certification to state-certified appraisers substantially comparable to those afforded to certified appraisers or licensees of that jurisdiction by this section, the board shall require certified appraisers or licensees of that jurisdiction who apply for nonresident certification to meet education, experience, and examination requirements substantially comparable to those required by that jurisdiction with respect to state-certified appraisers who seek nonresident licensure or certification, not to exceed such requirements as are prescribed in ss. 475.615 and 475.616.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident state-certified appraiser who becomes a nonresident shall, within 60 days, notify the board of the change in residency and comply with nonresident requirements. Failure to notify and comply is a violation of the license law, subject to the penalties in s. 475.624.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All nonresident applicants, certified appraisers, and licensees shall comply with all requirements of board rules and this part. The board may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 necessary for the regulation of nonresident certified appraisers and licensees.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 2003-164; s. 13, ch. 2012-208.</History></Section>