<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.622" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Display and disclosure of licensure, certification, or registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each appraiser registered, licensed, or certified under this part shall place her or his registration, license, or certification number adjacent to or immediately beneath the designation “state-registered trainee real estate appraiser,” “state-licensed real estate appraiser,” “state-certified residential real estate appraiser,” or “state-certified general real estate appraiser,” or their appropriate abbreviations as defined by rule, as applicable, when such term is used in an appraisal report or in a contract or other instrument used by the appraiser in conducting real property appraisal activities. The applicable designation shall be included in any newspaper, telephone directory, or other advertising medium, as defined by rule, used by the appraiser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered trainee appraiser or licensed or certified appraiser may not sign any appraisal report or certification or communicate same without disclosing in writing that she or he is a state-registered trainee appraiser or state-licensed, state-certified residential, or state-certified general appraiser, as applicable, even if the appraisal performed is outside of the scope of the appraiser’s registration, licensure, or certification as an appraiser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary or secondary supervisory appraiser of a registered trainee real estate appraiser must sign each appraisal report and certification signed by the registered trainee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisory appraiser of a registered trainee real estate appraiser must disclose her or his appropriate designation and number any time the registered trainee is required to make such disclosures.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 11, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 152, ch. 92-149; s. 389, ch. 97-103; s. 30, ch. 98-250; s. 2, ch. 2001-274; s. 13, ch. 2003-164.</History></Section>