<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.483" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conditions for recovery; eligibility.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person is eligible to seek recovery from the Real Estate Recovery Fund if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person has received a final judgment in a court of competent civil jurisdiction in this state against an individual broker or sales associate in any action wherein the cause of action was based on a real estate brokerage transaction. If such person is unable to secure a final judgment against a licensee due to the death of the licensee, the commission may waive the requirement for a final judgment. The filing of a bankruptcy petition by a broker or sales associate does not relieve a claimant from the obligation to obtain a final judgment against the licensee. In this instance, the claimant must seek to have assets involving the real estate transaction that gave rise to the claim removed from the bankruptcy proceedings so that the matter might be heard in a court of competent civil jurisdiction in this state. If, after due diligence, the claimant is precluded by action of the bankruptcy court from securing a final judgment against the licensee, the commission may waive the requirement for a final judgment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the action was commenced, such person gave notice thereof to the commission by certified mail; except that, if no notice has been given to the commission, the claim can still be honored if, in the opinion of the commission, the claim is otherwise valid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim for recovery is made within 2 years from the time of the act giving rise to the claim or within 2 years from the time the act is discovered or should have been discovered with the exercise of due diligence. In no event may a claim for recovery be made more than 4 years after the date of the act giving rise to the claim.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person has caused to be issued a writ of execution upon such judgment, and the person has executed an affidavit showing that no personal or real property of the judgment debtor liable to be levied upon in satisfaction of the judgment can be found or that the amount realized on the sale of the judgment debtor’s property pursuant to such execution was insufficient to satisfy the judgment; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such person is unable to comply with subparagraph 1. for a valid reason to be determined by the commission, such person has made all reasonable searches and inquiries to ascertain whether the judgment debtor is possessed of real or personal property or other assets subject to being sold or applied in satisfaction of the judgment and by her or his search the person has discovered no property or assets or she or he has discovered property and assets and has taken all necessary action and proceedings for the application thereof to the judgment but the amount thereby realized was insufficient to satisfy the judgment.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any amounts recovered by such person from the judgment debtor, or from any other source, have been applied to the damages awarded by the court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person is not a person who is precluded by this act from making a claim for recovery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person has executed an affidavit showing that the final judgment is not on appeal or, if it was the subject of an appeal, that the appellate proceedings have concluded and the outcome of the appeal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is not qualified to make a claim for recovery from the Real Estate Recovery Fund, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person is the spouse of the judgment debtor or a personal representative of such spouse;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person is a licensed broker or sales associate who acted as a single agent or transaction broker in the transaction that is the subject of the claim;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person’s claim is based upon a real estate transaction in which the licensed broker or sales associate was the owner of or controlled the property involved in the transaction; in which the licensee was dealing for the licensee’s own account; or in which the licensee was not acting as a broker or sales associate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person’s claim is based upon a real estate transaction in which the broker or sales associate did not hold a valid, current, and active license at the time of the real estate transaction; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judgment is against a real estate brokerage corporation, partnership, limited liability company, or limited liability partnership.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the claim is of the type described in s. 475.482(2), the commission shall pay the defendant’s reasonable attorney’s fees and court costs and, if the plaintiff prevails in court, the plaintiff’s reasonable attorney’s fees and court costs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-74; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 35, 42, 43, ch. 79-239; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 34, 38, ch. 82-1; s. 63, ch. 83-329; s. 2, ch. 85-90; ss. 21, 28, 30, ch. 88-20; s. 5, ch. 89-76; s. 18, ch. 90-228; s. 21, ch. 90-345; s. 10, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 20, ch. 93-261; s. 145, ch. 94-119; s. 15, ch. 94-170; s. 4, ch. 94-337; s. 378, ch. 97-103; s. 12, ch. 99-384; s. 47, ch. 2003-164.</History></Section>