<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.707" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recording commission notice; effectiveness.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a broker delivers the copies of a commission notice as provided in s. 475.705, the broker may record the commission notice in the public records maintained by the clerk of court in the county or counties in which the commercial real estate is located.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the limitation in paragraph (b), the broker’s lien created by this part against the owner’s net proceeds is perfected by such recording of the commission notice and takes priority pursuant to this part as of the date of the recording of the commission notice. The priority of the lien does not relate back to the date of the brokerage agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recording of the commission notice shall not constitute constructive notice to a closing agent unless the commission notice has been of record for at least 60 days.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recorded commission notice is effective under this part only with respect to dispositions made by the owner named in the commission notice, and after the recordation of a deed from the owner conveying the commercial real estate specified in the commission notice to a bona fide purchaser for value, the commission notice is ineffective with respect to any subsequent dispositions of that commercial real estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commission notice recorded under this part expires 1 year after the date of recording, unless the owner remains obligated to pay a commission to the broker after the expiration date of the commission notice and the broker records an extension notice in the same public records within the last 60 days before such expiration date. An extension notice shall refer to the recording information of the original commission notice, shall state that the owner remains obligated to pay a commission to the broker, and shall include the information and be executed in the manner as required by s. 475.705(1) for the original commission notice. A timely recorded extension notice shall extend the expiration date of the original recorded commission notice by 1 additional year. Successive extension notices may be recorded for so long as the owner remains obligated to pay a commission to the broker. Within 10 days after recording an extension notice, the broker shall deliver a copy thereof to the owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery or recording of a commission notice or the enforcement of a commission claim by a broker under this part does not relieve the owner from the owner’s obligation to close a disposition transaction for any commercial real estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a commission notice is recorded and a condition or event occurs or fails to occur that would preclude the broker from receiving the claimed commission under the terms of the brokerage agreement, including the filing of a commission notice in a manner that does not comply with this part, the broker shall, within 7 days following demand by the owner, record a written release of the commission notice in the public records of the county where the commission notice was recorded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a broker records a commission notice pursuant to this section and the claimed commission is paid or the commission notice is otherwise discharged or satisfied pursuant to this part, the broker shall, within 7 days after the commission is paid or the commission notice is otherwise discharged or satisfied, record a written release of the commission notice in the public records of the county where the commission notice was recorded.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-275; s. 10, ch. 2006-210.</History></Section>