<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0475.618" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Renewal of registration, license, certification, or instructor permit; continuing education.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall renew a registration, license, certification, or instructor permit upon receipt of the renewal application and proper fee. Such application shall include proof satisfactory to the board that the individual has satisfactorily completed any continuing education that has been prescribed by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A distance learning course or courses shall be approved by the board as an option to classroom hours as satisfactory completion of the course or courses as required by this section. The schools authorized by this section have the option of providing classroom courses, distance learning courses, or both.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may authorize independent certification organizations to certify or approve the delivery method of distance learning courses. Certification from such authorized organizations must be provided at the time a distance learning course is submitted to the board by an accredited college, university, community college, career center, proprietary real estate school, or board-approved sponsor for content approval.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing a procedure for the renewal of registration, licenses, certifications, and instructor permits at least every 4 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any registration, license, certification, or instructor permit which is not renewed at the end of the registration, license, certification, or instructor permit period prescribed by the department shall automatically revert to inactive status.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 60 days prior to the end of the registration, license, certification, or instructor permit period, the department shall cause to be mailed a notice of renewal and possible reversion to the last known address of the registered trainee, licensee, certificateholder, or permitholder.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 11, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 151, ch. 92-149; s. 27, ch. 98-250; s. 5, ch. 2002-9; s. 10, ch. 2003-164; s. 55, ch. 2004-357.</History></Section>