<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0475.613" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Real Estate Appraisal Board.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Florida Real Estate Appraisal Board, which shall consist of nine members appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. Four members of the board must be real estate appraisers who have been engaged in the general practice of appraising real property in this state for at least 5 years immediately preceding appointment. In appointing real estate appraisers to the board, while not excluding other appraisers, the Governor shall give preference to real estate appraisers who are not primarily engaged in real estate brokerage or mortgage lending activities. Two members of the board must represent the appraisal management industry. One member of the board must represent organizations that use appraisals for the purpose of eminent domain proceedings, financial transactions, or mortgage insurance. Two members of the board shall be representatives of the general public and shall not be connected in any way with the practice of real estate appraisal. The appraiser members shall be as representative of the entire industry as possible, and membership in a nationally recognized or state-recognized appraisal organization shall not be a prerequisite to membership on the board. To the extent possible, no more than two members of the board shall be primarily affiliated with any one particular national or state appraisal association. Two of the members must be licensed or certified residential real estate appraisers and two of the members must be certified general real estate appraisers at the time of their appointment.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the board shall be appointed for 4-year terms. Any vacancy occurring in the membership of the board shall be filled by appointment by the Governor for the unexpired term. Upon expiration of her or his term, a member of the board shall continue to hold office until the appointment and qualification of the member’s successor. A member may not be appointed for more than two consecutive terms. The Governor may remove any member for cause.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The headquarters for the board shall be in Orlando.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall meet at least once each calendar quarter to conduct its business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the board shall elect a chairperson at the first meeting each year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board is entitled to per diem and travel expenses as set by legislative appropriation for each day that the member engages in the business of the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have, through its rules, full power to regulate the issuance of licenses, certifications, registrations, and permits; to discipline appraisers in any manner permitted under this section; to establish qualifications for licenses, certifications, registrations, and permits consistent with this section; to regulate approved courses; to establish standards for real estate appraisals; and to establish standards for and regulate supervisory appraisers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 112.313, any member of the board who is a licensed or certified real estate appraiser and who holds an active appraiser instructor permit issued by the department, to the extent authorized pursuant to such permit, may offer, conduct, or teach any course prescribed or approved by the board or the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 11, ch. 91-89; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 150, ch. 92-149; s. 383, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 2003-164; s. 2, ch. 2010-84; s. 37, ch. 2010-106.</History>
</Section>