<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0475.807" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recording lien notice; effectiveness.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a commission is earned under this part, the broker may record a lien notice in the public records maintained by the clerk of court in the county or counties in which the commercial real estate is located. The lien notice shall be recorded no later than the earlier of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ninety days after the tenant takes possession of the leased premises or, in the case of a renewal commission that requires the broker to perform additional services as provided in s. 475.803(3), 90 days after the broker performs the additional services required for the renewal commission; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date on which the owner who is obligated to pay the commission records in the public records a deed or assignment transferring the owner’s interest in the commercial real estate to a bona fide purchaser for value.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A broker who fails to record a lien notice within the time period prescribed by this section may not enforce a lien for the claimed commission under this part, and a lien notice that is recorded outside of the time period prescribed by this section is void.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 7 days after recording the lien notice, the broker shall deliver a copy of the lien notice to the owner obligated to pay the claimed commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The broker’s lien created by this part against the commercial real estate is perfected by such recording of the lien notice and takes priority under this part as of the date of the recording of the lien notice. The priority of the lien notice does not relate back to the date of the brokerage agreement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the commission is to be paid in installments and any of those installments are due after the lease is executed, the lien notice is valid only to the extent that moneys remain unpaid by the owner to the broker.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recorded lien notice is effective under this part only with respect to leases made by the owner named in the lien notice, and the lien notice is ineffective with respect to any leases that are made by:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bona fide purchaser for value of the commercial real estate;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A purchaser at any mortgage foreclosure sale of the commercial real estate; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any successor owner acquiring the commercial real estate from a purchaser described in paragraph (a) or paragraph (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a lien notice is recorded and a condition or event occurs or fails to occur that would preclude the broker from receiving the claimed commission under the terms of the brokerage agreement, including the filing of a lien notice in a manner that does not comply with this part, the broker shall, within 7 days following demand by the owner, record a written release of the lien notice in the public records of the county where the lien notice was recorded.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a broker records a lien notice pursuant to this section and the claimed commission is paid or the lien notice is otherwise discharged or satisfied pursuant to this part, the broker shall, within 7 days after the commission is paid or the lien notice is otherwise discharged or satisfied, record a written release of the lien notice in the public records of the county where the lien notice was recorded.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (b), a lien notice recorded by a broker under this part for a claimed commission expires 2 years after the date of recording, unless within that time the broker commences an action to foreclose the lien under s. 475.809 and records a notice of lis pendens in the public records of the county where the lien notice was recorded.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that a lien notice recorded by a broker under this part claims an automatic renewal commission that is earned but not then payable, the lien notice expires 10 years after the date of recording, unless within that time the broker commences an action to foreclose the lien under s. 475.809 and records a notice of lis pendens in the public records of the county where the lien notice was recorded. If the owner remains obligated to pay a commission to the broker, the broker may extend the expiration date of a lien notice for an automatic renewal commission by recording an extension notice in the same public records within the last 6 months before such expiration date. An extension notice shall refer to the recording information of the original lien notice, shall state that the owner remains obligated to pay a commission to the broker, and shall include the same information and be executed in the same manner as required by s. 475.805(1) for the original lien notice. A timely recorded extension notice shall extend the expiration date of the original recorded lien notice by 10 additional years. Successive extension notices may be recorded for so long as the owner remains obligated to pay a commission to the broker. Within 10 days after recording an extension notice, the broker shall deliver a copy thereof to the owner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or the owner’s agent or attorney may elect to shorten the time within which the broker shall commence an action to foreclose a lien under s. 475.809, or to enforce a claim against a transfer bond or other security under s. 475.811, by recording in the clerk’s office a notice of contest in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">NOTICE OF CONTEST OF BROKER’S LIEN</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">To: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name and address of broker)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">You are notified that the undersigned contests the lien notice filed by you on <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, and recorded in Official Records Book <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, Page <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, of the public records of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida, and that the time within which you may file suit to enforce your lien is limited to 60 days from the date of service of this notice. This <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">Signed: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Owner or Attorney)</Directions></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The lien of any broker upon whom such a notice of contest is served and who fails to institute a suit to enforce the lien within 60 days after service of such notice of contest shall be extinguished automatically. The clerk shall mail a copy of the notice of contest to the broker at the address shown in the lien notice or most recent amendment thereto and shall certify to such service on the face of the notice of contest and record the notice of contest. Service of the notice of contest by the clerk shall be deemed complete upon mailing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the recording of a broker’s lien notice or any extension thereof nor the recording of any lis pendens to foreclose a broker’s lien thereunder shall constitute notice to any creditor or subsequent purchaser pursuant to s. 695.01 or chapter 712 of the existence of any lease described in the lien notice, extension notice, or lis pendens.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-275; s. 16, ch. 2006-210.</History>
</Section>