<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0377.33" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Injunctions against division.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interested person adversely affected by any statute of this state with respect to conservation of oil or gas, or both, or by provisions of this law may seek relief by a suit for injunction against the division, as defendant, or the members thereof by suit in the chancery court in the county or counties wherein the property involved is situated, or in the chancery court of Leon County. Such suit shall have precedence over all other causes, proceedings, or suits on the docket of a different nature, and the attorney representing the division may have the case set for trial after 10 days’ notice to the plaintiff or his or her attorney. Such trial shall be de novo, and the burden of proof shall be upon the plaintiff. The statute or provision of this law complained of shall be taken as prima facie valid, and such presumption shall not be overcome, in connection with any application for injunctive relief, including temporary restraining order, by verified complaint or affidavit of, or in behalf of, the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No temporary restraining order or injunction shall be granted against the division or against its attorneys, agents, employees, or representatives restraining the attorneys, agents, employees, or representatives from enforcing any statute of this state relating to conservation of oil or gas, or any of the provisions of this law, except after due notice, served upon the executive director of the department, and after a hearing at which it shall be shown to the court by legal evidence that the act done or threatened is without sanction of law or that the provisions of this law are invalid or unreasonable and, if enforced against the complaining party, will cause an irreparable injury. If the division shall so request at such hearing, it shall be entitled to a trial on the merits within 10 days after the granting of any temporary order, and, if the plaintiff is not ready for trial at such time, the court shall be authorized to dissolve the temporary restraining order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No temporary injunction of any kind against the division, or against its attorneys, agents, employees, or representatives, shall become effective until the plaintiff shall execute a bond in the amount and upon the conditions the court directs. The bond shall be made payable to the Governor and his or her successors in office, shall be approved by the court or clerk, and shall be for the use and benefit of all persons who may be injured by the acts done under the protection of the injunction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 27-29, ch. 22819, 1945; s. 10, ch. 26484, 1951; s. 2, ch. 29737, 1955; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 27, ch. 74-382; s. 23, ch. 78-95; s. 88, ch. 79-164; s. 626, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>