<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0377.244" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conditions for granting permits for surface exploratory and extraction operations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exploration for and extraction of minerals under and by virtue of the authority of a grant of oil, gas, or mineral rights, or which, subsequent to such grant, may be interpreted to include the right to explore for and extract minerals which are subject to extraction from the land by means other than through a well hole, that is by means of surface exploratory and extraction operations such as sifting of the sands, dragline, open pit mining, or other type of surface operation, which would include movement of sands, dirt, rock, or minerals, shall be exercised only pursuant to permit issued by the Division of Resource Management upon applicant complying with the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must own a valid deed, or other muniment of title, or lease granting applicant the right to explore for and extract oil, gas, and other minerals from said lands.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall post a good and sufficient surety bond with the division in such amount as the division may determine is adequate to afford full and complete protection for the owner of the surface rights of the lands described in the application, conditioned upon the full and complete restoration, by the applicant, of the area over which the exploratory and extraction operations are conducted to the same condition and contour in existence prior to such operations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this act shall not apply to the exploration and removal from lands of peat, muck, marl, limestone, limerock, kaolin, fuller’s earth, phosphate, common clays, gravel, shell, sand, and similar substances, it being the legislative determination that the mining and extraction operations, and the grants of authority under which these activities are conducted for said substances exempted from the provisions of this act, are dissimilar from the exploratory and extraction operations and the grants of authority under which these activities are conducted for substances which come within the purview of the regulatory provisions of this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 61-299; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 71, ch. 79-65.</History></Section>