<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0377.703" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional functions of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />Recognizing that energy supply and demand questions have become a major area of concern to the state which must be dealt with by effective and well-coordinated state action, it is the intent of the Legislature to promote the efficient, effective, and economical management of energy problems, centralize energy coordination responsibilities, pinpoint responsibility for conducting energy programs, and ensure the accountability of state agencies for the implementation of s. 377.601(2), the state energy policy. It is the specific intent of the Legislature that nothing in this act shall in any way change the powers, duties, and responsibilities assigned by the Florida Electrical Power Plant Siting Act, part II of chapter 403, or the powers, duties, and responsibilities of the Florida Public Service Commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DUTIES.<EmDash />The department shall perform the following functions, unless as otherwise provided, consistent with the development of a state energy policy:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Emergency Management is responsible for the development of an energy emergency contingency plan to respond to serious shortages of primary and secondary energy sources. Upon a finding by the Governor, implementation of any emergency program shall be upon order of the Governor that a particular kind or type of fuel is, or that the occurrence of an event which is reasonably expected within 30 days will make the fuel, in short supply. The Division of Emergency Management shall then respond by instituting the appropriate measures of the contingency plan to meet the given emergency or energy shortage. The Governor may utilize the provisions of s. 252.36(5) to carry out any emergency actions required by a serious shortage of energy sources.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is responsible for performing or coordinating the functions of any federal energy programs delegated to the state, including energy supply, demand, conservation, or allocation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall analyze present and proposed federal energy programs and make recommendations regarding those programs to the Governor and the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall coordinate efforts to seek federal support or other support for state energy activities, including energy conservation, research, or development, and is responsible for the coordination of multiagency energy conservation programs and plans.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall analyze energy data collected and prepare long-range forecasts of energy supply and demand in coordination with the Florida Public Service Commission, which is responsible for electricity and natural gas forecasts. To this end, the forecasts shall contain:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An analysis of the relationship of state economic growth and development to energy supply and demand, including the constraints to economic growth resulting from energy supply constraints.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plans for the development of renewable energy resources and reduction in dependence on depletable energy resources, particularly oil and natural gas, and an analysis of the extent to which renewable energy sources are being utilized in the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consideration of alternative scenarios of statewide energy supply and demand for 5, 10, and 20 years to identify strategies for long-range action, including identification of potential social, economic, and environmental effects.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the state’s energy resources, including examination of the availability of commercially developable and imported fuels, and an analysis of anticipated effects on the state’s environment and social services resulting from energy resource development activities or from energy supply constraints, or both.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall submit an annual report to the Governor and the Legislature reflecting its activities and making recommendations of policies for improvement of the state’s response to energy supply and demand and its effect on the health, safety, and welfare of the people of Florida. The report shall include a report from the Florida Public Service Commission on electricity and natural gas and information on energy conservation programs conducted and underway in the past year and shall include recommendations for energy conservation programs for the state, including, but not limited to, the following factors:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Formulation of specific recommendations for improvement in the efficiency of energy utilization in governmental, residential, commercial, industrial, and transportation sectors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collection and dissemination of information relating to energy conservation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development and conduct of educational and training programs relating to energy conservation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An analysis of the ways in which state agencies are seeking to implement s. 377.601(2), the state energy policy, and recommendations for better fulfilling this policy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall promote the development and use of renewable energy resources, in conformance with chapter 187 and s. 377.601, by:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing goals and strategies for increasing the use of solar energy in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding and promoting the commercialization of solar energy technology, in cooperation with the Florida Solar Energy Center, Enterprise Florida, Inc., and any other federal, state, or local governmental agency which may seek to promote research, development, and demonstration of solar energy equipment and technology.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identifying barriers to greater use of solar energy systems in this state, and developing specific recommendations for overcoming identified barriers, with findings and recommendations to be submitted annually in the report to the Governor and Legislature required under paragraph (f).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with the Department of Environmental Protection, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Economic Opportunity, Enterprise Florida, Inc., the Florida Solar Energy Center, and the Florida Solar Energy Industries Association, investigating opportunities, pursuant to the National Energy Policy Act of 1992, the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and any subsequent federal legislation, for solar electric vehicles and other solar energy manufacturing, distribution, installation, and financing efforts which will enhance this state’s position as the leader in solar energy research, development, and use.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Undertaking other initiatives to advance the development and use of renewable energy resources in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In the exercise of its responsibilities under this paragraph, the department shall seek the assistance of the solar energy industry in this state and other interested parties and is authorized to enter into contracts, retain professional consulting services, and expend funds appropriated by the Legislature for such purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall promote energy conservation in all energy use sectors throughout the state and shall constitute the state agency primarily responsible for this function. The Department of Management Services, in consultation with the department, shall coordinate the energy conservation programs of all state agencies and review and comment on the energy conservation programs of all state agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall serve as the state clearinghouse for indexing and gathering all information related to energy programs in state universities, in private universities, in federal, state, and local government agencies, and in private industry and shall prepare and distribute such information in any manner necessary to inform and advise the citizens of the state of such programs and activities. This shall include developing and maintaining a current index and profile of all research activities, which shall be identified by energy area and may include a summary of the project, the amount and sources of funding, anticipated completion dates, or, in case of completed research, conclusions, recommendations, and applicability to state government and private sector functions. The department shall coordinate, promote, and respond to efforts by all sectors of the economy to seek financial support for energy activities. The department shall provide information to consumers regarding the anticipated energy-use and energy-saving characteristics of products and services in coordination with any federal, state, or local governmental agencies as may provide such information to consumers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall coordinate energy-related programs of state government, including, but not limited to, the programs provided in this section. To this end, the department shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide assistance to other state agencies, counties, municipalities, and regional planning agencies to further and promote their energy planning activities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require, in cooperation with the Department of Management Services, all state agencies to operate state-owned and state-leased buildings in accordance with energy conservation standards as adopted by the Department of Management Services. Every 3 months, the Department of Management Services shall furnish the department data on agencies’ energy consumption and emissions of greenhouse gases in a format prescribed by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote the development and use of renewable energy resources, energy efficiency technologies, and conservation measures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote the recovery of energy from wastes, including, but not limited to, the use of waste heat, the use of agricultural products as a source of energy, and recycling of manufactured products. Such promotion shall be conducted in conjunction with, and after consultation with, the Department of Environmental Protection and the Florida Public Service Commission where electrical generation or natural gas is involved, and any other relevant federal, state, or local governmental agency having responsibility for resource recovery programs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop, coordinate, and promote a comprehensive research plan for state programs. Such plan shall be consistent with state energy policy and shall be updated on a biennial basis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In recognition of the devastation to the economy of this state and the dangers to the health and welfare of residents of this state caused by severe hurricanes, and the potential for such impacts caused by other natural disasters, the Division of Emergency Management shall include in its energy emergency contingency plan and provide to the Florida Building Commission for inclusion in the Florida Energy Efficiency Code for Building Construction specific provisions to facilitate the use of cost-effective solar energy technologies as emergency remedial and preventive measures for providing electric power, street lighting, and water heating service in the event of electric power outages.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On an annual basis, the department shall prepare an assessment of the utilization of the tax exemption authorized in s. 212.08(7)(hhh), the renewable energy technologies investment tax credit authorized in s. 220.192, and the renewable energy production credit authorized in s. 220.193, which the department shall submit to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Executive Office of the Governor by February 1 of each year. The assessment shall include, at a minimum, the following information:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the tax exemption authorized in s. 212.08(7)(hhh):</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each taxpayer receiving an exemption under this section;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the exemption received by each taxpayer; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type and description of each eligible item for which each taxpayer is applying.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the renewable energy technologies investment tax credit authorized in s. 220.192:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each taxpayer receiving an allocation under this section;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the credits allocated for that fiscal year for each taxpayer; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of technology and a description of each investment for which each taxpayer receives an allocation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the renewable energy production credit authorized in s. 220.193:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each taxpayer receiving an allocation under this section;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of credits allocated for that fiscal year for each taxpayer;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type and amount of renewable energy produced and sold, whether the facility producing that energy is a new or expanded facility, and the approximate date on which production began; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The aggregate amount of credits allocated for all taxpayers claiming credits under this section for the fiscal year.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection is responsible for the administration of the Coastal Energy Impact Program provided for and described in Pub. L. No. 94-370, 16 U.S.C. s. 1456a.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 75-256; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 78-25; s. 127, ch. 79-190; s. 1, ch. 80-167; s. 33, ch. 81-167; s. 32, ch. 81-169; s. 33, ch. 83-55; s. 12, ch. 91-113; s. 299, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 1, ch. 93-249; s. 24, ch. 94-321; s. 314, ch. 94-356; s. 39, ch. 95-196; s. 7, ch. 95-328; s. 89, ch. 98-200; s. 183, ch. 99-13; s. 13, ch. 2001-62; s. 15, ch. 2004-243; s. 3, ch. 2006-100; s. 55, ch. 2008-227; s. 513, ch. 2011-142; s. 58, ch. 2012-96; s. 12, ch. 2012-117.</History>
</Section>