<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0377.6015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services; powers and duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ staff and counsel as needed in the performance of its duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prosecute and defend legal actions in its own name.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Form advisory groups consisting of members of the public to provide information on specific issues.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer the Florida Renewable Energy and Energy-Efficient Technologies Grants Program pursuant to s. 377.804 to assure a robust grant portfolio.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop policy for requiring grantees to provide royalty-sharing or licensing agreements with state government for commercialized products developed under a state grant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer the Florida Green Government Grants Act pursuant to s. 377.808 and set annual priorities for grants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer the information gathering and reporting functions pursuant to ss. 377.601-377.608.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Represent Florida in the Southern States Energy Compact pursuant to ss. 377.71-377.712.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer the provisions of the Florida Energy and Climate Protection Act pursuant to ss. 377.801-377.807.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advocate for energy and climate change issues and provide educational outreach and technical assistance in cooperation with the state’s academic institutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a party in the proceedings to adopt goals and submit comments to the Public Service Commission pursuant to s. 366.82.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to chapter 120 in order to implement all powers and duties described in this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 46, ch. 2008-227; s. 54, ch. 2009-82; s. 10, ch. 2011-3; s. 505, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>