<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0377.806" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Solar Energy System Incentives Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />The Solar Energy System Incentives Program is established within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services to provide financial incentives for the purchase and installation of solar energy systems. Any resident of the state who purchases and installs a new solar energy system of 2 kilowatts or larger for a solar photovoltaic system, a solar energy system that provides at least 50 percent of a building’s hot water consumption for a solar thermal system, or a solar thermal pool heater, from July 1, 2006, through June 30, 2010, is eligible for a rebate on a portion of the purchase price of that solar energy system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SOLAR PHOTOVOLTAIC SYSTEM INCENTIVE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Eligibility requirements.</Font><EmDash />A solar photovoltaic system qualifies for a rebate if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The system is installed by a state-licensed master electrician, electrical contractor, or solar contractor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The system complies with state interconnection standards as provided by the Florida Public Service Commission.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The system complies with all applicable building codes as defined by the Florida Building Code.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Rebate amounts.</Font><EmDash />The rebate amount shall be set at $4 per watt based on the total wattage rating of the system. The maximum allowable rebate per solar photovoltaic system installation shall be as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty thousand dollars for a residence.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred thousand dollars for a place of business, a publicly owned or operated facility, or a facility owned or operated by a private, not-for-profit organization, including condominiums or apartment buildings.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SOLAR THERMAL SYSTEM INCENTIVE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Eligibility requirements.</Font><EmDash />A solar thermal system qualifies for a rebate if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Reference Number="1" />
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The system is installed by a state-licensed solar or plumbing contractor or a roofing contractor installing standing seam hybrid thermal roofs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The system complies with all applicable building codes as defined by the Florida Building Code.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Rebate amounts.</Font><EmDash />Authorized rebates for installation of solar thermal systems shall be as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five hundred dollars for a residence.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifteen dollars per 1,000 Btu up to a maximum of $5,000 for a place of business, a publicly owned or operated facility, or a facility owned or operated by a private, not-for-profit organization, including condominiums or apartment buildings.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SOLAR THERMAL POOL HEATER INCENTIVE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Eligibility requirements.</Font><EmDash />A solar thermal pool heater qualifies for a rebate if the system is installed by a state-licensed solar or plumbing contractor and the system complies with all applicable building codes as defined by the Florida Building Code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Rebate amount.</Font><EmDash />Authorized rebates for installation of solar thermal pool heaters shall be $100 per installation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION.<EmDash />Application for a rebate must be made within 120 days after the purchase of the solar energy equipment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REBATE AVAILABILITY.<EmDash />The department shall determine and publish on a regular basis the amount of rebate funds remaining in each fiscal year. The total dollar amount of all rebates issued is subject to the total amount of appropriations in any fiscal year for this program. If funds are insufficient during the current fiscal year, any requests for rebates received during that fiscal year may be processed during the following fiscal year. Requests for rebates received in a fiscal year that are processed during the following fiscal year shall be given priority over requests for rebates received during the following fiscal year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash />The department shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to develop rebate applications and administer the issuance of rebates.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2006-230; s. 3, ch. 2008-191; s. 61, ch. 2008-227; s. 518, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 3, ch. 2008-191. Subparagraph (3)(a)1. was also amended by s. 61, ch. 2008-227, and that version reads:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. The system is installed by a state-licensed solar or plumbing contractor, or for the installation of standing seam hybrid thermal roofs, a roofing contractor.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>