<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0377.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction of division.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall have jurisdiction and authority over all persons and property necessary to administer and enforce effectively the provisions of this law and all other laws relating to the conservation of oil and gas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall have authority, and it shall be its duty, to make such inquiries as it may deem proper to determine whether waste, over which it has jurisdiction, exists or is imminent. In the exercise of such power, the division shall have the authority to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect data.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make investigations and inspections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Examine properties, leases, papers, books, and records and to examine, survey, check, test, and gauge oil and gas wells, tanks, storage tanks, treatment plants and facilities, and modes of transportation used to gather and process crude oil or gas and products derived from wells within the state, prior to delivery to a common carrier.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold hearings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the keeping of records and the making of reports.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take such action as may be reasonably necessary to enforce this law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of the division shall extend to the state boundaries as set forth in s. 1, Art. II of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 22819, 1945; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-394; s. 1, ch. 76-188.</History></Section>