<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0377.701" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petroleum allocation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Emergency Management shall assume the state’s role in petroleum allocation and conservation, including the development of a fair and equitable petroleum plan. The Division of Emergency Management shall constitute the responsible state agency for performing the functions of any federal program delegated to the state, which relates to petroleum supply, demand, and allocation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Emergency Management shall, in addition to assuming the duties and responsibilities provided by subsection (1), perform the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In projecting available supplies of petroleum, coordinate with the Department of Revenue to secure information necessary to assure the sufficiency and accuracy of data submitted by persons affected by any federal fuel allocation program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require such periodic reports from public and private sources as may be necessary to the fulfillment of its responsibilities under this act. Such reports may include: petroleum use; all sales, including end-user sales, except retail gasoline and retail fuel oil sales; inventories; expected supplies and allocations; and petroleum conservation measures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with the Department of Revenue and other relevant state agencies, provide for long-range studies regarding the usage of petroleum in the state in order to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comprehend the consumption of petroleum resources.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Predict future petroleum demands in relation to available resources.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report the results of such studies to the Legislature.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of determining accuracy of data, all state agencies shall timely provide the Division of Emergency Management with petroleum-use information in a format suitable to the needs of the allocation program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state employee may not divulge or make known in any manner any proprietary information acquired under this act if the disclosure of such information would be likely to cause substantial harm to the competitive position of the person providing such information and if the person requests that such information be held confidential, except in accordance with a court order or in the publication of statistical information compiled by methods which do not disclose the identity of individual suppliers or companies. Such proprietary information is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1). Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent inspection of reports by the Attorney General, members of the Legislature, and interested state agencies; however, such agencies and their employees and members are bound by the requirements set forth in this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully fails to submit information required by this act or submits false information or who violates any provision of this act commits a misdemeanor of the first degree and shall be punished as provided in ss. 775.082 and 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 74-189; s. 2, ch. 75-256; s. 126, ch. 79-190; s. 31, ch. 81-169; s. 11, ch. 89-117; s. 113, ch. 90-360; s. 11, ch. 91-113; s. 180, ch. 96-406; s. 14, ch. 2004-243; s. 54, ch. 2008-227; s. 512, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>