<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0377.803" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 377.801-377.807, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Act” means the Florida Energy and Climate Protection Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual, partnership, joint venture, private or public corporation, association, firm, public service company, or any other public or private entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Renewable energy” means electrical, mechanical, or thermal energy produced from a method that uses one or more of the following fuels or energy sources: hydrogen, biomass, as defined in s. 366.91, solar energy, geothermal energy, wind energy, ocean energy, waste heat, or hydroelectric power.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Renewable energy technology” means any technology that generates or utilizes a renewable energy resource.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Solar energy system” means equipment that provides for the collection and use of incident solar energy for water heating, space heating or cooling, or other applications that would normally require a conventional source of energy such as petroleum products, natural gas, or electricity that performs primarily with solar energy. In other systems in which solar energy is used in a supplemental way, only those components that collect and transfer solar energy shall be included in this definition.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Solar photovoltaic system” means a device that converts incident sunlight into electrical current.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Solar thermal system” means a device that traps heat from incident sunlight in order to heat water.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2006-230; s. 59, ch. 2008-227; s. 516, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>