<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0377.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this law or any rule, regulation, or order of the division made under this chapter or who violates the terms of any permit to drill for or produce oil, gas, or other petroleum products referred to in s. 377.242(1), or any lessee, permitholder, or operator of equipment or facilities used in the exploration for, drilling for, or production of oil, gas, or other petroleum products who refuses inspection by the division as provided in this chapter, is liable to the state for any damage caused to the air, waters, or property, including animal, plant, or aquatic life, of the state and for reasonable costs and expenses of the state in tracing the source of the discharge, in controlling and abating the source and the pollutants, and in restoring the air, waters, and property, including animal, plant, and aquatic life, of the state. Furthermore, such person, lessee, permitholder, or operator is subject to the judicial imposition of a civil penalty in an amount of not more than $10,000 for each offense. However, the court may receive evidence in mitigation. Each day during any portion of which such violation occurs constitutes a separate offense. Nothing herein shall give the department the right to bring an action on behalf of any private person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever two or more persons pollute the air or waters of the state in violation of this chapter or any rule, regulation, or order of the department in such a manner that the damage is indivisible, each violator is jointly and severally liable for such damage and for the reasonable cost and expenses of the state incurred in tracing the source of the discharge; in controlling and abating the source and the pollutants; and in restoring the air, waters, and property, including the animal, plant, and aquatic life, of the state to their former condition. However, if the damage is divisible and may be attributed to a particular violator or violators, each violator is liable only for that damage attributable to his or her violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment of any damages or penalties as provided for herein shall not have the effect of changing illegal product into legal product, illegal oil into legal oil, or illegal gas into legal gas; nor shall such payment have the effect of authorizing the sale, purchase, acquisition, transportation, refining, processing, or handling in any other way of such illegal oil, illegal gas, or illegal product.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment of any such damages or penalties shall not impair or abridge any cause of action which any person may have against the person violating any provision of this law or any rule, regulation, or order for an injury resulting to him or her from such violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person knowingly and willfully aiding or abetting any other person in the violation of any statute of this state relating to the conservation of oil or gas or the violation of any provision of this law, or any rule, regulation, or order made hereunder shall be subject to the same damages as are prescribed herein for the violation by such other person.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 22819, 1945; ss. 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 7, ch. 72-394; s. 3, ch. 83-176; s. 628, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>