<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0377.712" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida participation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall appoint one member of the Southern States Energy Board. The member or the Governor may designate another person as the deputy or assistant to such member.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The President of the Senate shall appoint one member of the Southern States Energy Board. The member or the president may designate another person as the assistant or deputy to such member.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Speaker of the House of Representatives shall appoint one member of the Southern States Energy Board. The member or the speaker may designate another person as the assistant or deputy to such member.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any supplementary agreement entered into under s. 377.711(6) requiring the expenditure of funds shall not become effective as to Florida until the required funds are appropriated by the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Departments, agencies, and officers of this state, and its subdivisions are authorized to cooperate with the board in the furtherance of any of its activities pursuant to the compact, provided such proposed activities have been made known to, and have the approval of, either the Governor or the Department of Health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 61-227; s. 5, ch. 63-474; s. 22, ch. 65-420; ss. 17, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 78-373; s. 3, ch. 79-348; s. 65, ch. 95-143; s. 635, ch. 95-148; s. 70, ch. 99-8; s. 20, ch. 2011-213.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 290.32.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>