<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0351.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Railroad-highway grade-crossing warning signs and signals; audible warnings; exercise of reasonable care; blocking highways, roads, and streets during darkness.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every railroad company shall exercise reasonable care for the safety of motorists whenever its track crosses a highway and shall be responsible for erecting and maintaining crossbuck grade-crossing warning signs in accordance with the uniform system of traffic control devices adopted pursuant to s. 316.0745. Such crossbuck signs shall be erected and maintained at all public or private railroad-highway grade crossings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advance railroad warning signs and pavement markings shall be installed and maintained at public railroad-highway grade crossings in accordance with the uniform system of traffic control devices by the governmental entity having jurisdiction over or maintenance responsibility for the highway or street. All persons approaching a railroad-highway grade crossing shall exercise reasonable care for their own safety and for the safety of railroad train crews as well as for the safety of train or vehicle passengers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (4), any railroad train approaching within 1,500 feet of a public railroad-highway grade crossing shall emit a signal audible for such distance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation and the Federal Railroad Administration may authorize a municipality or county to implement a whistle ban provided the following conditions are met:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A traffic operations system is implemented to secure railroad-highway grade crossings for the purpose of preventing vehicles from going around, under, or through lowered railroad gates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The municipality or county has in effect an ordinance that unconditionally prohibits the sounding of railroad train horns and whistles during the hours of 10 p.m. and 6 a.m. at all public railroad-highway grade crossings within the municipality or county and where the municipality, county, or state has erected signs at the crossing announcing that railroad train horns and whistles may not be sounded during such hours. Signs so erected shall be in conformance with the uniform system of traffic control devices as specified in s. 316.0745.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon final approval and verification by the department and the Federal Railroad Administration that such traffic operations system meets all state and federal safety and traffic regulations and that such railroad-highway grade crossings can be secured, the municipality or county may pass an ordinance prohibiting the sounding of audible warning devices by trains upon approaching such railroad-highway grade crossings between the hours of 10 p.m. and 6 a.m.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to nullify the liability provisions of s. 768.28.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a railroad train engages in a switching operation or stops so as to block a public highway, street, or road at any time from one-half hour after sunset to one-half hour before sunrise, the crew of the railroad train shall cause to be placed a lighted fusee or other visual warning device in both directions from the railroad train upon or at the edge of the pavement of the highway, street, or road to warn approaching motorists of the railroad train blocking the highway, street, or road. However, this subsection does not apply to railroad-highway grade crossings at which there are automatic warning devices properly functioning or at which there is adequate lighting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates any provision of paragraph (a) is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 1987, 1874; RS 2264; GS 2841; ch. 7940, 1919; RGS 4529; CGL 6592; s. 1, ch. 73-336; s. 52, ch. 76-31; s. 5, ch. 80-289; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 12, 14, ch. 82-90; s. 1, ch. 84-73; s. 39, ch. 86-243; ss. 2, 5, 6, ch. 92-192; s. 143, ch. 99-13.</History></Section>