<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0050.0711" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court docket fund; service charges; publications.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the court in each county may establish a court docket fund for the purpose of paying the cost of publication of the fact of the filing of any civil case in the circuit court of the county by the style and of the calendar relating to such cases. This court docket fund shall be funded by $1 mandatory court cost for all civil actions, suits, or proceedings filed in the circuit court of the county. The clerk shall maintain such funds separate and apart, and the proceeds from this court cost shall not be diverted to any other fund or for any purpose other than that established in this section. The clerk of the court shall dispense the fund to the designated record newspaper in the county on a quarterly basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A newspaper qualified under the terms of s. 50.011 shall be designated as the record newspaper for such publication by an order of the majority of the judges in the judicial circuit in which such county is located, and such order shall be filed and recorded with the clerk of the circuit court for such county. The designated record newspaper may be changed at the end of any fiscal year of the county by a majority vote of the judges of the judicial circuit of the county ordering such change 30 days prior to the end of the fiscal year, notice of which order shall be given to the previously designated record newspaper.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The publishers of any designated record newspapers receiving payment from this court docket fund shall publish, without additional charge, the fact of the filing of any civil case, suit, or action filed in such county in the circuit. Such publication shall be in accordance with a schedule agreed upon between the record newspaper and the clerk of the court in such county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The publishers of any designated record newspapers receiving revenues from the court docket fund established in subsection (1) shall, without charge, accept legal advertisements for the purpose of service of process by publication under s. 49.011(4), (10), and (11) when such publication is required of persons authorized to proceed as indigent persons under s. 57.081.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 46, ch. 2004-265.</History></Section>