<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0050.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proof of publication; uniform affidavits required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All affidavits of publishers of newspapers (or their official representatives) made for the purpose of establishing proof of publication of public notices or legal advertisements shall be uniform throughout the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each such affidavit shall be printed upon white paper and shall be 8<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> inches in width and of convenient length, not less than 5<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> inches. A white margin of not less than 2<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> inches shall be left at the right side of each affidavit form and upon or in this space shall be substantially pasted a clipping which shall be a true copy of the public notice or legal advertisement for which proof is executed. Alternatively, the affidavit may be provided in electronic rather than paper form, provided the notarization of the affidavit complies with the requirements of s. 117.021.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all counties having a population in excess of 450,000 according to the latest official decennial census, in addition to the charges which are now or may hereafter be established by law for the publication of every official notice or legal advertisement, there may be a charge not to exceed $2 for the preparation and execution of each such proof of publication or publisher’s affidavit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 19290, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4668(1); s. 1, ch. 63-49; s. 26, ch. 67-254; s. 1, ch. 76-58; s. 2, ch. 2012-212.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-212, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect July 1, 2012, and shall apply to legal notices that must be published on or after that date.”</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 49.04.</Text></Note></Section>