<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0050.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amounts chargeable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The publisher of any newspaper publishing any and all official public notices or legal advertisements shall charge therefor the rates specified in this section without rebate, commission or refund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The charge for publishing each such official public notice or legal advertisement shall be 70 cents per square inch for the first insertion and 40 cents per square inch for each subsequent insertion, except that government notices required to be published more than once whose cost is paid for by the government and not paid in advance by or allowed to be recouped from private parties may not be charged for the second and successive insertions at a rate greater than 85 percent of the original rate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the regular established minimum commercial rate per square inch of the newspaper publishing such official public notices or legal advertisements is in excess of the rate herein stipulated, said minimum commercial rate per square inch may be charged for all such legal advertisements or official public notices for each insertion, except that government notices required to be published more than once whose cost is paid for by the government and not paid in advance by or allowed to be recouped from private parties may not be charged for the second and successive insertions at a rate greater than 85 percent of the original rate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A governmental agency publishing an official public notice or legal advertisement may procure publication by soliciting and accepting written bids from newspapers published in the county, in which case the specified charges in this section do not apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the public notice is published in a newspaper, the posting of the notice on the newspaper’s website pursuant to s. 50.0211(2) must be done at no additional charge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All official public notices and legal advertisements shall be charged and paid for on the basis of 6-point type on 6-point body, unless otherwise specified by statute.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person violating this section, either by allowing or accepting any rebate, commission, or refund, commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to charge the rates prescribed by this section shall in no way affect the validity of any official public notice or legal advertisement and shall not subject same to legal attack upon such grounds.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 3022, 1877; RS 1298; GS 1729; RGS 2944; s. 1, ch. 12215, 1927; CGL 4668; ss. 1, 2, 2A, 2B, ch. 20264, 1941; s. 1, ch. 23663, 1947; s. 1, ch. 57-160; s. 1, ch. 63-50; s. 1, ch. 65-569; s. 6, ch. 67-254; s. 15, ch. 71-136; s. 35, ch. 73-332; s. 1, ch. 90-279; s. 3, ch. 2012-212.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-212, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect July 1, 2012, and shall apply to legal notices that must be published on or after that date.”</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 49.06.</Text></Note></Section>