<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0050.0211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Internet website publication.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to legal notices that must be published in accordance with this chapter unless otherwise specified.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each legal notice must be placed on the newspaper’s website on the same day the notice appears in the newspaper, at no additional charge. A link to legal notices shall be provided on the front page of the newspaper’s website that provides access to the legal notices without charge. If there is a specified size and placement required for a printed legal notice, the size and placement of the notice on the newspaper’s website should optimize its online visibility in keeping with the print requirements. The newspaper’s web pages that contain legal notices shall present the legal notices as the dominant subject matter of those pages. The newspaper’s website shall contain a search function to facilitate searching the legal notices. This subsection shall take effect July 1, 2013.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a legal notice is published in a newspaper, the newspaper publishing the notice shall place the notice on the website established and maintained as an initiative of the Florida Press Association as a repository for such notices located at the following address: www.floridapublicnotices.com.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Newspapers that publish legal notices shall, upon request, provide e-mail notification of new legal notices when they are printed in the newspaper and added to the newspaper’s website. Such e-mail notification shall be provided without charge, and notification for such an e-mail registry shall be available on the front page of the legal notices section of the newspaper’s website. This subsection shall take effect July 1, 2013.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An error in the notice placed on the newspaper or statewide website shall be considered a harmless error and proper legal notice requirements shall be considered met if the notice published in the newspaper is correct.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2012-212.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-212, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect July 1, 2012, and shall apply to legal notices that must be published on or after that date.”</Text></Note></Section>