<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0457.116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice acupuncture unless the person is licensed under ss. 457.101-457.118;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use, in connection with his or her name or place of business, any title or description of services which incorporates the words “acupuncture,” “acupuncturist,” “certified acupuncturist,” “licensed acupuncturist,” “oriental medical practitioner”; the letters “L.Ac.,” “R.Ac.,” “A.P.,” or “D.O.M.”; or any other words, letters, abbreviations, or insignia indicating or implying that he or she practices acupuncture unless he or she is a holder of a valid license issued pursuant to ss. 457.101-457.118;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as his or her own the license of another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly give false or forged evidence to the board or a member thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a license that has been suspended, revoked, or placed on inactive or delinquent status;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ any person who is not licensed pursuant to ss. 457.101-457.118 to engage in the practice of acupuncture; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conceal information relating to any violation of ss. 457.101-457.118.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-375; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 13, 14, ch. 86-265; s. 57, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-156; s. 85, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 198, ch. 97-103; s. 13, ch. 97-264; s. 5, ch. 98-418.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 468.328.</Text></Note></Section>