<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0457.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Acupuncture” means a form of primary health care, based on traditional Chinese medical concepts and modern oriental medical techniques, that employs acupuncture diagnosis and treatment, as well as adjunctive therapies and diagnostic techniques, for the promotion, maintenance, and restoration of health and the prevention of disease. Acupuncture shall include, but not be limited to, the insertion of acupuncture needles and the application of moxibustion to specific areas of the human body and the use of electroacupuncture, Qi Gong, oriental massage, herbal therapy, dietary guidelines, and other adjunctive therapies, as defined by board rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Acupuncturist” means any person licensed as provided in this chapter to practice acupuncture as a primary health care provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Acupuncture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means the document of authorization issued by the department for a person to engage in the practice of acupuncture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Oriental medicine” means the use of acupuncture, electroacupuncture, Qi Gong, oriental massage, herbal therapy, dietary guidelines, and other adjunctive therapies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prescriptive rights” means the prescription, administration, and use of needles and devices, restricted devices, and prescription devices that are used in the practice of acupuncture and oriental medicine.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-375; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 38, ch. 83-329; ss. 2, 13, 14, ch. 86-265; s. 57, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 101, ch. 94-218; s. 6, ch. 97-264; s. 1, ch. 98-418; s. 90, ch. 99-397; s. 62, ch. 2000-318.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 468.322.</Text></Note></Section>