<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0457.107" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Renewal of licenses; continuing education.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall renew a license upon receipt of the renewal application and the required fee set by the board by rule, not to exceed $500.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing a procedure for the biennial renewal of licenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall by rule prescribe continuing education requirements, not to exceed 30 hours biennially, as a condition for renewal of a license. All education programs that contribute to the advancement, extension, or enhancement of professional skills and knowledge related to the practice of acupuncture, whether conducted by a nonprofit or profitmaking entity, are eligible for approval. The continuing professional education requirements must be in acupuncture or oriental medicine subjects, including, but not limited to, anatomy, biological sciences, adjunctive therapies, sanitation and sterilization, emergency protocols, and diseases. The board shall have the authority to set a fee, not to exceed $100, for each continuing education provider. The licensee shall retain in his or her records the certificates of completion of continuing professional education requirements to prove compliance with this subsection. The board may request such documentation without cause from applicants who are selected at random. All national and state acupuncture and oriental medicine organizations and acupuncture and oriental medicine schools are approved to provide continuing professional education in accordance with this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-375; ss. 2, 6, ch. 81-227; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 42, ch. 83-329; ss. 6, 13, 14, ch. 86-265; s. 3, ch. 88-205; s. 17, ch. 89-162; s. 57, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 161, ch. 94-119; s. 9, ch. 97-264; s. 4, ch. 98-418; s. 64, ch. 2000-318; s. 7, ch. 2001-277.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 468.324.</Text></Note></Section>