<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0092.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Videotaping of testimony of victim or witness under age 16 or person with mental retardation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On motion and hearing in camera and a finding that there is a substantial likelihood that a victim or witness who is under the age of 16 or who is a person with mental retardation as defined in s. 393.063 would suffer at least moderate emotional or mental harm due to the presence of the defendant if the child or person with mental retardation is required to testify in open court, or that such victim or witness is otherwise unavailable as defined in s. 90.804(1), the trial court may order the videotaping of the testimony of the victim or witness in a case, whether civil or criminal in nature, in which videotaped testimony is to be utilized at trial in lieu of trial testimony in open court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The motion may be filed by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The victim or witness, or the victim’s or witness’s attorney, parent, legal guardian, or guardian ad litem;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trial judge on his or her own motion;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any party in a civil proceeding; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prosecuting attorney or the defendant, or the defendant’s counsel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judge shall preside, or shall appoint a special master to preside, at the videotaping unless the following conditions are met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child or person with mental retardation is represented by a guardian ad litem or counsel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The representative of the victim or witness and the counsel for each party stipulate that the requirement for the presence of the judge or special master may be waived; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court finds at a hearing on the motion that the presence of a judge or special master is not necessary to protect the victim or witness.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant and the defendant’s counsel shall be present at the videotaping, unless the defendant has waived this right. The court may require the defendant to view the testimony from outside the presence of the child or person with mental retardation by means of a two-way mirror or another similar method that will ensure that the defendant can observe and hear the testimony of the victim or witness in person, but that the victim or witness cannot hear or see the defendant. The defendant and the attorney for the defendant may communicate by any appropriate private method.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any party, or the court on its own motion, may request the aid of an interpreter, as provided in s. 90.606, to aid the parties in formulating methods of questioning the child or person with mental retardation and in interpreting the answers of the child or person with mental retardation throughout proceedings conducted under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The motion referred to in subsection (1) may be made at any time with reasonable notice to each party to the cause, and videotaping of testimony may be made any time after the court grants the motion. The videotaped testimony shall be admissible as evidence in the trial of the cause; however, such testimony shall not be admissible in any trial or proceeding in which such witness testifies by use of closed circuit television pursuant to s. 92.54.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall make specific findings of fact, on the record, as to the basis for its ruling under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-69; s. 1, ch. 84-36; ss. 5, 9, ch. 85-53; s. 9, ch. 85-80; s. 1, ch. 93-131; s. 21, ch. 94-154; s. 1379, ch. 95-147; s. 30, ch. 99-2; s. 4, ch. 2000-338; s. 89, ch. 2004-267.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 918.17, 90.90.</Text></Note></Section>