<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0092.525" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Verification of documents; perjury by false written declaration, penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When it is authorized or required by law, by rule of an administrative agency, or by rule or order of court that a document be verified by a person, the verification may be accomplished in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under oath or affirmation taken or administered before an officer authorized under s. 92.50 to administer oaths; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the signing of the written declaration prescribed in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written declaration means the following statement: “Under penalties of perjury, I declare that I have read the foregoing [document] and that the facts stated in it are true,” followed by the signature of the person making the declaration, except when a verification on information or belief is permitted by law, in which case the words “to the best of my knowledge and belief” may be added. The written declaration shall be printed or typed at the end of or immediately below the document being verified and above the signature of the person making the declaration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly makes a false declaration under subsection (2) is guilty of the crime of perjury by false written declaration, a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “administrative agency” means any department or agency of the state or any county, municipality, special district, or other political subdivision.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “document” means any writing including, without limitation, any form, application, claim, notice, tax return, inventory, affidavit, pleading, or paper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirement that a document be verified means that the document must be signed or executed by a person and that the person must state under oath or affirm that the facts or matters stated or recited in the document are true, or words of that import or effect.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 86-201.</History></Section>