<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0092.153" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Production of documents by witnesses; reimbursement of costs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Disinterested witness” means a person to whom a summons is issued with respect to documents involving or relating to transactions of others and who has not initiated a proceeding, is not a party to a proceeding, and is not the subject of investigation in a proceeding and who, at the time the summons is issued, is not an officer, employee, accountant, or attorney, or acting as such, for a person who has initiated, is a party to, or is the subject of investigation in a proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Document” means any book, paper, record, or other data, or a reproduction thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proceeding” means any civil or criminal action before a court; any investigation, inquiry, or proceeding before a grand jury, a state attorney, or a state, county, municipal, or other governmental department, division, bureau, commission or other body, or any officer thereof; any action before an officer or person authorized to issue a summons; or any administrative action authorized by law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Summons” means any subpoena, subpoena duces tecum, order, or other legal process which requires the production of documents.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REIMBURSEMENT OF A DISINTERESTED WITNESS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any proceeding, a disinterested witness shall be paid for any costs the witness reasonably incurs either directly or indirectly in producing, searching for, reproducing, or transporting documents pursuant to a summons; however, the cost of documents produced pursuant to a subpoena or records request by a state attorney or public defender may not exceed 15 cents per page and $10 per hour for research or retrieval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding before a court or an administrative agency or officer, which is not an investigation or inquiry and which by law or rule includes the right to a public trial or hearing in the same proceeding and which involves adversary parties, responsibility for payment to the disinterested witness shall be fixed by the court, agency, or officer before which the proceeding is pending. Payment shall be enforced by the court, agency, or officer upon motion by the disinterested witness.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all other proceedings, payment to the disinterested witness shall be made by the person or governmental authority requesting the summons. Any disinterested witness who desires reimbursement of such costs shall submit a request for reimbursement, supported by an affidavit, to the person or governmental authority responsible for payment. Payment shall be made within 30 days from the date the request is submitted. If payment is not made within such time, the witness may enforce payment by bringing a separate action in a court which has jurisdiction of the total amount of such costs and which is located in the judicial circuit where the witness resides.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 81-196; s. 508, ch. 95-147; s. 77, ch. 2003-402.</History></Section>