<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0092.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Foreign records of regularly conducted business activity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign record of regularly conducted business activity” means a memorandum, report, record, or data compilation, in any form, of acts, events, conditions, opinions, or diagnoses, maintained in a foreign country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign certification” means a written declaration made and signed in a foreign country by the custodian of a foreign record of regularly conducted business activity or another qualified person that, if falsely made, would subject the maker to criminal penalty under the laws of that country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Business” means any business, institution, association, profession, occupation, or calling of any kind, whether or not conducted for profit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a criminal or civil proceeding in a court of the State of Florida, a foreign record of regularly conducted business activity, or a copy of such record, shall not be excluded as evidence by the hearsay rule if a foreign certification attests that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such record was made at or near the time of the occurrence of the matters set forth by, or from information transmitted by, a person with knowledge of those matters;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such record was kept in the course of a regularly conducted business activity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business activity made such a record as a regular practice; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such record is not the original, it is a duplicate of the original;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">unless the source of information or the method or circumstances of preparation indicate lack of trustworthiness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign certification under this section shall authenticate such record or duplicate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No evidence in such records in the form of opinion or diagnosis is admissible under subsection (2) unless such opinion or diagnosis would be admissible under ss. 90.701-90.705 if the person whose opinion is recorded were to testify to the opinion directly.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the arraignment or as soon after the arraignment as practicable, or 60 days prior to a civil trial, a party intending to offer in evidence under this section a foreign record of regularly conducted business activity shall provide written notice of that intention to each other party. A motion opposing admission in evidence of such record shall be made by the opposing party and determined by the court before trial. Failure by a party to file such motion before trial shall constitute a waiver of objection to such record or duplicate, but the court for cause shown may grant relief from the waiver.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 88-381; s. 1, ch. 97-189.</History></Section>