<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0092.51" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Oaths, affidavits, and acknowledgments; taken or administered by commissioned officer of United States Armed Forces.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Oaths, affidavits, and acknowledgments required or authorized by the laws of this state may be taken or administered within or without the United States by or before any commissioned officer in active service of the Armed Forces of the United States with the rank of second lieutenant or higher in the Army, Air Force or Marine Corps or ensign or higher in the Navy or Coast Guard when the person required or authorized to make and execute the oath, affidavit, or acknowledgment is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, the spouse of such member or a person whose duties require the person’s presence with the Armed Forces of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate endorsed upon the instrument which shows the date of the oath, affidavit, or acknowledgment and which states in substance that the person appearing before the officer acknowledged the instrument as the person’s act or made or signed the instrument under oath shall be sufficient for all intents and purposes. The instrument shall not be rendered invalid by the failure to state the place of execution or acknowledgment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the signature, rank, and branch of service or subdivision thereof of any commissioned officer appears upon such instrument, document or certificate no further proof of the authority of such officer so to act shall be required and such action by such commissioned officer shall be prima facie evidence that the person making such oath, affidavit or acknowledgment is within the purview of this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 61-196; s. 3, ch. 76-237; s. 1, ch. 77-77; s. 22, ch. 78-361; s. 1, ch. 78-379; s. 518, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 90.011.</Text></Note></Section>