<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Dentistry.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To carry out the provisions of this chapter, there is created within the department the Board of Dentistry consisting of 11 members who shall be appointed by the Governor and subject to confirmation by the Senate. Seven members of the board must be licensed dentists actively engaged in the clinical practice of dentistry in this state; two members must be licensed dental hygienists actively engaged in the practice of dental hygiene in this state; and the remaining two members must be laypersons who are not, and have never been, dentists, dental hygienists, or members of any closely related profession or occupation. Each member of the board who is a licensed dentist must have been actively engaged in the practice of dentistry primarily as a clinical practitioner for at least 5 years immediately preceding the date of her or his appointment to the board and must remain primarily in clinical practice during all subsequent periods of appointment to the board. Each member of the board who is connected in any way with any dental college or community college must be in compliance with s. 456.007. At least one member of the board must be 60 years of age or older. Members shall be appointed for 4-year terms, but may serve no more than a total of 10 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To advise the board, it is the intent of the Legislature that councils be appointed as specified in paragraphs (a), (b), and (c). The department shall provide administrative support to the councils and shall provide public notice of meetings and agenda of the councils. Councils shall include at least one board member who shall chair the council and shall include nonboard members. All council members shall be appointed by the board chair. Council members shall be appointed for 4-year terms, and all members shall be eligible for reimbursement of expenses in the manner of board members.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Council on Dental Hygiene shall be appointed by the board chair and shall include one dental hygienist member of the board, who shall chair the council, one dental member of the board, and three dental hygienists who are actively engaged in the practice of dental hygiene in this state. In making the appointments, the chair shall consider recommendations from the Florida Dental Hygiene Association. The council shall meet at the request of the board chair, a majority of the members of the board, or the council chair; however, the council must meet at least three times a year. The council is charged with the responsibility of and shall meet for the purpose of developing rules and policies for recommendation to the board, which the board shall consider, on matters pertaining to that part of dentistry consisting of educational, preventive, or therapeutic dental hygiene services; dental hygiene licensure, discipline, or regulation; and dental hygiene education. Rule and policy recommendations of the council shall be considered by the board at its next regularly scheduled meeting in the same manner in which it considers rule and policy recommendations from designated subcommittees of the board. Any rule or policy proposed by the board pertaining to the specified part of dentistry defined by this subsection shall be referred to the council for a recommendation before final action by the board. The board may take final action on rules pertaining to the specified part of dentistry defined by this subsection without a council recommendation if the council fails to submit a recommendation in a timely fashion as prescribed by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Council on Dental Assisting shall be appointed by the board chair and shall include one board member who shall chair the council and three dental assistants who are actively engaged in dental assisting. The council shall meet at the request of the board chair or a majority of the members of the board. The council shall meet for the purpose of developing recommendations to the board on matters pertaining to that part of dentistry related to dental assisting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the concurrence of the State Surgeon General, the board chair may create and abolish other advisory councils relating to dental subjects, including, but not limited to: examinations, access to dental care, indigent care, nursing home and institutional care, public health, disciplinary guidelines, and other subjects as appropriate. Such councils shall be appointed by the board chair and shall include at least one board member who shall serve as chair.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall maintain its headquarters in Tallahassee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board is authorized to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this chapter and chapter 456, including the establishment of a fee to defray the cost of duplicating any license certification or permit, not to exceed $10 per duplication.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board is authorized to publish and distribute such pamphlets, newsletters, and other publications as are reasonably necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All provisions of chapter 456 relating to the board shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 17, ch. 87-172; s. 47, ch. 90-228; s. 1, ch. 90-341; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 97, ch. 92-149; s. 127, ch. 94-218; s. 1, ch. 96-281; s. 1107, ch. 97-103; s. 69, ch. 98-166; s. 128, ch. 98-200; s. 55, ch. 99-5; s. 1, ch. 99-183; s. 1, ch. 2000-115; s. 128, ch. 2000-160; s. 2, ch. 2005-189; s. 55, ch. 2006-1; s. 85, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>