<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Persons exempt from operation of chapter.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this chapter shall apply to the following practices, acts, and operations:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of her or his profession including surgical procedures involving the oral cavity by a physician or surgeon licensed as such under the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified anesthetist giving an anesthetic for a dental operation under the direct supervision of a licensed dentist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of dentistry in the discharge of their official duties by graduate dentists or dental surgeons in the United States Army, Air Force, Marines, Navy, Public Health Service, Coast Guard, or United States Department of Veterans Affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of dentistry by licensed dentists of other states or countries at meetings of dental organizations approved by the board, while appearing as clinicians.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Students in Florida schools of dentistry and dental hygiene or dental assistant educational programs, while performing regularly assigned work under the curriculum of such schools.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instructors in Florida schools of dentistry, instructors in dental programs that prepare persons holding D.D.S. or D.M.D. degrees for certification by a specialty board and that are accredited in the United States by January 1, 2005, in the same manner as the board recognizes accreditation for Florida schools of dentistry that are not otherwise affiliated with a Florida school of dentistry, or instructors in Florida schools of dental hygiene or dental assistant educational programs, while performing regularly assigned instructional duties under the curriculum of such schools. A full-time dental instructor at a dental school or dental program approved by the board may be allowed to practice dentistry at the teaching facilities of such school or program, upon receiving a teaching permit issued by the board, in strict compliance with such rules as are adopted by the board pertaining to the teaching permit and with the established rules and procedures of the dental school or program as recognized in this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 22, ch. 93-268; s. 2, ch. 94-104; s. 250, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 2005-189.</History></Section>