<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0466.024">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delegation of duties; expanded functions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dentist may not delegate irremediable tasks to a dental hygienist or dental assistant, except as provided by law. A dentist may delegate remediable tasks to a dental hygienist or dental assistant when such tasks pose no risk to the patient. A dentist may only delegate remediable tasks so defined by law or rule of the board. The board by rule shall designate which tasks are remediable and delegable, except that the following are by law found to be remediable and delegable:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taking impressions for study casts but not for the purpose of fabricating any intraoral restorations or orthodontic appliance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing periodontal dressings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Removing periodontal or surgical dressings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Removing sutures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing or removing rubber dams.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing or removing matrices.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing or removing temporary restorations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applying cavity liners, varnishes, or bases.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Polishing amalgam restorations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Polishing clinical crowns of the teeth for the purpose of removing stains but not changing the existing contour of the tooth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining bacteriological cytological specimens not involving cutting of the tissue.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administering local anesthesia pursuant to s. 466.017(5).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion"> This subsection does not limit delegable tasks to those specified herein.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dental hygienist licensed in this state may perform the following remediable tasks in a health access setting as defined in s. 466.003 without the physical presence, prior examination, or authorization of a dentist:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform dental charting as defined in s. 466.0235 and as provided by rule.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Measure and record a patient’s blood pressure rate, pulse rate, respiration rate, and oral temperature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Record a patient’s case history.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply topical fluorides, including fluoride varnishes, which are approved by the American Dental Association or the Food and Drug Administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply dental sealants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remove calculus deposits, accretions, and stains from exposed surfaces of the teeth and from tooth surfaces within the gingival sulcus.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dentist licensed under this chapter or a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 must give medical clearance before a dental hygienist removes calculus deposits, accretions, and stains from exposed surfaces of the teeth or from tooth surfaces within the gingival sulcus.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dentist shall conduct a dental examination on a patient within 13 months after a dental hygienist removes the patient’s calculus deposits, accretions, and stains from exposed surfaces of the teeth or from tooth surfaces within the gingival sulcus. Additional oral hygiene services may not be performed under this paragraph without a clinical examination by a dentist who is licensed under this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This subsection does not authorize a dental hygienist to perform root planing or gingival curettage without supervision by a dentist.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all remediable tasks listed in subsection (2), the following disclaimer must be provided to the patient in writing before any procedure is performed:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services being offered are not a substitute for a comprehensive dental exam by a dentist.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The diagnosis of caries, soft tissue disease, oral cancer, temporomandibular joint disease (TMJ), and dentofacial malocclusions will be completed only by a dentist in the context of delivering a comprehensive dental exam.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prevent a program operated by one of the health access settings as defined in s. 466.003 or a nonprofit organization that is exempt from federal income taxation under s. 501(a) of the Internal Revenue Code and described in s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code from billing and obtaining reimbursement for the services described in this section which are provided by a dental hygienist or from making or maintaining any records pursuant to s. 456.057 necessary to obtain reimbursement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dental hygienist who performs, without supervision, the remediable tasks listed in subsection (2) shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a dental referral in strict compliance with federal and state patient referral, anti-kickback, and patient brokering laws.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage the establishment of a dental home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain professional malpractice insurance coverage that has minimum limits of $100,000 per occurrence and $300,000 in the aggregate through the employing health access setting or individual policy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1) or subsection (2), a dentist may delegate the tasks of gingival curettage and root planing to a dental hygienist but not to a dental assistant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other remediable tasks shall be performed under the direct, indirect, or general supervision of a dentist, as determined by rule of the board, and after such formal or on-the-job training by the dental hygienist or dental assistant as the board by rule may require. The board by rule may establish a certification process for expanded-duty dental assistants, establishing such training or experience criteria or examinations as it deems necessary and specifying which tasks may be delegable only to such assistants. If the board does establish such a certification process, the department shall implement the application process for such certification and administer any examinations required.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1) or subsection (2), a dentist may not delegate to anyone other than another licensed dentist:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any prescription of drugs or medications requiring the written order or prescription of a licensed dentist or physician.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any diagnosis for treatment or treatment planning.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a dentist is primarily responsible for all procedures delegated by her or him.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dental assistant may not perform an intraoral procedure except after such formal or on-the-job training as the board by rule shall prescribe.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 13, 15, 25, 28, 30, 34, 62, ch. 80-406; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 2, ch. 85-156; ss. 15, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 259, ch. 97-103; s. 7, ch. 2011-95; s. 5, ch. 2012-14.</History>
</Section>