<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.0275" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lawful investigations; consent handwriting samples; mental or physical examination.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every dentist who accepts a license to practice dentistry in this state shall, by so accepting the license or by making and filing a renewal of licensure to practice in this state, be deemed to have given consent, during a lawful investigation of a complaint to the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To render a handwriting sample to an agent of the department and, further, to have waived any objections to its use as evidence against her or him.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only in those circumstances where there is probable cause that the dentist is guilty of violations involving moral turpitude, impairment, violations of laws governing controlled substances, or any violation of criminal law, the dentist shall be deemed to waive the confidentiality and to execute a release of medical reports pertaining to the mental or physical condition of the dentist herself or himself. The department shall issue an order, based on the need for additional information, to produce such medical reports for the time period relevant to the investigation. As used in this section, “medical reports” means a compilation of medical treatment of the dentist herself or himself which includes symptoms, diagnosis, treatment prescribed, relevant history, and progress. The dentist shall also be deemed to waive any objection to the admissibility of the reports as constituting privileged communications. Such material maintained by the department shall remain confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) until probable cause is found and an administrative complaint issued.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 88-392; s. 1, ch. 89-296; ss. 60, 64, ch. 91-137; s. 23, ch. 91-140; ss. 7, 8, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 319, ch. 96-406; s. 1110, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>