<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retention of dental laboratories by dentist; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed dentist who uses the services of any dental laboratory for the purpose of constructing, altering, repairing, or duplicating any denture, implant, veneer, partial denture, bridge splint, orthodontic or other prosthetic appliance, or other suitable form of artificial oral restorative device shall be required to furnish the dental laboratory with a written prescription in a form prescribed by rule of the board. This prescription shall be dated and signed by the dentist and shall include the license number of the dentist, the patient’s name or number with sufficient descriptive information to clearly identify each separate and individual piece of work to be performed by the dental laboratory, and a specification of materials to be contained in each work product. A copy of the prescription shall be retained in a file in the prescribing dentist’s office for a period of 4 years following the date the prescription was issued, and the original prescription shall be retained in a file by the dental laboratory for a period of 4 years. A registered dental laboratory shall disclose in writing at the time of delivery of the final restoration to the prescribing dentist the materials and all certificates of authenticity that constitute each product manufactured and the point of origin of manufacture of each restoration, including the address and contact information of the dental laboratory. The file of prescriptions to be kept by the dentist and the dental laboratory shall be open to inspection at any reasonable time by the department or its constituted agent. Failure of the dentist to keep records of each prescription shall subject the dentist to suspension or revocation of her or his license to practice dentistry in this state. Failure of a dental laboratory that has accepted a prescription to have the original or electronic copy of each prescription and to ensure the accuracy of each product’s material disclosure at the time it is delivered to the prescribing dentist as required by this section is admissible evidence of a violation of this chapter and constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. This section does not preclude a registered dental laboratory from working for another registered dental laboratory if that work is performed pursuant to written authorization, in a form to be prescribed by rule of the board, which evidences that the originating laboratory has obtained a valid prescription and which sets forth the work to be performed and the resulting material certifications to be provided. A dental laboratory accepting prescriptions from dentists is liable for damages caused by inaccuracies in the material disclosure, certificates of authenticity, or point of origin provided by the dental laboratory to the prescribing dentist. This section does not preclude a registered laboratory from providing its services to dentists licensed and practicing in another state if that work is requested or otherwise authorized in written form that clearly identifies the name and address of the requesting dentist and sets forth the work to be performed and otherwise complies with all applicable laws and treaties.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 93, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 258, ch. 97-103; s. 2, ch. 99-183; s. 126, ch. 99-397; s. 6, ch. 2005-189; s. 9, ch. 2008-64.</History></Section>