<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.0135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Continuing education; dentists.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the other requirements for renewal set out in this chapter, each licensed dentist shall be required to complete biennially not less than 30 hours of continuing professional education in dental subjects. Programs of continuing education shall be programs of learning that contribute directly to the dental education of the dentist and may include, but shall not be limited to, attendance at lectures, study clubs, college postgraduate courses, or scientific sessions of conventions; and research, graduate study, teaching, or service as a clinician. Programs of continuing education shall be acceptable when adhering to the following general guidelines:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The aim of continuing education for dentists is to improve all phases of dental health care delivery to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continuing education courses shall address one or more of the following areas of professional development, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Basic medical and scientific subjects, including, but not limited to, biology, physiology, pathology, biochemistry, and pharmacology;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical and technological subjects, including, but not limited to, clinical techniques and procedures, materials, and equipment; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subjects pertinent to oral health and safety.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may also authorize up to three hours of credit biennially for a practice management course that includes principles of ethical practice management, provides substance abuse, effective communication with patients, time management, and burnout prevention instruction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continuing education credits shall be earned at the rate of one-half credit hour per 25-30 contact minutes of instruction and one credit hour per 50-60 contact minutes of instruction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Programs meeting the general requirements of subsection (1) may be developed and offered to dentists by any of the following agencies or organizations:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The American Dental Association, the National Dental Association, and state, district, or local dental associations and societies affiliated with the American Dental Association or the National Dental Association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">National, state, district, or local dental specialty organizations affiliated with the American Dental Association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dental colleges or schools accredited as provided in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other organizations, schools, or agencies approved by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In applying for license renewal, the dentist shall submit a sworn affidavit, on a form acceptable to the department, attesting that she or he has completed the continuing education required in this section in accordance with the guidelines and provisions of this section and listing the date, location, sponsor, subject matter, and hours of completed continuing education courses. The applicant shall retain in her or his records such receipts, vouchers, or certificates as may be necessary to document completion of the continuing education courses listed in accordance with this subsection. With cause, the board may request such documentation by the applicant, and the board may request such documentation from applicants selected at random without cause.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with the continuing education requirements of this section shall be mandatory for the issuance of a renewal certificate by the department; however, the board shall have the authority to excuse licensees, as a group or as individuals, from said requirements, or any part thereof, in the event of an unusual circumstance, emergency, or special hardship.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 5, ch. 85-156; ss. 7, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 253, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 2005-189.</History></Section>