<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.019" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advertising by dentists.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to ensure that the public has access to information which provides a sufficient basis upon which to make an informed selection of dentists while also ensuring that the public is protected from false or misleading advertisements which would detract from a fair and rational selection process. The board shall adopt rules to carry out the intent of this section, the purpose of which shall be to regulate the manner of such advertising in keeping with the provisions hereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No advertisement by a licensed dentist shall contain any false, fraudulent, misleading, or deceptive statement or claim or any statement or claim which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains misrepresentations of fact;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is likely to mislead or deceive because in context it makes only a partial disclosure of relevant facts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains laudatory statements about the dentist or group of dentists;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is intended or is likely to create false, unjustified expectations of favorable results;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relates to the quality of dental services provided as compared to other available dental services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is intended or is likely to appeal primarily to a layperson’s fears;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains fee information without a disclaimer that such is a minimum fee only; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains other representations or implications that in reasonable probability will cause an ordinary, prudent person to misunderstand or to be deceived.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, D.D.S. or D.M.D. are synonymous and may be used interchangeably by licensed dentists who have graduated from an accredited American dental school with a D.D.S. or D.M.D. degree, when advertising dental services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 12, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; ss. 14, 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>