<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permitting of dental interns serving at state institutions; certification of dentists practicing at government facilities; permitting of nonprofit corporations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, upon presentation of satisfactory credentials meeting such requirements as the board may by rule prescribe, issue a permit to a graduate of an approved dental school or college who has not been licensed to practice dentistry in this state to serve as a dental intern in state-maintained and state-operated hospitals or institutes of Florida that may offer such a post or in such hospitals or institutions as shall be approved by the board; provided such hospitals or institutions maintain a recognized staff of one or more licensed dentists. Such intern shall function under the general supervision of the dental staff of such hospital. Her or his work shall be limited to the patients confined to the hospital in which she or he serves, and she or he shall serve without fee or compensation other than that received in salary or other remuneration from such hospital. The board shall have the power to revoke the permit of any such intern at any time upon the recommendation by the executive officer of the dental staff of the hospital or institution in which the intern serves or for any other just cause.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the authority to issue temporary certificates to graduates of accredited dental schools to practice in state and county government facilities, working under the general supervision of licensed dentists of this state in the state or county facility, provided such certificates shall be issued only to graduates of schools approved by the board and further subject to cancellation for just cause. A certificate issued under this section is valid only for such time as the dentist remains employed by a state or county government facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the authority, upon presentation of satisfactory credentials and under such rules as the board may prescribe, to issue a permit to a nonprofit corporation chartered for one or more of the following purposes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Training and teaching dental assistants in the public schools of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting research and training among duly licensed dentists in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing dental care for indigent persons.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such nonprofit corporations shall function pursuant to rule of the board. The board shall have the power to revoke the permit issued to any such corporations for any violation of the rules. Such permits shall be granted and issued for a period of 1 year and shall be renewed only upon application and approval of the board and upon a showing by the nonprofit corporation that it is complying and will comply with the rules and regulations and all provisions prescribed by the board.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 13, 15, 25, 29, 30, 34, 62, ch. 80-406; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 16, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 100, ch. 92-149; s. 260, ch. 97-103; s. 7, ch. 2005-189.</History></Section>