<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0466.0235" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dental charting.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “dental charting” means a recording of visual observations of clinical conditions of the oral cavity without the use of X rays, laboratory tests, or other diagnostic methods or equipment, except the instruments necessary to record visual restorations, missing teeth, suspicious areas, and periodontal pockets.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dental hygienist may, without supervision and within the lawful scope of his or her duties as authorized by law, perform dental charting of hard and soft tissues in public and private educational institutions of the state and Federal Government, nursing homes, assisted living and long-term care facilities, community health centers, county health departments, mobile dental or health units, health access settings as defined in s. 466.003, and epidemiological surveys for public health. A dental hygienist may also perform dental charting on a volunteer basis at health fairs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who receives a dental charting pursuant to this section, or the parent or legal guardian of the person, shall receive and acknowledge a written disclosure form before receiving the dental charting procedure that states that the purpose of the dental charting is to collect data for use by a dentist at a prompt subsequent examination. The disclosure form shall also emphasize that diagnosis of caries, soft tissue disease, oral cancer, temporomandibular joint disease (TMJ), and dentofacial malocclusions can only be completed by a dentist in the context of delivering a comprehensive dental examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall approve the content of charting and disclosure forms to be used under this section. Both forms shall emphasize the inherent limitations of dental charting and encourage complete examination by a dentist in rendering a professional diagnosis of the patient’s overall oral health needs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dental charting performed under this section is not a substitute for a comprehensive dental examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical clearance by a physician or dentist is required before a periodontal probe may be used on a person who receives a dental charting.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit direct reimbursement for dental charting performed under this section by Medicaid, health insurers, health maintenance organizations, prepaid dental plans, or other third-party payors beyond what is otherwise allowable by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All referrals made in conjunction with the provision of dental charting services under this section shall be in strict conformance with federal and state patient referral, anti-kickback, and patient brokering laws.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dental hygienist performing dental charting without supervision shall not be deemed to have created either a patient of record or a medical record.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2006-149; s. 6, ch. 2011-95.</History>
</Section>