<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0466.017" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prescription of drugs; anesthesia.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dentist shall have the right to prescribe drugs or medicine, subject to limitations imposed by law; perform surgical operations within the scope of her or his practice and training; administer general or local anesthesia or sedation, subject to limitations imposed by law; and use such appliances as may be necessary to the proper practice of dentistry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pharmacists licensed pursuant to chapter 465 may fill prescriptions of legally licensed dentists in this state for any drugs necessary for the practice of dentistry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Define general anesthesia.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify which methods of general or local anesthesia or sedation, if any, are limited or prohibited for use by dentists.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish minimal training, education, experience, or certification for a dentist to use general anesthesia or sedation, which rules may exclude, in the board’s discretion, those dentists using general anesthesia or sedation in a competent and effective manner as of the effective date of the rules.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish further requirements relating to the use of general anesthesia or sedation, including, but not limited to, office equipment and the training of dental assistants or dental hygienists who work with dentists using general anesthesia or sedation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish an administrative mechanism enabling the board to verify compliance with training, education, experience, equipment, or certification requirements of dentists, dental hygienists, and dental assistants adopted pursuant to this subsection. The board may charge a fee to defray the cost of verifying compliance with requirements adopted pursuant to this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dentist or dental hygienist who administers or employs the use of any form of anesthesia must possess a certification in either basic cardiopulmonary resuscitation for health professionals or advanced cardiac life support approved by the American Heart Association or the American Red Cross or an equivalent agency-sponsored course with recertification every 2 years. Each dental office which uses any form of anesthesia must have immediately available and in good working order such resuscitative equipment, oxygen, and other resuscitative drugs as are specified by rule of the board in order to manage possible adverse reactions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dental hygienist under the direct supervision of a dentist may administer local anesthesia, including intraoral block anesthesia, soft tissue infiltration anesthesia, or both, to a nonsedated patient who is 18 years of age or older, if the following criteria are met:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dental hygienist has successfully completed a course in the administration of local anesthesia which is offered by a dental or dental hygiene program accredited by the Commission on Dental Accreditation of the American Dental Association or approved by the board. The course must include a minimum of 30 hours of didactic instruction and 30 hours of clinical experience, and instruction in:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Theory of pain control.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selection-of-pain-control modalities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Anatomy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neurophysiology.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pharmacology of local anesthetics.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pharmacology of vasoconstrictors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Psychological aspects of pain control.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Systematic complications.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Techniques of maxillary anesthesia.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Techniques of mandibular anesthesia.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Infection control.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical emergencies involving local anesthesia.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dental hygienist presents evidence of current certification in basic or advanced cardiac life support.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dental hygienist possesses a valid certificate issued under subsection (6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dental hygienist seeking a certificate to administer local anesthesia must apply to the department, remit an application fee, and submit proof of successful completion of a course in the administration of local anesthesia pursuant to subsection (5). The board shall certify, and the department shall issue a certificate to, any dental hygienist who fulfills the qualifications of subsection (5). The board shall establish a one-time application fee not to exceed $35. The certificate is not subject to renewal but is part of the dental hygienist’s permanent record and must be prominently displayed at the location where the dental hygienist is authorized to administer local anesthesia. The board shall adopt rules necessary to administer subsection (5) and this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed dentist may utilize an X-ray machine, expose dental X-ray films, and interpret or read such films. The provisions of part IV of chapter 468 to the contrary notwithstanding, a licensed dentist may authorize or direct a dental assistant to operate such equipment and expose such films under her or his direction and supervision, pursuant to rules adopted by the board in accordance with s. 466.024 which ensure that said assistant is competent by reason of training and experience to operate said equipment in a safe and efficient manner. The board may charge a fee not to exceed $35 to defray the cost of verifying compliance with requirements adopted pursuant to this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 465.0276 notwithstanding, a dentist need not register with the board or comply with the continuing education requirements of that section if the dentist confines her or his dispensing activity to the dispensing of fluorides and chlorohexidine rinse solutions; provided that the dentist complies with and is subject to all laws and rules applicable to pharmacists and pharmacies, including, but not limited to, chapters 465, 499, and 893, and all applicable federal laws and regulations, when dispensing such products.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 13, 15, 25, 27, 30, 34, 62, ch. 80-406; s. 328, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 85-156; ss. 10, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 1, ch. 87-208; s. 37, ch. 89-162; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 34, ch. 95-144; s. 256, ch. 97-103; s. 109, ch. 97-264; s. 3, ch. 2012-14.</History>
</Section>