<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.014" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Continuing education; dental hygienists.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the other requirements for relicensure for dental hygienists set out in this act, the board shall require each licensed dental hygienist to complete not less than 24 hours or more than 36 hours of continuing professional education in dental subjects, biennially, in programs prescribed or approved by the board or in equivalent programs of continuing education. Programs of continuing education approved by the board shall be programs of learning which, in the opinion of the board, contribute directly to the dental education of the dental hygienist. The board shall adopt rules and guidelines to administer and enforce the provisions of this section. In applying for license renewal, the dental hygienist shall submit a sworn affidavit, on a form acceptable to the department, attesting that she or he has completed the continuing education required in this section in accordance with the guidelines and provisions of this section and listing the date, location, sponsor, subject matter, and hours of completed continuing education courses. The applicant shall retain in her or his records such receipts, vouchers, or certificates as may be necessary to document completion of the continuing education courses listed in accordance with this section. With cause, the board may request such documentation by the applicant, and the board may request such documentation from applicants selected at random without cause. Compliance with the continuing education requirements shall be mandatory for issuance of the renewal certificate. The board shall have the authority to excuse licensees, as a group or as individuals, from the continuing educational requirements, or any part thereof, in the event an unusual circumstance, emergency, or hardship has prevented compliance with this section.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 8, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 254, ch. 97-103; s. 122, ch. 2000-153.</History></Section>