<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0466.006">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examination of dentists.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to reduce the costs associated with an independent state-developed practical or clinical examination to measure an applicant’s ability to practice the profession of dentistry and to use the American Dental Licensing Examination developed by the American Board of Dental Examiners, Inc., in lieu of an independent state-developed practical or clinical examination. The Legislature finds that the American Dental Licensing Examination, in both its structure and function, consistently meets generally accepted testing standards and has been found, as it is currently organized and operating, to adequately and reliably measure an applicant’s ability to practice the profession of dentistry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed as a dentist shall apply to the department to take the licensure examinations and shall verify the information required on the application by oath. The application shall include two recent photographs. There shall be an application fee set by the board not to exceed $100 which shall be nonrefundable. There shall also be an examination fee set by the board, which shall not exceed $425 plus the actual per applicant cost to the department for purchase of some or all of the examination from the American Board of Dental Examiners or its successor entity, if any, provided the board finds the successor entity’s clinical examination complies with the provisions of this section. The examination fee may be refundable if the applicant is found ineligible to take the examinations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant shall be entitled to take the examinations required in this section to practice dentistry in this state if the applicant:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age or older.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of a dental school accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation or its successor entity, if any, or any other dental accrediting entity recognized by the United States Department of Education; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a dental student in the final year of a program at such an accredited dental school who has completed all the coursework necessary to prepare the student to perform the clinical and diagnostic procedures required to pass the examinations. With respect to a dental student in the final year of a program at a dental school, a passing score on the examinations is valid for 365 days after the date the examinations were completed. A dental school student who takes the licensure examinations during the student’s final year of an approved dental school must have graduated before being certified for licensure pursuant to s. 466.011.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed the National Board of Dental Examiners dental examination; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has an active health access dental license in this state; and</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has at least 5,000 hours within 4 consecutive years of clinical practice experience providing direct patient care in a health access setting as defined in s. 466.003; the applicant is a retired veteran dentist of any branch of the United States Armed Services who has practiced dentistry while on active duty and has at least 3,000 hours within 3 consecutive years of clinical practice experience providing direct patient care in a health access setting as defined in s. 466.003; or the applicant has provided a portion of his or her salaried time teaching health profession students in any public education setting, including, but not limited to, a community college, college, or university, and has at least 3,000 hours within 3 consecutive years of clinical practice experience providing direct patient care in a health access setting as defined in s. 466.003;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has not been disciplined by the board, except for citation offenses or minor violations;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has not filed a report pursuant to s. 456.049; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has not been convicted of or pled nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, any felony or misdemeanor related to the practice of a health care profession.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an applicant is a graduate of a dental college or school not accredited in accordance with paragraph (2)(b) or of a dental college or school not approved by the board, the applicant is not entitled to take the examinations required in this section to practice dentistry until she or he satisfies one of the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completes a program of study, as defined by the board by rule, at an accredited American dental school and demonstrates receipt of a D.D.S. or D.M.D. from said school; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits proof of having successfully completed at least 2 consecutive academic years at a full-time supplemental general dentistry program accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation. This program must provide didactic and clinical education at the level of a D.D.S. or D.M.D. program accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law in chapter 456 pertaining to the clinical dental licensure examination or national examinations, to be licensed as a dentist in this state, an applicant must successfully complete the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written examination on the laws and rules of the state regulating the practice of dentistry;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A practical or clinical examination, which shall be the American Dental Licensing Examination produced by the American Board of Dental Examiners, Inc., or its successor entity, if any, that is administered in this state and graded by dentists licensed in this state and employed by the department for just such purpose, provided that the board has attained, and continues to maintain thereafter, representation on the board of directors of the American Board of Dental Examiners, the examination development committee of the American Board of Dental Examiners, and such other committees of the American Board of Dental Examiners as the board deems appropriate by rule to assure that the standards established herein are maintained organizationally. A passing score on the American Dental Licensing Examination administered in this state and graded by dentists who are licensed in this state is valid for 365 days after the date the official examination results are published.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As an alternative to the requirements of subparagraph 1., an applicant may submit scores from an American Dental Licensing Examination previously administered in a jurisdiction other than this state after October 1, 2011, and such examination results shall be recognized as valid for the purpose of licensure in this state. A passing score on the American Dental Licensing Examination administered out-of-state shall be the same as the passing score for the American Dental Licensing Examination administered in this state and graded by dentists who are licensed in this state. The examination results are valid for 365 days after the date the official examination results are published. The applicant must have completed the examination after October 1, 2011.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subparagraph may not be given retroactive application.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the date of an applicant’s passing American Dental Licensing Examination scores from an examination previously administered in a jurisdiction other than this state under subparagraph 2. is older than 365 days, then such scores shall nevertheless be recognized as valid for the purpose of licensure in this state, but only if the applicant demonstrates that all of the following additional standards have been met:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant completed the American Dental Licensing Examination after October 1, 2011.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This sub-subparagraph may not be given retroactive application;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant graduated from a dental school accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation or its successor entity, if any, or any other dental accrediting organization recognized by the United States Department of Education. Provided, however, if the applicant did not graduate from such a dental school, the applicant may submit proof of having successfully completed a full-time supplemental general dentistry program accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation of at least 2 consecutive academic years at such accredited sponsoring institution. Such program must provide didactic and clinical education at the level of a D.D.S. or D.M.D. program accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant currently possesses a valid and active dental license in good standing, with no restriction, which has never been revoked, suspended, restricted, or otherwise disciplined, from another state or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant submits proof that he or she has never been reported to the National Practitioner Data Bank, the Healthcare Integrity and Protection Data Bank, or the American Association of Dental Boards Clearinghouse. This sub-subparagraph does not apply if the applicant successfully appealed to have his or her name removed from the data banks of these agencies;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the 5 years immediately preceding the date of application for licensure in this state, the applicant must submit proof of having been consecutively engaged in the full-time practice of dentistry in another state or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or, if the applicant has been licensed in another state or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for less than 5 years, the applicant must submit proof of having been engaged in the full-time practice of dentistry since the date of his or her initial licensure.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “full-time practice” is defined as a minimum of 1,200 hours per year for each and every year in the consecutive 5-year period or, where applicable, the period since initial licensure, and must include any combination of the following:</Text>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="A">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Active clinical practice of dentistry providing direct patient care.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="B">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time practice as a faculty member employed by a dental or dental hygiene school approved by the board or accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="C">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time practice as a student at a postgraduate dental education program approved by the board or accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall develop rules to determine what type of proof of full-time practice is required and to recoup the cost to the board of verifying full-time practice under this section. Such proof must, at a minimum, be:</Text>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="A">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Admissible as evidence in an administrative proceeding;</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="B">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted in writing;</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="C">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted by the applicant under oath with penalties of perjury attached;</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="D">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Further documented by an affidavit of someone unrelated to the applicant who is familiar with the applicant’s practice and testifies with particularity that the applicant has been engaged in full-time practice; and</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="E">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifically found by the board to be both credible and admissible.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affidavit of only the applicant is not acceptable proof of full-time practice unless it is further attested to by someone unrelated to the applicant who has personal knowledge of the applicant’s practice. If the board deems it necessary to assess credibility or accuracy, the board may require the applicant or the applicant’s witnesses to appear before the board and give oral testimony under oath;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must submit documentation that he or she has completed, or will complete, prior to licensure in this state, continuing education equivalent to this state’s requirements for the last full reporting biennium;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must prove that he or she has never been convicted of, or pled nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, any felony or misdemeanor related to the practice of a health care profession in any jurisdiction;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must successfully pass a written examination on the laws and rules of this state regulating the practice of dentistry and must successfully pass the computer-based diagnostic skills examination; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must submit documentation that he or she has successfully completed the National Board of Dental Examiners dental examination.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practical examination required under subsection (4) shall be the American Dental Licensing Examination developed by the American Board of Dental Examiners, Inc., or its successor entity, if any, provided the board finds that the successor entity’s clinical examination complies with the provisions of this section, and shall include, at a minimum:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A comprehensive diagnostic skills examination covering the full scope of dentistry and an examination on applied clinical diagnosis and treatment planning in dentistry for dental candidates;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two restorations on a live patient or patients. The board by rule shall determine the class of such restorations;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A demonstration of periodontal skills on a live patient;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A demonstration of prosthetics and restorative skills in complete and partial dentures and crowns and bridges and the utilization of practical methods of evaluation, specifically including the evaluation by the candidate of completed laboratory products such as, but not limited to, crowns and inlays filled to prepared model teeth;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A demonstration of restorative skills on a mannequin which requires the candidate to complete procedures performed in preparation for a cast restoration; </Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A demonstration of endodontic skills; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A diagnostic skills examination demonstrating ability to diagnose conditions within the human oral cavity and its adjacent tissues and structures from photographs, slides, radiographs, or models pursuant to rules of the board. If an applicant fails to pass the diagnostic skills examination in three attempts, the applicant shall not be eligible for reexamination unless she or he completes additional educational requirements established by the board.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall consult with the board in planning the times, places, physical facilities, training of personnel, and other arrangements concerning the administration of the examination. The board or a duly designated committee thereof shall approve the final plans for the administration of the examination;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant fails to pass the clinical examination in three attempts, the applicant shall not be eligible for reexamination unless she or he completes additional educational requirements established by the board; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may by rule provide for additional procedures which are to be tested, provided such procedures shall be common to the practice of general dentistry. The board by rule shall determine the passing grade for each procedure and the acceptable variation for examiners. No such rule shall apply retroactively.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department shall require a mandatory standardization exercise for all examiners prior to each practical or clinical examination and shall retain for employment only those dentists who have substantially adhered to the standard of grading established at such exercise.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the finding of the Legislature that absent a threat to the health, safety, and welfare of the public, the relocation of applicants to practice dentistry within the geographic boundaries of this state, who are lawfully and currently practicing dentistry in another state or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, based on their scores from the American Dental Licensing Examination administered in a state other than this state, is substantially related to achieving the important state interest of improving access to dental care for underserved citizens of this state and furthering the economic development goals of the state. Therefore, in order to maintain valid active licensure in this state, all applicants for licensure who are relocating to this state based on scores from the American Dental Licensing Examination administered in a state other than this state must actually engage in the full-time practice of dentistry inside the geographic boundaries of this state within 1 year of receiving such licensure in this state. The Legislature finds that, if such applicants do not actually engage in the full-time practice of dentistry within the geographic boundaries of this state within 1 year of receiving such a license in this state, access to dental care for the public will not significantly increase, patients’ continuity of care will not be attained, and the economic development goals of the state will not be significantly met.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “full-time practice of dentistry within the geographic boundaries of this state within 1 year” is defined as a minimum of 1,200 hours in the initial year of licensure, which must include any combination of the following:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Active clinical practice of dentistry providing direct patient care within the geographic boundaries of this state.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time practice as a faculty member employed by a dental or dental hygiene school approved by the board or accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation and located within the geographic boundaries of this state.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full-time practice as a student at a postgraduate dental education program approved by the board or accredited by the American Dental Association Commission on Dental Accreditation and located within the geographic boundaries of this state.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall develop rules to determine what type of proof of full-time practice of dentistry within the geographic boundaries of this state for 1 year is required in order to maintain active licensure and shall develop rules to recoup the cost to the board of verifying maintenance of such full-time practice under this section. Such proof must, at a minimum:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be admissible as evidence in an administrative proceeding;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be submitted in writing;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be submitted by the applicant under oath with penalties of perjury attached;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be further documented by an affidavit of someone unrelated to the applicant who is familiar with the applicant’s practice and testifies with particularity that the applicant has been engaged in full-time practice of dentistry within the geographic boundaries of this state within the last 365 days; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include such additional proof as specifically found by the board to be both credible and admissible.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affidavit of only the applicant is not acceptable proof of full-time practice of dentistry within the geographic boundaries of this state within 1 year, unless it is further attested to by someone unrelated to the applicant who has personal knowledge of the applicant’s practice within the last 365 days. If the board deems it necessary to assess credibility or accuracy, the board may require the applicant or the applicant’s witnesses to appear before the board and give oral testimony under oath.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the further intent of the Legislature that a license issued pursuant to paragraph (a) shall expire in the event the board finds that it did not receive acceptable proof of full-time practice within the geographic boundaries of this state within 1 year after the initial issuance of the license. The board shall make reasonable attempts within 30 days prior to the expiration of such a license to notify the licensee in writing at his or her last known address of the need for proof of full-time practice in order to continue licensure. If the board has not received a satisfactory response from the licensee within the 30-day period, the licensee must be served with actual or constructive notice of the pending expiration of licensure and be given 20 days in which to submit proof required in order to continue licensure. If the 20-day period expires and the board finds it has not received acceptable proof of full-time practice within the geographic boundaries of this state within 1 year after the initial issuance of the license, then the board must issue an administrative order finding that the license has expired. Such an order may be appealed by the former licensee in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120. In the event of expiration, the licensee shall immediately cease and desist from practicing dentistry and shall immediately surrender to the board the wallet-size identification card and wall card. A person who uses or attempts to use a license issued pursuant to this section which has expired commits unlicensed practice of dentistry, a felony of the third degree pursuant to s. 466.026(1)(b), punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 13, 15, 25, 26, 30, 34, 62, ch. 80-406; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 8, 38, 41, ch. 82-179; s. 1, ch. 82-220; s. 1, ch. 83-172; s. 87, ch. 83-218; s. 4, ch. 85-156; ss. 5, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 15, ch. 88-205; s. 10, ch. 89-66; s. 48, ch. 90-228; s. 2, ch. 90-341; ss. 13, 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 251, ch. 97-103; s. 108, ch. 97-264; s. 1, ch. 2004-300; s. 3, ch. 2005-189; s. 2, ch. 2008-64; s. 9, ch. 2011-95; s. 1, ch. 2012-14.</History>
</Section>