<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0466.026" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each of the following acts constitutes a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing dentistry or dental hygiene unless the person has an appropriate, active license issued by the department pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using or attempting to use a license issued pursuant to this chapter which license has been suspended or revoked.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly employing any person to perform duties outside the scope allowed such person under this chapter or the rules of the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Giving false or forged evidence to the department or board for the purpose of obtaining a license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selling or offering to sell a diploma conferring a degree from a dental college or dental hygiene school or college, or a license issued pursuant to this chapter, or procuring such diploma or license with intent that it shall be used as evidence of that which the document stands for, by a person other than the one upon whom it was conferred or to whom it was granted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each of the following acts constitutes a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using the name or title “dentist,” the letters “D.D.S.” or “D.M.D.”, or any other words, letters, title, or descriptive matter which in any way represents a person as being able to diagnose, treat, prescribe, or operate for any disease, pain, deformity, deficiency, injury, or physical condition of the teeth or jaws or oral-maxillofacial region unless the person has an active dentist’s license issued by the department pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using the name “dental hygienist” or the initials “R.D.H.” or otherwise holding herself or himself out as an actively licensed dental hygienist or implying to any patient or consumer that she or he is an actively licensed dental hygienist unless that person has an active dental hygienist’s license issued by the department pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Presenting as her or his own the license of another.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly concealing information relative to violations of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing any services as a dental assistant as defined herein, except in the office of a licensed dentist, unless authorized by this chapter or by rule of the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 79-330; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 17, 23, 24, ch. 86-291; s. 60, ch. 91-137; s. 7, ch. 91-156; s. 94, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 261, ch. 97-103; s. 56, ch. 2000-318.</History></Section>