<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0455.2228" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Barbers and cosmetologists; instruction on HIV and AIDS.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, or the department where there is no board, shall require each person licensed or certified under chapter 476 or chapter 477 to complete a continuing educational course approved by the board, or the department where there is no board, on human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immune deficiency syndrome as part of biennial relicensure or recertification. The course shall consist of education on modes of transmission, infection control procedures, clinical management, and prevention of human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immune deficiency syndrome, with an emphasis on appropriate behavior and attitude change.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When filing fees for each biennial renewal, each licensee shall submit confirmation of having completed said course, on a form provided by the board or by the department if there is no board. At the time of the subsequent biennial renewal when coursework is to be completed, if the licensee has not submitted confirmation which has been received and recorded by the board, or department if there is no board, the department shall not renew the license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, or the department where there is no board, shall have the authority to approve additional equivalent courses that may be used to satisfy the requirements in subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As of December 31, 1992, the board, or the department where there is no board, shall require, as a condition of granting a license under any of the chapters or parts thereof specified in subsection (1), that an applicant making initial application for licensure complete an educational course acceptable to the board, or the department where there is no board, on human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immune deficiency syndrome. An applicant who has not taken a course at the time of licensure shall, upon an affidavit showing good cause, be allowed 6 months to complete this requirement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, or the department where there is no board, shall have the authority to adopt rules to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any professional holding two or more licenses subject to the provisions of this section shall be permitted to show proof of having taken one board-approved course, or one department-approved course where there is no board, on human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immune deficiency syndrome, for purposes of relicensure or recertification for additional licenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 89-350; ss. 73, 74, ch. 91-297; s. 16, ch. 95-388; s. 18, ch. 97-261; s. 147, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>