<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0455.2179" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Continuing education provider and course approval; cease and desist orders.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a board, or the department if there is no board, requires completion of continuing education as a requirement for renewal of a license, the board, or the department if there is no board, shall approve the providers and courses for the continuing education. Notwithstanding this subsection or any other provision of law, the department may approve continuing education providers or courses even if there is a board. If the department determines that an application for a continuing education provider or course requires expert review or should be denied, the department shall forward the application to the appropriate board for review and approval or denial. The approval of continuing education providers and courses must be for a specified period of time, not to exceed 4 years. An approval that does not include such a time limitation may remain in effect pursuant to the applicable practice act or the rules adopted under the applicable practice act. Notwithstanding this subsection or any other provision of law, only the department may determine the contents of any documents submitted for approval of a continuing education provider or course.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, or the department if there is no board, shall issue an order requiring a person or entity to cease and desist from offering any continuing education programs for licensees, and fining, suspending, or revoking any approval of the provider previously granted by the board, or the department if there is no board, if the board, or the department if there is no board, determines that the person or entity failed to provide appropriate continuing education services that conform to approved course material. Such fine may not exceed $500 per violation. Investigations and prosecutions of a provider’s failure to comply with its duties under this section shall be conducted under s. 455.225.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board authorized to approve continuing education providers, or the department if there is no board, may establish, by rule, a fee not to exceed $250 for anyone seeking approval to provide continuing education courses and may establish, by rule, a biennial fee not to exceed $250 for the renewal of providership of such courses. The Florida Real Estate Commission, authorized under the provisions of chapter 475 to approve prelicensure, precertification, and postlicensure education providers, may establish, by rule, an application fee not to exceed $250 for anyone seeking approval to offer prelicensure, precertification, or postlicensure education courses and may establish, by rule, a biennial fee not to exceed $250 for the renewal of such courses. Such postlicensure education courses are subject to the reporting, monitoring, and compliance provisions of this section and ss. 455.2177 and 455.2178.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and each affected board may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 159, ch. 99-251; s. 7, ch. 2000-356; s. 4, ch. 2004-292; s. 4, ch. 2012-72.</History>
</Section>