<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0455.2177" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Monitoring of compliance with continuing education requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a system to monitor licensee compliance with applicable continuing education requirements and to determine each licensee’s continuing education status. As used in this section, the term “monitor” means the act of determining, for each licensee, whether the licensee was in full compliance with applicable continuing education requirements as of the time of the licensee’s license renewal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may refuse renewal of a licensee’s license until the licensee has satisfied all applicable continuing education requirements. This subsection does not preclude the department or boards from imposing additional penalties pursuant to the applicable practice act or rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may waive the continuing education monitoring requirements of this section for any profession that demonstrates to the department that the monitoring system places an undue burden on the profession. The department shall waive the continuing education monitoring requirements of this section for any profession that has a program in place which measures compliance with continuing education requirements through statistical sampling techniques or other methods and can indicate that at least 95 percent of its licensees are in compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 157, ch. 99-251; s. 17, ch. 2001-278; s. 43, ch. 2002-207; s. 2, ch. 2004-292; s. 82, ch. 2005-2.</History></Section>