<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0455.204" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Long-range policy planning; plans, reports, and recommendations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To facilitate efficient and cost-effective regulation, the department and the board, where appropriate, shall develop and implement a long-range policy planning and monitoring process to include recommendations specific to each profession. Such process shall include estimates of revenues, expenditures, cash balances, and performance statistics for each profession. The period covered shall not be less than 5 years. The department, with input from the boards, shall develop the long-range plan and must obtain the approval of the secretary. The department shall monitor compliance with the approved long-range plan and, with input from the boards, shall annually update the plans for approval by the secretary. The department shall provide concise management reports to the boards quarterly. As part of the review process, the department shall evaluate:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the department, including the boards and the various functions performed by the department, is operating efficiently and effectively and if there is a need for a board or council to assist in cost-effective regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How and why the various professions are regulated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether there is a need to continue regulation, and to what degree.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether or not consumer protection is adequate, and how it can be improved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether there is consistency between the various practice acts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether unlicensed activity is adequately enforced.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such plans should include conclusions and recommendations on these and other issues as appropriate. Such plans shall be provided to the Governor and the Legislature by November 1 of each year.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 92-149.</History></Section>