<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0455.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means any board or commission, or other statutorily created entity to the extent such entity is authorized to exercise regulatory or rulemaking functions, within the department, including the Florida Real Estate Commission; except that, for ss. 455.201-455.245, “board” means only a board, or other statutorily created entity to the extent such entity is authorized to exercise regulatory or rulemaking functions, within the Division of Certified Public Accounting, the Division of Professions, or the Division of Real Estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consumer member” means a person appointed to serve on a specific board or who has served on a specific board, who is not, and never has been, a member or practitioner of the profession, or of any closely related profession, regulated by such board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means any permit, registration, certificate, or license issued by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means any person issued a permit, registration, certificate, or license by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Profession” means any activity, occupation, profession, or vocation regulated by the department in the Divisions of Certified Public Accounting, Professions, Real Estate, and Regulation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 21885, 1943; s. 1, ch. 28215, 1953; s. 12, ch. 63-195; s. 2, ch. 65-170; s. 27, ch. 67-248; s. 3, ch. 67-409; s. 1, ch. 67-596; s. 121, ch. 71-355; s. 122, ch. 73-333; s. 5, ch. 79-36; s. 123, ch. 79-164; s. 2, ch. 84-70; s. 9, ch. 91-220; s. 4, ch. 92-149; s. 5, ch. 93-220; s. 1, ch. 96-291; s. 3, ch. 97-261; s. 109, ch. 2000-153; s. 23, ch. 2000-160.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 485.01.</Text></Note></Section>