<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0455.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board rules; final agency action; challenges.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary of the department shall have standing to challenge any rule or proposed rule of a board under its jurisdiction pursuant to s. 120.56. In addition to challenges for any invalid exercise of delegated legislative authority, the administrative law judge, upon such a challenge by the secretary, may declare all or part of a rule or proposed rule invalid if it:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not protect the public from any significant and discernible harm or damages;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably restricts competition or the availability of professional services in the state or in a significant part of the state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unnecessarily increases the cost of professional services without a corresponding or equivalent public benefit.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, there shall not be created a presumption of the existence of any of the conditions cited in this subsection in the event that the rule or proposed rule is challenged.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, either the secretary or the board shall be a substantially interested party for purposes of s. 120.54(7). The board may, as an adversely affected party, initiate and maintain an action pursuant to s. 120.68 challenging the final agency action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No board created within the department shall have standing to challenge a rule or proposed rule of another board. However, if there is a dispute between boards concerning a rule or proposed rule, the boards may avail themselves of the provisions of s. 455.207(5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any proposed board rule that has not been modified to remove proposed committee objections of the Administrative Procedures Committee must receive approval from the department prior to filing the rule with the Department of State for final adoption. The department may repeal any rule enacted by the board which has taken effect without having met proposed committee objections of the Administrative Procedures Committee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 79-36; s. 42, ch. 92-33; s. 12, ch. 92-149; s. 23, ch. 93-129; s. 69, ch. 94-218; s. 207, ch. 96-410; s. 9, ch. 97-261; s. 5, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>