<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0540.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unauthorized publication of name or likeness.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall publish, print, display or otherwise publicly use for purposes of trade or for any commercial or advertising purpose the name, portrait, photograph, or other likeness of any natural person without the express written or oral consent to such use given by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such person; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other person, firm or corporation authorized in writing by such person to license the commercial use of her or his name or likeness; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such person is deceased, any person, firm or corporation authorized in writing to license the commercial use of her or his name or likeness, or if no person, firm or corporation is so authorized, then by any one from among a class composed of her or his surviving spouse and surviving children.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the consent required in subsection (1) is not obtained, the person whose name, portrait, photograph, or other likeness is so used, or any person, firm, or corporation authorized by such person in writing to license the commercial use of her or his name or likeness, or, if the person whose likeness is used is deceased, any person, firm, or corporation having the right to give such consent, as provided hereinabove, may bring an action to enjoin such unauthorized publication, printing, display or other public use, and to recover damages for any loss or injury sustained by reason thereof, including an amount which would have been a reasonable royalty, and punitive or exemplary damages.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person uses the name, portrait, photograph, or other likeness of a member of the armed forces without obtaining the consent required in subsection (1) and such use is not subject to any exception listed in this section, a court may impose a civil penalty of up to $1,000 per violation in addition to the civil remedies contained in subsection (2). Each commercial transaction constitutes a violation under this section. As used in this section, the term “member of the armed forces” means an officer or enlisted member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard of the United States, the Florida National Guard, and the United States Reserve Forces, including any officer or enlisted member who died as a result of injuries sustained in the line of duty.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The publication, printing, display, or use of the name or likeness of any person in any newspaper, magazine, book, news broadcast or telecast, or other news medium or publication as part of any bona fide news report or presentation having a current and legitimate public interest and where such name or likeness is not used for advertising purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of such name, portrait, photograph, or other likeness in connection with the resale or other distribution of literary, musical, or artistic productions or other articles of merchandise or property where such person has consented to the use of her or his name, portrait, photograph, or likeness on or in connection with the initial sale or distribution thereof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any photograph of a person solely as a member of the public and where such person is not named or otherwise identified in or in connection with the use of such photograph.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No action shall be brought under this section by reason of any publication, printing, display, or other public use of the name or likeness of a person occurring after the expiration of 40 years from and after the death of such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, a person’s “surviving spouse” is the person’s surviving spouse under the law of her or his domicile at the time of her or his death, whether or not the spouse has later remarried; and a person’s “children” are her or his immediate offspring and any children legally adopted by the person. Any consent provided for in subsection (1) shall be given on behalf of a minor by the guardian of her or his person or by either parent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remedies provided for in this section shall be in addition to and not in limitation of the remedies and rights of any person under the common law against the invasion of her or his privacy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-57; s. 751, ch. 97-103; s. 2, ch. 2007-164.</History></Section>