<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0117.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Electronic notarization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any document requiring notarization may be notarized electronically. The provisions of ss. 117.01, 117.03, 117.04, 117.05(1)-(11), (13), and (14), 117.105, and 117.107 apply to all notarizations under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In performing an electronic notarial act, a notary public shall use an electronic signature that is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unique to the notary public;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Capable of independent verification;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retained under the notary public’s sole control; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attached to or logically associated with the electronic document in a manner that any subsequent alteration to the electronic document displays evidence of the alteration.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a signature is required to be accompanied by a notary public seal, the requirement is satisfied when the electronic signature of the notary public contains all of the following seal information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name of the notary public exactly as provided on the notary public’s application for commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The words “Notary Public State of Florida”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of expiration of the commission of the notary public; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary public’s commission number.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of a notary public to comply with any of the requirements of this section may constitute grounds for suspension of the notary public’s commission by the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may adopt rules to ensure the security, reliability, and uniformity of signatures and seals authorized in this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-257.</History></Section>