<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0117.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of notary commission; unlawful use; notary fee; seal; duties; employer liability; name change; advertising; photocopies; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall obtain or use a notary public commission in other than his or her legal name, and it is unlawful for a notary public to notarize his or her own signature. Any person applying for a notary public commission must submit proof of identity to the Department of State if so requested. Any person who violates the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee of a notary public may not exceed $10 for any one notarial act, except as provided in s. 117.045.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public may not charge a fee for witnessing an absentee ballot in an election, and must witness such a ballot upon the request of an elector, provided the notarial act is in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public seal shall be affixed to all notarized paper documents and shall be of the rubber stamp type and shall include the words “Notary Public-State of Florida.” The seal shall also include the name of the notary public, the date of expiration of the commission of the notary public, and the commission number. The rubber stamp seal must be affixed to the notarized paper document in photographically reproducible black ink. Every notary public shall print, type, or stamp below his or her signature on a paper document his or her name exactly as commissioned. An impression-type seal may be used in addition to the rubber stamp seal, but the rubber stamp seal shall be the official seal for use on a paper document, and the impression-type seal may not be substituted therefor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any notary public whose term of appointment extends beyond January 1, 1992, is required to use a rubber stamp type notary public seal on paper documents only upon reappointment on or after January 1, 1992.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary public official seal and the certificate of notary public commission are the exclusive property of the notary public and must be kept under the direct and exclusive control of the notary public. The seal and certificate of commission must not be surrendered to an employer upon termination of employment, regardless of whether the employer paid for the seal or for the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public whose official seal is lost, stolen, or believed to be in the possession of another person shall immediately notify the Department of State or the Governor in writing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who unlawfully possesses a notary public official seal or any papers or copies relating to notarial acts is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When notarizing a signature, a notary public shall complete a jurat or notarial certificate in substantially the same form as those found in subsection (13). The jurat or certificate of acknowledgment shall contain the following elements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The venue stating the location of the notarization in the format, “State of Florida, County of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of notarial act performed, an oath or an acknowledgment, evidenced by the words “sworn” or “acknowledged.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the signer personally appeared before the notary public at the time of the notarization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exact date of the notarial act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the person whose signature is being notarized. It is presumed, absent such specific notation by the notary public, that notarization is to all signatures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific type of identification the notary public is relying upon in identifying the signer, either based on personal knowledge or satisfactory evidence specified in subsection (5).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary’s official signature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary’s name, typed, printed, or stamped below the signature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary’s official seal affixed below or to either side of the notary’s signature.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public may not notarize a signature on a document unless he or she personally knows, or has satisfactory evidence, that the person whose signature is to be notarized is the individual who is described in and who is executing the instrument. A notary public shall certify in the certificate of acknowledgment or jurat the type of identification, either based on personal knowledge or other form of identification, upon which the notary public is relying.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, “personally knows” means having an acquaintance, derived from association with the individual, which establishes the individual’s identity with at least a reasonable certainty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection, “satisfactory evidence” means the absence of any information, evidence, or other circumstances which would lead a reasonable person to believe that the person whose signature is to be notarized is not the person he or she claims to be and any one of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sworn written statement of one credible witness personally known to the notary public or the sworn written statement of two credible witnesses whose identities are proven to the notary public upon the presentation of satisfactory evidence that each of the following is true:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the person whose signature is to be notarized is the person named in the document;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the person whose signature is to be notarized is personally known to the witnesses;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it is the reasonable belief of the witnesses that the circumstances of the person whose signature is to be notarized are such that it would be very difficult or impossible for that person to obtain another acceptable form of identification;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it is the reasonable belief of the witnesses that the person whose signature is to be notarized does not possess any of the identification documents specified in subparagraph 2.; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the witnesses do not have a financial interest in nor are parties to the underlying transaction; or</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable reliance on the presentation to the notary public of any one of the following forms of identification, if the document is current or has been issued within the past 5 years and bears a serial or other identifying number:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida identification card or driver’s license issued by the public agency authorized to issue driver’s licenses;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A passport issued by the Department of State of the United States;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A passport issued by a foreign government if the document is stamped by the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A driver’s license or an identification card issued by a public agency authorized to issue driver’s licenses in a state other than Florida, a territory of the United States, or Canada or Mexico;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An identification card issued by any branch of the armed forces of the United States;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inmate identification card issued on or after January 1, 1991, by the Florida Department of Corrections for an inmate who is in the custody of the department;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inmate identification card issued by the United States Department of Justice, Bureau of Prisons, for an inmate who is in the custody of the department;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn, written statement from a sworn law enforcement officer that the forms of identification for an inmate in an institution of confinement were confiscated upon confinement and that the person named in the document is the person whose signature is to be notarized; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An identification card issued by the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer of a notary public shall be liable to the persons involved for all damages proximately caused by the notary’s official misconduct, if the notary public was acting within the scope of his or her employment at the time the notary engaged in the official misconduct.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who acts as or otherwise willfully impersonates a notary public while not lawfully appointed and commissioned to perform notarial acts is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any notary public who knowingly acts as a notary public after his or her commission has expired is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any notary public who lawfully changes his or her name shall, within 60 days after such change, request an amended commission from the Secretary of State and shall send $25, his or her current commission, and a notice of change form, obtained from the Secretary of State, which shall include the new name and contain a specimen of his or her official signature. The Secretary of State shall issue an amended commission to the notary public in the new name. A rider to the notary public’s bond must accompany the notice of change form. After submitting the required notice of change form and rider to the Secretary of State, the notary public may continue to perform notarial acts in his or her former name for 60 days or until receipt of the amended commission, whichever date is earlier.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public who is not an attorney who advertises the services of a notary public in a language other than English, whether by radio, television, signs, pamphlets, newspapers, or other written communication, with the exception of a single desk plaque, shall post or otherwise include with the advertisement a notice in English and in the language used for the advertisement. The notice shall be of a conspicuous size, if in writing, and shall state: “I AM NOT AN ATTORNEY LICENSED TO PRACTICE LAW IN THE STATE OF FLORIDA, AND I MAY NOT GIVE LEGAL ADVICE OR ACCEPT FEES FOR LEGAL ADVICE.” If the advertisement is by radio or television, the statement may be modified but must include substantially the same message.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Literal translation of the phrase “Notary Public” into a language other than English is prohibited in an advertisement for notarial services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public may supervise the making of a photocopy of an original document and attest to the trueness of the copy, provided the document is neither a vital record in this state, another state, a territory of the United States, or another country, nor a public record, if a copy can be made by the custodian of the public record.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public must use a certificate in substantially the following form in notarizing an attested copy:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">On this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, I attest that the preceding or attached document is a true, exact, complete, and unaltered photocopy made by me of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(description of document)</Directions> presented to me by the document’s custodian, <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, and, to the best of my knowledge, that the photocopied document is neither a vital record nor a public record, certified copies of which are available from an official source other than a notary public.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Official Notary Signature and Notary Seal)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of Notary Typed, Printed or Stamped)</Directions></Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following notarial certificates are sufficient for the purposes indicated, if completed with the information required by this chapter. The specification of forms under this subsection does not preclude the use of other forms.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an oath or affirmation:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to (or affirmed) and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an acknowledgment in an individual capacity:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The foregoing instrument was acknowledged before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person acknowledging)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an acknowledgment in a representative capacity:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The foregoing instrument was acknowledged before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person)</Directions> as <Directions xml:space="preserve">(type of authority, . . . e.g. officer, trustee, attorney in fact)</Directions> for <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of party on behalf of whom instrument was executed)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public must make reasonable accommodations to provide notarial services to persons with disabilities.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public may notarize the signature of a person who is blind after the notary public has read the entire instrument to that person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public may notarize the signature of a person who signs with a mark if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The document signing is witnessed by two disinterested persons;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary prints the person’s first name at the beginning of the designated signature line and the person’s last name at the end of the designated signature line; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary prints the words “his (or her) mark” below the person’s signature mark.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following notarial certificates are sufficient for the purpose of notarizing for a person who signs with a mark:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an oath or affirmation:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(First Name)</Directions><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Last Name)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">His (or Her) Mark</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>, who signed with a mark in the presence of these witnesses:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an acknowledgment in an individual capacity:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(First Name)</Directions><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Last Name)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">His (or Her) Mark</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The foregoing instrument was acknowledged before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person acknowledging)</Directions>, who signed with a mark in the presence of these witnesses:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notary public may sign the name of a person whose signature is to be notarized when that person is physically unable to sign or make a signature mark on a document if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person with a disability directs the notary to sign in his or her presence;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The document signing is witnessed by two disinterested persons;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notary writes below the signature the following statement: “Signature affixed by notary, pursuant to s. 117.05(14), Florida Statutes,” and states the circumstances of the signing in the notarial certificate.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following notarial certificates are sufficient for the purpose of notarizing for a person with a disability who directs the notary to sign his or her name:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an oath or affirmation:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to (or affirmed) before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>, and subscribed by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of notary)</Directions> at the direction of and in the presence of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>, and in the presence of these witnesses:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an acknowledgment in an individual capacity:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The foregoing instrument was acknowledged before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person acknowledging)</Directions> and subscribed by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of notary)</Directions> at the direction of and in the presence of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person acknowledging)</Directions>, and in the presence of these witnesses:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ch. 3874, 1889; RS 221; GS 306; RGS 417; CGL 483; s. 8, ch. 81-260; s. 4, ch. 91-291; s. 3, ch. 92-209; s. 4, ch. 93-62; s. 747, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 97-241; s. 33, ch. 98-129; s. 5, ch. 98-246; s. 46, ch. 99-2; s. 7, ch. 2004-5.</History></Section>