<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0195.062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Manual of instructions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare and maintain a current manual of instructions for property appraisers and other officials connected with the administration of property taxes. This manual shall contain all:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules and regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standard measures of value.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forms and instructions relating to the use of forms and maps.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Consistent with s. 195.032, the standard measures of value shall be adopted in general conformity with the procedures set forth in s. 120.54, but shall not have the force or effect of such rules and shall be used only to assist tax officers in the assessment of property as provided by s. 195.002. Guidelines may be updated annually to incorporate new market data, which may be in tabular form, technical changes, changes indicated by established decisions of the Supreme Court, and, if a summary of justification is set forth in the notice required under s. 120.54, other changes relevant to appropriate assessment practices or standard measurement of value. Such new data may be incorporated into the guidelines on the approval of the executive director if after notice in substantial conformity with s. 120.54 there is no objection filed with the department within 45 days, and the procedures set forth in s. 120.54 do not apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may also include in such manual any other information which it deems pertinent or helpful in the administration of taxes. Such manual shall instruct that the mere recordation of a plat on previously unplatted acreage shall not be construed as evidence of sufficient change in the character of the land to require reassessment until such time as development is begun on the platted acreage. Such manual shall be made available for distribution to the public at a nominal cost, to include cost of printing and circulation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 41, ch. 70-243; s. 1, ch. 71-367; s. 2, ch. 73-172; s. 9, ch. 74-234; s. 1, ch. 75-12; s. 10, ch. 76-234; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 5, ch. 2002-18; s. 3, ch. 2004-349.</History></Section>