<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0195.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Forms to be prescribed by Department of Revenue.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall prescribe all forms to be used by property appraisers, tax collectors, clerks of the circuit court, and value adjustment boards in administering and collecting ad valorem taxes. The department shall prescribe a form for each purpose. The county officer shall reproduce forms for distribution at the expense of his or her office. A county officer may use a form other than the form prescribed by the department upon obtaining written permission from the executive director of the department; however, a county officer may not use a form if the substantive content of the form varies from the form prescribed by the department for the same or a similar purpose. If the executive director finds good cause to grant such permission he or she may do so. The county officer may continue to use the approved form until the law that specifies the form is amended or repealed or until the officer receives written disapproval from the executive director. Otherwise, all such officers and their employees shall use the forms, and follow the instructions applicable to the forms, which are prescribed by the department. Upon request of any property appraiser or, in any event, at least once every 3 years, the department shall prescribe and furnish such aerial photographs and nonproperty ownership maps to the property appraisers as necessary to ensure that all real property within the state is properly listed on the roll. All photographs and maps furnished to counties with a population of 25,000 or fewer shall be paid for by the department as provided by law. For counties with a population greater than 25,000, the department shall furnish such items at the property appraiser’s expense. The department may incur reasonable expenses for procuring aerial photographs and nonproperty ownership maps and may charge a fee to the respective property appraiser equal to the cost incurred. The department shall deposit such fees into the Certification Program Trust Fund created pursuant to s. 195.002. There shall be a separate account in the trust fund for the aid and assistance activity of providing aerial photographs and nonproperty ownership maps to property appraisers. The department shall use money in the fund to pay such expenses. All forms and maps and instructions relating to their use must be substantially uniform throughout the state. An officer may employ supplemental forms and maps, at the expense of his or her office, which he or she deems expedient for the purpose of administering and collecting ad valorem taxes. The forms required in ss. 193.461(3)(a) and 196.011(1) for renewal purposes must require sufficient information for the property appraiser to evaluate the changes in use since the prior year. If the property appraiser determines, in the case of a taxpayer, that he or she has insufficient current information upon which to approve the exemption, or if the information on the renewal form is inadequate for him or her to evaluate the taxable status of the property, he or she may require the resubmission of an original application.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 70-243; s. 4, ch. 73-172; s. 7, ch. 74-234; s. 10, ch. 76-133; s. 2, ch. 78-185; s. 1, ch. 78-193; s. 153, ch. 91-112; s. 8, ch. 93-132; ss. 70, 71, ch. 2003-399; s. 1, ch. 2004-22; s. 2, ch. 2008-138; s. 1, ch. 2009-67.</History></Section>