<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0477.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Cosmetology.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the department the Board of Cosmetology consisting of seven members, who shall be appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate, and whose function it shall be to carry out the provisions of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five members of the board shall be licensed cosmetologists and shall have been engaged in the practice of cosmetology in this state for not less than 5 years. Two members of the board shall be laypersons. Each board member shall be a resident of this state and shall have been a resident of this state for not less than 5 continuous years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor may at any time fill vacancies on the board for the remainder of unexpired terms. Each member of the board shall hold over after the expiration of his or her term until a successor is duly appointed and qualified. No board member shall serve more than two consecutive terms, whether full or partial.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before assuming his or her duties as a board member, each appointee shall take the constitutional oath of office and shall file it with the Department of State, which shall then issue to such member a certificate of his or her appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall, in the month of January, elect from its number a chair and a vice chair.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall hold such meetings during the year as it may determine to be necessary, one of which shall be the annual meeting. The chair of the board shall have the authority to call other meetings at his or her discretion. A quorum of the board shall consist of not less than four members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board shall receive $50 for each day spent in the performance of official board business, with the total annual compensation per member not to exceed $2,000. Additionally, board members shall receive per diem and mileage as provided in s. 112.061, from place of residence to place of meeting and return.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each board member shall be held accountable to the Governor for the proper performance of all his or her duties and obligations. The Governor shall investigate any complaints or unfavorable reports received concerning the actions of the board, or its members, and shall take appropriate action thereon, which action may include removal of any board member. The Governor may remove from office any board member for neglect of duty, incompetence, or unprofessional or dishonorable conduct.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-253; ss. 13, 15, 25, 30, 34, 39, 62, ch. 80-406; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 23, 35, 36, ch. 85-297; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 167, ch. 94-218; s. 402, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>