<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0477.0135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not apply to the following persons when practicing pursuant to their professional or occupational responsibilities and duties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons authorized under the laws of this state to practice medicine, surgery, osteopathic medicine, chiropractic medicine, massage, naturopathy, or podiatric medicine.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commissioned medical or surgical officers of the United States Armed Forces hospital services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registered nurses under the laws of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons practicing barbering under the laws of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons employed in federal, state, or local institutions, hospitals, or military bases as cosmetologists whose practices are limited to the inmates, patients, or authorized military personnel of such institutions, hospitals, or bases.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons whose practice is limited to the application of cosmetic products to another person in connection with the sale, or attempted sale, of such products at retail without compensation from such other person other than the regular retail price of such merchandise.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license is not required of any person whose occupation or practice is confined solely to shampooing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license or registration is not required of any person whose occupation or practice is confined solely to cutting, trimming, polishing, or cleansing the fingernails of any person when said cutting, trimming, polishing, or cleansing is done in a barbershop licensed pursuant to chapter 476 which is carrying on a regular and customary business of barbering, and such individual has been practicing the activities set forth in this subsection prior to October 1, 1985.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A photography studio salon is exempt from the licensure provisions of this chapter. However, the hair-arranging services of such salon must be performed under the supervision of a licensed cosmetologist employed by the salon. The salon must use disposable hair-arranging implements or use a wet or dry sanitizing system approved by the federal Environmental Protection Agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license is not required of any individual providing makeup, special effects, or cosmetology services to an actor, stunt person, musician, extra, or other talent during a production recognized by the Office of Film and Entertainment as a qualified production as defined in s. 288.1254(1). Such services are not required to be performed in a licensed salon. Individuals exempt under this subsection may not provide such services to the general public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license is not required of any individual providing makeup or special effects services in a theme park or entertainment complex to an actor, stunt person, musician, extra, or other talent, or providing makeup or special effects services to the general public. The term “theme park or entertainment complex” has the same meaning as in s. 509.013(9).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 68, 117, ch. 83-329; ss. 22, 35, 36, ch. 85-297; s. 2, ch. 87-69; s. 28, ch. 88-392; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 401, ch. 97-103; s. 54, ch. 97-264; ss. 217, 285, ch. 98-166; s. 9, ch. 98-323; s. 1, ch. 2004-284; s. 126, ch. 2008-4.</History></Section>