<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0477.028" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have the power to revoke or suspend the license of a cosmetologist licensed under this chapter, or the registration of a specialist registered under this chapter, and to reprimand, censure, deny subsequent licensure or registration of, or otherwise discipline a cosmetologist or a specialist licensed or registered under this chapter in any of the following cases:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proof that a license or registration has been obtained by fraud or misrepresentation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proof that the holder of a license or registration is guilty of fraud or deceit or of gross negligence, incompetency, or misconduct in the practice or instruction of cosmetology or a specialty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proof that the holder of a license or registration is guilty of aiding, assisting, procuring, or advising any unlicensed person to practice as a cosmetologist.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have the power to revoke or suspend the license of a cosmetology salon or a specialty salon licensed under this chapter, to deny subsequent licensure of such salon, or to reprimand, censure, or otherwise discipline the owner of such salon in either of the following cases:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proof that a license has been obtained by fraud or misrepresentation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon proof that the holder of a license is guilty of fraud or deceit or of gross negligence, incompetency, or misconduct in the operation of the salon so licensed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary proceedings shall be conducted pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue or renew a license or certificate of registration under this chapter to any person against whom or salon against which the board has assessed a fine, interest, or costs associated with investigation and prosecution until the person or salon has paid in full such fine, interest, or costs associated with investigation and prosecution or until the person or salon complies with or satisfies all terms and conditions of the final order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-253; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 73, ch. 83-329; ss. 32, 35, 36, ch. 85-297; s. 7, ch. 87-69; s. 44, ch. 89-344; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 16, ch. 98-323.</History></Section>