<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0477.013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Cosmetology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cosmetologist” means a person who is licensed to engage in the practice of cosmetology in this state under the authority of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cosmetology” means the mechanical or chemical treatment of the head, face, and scalp for aesthetic rather than medical purposes, including, but not limited to, hair shampooing, hair cutting, hair arranging, hair coloring, permanent waving, and hair relaxing for compensation. This term also includes performing hair removal, including wax treatments, manicures, pedicures, and skin care services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Specialist” means any person holding a specialty registration in one or more of the specialties registered under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Specialty” means the practice of one or more of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manicuring, or the cutting, polishing, tinting, coloring, cleansing, adding, or extending of the nails, and massaging of the hands. This term includes any procedure or process for the affixing of artificial nails, except those nails which may be applied solely by use of a simple adhesive.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pedicuring, or the shaping, polishing, tinting, or cleansing of the nails of the feet, and massaging or beautifying of the feet.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facials, or the massaging or treating of the face or scalp with oils, creams, lotions, or other preparations, and skin care services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Shampooing” means the washing of the hair with soap and water or with a special preparation, or applying hair tonics.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Specialty salon” means any place of business wherein the practice of one or all of the specialties as defined in subsection (6) are engaged in or carried on.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hair braiding” means the weaving or interweaving of natural human hair for compensation without cutting, coloring, permanent waving, relaxing, removing, or chemical treatment and does not include the use of hair extensions or wefts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hair wrapping” means the wrapping of manufactured materials around a strand or strands of human hair, for compensation, without cutting, coloring, permanent waving, relaxing, removing, weaving, chemically treating, braiding, using hair extensions, or performing any other service defined as cosmetology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Photography studio salon” means an establishment where the hair-arranging services and the application of cosmetic products are performed solely for the purpose of preparing the model or client for the photographic session without shampooing, cutting, coloring, permanent waving, relaxing, or removing of hair or performing any other service defined as cosmetology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Body wrapping” means a treatment program that uses herbal wraps for the purposes of cleansing and beautifying the skin of the body, but does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of oils, lotions, or other fluids to the body, except fluids contained in presoaked materials used in the wraps; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manipulation of the body’s superficial tissue, other than that arising from compression emanating from the wrap materials.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Skin care services” means the treatment of the skin of the body, other than the head, face, and scalp, by the use of a sponge, brush, cloth, or similar device to apply or remove a chemical preparation or other substance, except that chemical peels may be removed by peeling an applied preparation from the skin by hand. Skin care services must be performed by a licensed cosmetologist or facial specialist within a licensed cosmetology or specialty salon, and such services may not involve massage, as defined in s. 480.033(3), through manipulation of the superficial tissue.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-253; ss. 13, 15, 25, 30, 34, 38, 62, ch. 80-406; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 21, 35, 36, ch. 85-297; s. 1, ch. 87-69; s. 35, ch. 89-344; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 150, ch. 94-119; s. 166, ch. 94-218; s. 66, ch. 95-144; s. 7, ch. 98-323; s. 146, ch. 99-251; s. 68, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>