<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0477.0132" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hair braiding, hair wrapping, and body wrapping registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons whose occupation or practice is confined solely to hair braiding must register with the department, pay the applicable registration fee, and take a two-day 16-hour course. The course shall be board approved and consist of 5 hours of HIV/AIDS and other communicable diseases, 5 hours of sanitation and sterilization, 4 hours of disorders and diseases of the scalp, and 2 hours of studies regarding laws affecting hair braiding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons whose occupation or practice is confined solely to hair wrapping must register with the department, pay the applicable registration fee, and take a one-day 6-hour course. The course shall be board approved and consist of education in HIV/AIDS and other communicable diseases, sanitation and sterilization, disorders and diseases of the scalp, and studies regarding laws affecting hair wrapping.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise licensed or exempted from licensure under this chapter, any person whose occupation or practice is body wrapping must register with the department, pay the applicable registration fee, and take a two-day 12-hour course. The course shall be board approved and consist of education in HIV/AIDS and other communicable diseases, sanitation and sterilization, disorders and diseases of the skin, and studies regarding laws affecting body wrapping.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only the board may review, evaluate, and approve a course required of an applicant for registration under this subsection in the occupation or practice of hair braiding, hair wrapping, or body wrapping. A provider of such a course is not required to hold a license under chapter 1005.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hair braiding, hair wrapping, and body wrapping are not required to be practiced in a cosmetology salon or specialty salon. When hair braiding, hair wrapping, or body wrapping is practiced outside a cosmetology salon or specialty salon, disposable implements must be used or all implements must be sanitized in a disinfectant approved for hospital use or approved by the federal Environmental Protection Agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pending issuance of registration, a person is eligible to practice hair braiding, hair wrapping, or body wrapping upon submission of a registration application that includes proof of successful completion of the education requirements and payment of the applicable fees required by this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 151, ch. 94-119; s. 8, ch. 98-323; s. 147, ch. 99-251; s. 53, ch. 2000-356; s. 1021, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>