<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.189" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Establishment of municipal and county speed zones.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MUNICIPAL SPEED.<EmDash />The maximum speed within any municipality is 30 miles per hour. With respect to residence districts, a municipality may set a maximum speed limit of 20 or 25 miles per hour on local streets and highways after an investigation determines that such a limit is reasonable. It shall not be necessary to conduct a separate investigation for each residence district. A municipality may set speed zones altering the speed limit, both as to maximum, not to exceed 60 miles per hour, and minimum, after investigation determines such a change is reasonable and in conformity to criteria promulgated by the Department of Transportation, except that no changes shall be made on state highways or connecting links or extensions thereof, which shall be changed only by the Department of Transportation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SPEED ON COUNTY ROADS.<EmDash />The maximum speed on any county-maintained road is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any business or residence district, 30 miles per hour in the daytime or nighttime; provided that with respect to residence districts a county may set a maximum speed limit of 25 miles per hour after an investigation determines that such a limit is reasonable; and it shall not be necessary to conduct a separate investigation in each residence district.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On any other part of a county road not a business or residence district, as set forth in s. 316.183.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, the board of county commissioners may set speed zones altering such speeds, both as to maximum and minimum, after investigation determines such a change is reasonable and in conformity to criteria promulgated by the Department of Transportation, except that no such speed zone shall permit a speed of more than 60 miles per hour.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POSTING OF SPEED LIMITS.<EmDash />All speed zones shall be posted with clearly legible signs. No change in speeds from 30 miles per hour or from those established in s. 316.183 shall take effect until the zone is posted by the authority changing the speed pursuant to this section and s. 316.187. All signs which limit or establish speed limits, maximum and minimum, shall be so placed and so painted as to be plainly visible and legible in daylight or in darkness when illuminated by headlights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PENALTY.<EmDash />Violation of the speed limits established under this section must be cited as a moving violation, punishable as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; ss. 1, 19, ch. 76-31; s. 2, ch. 76-218; s. 1, ch. 88-47; s. 22, ch. 90-227; s. 48, ch. 96-323; s. 22, ch. 96-350.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.182.</Text></Note></Section>