<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0316.1001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of toll on toll facilities required; penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not use any toll facility without payment of tolls, except as provided in s. 338.155. Failure to pay a prescribed toll is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation under chapter 318.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of enforcing this section, any governmental entity, as defined in s. 334.03, that owns or operates a toll facility may, by rule or ordinance, authorize a toll enforcement officer to issue a uniform traffic citation for a violation of this section. Toll enforcement officer means the designee of a governmental entity whose authority is to enforce the payment of tolls. The governmental entity may designate toll enforcement officers pursuant to s. 316.640(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A citation issued under this subsection may be issued by mailing the citation by first-class mail or by certified mail to the address of the registered owner of the motor vehicle involved in the violation. Mailing the citation to such address constitutes notification. In the case of joint ownership of a motor vehicle, the traffic citation must be mailed to the first name appearing on the registration, unless the first name appearing on the registration is a business organization, in which case the second name appearing on the registration may be used. A citation issued under this paragraph must be mailed to the registered owner of the motor vehicle involved in the violation within 14 days after the date of issuance of the citation. In addition to the citation, notification must be sent to the registered owner of the motor vehicle involved in the violation specifying remedies available under ss. 318.14(12) and 318.18(7).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of the motor vehicle involved in the violation is responsible and liable for payment of a citation issued for failure to pay a toll, unless the owner can establish the motor vehicle was, at the time of the violation, in the care, custody, or control of another person. In order to establish such facts, the owner of the motor vehicle is required, within 14 days after the date of issuance of the citation, to furnish to the appropriate governmental entity an affidavit setting forth:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, date of birth, and, if known, the driver license number of the person who leased, rented, or otherwise had the care, custody, or control of the motor vehicle at the time of the alleged violation; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If stolen, the police report indicating that the vehicle was stolen at the time of the alleged violation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Upon receipt of an affidavit the person designated as having care, custody, and control of the motor vehicle at the time of the violation may be issued a citation for failure to pay a required toll. The affidavit shall be admissible in a proceeding pursuant to this section for the purpose of providing that the person identified in the affidavit was in actual care, custody, or control of the motor vehicle. The owner of a leased vehicle for which a citation is issued for failure to pay a toll is not responsible for payment of the citation and is not required to submit an affidavit as specified in this subsection if the motor vehicle involved in the violation is registered in the name of the lessee of such motor vehicle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written report of a toll enforcement officer to photographic evidence that a required toll was not paid is admissible in any proceeding to enforce this section and raises a rebuttable presumption that the motor vehicle named in the report or shown in the photographic evidence was used in violation of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The submission of a false affidavit is a misdemeanor of the second degree.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any governmental entity, including, without limitation, a clerk of court, may provide the department with data that is machine readable by the department’s computer system, listing persons who have one or more outstanding violations of this section, with reference to the person’s driver’s license number or vehicle registration number in the case of a business entity. Pursuant to s. 320.03(8), those persons may not be issued a license plate or revalidation sticker for any motor vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (2)-(4) supplement the enforcement of this section by law enforcement officers, and this section does not prohibit a law enforcement officer from issuing a citation for a violation of this section in accordance with normal traffic enforcement techniques.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 85-184; s. 16, ch. 93-164; s. 15, ch. 96-350; s. 26, ch. 97-300; s. 10, ch. 2003-286; s. 8, ch. 2006-290; s. 9, ch. 2010-225; s. 17, ch. 2012-174.</History>
</Section>