<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Equipment for motorcycle and moped riders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not operate or ride upon a motorcycle unless the person is properly wearing protective headgear securely fastened upon his or her head which complies with Federal Motorcycle Vehicle Safety Standard 218 promulgated by the United States Department of Transportation. The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall adopt this standard by agency rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not operate a motorcycle unless the person is wearing an eye-protective device over his or her eyes of a type approved by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to persons riding within an enclosed cab or to any person 16 years of age or older who is operating or riding upon a motorcycle powered by a motor with a displacement of 50 cubic centimeters or less or is rated not in excess of 2 brake horsepower and which is not capable of propelling such motorcycle at a speed greater than 30 miles per hour on level ground.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), a person over 21 years of age may operate or ride upon a motorcycle without wearing protective headgear securely fastened upon his or her head if such person is covered by an insurance policy providing for at least $10,000 in medical benefits for injuries incurred as a result of a crash while operating or riding on a motorcycle.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person under 16 years of age may not operate or ride upon a moped unless the person is properly wearing protective headgear securely fastened upon his or her head which complies with Federal Motorcycle Vehicle Safety Standard 218 promulgated by the United States Department of Transportation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall make available a list of protective headgear approved in this section, and the list shall be provided on request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each motorcycle registered to a person under 21 years of age must display a license plate that is unique in design and color.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 1, ch. 85-329; s. 23, ch. 87-161; s. 2, ch. 88-405; s. 321, ch. 95-148; ss. 4, 167, ch. 99-248; s. 6, ch. 2000-313; s. 13, ch. 2006-290.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.287.</Text></Note></Section>