<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.1575" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obedience to traffic control devices at railroad-highway grade crossings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person walking or driving a vehicle and approaching a railroad-highway grade crossing under any of the circumstances stated in this section shall stop within 50 feet but not less than 15 feet from the nearest rail of such railroad and shall not proceed until he or she can do so safely. The foregoing requirements apply when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clearly visible electric or mechanical signal device gives warning of the immediate approach of a railroad train;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A crossing gate is lowered or a law enforcement officer or a human flagger gives or continues to give a signal of the approach or passage of a railroad train;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An approaching railroad train emits an audible signal or the railroad train, by reason of its speed or nearness to the crossing, is an immediate hazard; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An approaching railroad train is plainly visible and is in hazardous proximity to the railroad-highway grade crossing, regardless of the type of traffic control devices installed at the crossing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall drive any vehicle through, around, or under any crossing gate or barrier at a railroad-highway grade crossing while the gate or barrier is closed or is being opened or closed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable pursuant to chapter 318 as either a pedestrian violation or, if the infraction resulted from the operation of a vehicle, as a moving violation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 6, ch. 86-243; s. 310, ch. 95-148; s. 132, ch. 99-248; s. 2, ch. 2008-176.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.054.</Text></Note></Section>