<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Crashes involving damage to vehicle or property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The driver of any vehicle involved in a crash resulting only in damage to a vehicle or other property which is driven or attended by any person shall immediately stop such vehicle at the scene of such crash or as close thereto as possible, and shall forthwith return to, and in every event shall remain at, the scene of the crash until he or she has fulfilled the requirements of s. 316.062. A person who violates this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, $5 shall be added to a fine imposed pursuant to this section, which $5 shall be deposited in the Emergency Medical Services Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every stop must be made without obstructing traffic more than is necessary, and, if a damaged vehicle is obstructing traffic, the driver of such vehicle must make every reasonable effort to move the vehicle or have it moved so as not to block the regular flow of traffic. Any person failing to comply with this subsection shall be cited for a nonmoving violation, punishable as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employees or authorized agents of the Department of Transportation, law enforcement with proper jurisdiction, or an expressway authority created pursuant to chapter 348, in the exercise, management, control, and maintenance of its highway system, may undertake the removal from the main traveled way of roads on its highway system of all vehicles incapacitated as a result of a motor vehicle crash and of debris caused thereby. Such removal is applicable when such a motor vehicle crash results only in damage to a vehicle or other property, and when such removal can be accomplished safely and will result in the improved safety or convenience of travel upon the road. The driver or any other person who has removed a motor vehicle from the main traveled way of the road as provided in this section shall not be considered liable or at fault regarding the cause of the accident solely by reason of moving the vehicle.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 3, ch. 74-377; s. 2, ch. 75-72; s. 9, ch. 76-31; s. 22, ch. 85-167; s. 3, ch. 85-337; s. 30, ch. 92-78; s. 296, ch. 95-148; s. 6, ch. 96-350; s. 83, ch. 99-248; s. 3, ch. 2002-235.</History></Section>