<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.2127" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Operation of utility vehicles on certain roadways by homeowners’ associations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation of a utility vehicle, as defined in s. 320.01, upon the public roads or streets of this state by a homeowners’ association, as defined in s. 720.301, or its agents is prohibited except as provided herein:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A utility vehicle may be operated by a homeowners’ association or its agents only upon a county road that has been designated by a county, or a city street that has been designated by a city, for use by a utility vehicle for general maintenance, security, and landscaping purposes. Prior to making such a designation, the responsible local governmental entity must first determine that utility vehicles may safely travel on or cross the public road or street, considering factors including the speed, volume, and character of motor vehicle traffic on the road or street. Upon a determination that utility vehicles may be safely operated on a designated road or street, the responsible governmental entity shall post appropriate signs to indicate that such operation is allowed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A utility vehicle may be operated by a homeowners’ association or its agents on a portion of the State Highway System only under the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To cross a portion of the State Highway System which intersects a county road or a city street that has been designated for use by utility vehicles if the Department of Transportation has reviewed and approved the location and design of the crossing and any traffic control devices needed for safety purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To cross, at midblock, a portion of the State Highway System where the highway bisects property controlled or maintained by a homeowners’ association if the Department of Transportation has reviewed and approved the location and design of the crossing and any traffic control devices needed for safety purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To travel on a state road that has been designated for transfer to a local government unit pursuant to s. 335.0415 if the Department of Transportation determines that the operation of a utility vehicle within the right-of-way of the road will not impede the safe and efficient flow of motor vehicle traffic. The department may authorize the operation of utility vehicles on such a road if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The road is the only available public road on which utility vehicles may travel or cross or the road provides the safest travel route among alternative routes available; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The speed, volume, and character of motor vehicle traffic on the road is considered in making such a determination.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Upon its determination that utility vehicles may be operated on a given road, the department shall post appropriate signs on the road to indicate that such operation is allowed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A utility vehicle may be operated by a homeowners’ association or its agents only during the hours between sunrise and sunset, unless the responsible governmental entity has determined that a utility vehicle may be operated during the hours between sunset and sunrise and the utility vehicle is equipped with headlights, brake lights, turn signals, and a windshield.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A utility vehicle must be equipped with efficient brakes, a reliable steering apparatus, safe tires, a rearview mirror, and red reflectorized warning devices in both the front and the rear.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A utility vehicle may not be operated on public roads or streets by any person under the age of 14.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable pursuant to chapter 318 as either a moving violation for infractions of subsection (1), subsection (2), subsection (3), or subsection (4) or as a nonmoving violation for infractions of subsection (5).</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 104, ch. 2002-20.</History></Section>