<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.233" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Spot lamps and auxiliary lamps.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SPOT LAMPS.<EmDash />Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two spot lamps and every lighted spot lamp shall be so aimed and used that no part of the high intensity portion of the beam will strike the windshield, or any windows, mirror, or occupant of another vehicle in use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOG LAMPS.<EmDash />Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two fog lamps mounted on the front at a height not less than 12 inches nor more than 30 inches above the level surface upon which the vehicle stands and so aimed that when the vehicle is not loaded none of the high intensity portion of the light to the left of the center of the vehicle shall at a distance of 25 feet ahead project higher than a level of 4 inches below the level of the center of the lamp from which it comes. Lighted fog lamps meeting the above requirements may be used with lower headlamp beams as specified in s. 316.237(1)(b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUXILIARY PASSING LAMPS.<EmDash />Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two auxiliary passing lamps mounted on the front at a height not less than 24 inches nor more than 42 inches above the level surface upon which the vehicle stands. The provisions of s. 316.237 shall apply to any combination of headlamps and auxiliary passing lamps.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUXILIARY DRIVING LAMPS.<EmDash />Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not to exceed two auxiliary driving lamps mounted on the front at a height not less than 16 inches nor more than 42 inches above the level surface upon which the vehicle stands. The provisions of s. 316.237 shall apply to any combination of headlamps and auxiliary driving lamps.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VIOLATIONS.<EmDash />A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 183, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>