<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.217" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">When lighted lamps are required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every vehicle operated upon a highway within this state shall display lighted lamps and illuminating devices as herein respectively required for different classes of vehicles, subject to exceptions with respect to parked vehicles, under the following conditions;</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time from sunset to sunrise including the twilight hours. Twilight hours shall mean the time between sunset and full night or between full night and sunrise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During any rain, smoke, or fog.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stop lights, turn signals, and other signaling devices shall be lighted as prescribed for use of such devices.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever requirement is hereinafter declared as to the distance from which certain lamps and devices shall render objects visible, said provisions shall apply during the times stated in subsection (1) in respect to a vehicle without load when upon a straight, level, unlighted highway under normal atmospheric conditions, unless a different time or condition is expressly stated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever requirement is hereinafter declared as to the mounted height of lamps or devices, it shall mean from the center of such lamp or device to the level ground upon which the vehicle stands when the vehicle is without a load.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Law enforcement vehicles may be operated without the display of lighted lamps required by this chapter under the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operation without the display of lighted lamps is necessary to the performance of a law enforcement officer’s duties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law enforcement agency has a written policy authorizing and providing guidelines for vehicle operation without the display of lighted lamps.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law enforcement vehicle is operated in compliance with agency policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation without the display of lighted lamps may be safely accomplished.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The provisions of this subsection shall not relieve the operator of such a vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for the safety of all persons, nor shall such provisions protect the vehicle operator from the consequences of his or her reckless disregard for the safety of others.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 4, ch. 76-218; s. 22, ch. 94-306; s. 171, ch. 99-248; s. 1, ch. 2004-74.</History></Section>