<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.194" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Stopping, standing or parking outside of municipalities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon any highway outside of a municipality, no person shall stop, park, or leave standing any vehicle, whether attended or unattended, upon the paved or main-traveled part of the highway when it is practicable to stop, park, or so leave the vehicle off such part of the highway; but in every event an unobstructed width of the highway opposite a standing vehicle shall be left for the free passage of other vehicles, and a clear view of the stopped vehicle shall be available from a distance of 200 feet in each direction upon the highway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to the driver or owner of any vehicle which is disabled while on the paved or main-traveled portion of a highway in such manner and to such extent that it is impossible to avoid stopping and temporarily leaving the disabled vehicle in such position, or to passenger-carrying buses temporarily parked while loading or discharging passengers, where highway conditions render such parking off the paved portion of the highway hazardous or impractical.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any police officer or traffic accident investigation officer finds a vehicle standing upon a highway in violation of any of the foregoing provisions of this section, the officer is authorized to move the vehicle, or require the driver or other persons in charge of the vehicle to move the vehicle, to a position off the paved or main-traveled part of the highway.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Officers and traffic accident investigation officers may provide for the removal of any abandoned vehicle to the nearest garage or other place of safety, cost of such removal to be a lien against motor vehicle, when an abandoned vehicle is found unattended upon a bridge or causeway or in any tunnel, or on any public highway in the following instances:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where such vehicle constitutes an obstruction of traffic;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where such vehicle has been parked or stored on the public right-of-way for a period exceeding 48 hours, in other than designated parking areas, and is within 30 feet of the pavement edge; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where an operative vehicle has been parked or stored on the public right-of-way for a period exceeding 10 days, in other than designated parking areas, and is more than 30 feet from the pavement edge. However, the agency removing such vehicle shall be required to report same to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles within 24 hours of such removal.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vehicle moved under the provisions of this chapter which is a stolen vehicle shall not be subject to the provisions hereof unless the moving authority has reported to the Florida Highway Patrol the taking into possession of the vehicle within 24 hours of the moving of the vehicle.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 71-352; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 142, ch. 99-248; s. 35, ch. 2005-164.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.124.</Text></Note></Section>