<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.1906" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Radar speed-measuring devices; evidence, admissibility.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Audio Doppler” means a backup audible signal that translates the radar’s Doppler shift into a tone which can be heard by the radar operator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Audio warning tone” refers to an auxiliary radar device which alerts the operator, by means of an audible tone, to the presence of a speed registration above a preset level.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Automatic speed lock” refers to an auxiliary radar device which immediately holds any speed reading obtained above a preset level.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Officer” means any:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law enforcement officer” who is elected, appointed, or employed full time by any municipality or the state or any political subdivision thereof; who is vested with the authority to bear arms and make arrests; and whose primary responsibility is the prevention and detection of crime or the enforcement of the penal, criminal, traffic, or highway laws of the state;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Part-time law enforcement officer” who is employed or appointed less than full time, as defined by an employing agency, with or without compensation; who is vested with authority to bear arms and make arrests; and whose primary responsibility is the prevention and detection of crime or the enforcement of the penal, criminal, traffic, or highway laws of the state; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Auxiliary law enforcement officer” who is employed or appointed, with or without compensation; who aids or assists a full-time or part-time law enforcement officer; and who, while under the direct supervision of a full-time or part-time law enforcement officer, has the authority to arrest and perform law enforcement functions.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radar” means law enforcement speed radar, any laser-based or microwave-based speed-measurement system employed by a law enforcement agency to detect the speed of motorists.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of the speed of a vehicle measured by any radar speed-measuring device shall be inadmissible in any proceeding with respect to an alleged violation of provisions of law regulating the lawful speed of vehicles, unless such evidence of speed is obtained by an officer who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has satisfactorily completed the radar training course established by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission pursuant to s. 943.17(1)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made an independent visual determination that the vehicle is operating in excess of the applicable speed limit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has written a citation based on evidence obtained from radar when conditions permit the clear assignment of speed to a single vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is using radar which has no automatic speed locks and no audio alarms, unless disconnected or deactivated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is operating radar with audio Doppler engaged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is using a radar unit which meets the minimum design criteria for such units established by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-276; s. 24, ch. 84-258; s. 1, ch. 92-193.</History></Section>