<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.304" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Wearing of headsets.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall operate a vehicle while wearing a headset, headphone, or other listening device, other than a hearing aid or instrument for the improvement of defective human hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer equipped with any communication device necessary in performing his or her assigned duties or to any emergency vehicle operator equipped with any ear protection device.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any applicant for a license to operate a motorcycle while taking the examination required by s. 322.12(5).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person operating a motorcycle who is using a headset that is installed in a helmet and worn so as to prevent the speakers from making direct contact with the user’s ears so that the user can hear surrounding sounds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person using a headset in conjunction with a cellular telephone that only provides sound through one ear and allows surrounding sounds to be heard with the other ear.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person using a headset in conjunction with communicating with the central base operation that only provides sound through one ear and allows surrounding sounds to be heard with the other ear.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall promulgate, by administrative rule, standards and specifications for headset equipment the use of which is permitted under this section. The department shall inspect and review all such devices submitted to it and shall publish a list by name and type of approved equipment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-4; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 8, ch. 83-228; s. 4, ch. 84-284; s. 2, ch. 85-329; s. 24, ch. 87-161; s. 3, ch. 88-405; s. 3, ch. 92-18; s. 24, ch. 95-143; s. 327, ch. 95-148; s. 219, ch. 99-248; s. 105, ch. 2002-20.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.0285.</Text></Note></Section>