<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.172" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Traffic to stop for school bus.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person using, operating, or driving a vehicle on or over the roads or highways of this state shall, upon approaching any school bus which displays a stop signal, bring such vehicle to a full stop while the bus is stopped, and the vehicle shall not pass the school bus until the signal has been withdrawn. A person who violates this section commits a moving violation, punishable as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person using, operating, or driving a vehicle that passes a school bus on the side that children enter and exit when the school bus displays a stop signal commits a moving violation, punishable as provided in chapter 318, and is subject to a mandatory hearing under the provisions of s. 318.19.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The driver of a vehicle upon a divided highway with an unpaved space of at least 5 feet, a raised median, or a physical barrier is not required to stop when traveling in the opposite direction of a school bus which is stopped in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every school bus shall stop as far to the right of the street as possible and shall display warning lights and stop signals as required by rules of the State Board of Education before discharging or loading passengers. When possible, a school bus shall not stop where the visibility is obscured for a distance of 200 feet either way from the bus.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 89, ch. 77-104; s. 3, ch. 85-309; s. 1, ch. 87-167; s. 23, ch. 95-143; s. 19, ch. 96-350; s. 1, ch. 97-10.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.139.</Text></Note></Section>