<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.2954" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Windows behind the driver; restrictions on sunscreening material.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person shall not operate any motor vehicle on any public highway, road, or street on which vehicle any windows behind the driver are composed of, covered by, or treated with any sunscreening material, or other product or material which has the effect of making the window nontransparent or which would alter the window’s color, increase its reflectivity, or reduce its light transmittance, except as specified below:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sunscreening material consisting of film which, when applied to and tested on the rear window glass of the specific motor vehicle, has a total solar reflectance of visible light of not more than 35 percent as measured on the nonfilm side and a light transmittance of at least 15 percent in the visible light range; however, sunscreening material which, when applied to and tested on the rear window glass of the specific motor vehicle, has a total solar reflectance of visible light of not more than 35 percent as measured on the nonfilm side and a light transmittance of at least 6 percent in the visible light range may be used on multipurpose passenger vehicles.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perforated sunscreening material which, when tested in conjunction with existing glazing or film material, has a total reflectance of visible light of not more than 35 percent and a light transmittance of no less than 30 percent. For those products or materials having different levels of reflectance, the highest reflectance from the product or material will be measured by dividing the area into 16 equal sections and averaging the overall reflectance. The measured reflectance of any of those sections may not exceed 50 percent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Louvered materials, if the installation of the materials does not reduce driver visibility by more than 50 percent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Privacy drapes, curtains and blinds, provided such covering is in an open and secure position when the motor vehicle is being operated on any public highway, road, or street.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person shall not operate any motor vehicle upon any public highway, road, or street, on which vehicle the rear window is composed of, covered by, or treated with any material which has the effect of making the window nontransparent, unless the vehicle is equipped with side mirrors on both sides that meet the requirements of s. 316.294.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-296; s. 2, ch. 91-42; s. 210, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>