<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.2951" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Motor vehicle windows; definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever used in ss. 316.2951-316.2957, unless the context otherwise requires, the following terms have the following meanings:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motor vehicle” means any vehicle as defined in s. 316.003, except vehicles used in farm husbandry, which is registered or required to be registered in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Multipurpose passenger vehicle” means a motor vehicle with motive power designed to carry 10 persons or fewer which is constructed either on a truck chassis or with special features for occasional off-road operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Reflectance” means the ratio of the amount of total light, expressed in a percentage, which is reflected outward by the product or material to the amount of total light falling on the product or material.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sunscreening material” means a product or material, including film, glazing, and perforated sunscreening, which, when applied to the windshield or windows of a motor vehicle, reduces the effects of the sun with respect to light reflectance or transmittance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transmittance” means the ratio of the amount of total light, expressed in a percentage, which is allowed to pass through the product or material, including glazing, to the amount of total light falling on the product or material and the glazing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Window” means any device designed for exterior viewing from a motor vehicle, except the windshield, any roof-mounted viewing device, and any viewing device having less than 150 square inches in area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Windshield” means the front exterior viewing device of a motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-296.</History></Section>