<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.6105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Violations involving operation of motor vehicle in unsafe condition or without required equipment; procedure for disposition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that a law enforcement officer issues a traffic citation for a violation of s. 316.2935 or for the operation of a motor vehicle which is in an unsafe condition or which is not properly equipped as required pursuant to s. 316.610, the law enforcement officer shall also issue an affidavit-of-compliance form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person to whom the citation has been issued may mitigate the civil penalty by making the necessary repair and presenting the vehicle to any local police department or sheriff’s department in this state for inspection within 30 days after the issuance of the citation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The police or sheriff’s department shall make available a person or persons to confirm that the defect has been corrected. If the correction has been made, such employee shall execute the affidavit-of-compliance form in a manner established by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles and return it to the person who received the citation. The person who received the citation shall, upon receipt of the executed affidavit of compliance, pay the appropriate fine to the law enforcement agency pursuant to s. 318.18(2)(c) thereby completing the affidavit of compliance. The affidavit of compliance shall not be construed by the courts as a warranty of the mechanical condition of the motor vehicle. Neither the person who confirms that a defect has been corrected nor the department by which he or she is employed shall be liable in damages for any defect, failure, or improper functioning of any item of equipment on such motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person to whom the citation was issued shall mail or present the traffic citation and the affidavit-of-compliance form to the clerk of the court where the traffic citation was issued and shall thereupon pay the appropriate fine pursuant to s. 318.18(2)(c).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that the person to whom the traffic citation has been issued chooses not to correct the defect, the procedure for the collection of the fine and any other penalties shall proceed as provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to commercial motor vehicles as defined in s. 316.003(66) or transit buses owned or operated by a governmental entity.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 86-260; s. 7, ch. 90-290; s. 1, ch. 91-136; s. 81, ch. 91-221; s. 329, ch. 95-148; s. 34, ch. 96-350.</History></Section>