<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.237" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Multiple-beam road-lighting equipment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as hereinafter provided, the headlamps or the auxiliary driving lamp or the auxiliary passing lamp or combination thereof on motor vehicles shall be so arranged that the driver may select at will between distributions of light projected to different elevations and such lamps may, in addition, be so arranged that such selection can be made automatically, subject to the following limitations:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be an uppermost distribution of light, or composite beam, so aimed and of such intensity as to reveal persons and vehicles at a distance of at least 450 feet ahead for all conditions of loading.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a lowermost distribution of light, or composite beam, so aimed and of sufficient intensity to reveal persons and vehicles at a distance of at least 150 feet ahead; and on a straight level road under any condition of loading none of the high intensity portion of the beam shall be directed to strike the eyes of an approaching driver.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">An object, material, or covering that alters the headlamp’s visibility from at least 450 feet for an uppermost distribution of light or at least 150 feet for a lowermost distribution of light may not be placed, displayed, installed, affixed, or applied over a headlamp.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every new motor vehicle registered in this state shall be equipped with a beam indicator, which shall be lighted whenever the uppermost distribution of light from the headlamps is in use, and shall not otherwise be lighted. Said indicator shall be so designed and located that when lighted it will be readily visible without glare to the driver of the vehicle so equipped.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 186, ch. 99-248; s. 13, ch. 2000-313.</History></Section>