<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0316.2126" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authorized use of golf carts, low-speed vehicles, and utility vehicles.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the powers granted by ss. 316.212 and 316.2125, municipalities are authorized to use golf carts and utility vehicles, as defined in s. 320.01, upon any state, county, or municipal roads located within the corporate limits of such municipalities, subject to the following conditions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts and utility vehicles must comply with the operational and safety requirements in ss. 316.212 and 316.2125, and with any more restrictive ordinances enacted by the local governmental entity pursuant to s. 316.212(8), and shall be operated only by municipal employees for municipal purposes, including, but not limited to, police patrol, traffic enforcement, and inspection of public facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the safety equipment required in s. 316.212(6) and any more restrictive safety equipment required by the local governmental entity pursuant to s. 316.212(8), such golf carts and utility vehicles must be equipped with sufficient lighting and turn signal equipment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts and utility vehicles may be operated only on state roads that have a posted speed limit of 30 miles per hour or less.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts and utility vehicles may cross a portion of the State Highway System which has a posted speed limit of 45 miles per hour or less only at an intersection with an official traffic control device.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts and utility vehicles may operate on sidewalks adjacent to state highways only if such golf carts and utility vehicles yield to pedestrians and if the sidewalks are at least 5 feet wide.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State employees, state park volunteers, and state park visitors are authorized to use golf carts and utility vehicles, as defined in s. 320.01, upon any public roads within the boundaries of state parks managed by the Division of Recreation and Parks of the Department of Environmental Protection, subject to the following conditions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts and utility vehicles must comply with the operational and safety requirements in s. 316.212.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts and utility vehicles shall be operated only by state employees and state park volunteers for state purposes and by state park visitors for uses authorized by the Division of Recreation and Parks of the Department of Environmental Protection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Golf cart” means a motor vehicle as defined in s. 320.01(22), including vehicles modified to have a cargo platform or bin to transport parcels or a hitch to tow a trailer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residential area” means areas zoned primarily or exclusively for single-family or multifamily residential use.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Seasonal delivery personnel” means employees of a licensed commercial delivery service that has at least 10,000 persons employed in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seasonal delivery personnel may use the following vehicles solely for the purpose of delivering express envelopes and packages having a maximum size of 130 inches for the combined length and girth and weighing not more than 150 pounds from midnight October 15 until midnight December 31 of each year:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Low-speed vehicles and utility vehicles as defined in s. 320.01 upon any public road within a residential area that has a posted speed limit of 35 miles per hour or less.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts upon a public road within a residential area that has a posted speed limit of 30 miles per hour or less.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Golf carts upon a public road within a residential area that has a posted speed limit of 30 to 35 miles per hour, unless a municipality having jurisdiction over the public road has enacted an ordinance restricting personnel from driving on such roads.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Seasonal delivery personnel may pull a trailer from any of these vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All vehicles specified in this subsection must be:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marked in a conspicuous manner with the name of the delivery service.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Equipped with, at a minimum, the equipment required under s. 316.212(6).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Equipped with head lamps and tail lamps, in addition to the safety requirements in s. 316.212(6), if operated after sunset.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Anyone operating a golf cart, low-speed vehicle, or utility vehicle pursuant to this section must possess a valid driver’s license as required by s. 322.03.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 96-413; s. 90, ch. 99-13; s. 4, ch. 99-163; s. 169, ch. 99-248; s. 7, ch. 2005-164; s. 5, ch. 2008-98; s. 1, ch. 2009-208; s. 8, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>