<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.530" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Towing requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When one vehicle is towing another vehicle the drawbar or other connection shall be of sufficient strength to pull all weight towed thereby, and said drawbar or other connection shall not exceed 15 feet from one vehicle to the other except the connection between any two vehicles transporting poles, pipe, machinery or other objects of structural nature which cannot readily be dismembered. When one vehicle is towing another vehicle and the connection consists of a chain, rope, or cable, there shall be displayed upon such connection a white flag or cloth not less than 12 inches square.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a vehicle is towing a trailer or semitrailer on a public road or highway by means of a trailer hitch to the rear of the vehicle, there shall be attached in addition thereto safety chains, cables, or other safety devices that comply with 49 C.F.R. subpart F, ss. 393.71(g)(2)(1) and 393.71(h)(10) from the trailer or semitrailer to the vehicle. These safety chains, cables, or other safety devices shall be of sufficient strength to maintain connection of the trailer or semitrailer to the pulling vehicle under all conditions while the trailer or semitrailer is being towed by the vehicle. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to trailers or semitrailers using a hitch known as a fifth wheel nor to farm equipment traveling less than 20 miles per hour.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a motor vehicle becomes disabled upon the highways of this state and a wrecker or tow truck is required to remove it to a repair shop or other appropriate location, if the combined weights of those two vehicles and the loads thereon exceed the maximum allowable weights as established by s. 316.535, no penalty shall be assessed either vehicle or driver. However, this exception shall not apply to the load limits for bridges and culverts established by the department as provided in s. 316.555.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 1, ch. 76-91; s. 124, ch. 79-400; s. 237, ch. 99-248; s. 17, ch. 2000-313.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.205.</Text></Note></Section>