<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.3045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Operation of radios or other mechanical soundmaking devices or instruments in vehicles; exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person operating or occupying a motor vehicle on a street or highway to operate or amplify the sound produced by a radio, tape player, or other mechanical soundmaking device or instrument from within the motor vehicle so that the sound is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plainly audible at a distance of 25 feet or more from the motor vehicle; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Louder than necessary for the convenient hearing by persons inside the vehicle in areas adjoining churches, schools, or hospitals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not apply to any law enforcement motor vehicle equipped with any communication device necessary in the performance of law enforcement duties or to any emergency vehicle equipped with any communication device necessary in the performance of any emergency procedures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section do not apply to motor vehicles used for business or political purposes, which in the normal course of conducting such business use soundmaking devices. The provisions of this subsection shall not be deemed to prevent local authorities, with respect to streets and highways under their jurisdiction and within the reasonable exercise of the police power, from regulating the time and manner in which such business may be operated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section do not apply to the noise made by a horn or other warning device required or permitted by s. 316.271. The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall promulgate rules defining “plainly audible” and establish standards regarding how sound should be measured by law enforcement personnel who enforce the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-256; s. 220, ch. 99-248; s. 9, ch. 2005-164.</History></Section>