<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.2074" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">All-terrain vehicles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature through the adoption of this section to provide safety protection for minors while operating an all-terrain vehicle in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “all-terrain vehicle” means any motorized off-highway vehicle 50 inches or less in width, having a dry weight of 1,200 pounds or less, designed to travel on three or more nonhighway tires, having a seat designed to be straddled by the operator and handlebars for steering control, and intended for use by a single operator with no passenger. For the purposes of this section, “all-terrain vehicle” also includes any “two-rider ATV” as defined in s. 317.0003.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person under 16 years of age shall operate, ride, or be otherwise propelled on an all-terrain vehicle unless the person wears a safety helmet meeting United States Department of Transportation standards and eye protection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a crash results in the death of any person or in the injury of any person which results in treatment of the person by a physician, the operator of each all-terrain vehicle involved in the crash shall give notice of the crash pursuant to s. 316.066.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, an all-terrain vehicle may not be operated upon the public roads, streets, or highways of this state, except as otherwise permitted by the managing state or federal agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An all-terrain vehicle having four wheels may be used by police officers on public beaches designated as public roadways for the purpose of enforcing the traffic laws of the state. All-terrain vehicles may also be used by the police to travel on public roadways within 5 miles of beach access only when getting to and from the beach.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An all-terrain vehicle having four wheels may be used by law enforcement officers on public roads within public lands while in the course and scope of their duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, ch. 88-221; s. 5, ch. 95-333; s. 30, ch. 96-350; s. 3, ch. 96-413; s. 162, ch. 99-248; s. 54, ch. 2002-295; s. 37, ch. 2005-164; s. 2, ch. 2009-137.</History></Section>