<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.1934" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Presumption of impairment; testing methods.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful and punishable as provided in chapter 322 and in s. 316.193 for any person who is under the influence of alcoholic beverages or controlled substances, when affected to the extent that the person’s normal faculties are impaired or to the extent that the person is deprived of full possession of normal faculties, to drive or be in actual physical control of any motor vehicle within this state. Such normal faculties include, but are not limited to, the ability to see, hear, walk, talk, judge distances, drive an automobile, make judgments, act in emergencies, and, in general, normally perform the many mental and physical acts of daily life.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the trial of any civil or criminal action or proceeding arising out of acts alleged to have been committed by any person while driving, or in actual physical control of, a vehicle while under the influence of alcoholic beverages or controlled substances, when affected to the extent that the person’s normal faculties were impaired or to the extent that he or she was deprived of full possession of his or her normal faculties, the results of any test administered in accordance with s. 316.1932 or s. 316.1933 and this section are admissible into evidence when otherwise admissible, and the amount of alcohol in the person’s blood or breath at the time alleged, as shown by chemical analysis of the person’s blood, or by chemical or physical test of the person’s breath, gives rise to the following presumptions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there was at that time a blood-alcohol level or breath-alcohol level of 0.05 or less, it is presumed that the person was not under the influence of alcoholic beverages to the extent that his or her normal faculties were impaired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there was at that time a blood-alcohol level or breath-alcohol level in excess of 0.05 but less than 0.08, that fact does not give rise to any presumption that the person was or was not under the influence of alcoholic beverages to the extent that his or her normal faculties were impaired but may be considered with other competent evidence in determining whether the person was under the influence of alcoholic beverages to the extent that his or her normal faculties were impaired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there was at that time a blood-alcohol level or breath-alcohol level of 0.08 or higher, that fact is prima facie evidence that the person was under the influence of alcoholic beverages to the extent that his or her normal faculties were impaired. Moreover, such person who has a blood-alcohol level or breath-alcohol level of 0.08 or higher is guilty of driving, or being in actual physical control of, a motor vehicle, with an unlawful blood-alcohol level or breath-alcohol level.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The presumptions provided in this subsection do not limit the introduction of any other competent evidence bearing upon the question of whether the person was under the influence of alcoholic beverages to the extent that his or her normal faculties were impaired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A chemical analysis of a person’s blood to determine alcoholic content or a chemical or physical test of a person’s breath, in order to be considered valid under this section, must have been performed substantially in accordance with methods approved by the Department of Law Enforcement and by an individual possessing a valid permit issued by the department for this purpose. Any insubstantial differences between approved techniques and actual testing procedures or any insubstantial defects concerning the permit issued by the department, in any individual case do not render the test or test results invalid. The Department of Law Enforcement may approve satisfactory techniques or methods, ascertain the qualifications and competence of individuals to conduct such analyses, and issue permits that are subject to termination or revocation in accordance with rules adopted by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person charged with a violation of s. 316.193, whether in a municipality or not, is entitled to trial by jury according to the Florida Rules of Criminal Procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affidavit containing the results of any test of a person’s blood or breath to determine its alcohol content, as authorized by s. 316.1932 or s. 316.1933, is admissible in evidence under the exception to the hearsay rule in s. 90.803(8) for public records and reports. Such affidavit is admissible without further authentication and is presumptive proof of the results of an authorized test to determine alcohol content of the blood or breath if the affidavit discloses:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of test administered and the procedures followed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time of the collection of the blood or breath sample analyzed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The numerical results of the test indicating the alcohol content of the blood or breath;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type and status of any permit issued by the Department of Law Enforcement which was held by the person who performed the test; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the test was administered by means of a breath testing instrument, the date of performance of the most recent required maintenance on such instrument.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Department of Law Enforcement shall provide a form for the affidavit. Admissibility of the affidavit does not abrogate the right of the person tested to subpoena the person who administered the test for examination as an adverse witness at a civil or criminal trial or other proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section prohibits the prosecution of a person under s. 322.62. The provisions of subsection (2) do not apply to such prosecution and the presumptions made pursuant to that subsection may not be introduced into evidence during such prosecution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 67-308; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 3, 4, ch. 70-279; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 3, ch. 74-384; s. 42, ch. 76-31; s. 1, ch. 76-153; s. 51, ch. 77-147; s. 5, ch. 82-155; s. 2, ch. 83-218; s. 5, ch. 84-359; s. 17, ch. 86-296; s. 5, ch. 88-5; s. 2, ch. 88-82; s. 27, ch. 89-282; s. 4, ch. 91-255; s. 22, ch. 92-58; ss. 2, 4, ch. 93-124; s. 316, ch. 95-148; s. 5, ch. 96-330.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 322.262.</Text></Note></Section>