<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.063" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duty upon damaging unattended vehicle or other property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The driver of any vehicle which collides with, or is involved in a crash with, any vehicle or other property which is unattended, resulting in any damage to such other vehicle or property, shall immediately stop and shall then and there either locate and notify the operator or owner of the vehicle or other property of the driver’s name and address and the registration number of the vehicle he or she is driving, or shall attach securely in a conspicuous place in or on the vehicle or other property a written notice giving the driver’s name and address and the registration number of the vehicle he or she is driving, and shall without unnecessary delay notify the nearest office of a duly authorized police authority. Any person who fails to comply with this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every such stop shall be made without obstructing traffic more than is necessary. If a damaged vehicle is obstructing traffic, the driver shall make every reasonable effort to move the vehicle or have it moved so as not to obstruct the regular flow of traffic. A violation of this subsection is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law enforcement officer at the scene of a crash required to be reported in accordance with the provisions of subsection (1) or the law enforcement officer receiving a report by a driver as required by subsection (1) shall, if part or any of the property damaged is a fence or other structure used to house or contain livestock, promptly make a reasonable effort to notify the owner, occupant, or agent of this damage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 3, ch. 75-72; s. 10, ch. 76-31; s. 1, ch. 77-265; s. 298, ch. 95-148; s. 7, ch. 96-350; s. 43, ch. 97-300; ss. 1, 85, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>