<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0316.1951" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Parking for certain purposes prohibited; sale of motor vehicles; prohibited acts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to park a motor vehicle, as defined in s. 320.01, upon a public street or highway, a public parking lot, or other public property, or upon private property where the public has the right to travel by motor vehicle, for the principal purpose and intent of displaying the motor vehicle thereon for sale, hire, or rental unless the sale, hire, or rental of the motor vehicle is specifically authorized on such property by municipal or county regulation and the person is in compliance with all municipal or county licensing regulations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsection (1) do not prohibit a person from parking his or her own motor vehicle or his or her other personal property on any private real property which the person owns or leases or on private real property which the person does not own or lease, but for which he or she obtains the permission of the owner, or on the public street immediately adjacent thereto, for the principal purpose and intent of sale, hire, or rental.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) does not prohibit a licensed motor vehicle dealer from displaying for sale or offering for sale motor vehicles at locations other than the dealer’s licensed location if the dealer has been issued a supplemental license for off-premises sales, as provided in s. 320.27(5), and has complied with the requirements in subsection (1). A vehicle displayed for sale by a licensed dealer at any location other than the dealer’s licensed location is subject to immediate removal without warning.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local government may adopt an ordinance to allow the towing of a motor vehicle parked in violation of this section. A law enforcement officer, compliance officer, code enforcement officer from any local government agency, or supervisor of the department may issue a citation and cause to be immediately removed at the owner’s expense any motor vehicle found in violation of subsection (1), except as provided in subsections (2) and (3), or in violation of subsection (5), subsection (6), subsection (7), or subsection (8), and the owner shall be assessed a penalty as provided in s. 318.18(21) by the government agency or authority that orders immediate removal of the motor vehicle. A motor vehicle removed under this section shall not be released from an impound or towing and storage facility before a release form prescribed by the department has been completed verifying that the fine has been paid to the government agency or authority that ordered immediate removal of the motor vehicle. However, the owner may pay towing and storage charges to the towing and storage facility pursuant to s. 713.78 before payment of the fine or before the release form has been completed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to offer a vehicle for sale if the vehicle identification number has been destroyed, removed, covered, altered, or defaced, as described in s. 319.33(1)(d). A vehicle found in violation of this subsection is subject to immediate removal without warning.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to knowingly attach to any motor vehicle a registration that was not assigned or lawfully transferred to the vehicle pursuant to s. 320.261. A vehicle found in violation of this subsection is subject to immediate removal without warning.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to display or offer for sale a vehicle that does not have a valid registration as provided in s. 320.02. A vehicle found in violation of this subsection is subject to immediate removal without warning. This subsection does not apply to vehicles and recreational vehicles being offered for sale through motor vehicle auctions as defined in s. 320.27(1)(c)4.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vehicle is subject to immediate removal without warning if it bears a telephone number that has been displayed on three or more vehicles offered for sale within a 12-month period.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, a violation of subsection (1), subsection (5), subsection (6), subsection (7), or subsection (8) shall subject the owner of such motor vehicle to towing fees reasonably necessitated by removal and storage of the motor vehicle and a fine as required by s. 318.18.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit the governing body of a municipality or county, with respect to streets, highways, or other property under its jurisdiction, from regulating the parking of motor vehicles for any purpose.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318, unless otherwise mandated by general law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-93; s. 19, ch. 94-306; s. 897, ch. 95-148; s. 64, ch. 95-333; s. 145, ch. 99-248; ss. 44, 45, ch. 2000-171; s. 1, ch. 2001-196; s. 63, ch. 2007-196; s. 3, ch. 2010-198.</History>
</Section>