<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0316.302" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Commercial motor vehicles; safety regulations; transporters and shippers of hazardous materials; enforcement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All owners and drivers of commercial motor vehicles that are operated on the public highways of this state while engaged in interstate commerce are subject to the rules and regulations contained in 49 C.F.R. parts 382, 385, and 390-397.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, all owners or drivers of commercial motor vehicles that are engaged in intrastate commerce are subject to the rules and regulations contained in 49 C.F.R. parts 382, 385, and 390-397, with the exception of 49 C.F.R. s. 390.5 as it relates to the definition of bus, as such rules and regulations existed on October 1, 2011.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 316.215(5), and except as provided in s. 316.228 for rear overhang lighting and flagging requirements for intrastate operations, the requirements of this section supersede all other safety requirements of this chapter for commercial motor vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely in intrastate commerce not transporting any hazardous material in amounts that require placarding pursuant to 49 C.F.R. part 172 need not comply with 49 C.F.R. ss. 391.11(b)(1) and 395.3(a) and (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in 49 C.F.R. s. 395.1, a person who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely in intrastate commerce not transporting any hazardous material in amounts that require placarding pursuant to 49 C.F.R. part 172 may not drive:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">More than 12 hours following 10 consecutive hours off duty; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any period after the end of the 16th hour after coming on duty following 10 consecutive hours off duty.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The provisions of this paragraph do not apply to drivers of utility service vehicles as defined in 49 C.F.R. s. 395.2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in 49 C.F.R. s. 395.1, a person who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely in intrastate commerce not transporting any hazardous material in amounts that require placarding pursuant to 49 C.F.R. part 172 may not drive after having been on duty more than 70 hours in any period of 7 consecutive days or more than 80 hours in any period of 8 consecutive days if the motor carrier operates every day of the week. Thirty-four consecutive hours off duty shall constitute the end of any such period of 7 or 8 consecutive days. This weekly limit does not apply to a person who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely within this state while transporting, during harvest periods, any unprocessed agricultural products or unprocessed food or fiber that is subject to seasonal harvesting from place of harvest to the first place of processing or storage or from place of harvest directly to market or while transporting livestock, livestock feed, or farm supplies directly related to growing or harvesting agricultural products. Upon request of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, motor carriers shall furnish time records or other written verification to that department so that the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles can determine compliance with this subsection. These time records must be furnished to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles within 2 days after receipt of that department’s request. Falsification of such information is subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $100. The provisions of this paragraph do not apply to operators of farm labor vehicles operated during a state of emergency declared by the Governor or operated pursuant to s. 570.07(21), and do not apply to drivers of utility service vehicles as defined in 49 C.F.R. s. 395.2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely in intrastate commerce not transporting any hazardous material in amounts that require placarding pursuant to 49 C.F.R. part 172 within a 150 air-mile radius of the location where the vehicle is based need not comply with 49 C.F.R. s. 395.8, if the requirements of 49 C.F.R. s. 395.1(e)(1)(iii) and (v) are met. If a driver is not released from duty within 12 hours after the driver arrives for duty, the motor carrier must maintain documentation of the driver’s driving times throughout the duty period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely in intrastate commerce is exempt from subsection (1) while transporting agricultural products, including horticultural or forestry products, from farm or harvest place to the first place of processing or storage, or from farm or harvest place directly to market. However, such person must comply with 49 C.F.R. parts 382, 392, and 393, and with 49 C.F.R. ss. 396.3(a)(1) and 396.9. A vehicle or combination of vehicles operated pursuant to this paragraph having a gross vehicle weight of 26,001 pounds or more or having three or more axles on the power unit, regardless of weight, must display the name of the vehicle owner or motor carrier and the municipality or town where the vehicle is based on each side of the power unit in letters that contrast with the background and that are readable from a distance of 50 feet. A person who violates this vehicle identification requirement may be assessed a penalty as provided in s. 316.3025(3)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who operates a commercial motor vehicle having a declared gross vehicle weight of less than 26,001 pounds solely in intrastate commerce and who is not transporting hazardous materials in amounts that require placarding pursuant to 49 C.F.R. part 172, or who is transporting petroleum products as defined in s. 376.301, is exempt from subsection (1). However, such person must comply with 49 C.F.R. parts 382, 392, and 393, and with 49 C.F.R. ss. 396.3(a)(1) and 396.9.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose driving record shows no convictions for the preceding 3 years and who, as of October 1, 1988, is employed as a driver-salesperson, as defined in 49 C.F.R. s. 395.2, and who operates solely in intrastate commerce, is exempt from 49 C.F.R. part 391.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is an employee of an electric utility, as defined in s. 361.11, or a telephone company, as defined in s. 364.02, and who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely in intrastate commerce and within a 200 air-mile radius of the location where the vehicle is based, is exempt from 49 C.F.R. ss. 396.11 and 396.13 and 49 C.F.R. part 391, subparts D and E.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose driving record shows no traffic convictions, pursuant to s. 322.61, during the 2-year period immediately preceding the application for the commercial driver’s license, who is otherwise qualified as a driver under 49 C.F.R. part 391, and who operates a commercial vehicle in intrastate commerce only shall be exempt from the requirements of 49 C.F.R. part 391, subpart E, s. 391.41(b)(10). However, such operators are still subject to the requirements of ss. 322.12 and 322.121. As proof of eligibility, such driver shall have in his or her possession a physical examination form dated within the past 24 months.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is otherwise qualified as a driver under 49 C.F.R. part 391, who operates a commercial motor vehicle in intrastate commerce only, and who does not transport hazardous materials in amounts that require placarding pursuant to 49 C.F.R. part 172, is exempt from the requirements of 49 C.F.R. part 391, subpart E, ss. 391.41(b)(3) and 391.43(e), relating to diabetes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person holding a commercial driver’s license who is a regularly employed driver of a commercial motor vehicle and is subject to an alcohol and controlled substance testing program related to that employment shall not be required to be part of a separate testing program for operating any bus owned and operated by a church when the driver does not receive any form of compensation for operating the bus and when the bus is used to transport people to or from church-related activities at no charge. The provisions of this paragraph may not be implemented if the Federal Government notifies the department that implementation will adversely affect the allocation of federal funds to the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has not attained 18 years of age may not operate a commercial motor vehicle, except that a person who has not attained 18 years of age may operate a commercial motor vehicle which has a gross vehicle weight of less than 26,001 pounds while transporting agricultural products, including horticultural or forestry products, from farm or harvest place to storage or market.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this subsection, all commercial motor vehicles transporting any hazardous material on any road, street, or highway open to the public, whether engaged in interstate or intrastate commerce, and any person who offers hazardous materials for such transportation, are subject to the regulations contained in 49 C.F.R. part 107, subpart G, and 49 C.F.R. parts 171, 172, 173, 177, 178, and 180. Effective July 1, 1997, the exceptions for intrastate motor carriers provided in 49 C.F.R. 173.5 and 173.8 are hereby adopted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the penalties provided in s. 316.3025(3)(b), (c), (d), and (e), any motor carrier or any of its officers, drivers, agents, representatives, employees, or shippers of hazardous materials that do not comply with this subsection or any rule adopted by a state agency that is consistent with the federal rules and regulations regarding hazardous materials commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. To ensure compliance with this subsection, state highway patrol officers may inspect shipping documents and cargo of any vehicle known or suspected to be a transporter of hazardous materials.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may adopt and revise rules to assure the safe operation of commercial motor vehicles. The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may enter into cooperative agreements as provided in 49 C.F.R. part 388. Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles personnel may conduct motor carrier and shipper compliance reviews for the purpose of determining compliance with this section and s. 627.7415.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall perform the duties that are assigned to the Field Administrator, Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration under the federal rules, and an agent of that department may enforce those rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who operates a commercial motor vehicle solely in intrastate commerce shall direct to the state Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles any communication that the federal rules require persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States Department of Transportation to direct to that department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of enforcing this section, any law enforcement officer of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles or duly appointed agent who holds a current safety inspector certification from the Commercial Vehicle Safety Alliance may require the driver of any commercial vehicle operated on the highways of this state to stop and submit to an inspection of the vehicle or the driver’s records. If the vehicle or driver is found to be operating in an unsafe condition, or if any required part or equipment is not present or is not in proper repair or adjustment, and the continued operation would present an unduly hazardous operating condition, the officer may require the vehicle or the driver to be removed from service pursuant to the North American Standard Out-of-Service Criteria, until corrected. However, if continuous operation would not present an unduly hazardous operating condition, the officer may give written notice requiring correction of the condition within 14 days.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of the Florida Highway Patrol or any law enforcement officer employed by a sheriff’s office or municipal police department authorized to enforce the traffic laws of this state pursuant to s. 316.640 who has reason to believe that a vehicle or driver is operating in an unsafe condition may, as provided in subsection (10), enforce the provisions of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who fails to comply with an officer’s request to submit to an inspection under this subsection commits a violation of s. 843.02 if the person resists the officer without violence or a violation of s. 843.01 if the person resists the officer with violence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is not applicable to the transporting of liquefied petroleum gas. The rules and regulations applicable to the transporting of liquefied petroleum gas on the highways, roads, or streets of this state shall be only those adopted by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services under chapter 527. However, transporters of liquefied petroleum gas must comply with the requirements of 49 C.F.R. parts 393 and 396.9.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to any nonpublic sector bus.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any traffic enforcement officer or any person otherwise authorized to enforce this section may issue a traffic citation as provided by s. 316.650 to an alleged violator of any provision of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalty provided in this section, a person who operates a commercial motor vehicle that bears an identification number required by this section which is false, fraudulent, or displayed without the consent of the person to whom it is assigned commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a provision, clause, covenant, or agreement contained in, collateral to, or affecting a motor carrier transportation contract that purports to indemnify, defend, or hold harmless, or has the effect of indemnifying, defending, or holding harmless, the promisee from or against any liability for loss or damage resulting from the negligence or intentional acts or omissions of the promisee is against the public policy of this state and is void and unenforceable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “promisee” means the contract’s promisee and any agents, employees, servants, or independent contractors who are directly responsible to the contract’s promisee, except that the term does not include motor carriers which are party to a motor carrier transportation contract with the contract’s promisee, including such motor carrier’s agents, employees, servants, or independent contractors directly responsible to such motor carrier.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection only applies to motor carrier transportation contracts entered into or renewed on or after July 1, 2010.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 1, ch. 79-254; s. 24, ch. 82-186; s. 3, ch. 83-218; s. 63, ch. 85-180; s. 2, ch. 87-270; s. 1, ch. 87-536; s. 1, ch. 88-2; s. 1, ch. 88-306; ss. 61, 65, ch. 89-282; s. 1, ch. 90-200; ss. 23, 24, ch. 90-227; s. 1, ch. 90-355; s. 1, ch. 91-243; s. 10, ch. 92-316; s. 25, ch. 94-306; s. 901, ch. 95-148; s. 2, ch. 95-247; s. 3, ch. 95-317; s. 19, ch. 96-263; s. 15, ch. 96-277; s. 8, ch. 97-280; s. 32, ch. 97-300; s. 16, ch. 98-189; s. 92, ch. 99-13; s. 215, ch. 99-248; s. 11, ch. 99-385; s. 3, ch. 2002-20; s. 11, ch. 2003-286; s. 4, ch. 2005-50; ss. 8, 38, ch. 2005-164; s. 18, ch. 2006-290; s. 8, ch. 2008-176; s. 10, ch. 2010-225; s. 9, ch. 2011-66; s. 43, ch. 2012-5; s. 9, ch. 2012-128; s. 11, ch. 2012-181.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.286.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>