<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.300" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain vehicles to carry flares or other devices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall operate any truck, bus, truck tractor, trailer, semitrailer, pole trailer, or motor vehicle towing a house trailer, when such vehicle is 80 inches or more in overall width or 30 feet or more in overall length, upon any highway outside an urban district or upon any divided highway at any time between sunset and sunrise unless there is carried in such vehicle the following equipment, except as provided in subsection (2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least three flares, three red electric lanterns, or three portable red emergency reflectors, each of which shall be capable of being seen and distinguished at a distance of not less than 600 feet under normal atmospheric conditions at nighttime. No flare, fusee, electric lantern, or warning flag shall be used for the purpose of compliance with the requirements of this section unless such equipment is of a type which has been submitted to the department and approved by it. No portable reflector unit shall be used for the purpose of compliance with the requirements of this section unless it is so designed and constructed as to be capable of reflecting red light clearly visible from all distances within 600 feet to 100 feet under normal atmospheric conditions at night when directly in front of lawful lower beams of headlamps and unless it is of a type which has been submitted to the department and approved by it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least three red-burning fusees, unless red electric lanterns or red portable emergency reflectors are carried.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall operate at the time and under conditions stated in subsection (1) any motor vehicle used for the transportation of explosives or any cargo tank truck used for the transportation of flammable liquids or compressed gases unless there is carried in such vehicle three red electric lanterns or three portable red emergency reflectors meeting the requirements of subsection (1), and there shall not be carried in any such vehicle any flares, fusees, or signal produced by flame.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall operate any vehicle described in subsection (1) or subsection (2) upon any highway outside an urban district or upon a divided highway at any time when lighted lamps are not required by s. 316.217 unless there is carried in such vehicle at least two red flags, not less than 12 inches square, with standards to support such flags, or two red portable emergency reflectors of the type described in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 1, ch. 81-49; s. 213, ch. 99-248.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.274.</Text></Note></Section>