<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.1939" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Refusal to submit to testing; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has refused to submit to a chemical or physical test of his or her breath, blood, or urine, as described in s. 316.1932, and whose driving privilege was previously suspended for a prior refusal to submit to a lawful test of his or her breath, urine, or blood, and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who the arresting law enforcement officer had probable cause to believe was driving or in actual physical control of a motor vehicle in this state while under the influence of alcoholic beverages, chemical substances, or controlled substances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who was placed under lawful arrest for a violation of s. 316.193 unless such test was requested pursuant to s. 316.1932(1)(c);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who was informed that, if he or she refused to submit to such test, his or her privilege to operate a motor vehicle would be suspended for a period of 1 year or, in the case of a second or subsequent refusal, for a period of 18 months;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who was informed that a refusal to submit to a lawful test of his or her breath, urine, or blood, if his or her driving privilege has been previously suspended for a prior refusal to submit to a lawful test of his or her breath, urine, or blood, is a misdemeanor; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who, after having been so informed, refused to submit to any such test when requested to do so by a law enforcement officer or correctional officer</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits a misdemeanor of the first degree and is subject to punishment as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disposition of any administrative proceeding that relates to the suspension of a person’s driving privilege does not affect a criminal action under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disposition of a criminal action under this section does not affect any administrative proceeding that relates to the suspension of a person’s driving privilege. The department’s records showing that a person’s license has been previously suspended for a prior refusal to submit to a lawful test of his or her breath, urine, or blood shall be admissible and shall create a rebuttable presumption of such suspension.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-263.</History></Section>