<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.1945" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Stopping, standing, or parking prohibited in specified places.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except when necessary to avoid conflict with other traffic, or in compliance with law or the directions of a police officer or official traffic control device, no person shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stop, stand, or park a vehicle:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the roadway side of any vehicle stopped or parked at the edge or curb of a street.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a sidewalk.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within an intersection.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a crosswalk.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Between a safety zone and the adjacent curb or within 30 feet of points on the curb immediately opposite the ends of a safety zone, unless the Department of Transportation indicates a different length by signs or markings.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alongside or opposite any street excavation or obstruction when stopping, standing, or parking would obstruct traffic.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon any bridge or other elevated structure upon a highway or within a highway tunnel.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On any railroad tracks.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a bicycle path.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any place where official traffic control devices prohibit stopping.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the roadway or shoulder of a limited access facility, except as provided by regulation of the Department of Transportation, or on the paved portion of a connecting ramp; except that a vehicle which is disabled or in a condition improper to be driven as a result of mechanical failure or crash may be parked on such shoulder for a period not to exceed 6 hours. This provision is not applicable to a person stopping a vehicle to render aid to an injured person or assistance to a disabled vehicle in obedience to the directions of a law enforcement officer or to a person stopping a vehicle in compliance with applicable traffic laws.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of loading or unloading a passenger on the paved roadway or shoulder of a limited access facility or on the paved portion of any connecting ramp. This provision is not applicable to a person stopping a vehicle to render aid to an injured person or assistance to a disabled vehicle.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stand or park a vehicle, whether occupied or not, except momentarily to pick up or discharge a passenger or passengers:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In front of a public or private driveway.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 feet of a fire hydrant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 20 feet of a crosswalk at an intersection.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 feet upon the approach to any flashing signal, stop sign, or traffic control signal located at the side of a roadway.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 20 feet of the driveway entrance to any fire station and on the side of a street opposite the entrance to any fire station within 75 feet of such entrance (when property signposted).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On an exclusive bicycle lane.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any place where official traffic control devices prohibit standing.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Park a vehicle, whether occupied or not, except temporarily for the purpose of, and while actually engaged in, loading or unloading merchandise or passengers:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 50 feet of the nearest rail of a railroad crossing unless the Department of Transportation establishes a different distance due to unusual circumstances.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any place where official signs prohibit parking.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall move a vehicle not lawfully under his or her control into any such prohibited area or away from a curb such a distance as is unlawful.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A law enforcement officer or parking enforcement specialist who discovers a vehicle parked in violation of this section or a municipal or county ordinance may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a ticket form as may be used by a political subdivision or municipality to the driver; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the vehicle is unattended, attach such ticket to the vehicle in a conspicuous place, except that the uniform traffic citation prepared by the department pursuant to s. 316.650 may not be issued by being attached to an unattended vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The uniform traffic citation prepared by the department pursuant to s. 316.650 may not be issued for violation of a municipal or county parking ordinance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 2, ch. 78-52; s. 1, ch. 79-403; s. 2, ch. 80-316; s. 5, ch. 83-68; s. 5, ch. 84-309; s. 1, ch. 85-81; s. 2, ch. 88-91; s. 317, ch. 95-148; s. 143, ch. 99-248.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.160.</Text></Note></Section>