<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.2225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional equipment required on certain vehicles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to other equipment required in this chapter, the following vehicles shall be equipped as herein stated under the conditions stated in s. 316.217.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On every bus or truck, whatever its size, there shall be the following: On the rear, two reflectors, one at each side, and one stop light.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On every bus or truck 80 inches or more in overall width, in addition to the requirements in subsection (1):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the front, two clearance lamps, one at each side.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the rear, two clearance lamps, one at each side.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On each side, two side marker lamps, one at or near the front and one at or near the rear.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On each side, two reflectors, one at or near the front and one at or near the rear.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On every truck tractor:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the front, two clearance lamps, one at each side.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the rear, one stop light.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On every trailer or semitrailer having a gross weight in excess of 3,000 pounds:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the front, two clearance lamps, one at each side.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On each side, two side marker lamps, one at or near the front and one at or near the rear.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On each side, two reflectors, one at or near the front and one at or near the rear.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the rear, two clearance lamps, one at each side, also two reflectors, one at each side, and one stop light.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On every pole trailer in excess of 3,000 pounds gross weight:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On each side, one side marker lamp and one clearance lamp which may be in combination, to show to the front, side and rear.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the rear of the pole trailer or load, two reflectors, one at each side.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On every trailer, semitrailer, and pole trailer weighing 3,000 pounds gross, or less: On the rear, two reflectors, one on each side. If any trailer or semitrailer is so loaded, or is of such dimensions as to obscure the stop light on the towing vehicle, then such vehicle shall also be equipped with one stop light.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On every slow-moving vehicle or equipment, animal-drawn vehicle, or other machinery designed for use and speeds less than 25 miles per hour, including all road construction and maintenance machinery except when engaged in actual construction or maintenance work either guarded by a flagger or a clearly visible warning sign, which normally travels or is normally used at a speed of less than 25 miles per hour and which is operated on a public highway:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A triangular slow-moving vehicle emblem SMV as described in, and displayed as provided in paragraph (b). The requirement of the emblem shall be in addition to any other equipment required by law. The emblem shall not be displayed on objects which are customarily stationary in use except while being transported on the roadway of any public highway of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall adopt such rules and regulations as are required to carry out the purpose of this section. The requirements of such rules and regulations shall incorporate the current specifications for SMV emblems of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 323, ch. 95-148; s. 175, ch. 99-248.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.276.</Text></Note></Section>