<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.228" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lamps or flags on projecting load.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2), whenever the load upon any vehicle extends to the rear 4 feet or more beyond the bed or body of such vehicle, there shall be displayed at the extreme rear end of the load, at the times specified in s. 316.217, two red lamps visible from a distance of at least 500 feet to the rear, two red reflectors visible at night from all distances within 600 feet to 100 feet to the rear when directly in front of lawful lower beams of headlamps and located so as to indicate maximum width, and on each side one red lamp visible from a distance of at least 500 feet to the side and located so as to indicate maximum overhang. There shall be displayed at all other times on any vehicle having a load which extends beyond its sides or more than 4 feet beyond its rear, red flags, not less than 12 inches square, marking the extremities of such load, at each point where a lamp would otherwise be required by this section. A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any commercial motor vehicle or trailer transporting a load of unprocessed logs or pulpwood, which load extends more than 4 feet beyond the rear of the body or bed of such vehicle, must have securely fixed as close as practical to the end of any such projection one amber strobe-type lamp equipped with a multidirectional type lens so mounted as to be visible from the rear and both sides of the projecting load. If the mounting of one strobe lamp cannot be accomplished so that it is visible from the rear and both sides of the projecting load, multiple strobe lights must be used to meet the visibility requirements of this subsection. The strobe lamp must flash at a rate of at least 60 flashes per minute and must be plainly visible from a distance of at least 500 feet to the rear and sides of the projecting load at any time of the day or night. The lamp must be operating at any time of the day or night when the vehicle is operated on any highway or parked on the shoulder or immediately adjacent to the traveled portion of any public roadway. The projecting load must also be marked with a red flag as described in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 179, ch. 99-248; s. 11, ch. 2000-313; s. 3, ch. 2001-196; s. 6, ch. 2001-279.</History></Section>