<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0316.3025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commercial motor vehicle that is found to be operating in such an unsafe condition as to be declared out-of-service or a driver declared out-of-service or removed from driving status pursuant to the North American Standard Out-of-Service Criteria must be repaired or returned to driving status before being returned to service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who owns, operates, or causes or permits a commercial motor vehicle that has been declared out-of-service pursuant to the North American Standard Out-of-Service Criteria to be driven before the completion of required repairs is subject to the imposition of a penalty as provided in 49 C.F.R. s. 383.53, in addition to any other penalties imposed against him or her. Any person who operates a commercial motor vehicle while he or she is declared out-of-service or removed from driving status pursuant to the North American Standard Out-of-Service Criteria, or who causes or permits such out-of-service driver to operate a commercial motor vehicle, is subject to the imposition of a penalty as provided in 49 C.F.R. s. 383.53, in addition to any other penalties imposed against the person.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil penalty of $50 may be assessed for a violation of the identification requirements of 49 C.F.R. s. 390.21 or s. 316.302(2)(e).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil penalty of $100 may be assessed for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each violation of the North American Uniform Driver Out-of-Service Criteria;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of s. 316.302(2)(b) or (c);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 392.60; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the North American Standard Vehicle Out-of-Service Criteria resulting from an inspection of a commercial motor vehicle involved in a crash.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil penalty of $250 may be assessed for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the placarding requirements of 49 C.F.R. parts 171-179;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the shipping paper requirements of 49 C.F.R. parts 171-179;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 392.10;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 397.5;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 397.7;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 397.13; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 397.15.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil penalty of $500 may be assessed for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each violation of the North American Standard Hazardous Materials Out-of-Service Criteria;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 390.19, for failure of an interstate or intrastate motor carrier to register;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 392.9a, for failure of an interstate motor carrier to obtain operating authority; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 392.9a, for operating beyond the scope of an interstate motor carrier’s operating authority.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil penalty not to exceed $5,000 in the aggregate may be assessed for violations found in the conduct of compliance reviews pursuant to s. 316.302(5). A civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 in the aggregate may be assessed for violations found in a followup compliance review conducted within a 24-month period. A civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 in the aggregate may be assessed and the motor carrier may be enjoined pursuant to s. 316.3026 if violations are found after a second followup compliance review within 12 months after the first followup compliance review. Motor carriers found to be operating without insurance required by s. 627.7415 may be enjoined as provided in s. 316.3026.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vehicle operated by an interstate motor carrier found to be in violation of 49 C.F.R. s. 392.9a may be placed out of service for the carrier’s failure to obtain operating authority or operating beyond the scope of its operating authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any person or motor carrier as defined in chapter 320 violates the provisions of this section and becomes indebted to the state because of such violation and refuses to pay the appropriate penalty, in addition to the provisions of s. 316.3026, such penalty becomes a lien upon the property including the motor vehicles of such person or motor carrier and may be foreclosed by the state in a civil action in any court of this state. It shall be presumed that the owner of the motor vehicle is liable for the sum, and the vehicle may be detained or impounded until the penalty is paid.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only an officer or agent of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles is authorized to collect the penalty provided by this section. Such officer or agent shall cooperate with the owner or driver of the motor vehicle so as not to unduly delay the vehicle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All penalties imposed and collected under this section shall be paid to the Chief Financial Officer, who shall credit the total amount collected to the State Transportation Trust Fund for use in repairing and maintaining the roads of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person aggrieved by the imposition of a civil penalty pursuant to this section may apply to the Commercial Motor Vehicle Review Board for a modification, cancellation, or revocation of the penalty. The Commercial Motor Vehicle Review Board may modify, cancel, revoke, or sustain such penalty.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 87-270; s. 2, ch. 88-306; s. 62, ch. 89-282; s. 25, ch. 90-227; s. 326, ch. 95-148; s. 3, ch. 95-247; s. 216, ch. 99-248; s. 12, ch. 99-385; s. 4, ch. 2002-20; s. 356, ch. 2003-261; s. 12, ch. 2003-286; s. 10, ch. 2011-66.</History>
</Section>