<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">When signal required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may turn a vehicle from a direct course or move right or left upon a highway unless and until such movement can be made with reasonable safety, and then only after giving an appropriate signal in the manner hereinafter provided, in the event any other vehicle may be affected by the movement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A signal of intention to turn right or left must be given continuously during not less than the last 100 feet traveled by the vehicle before turning, except that such a signal by hand or arm need not be given continuously by a bicyclist if the hand is needed in the control or operation of the bicycle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may stop or suddenly decrease the speed of a vehicle without first giving an appropriate signal in the manner provided herein to the driver of any vehicle immediately to the rear, when there is opportunity to give such signal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The signals provided for in s. 316.156 shall be used to indicate an intention to turn, to overtake, or to pass a vehicle and may not, except as provided in s. 316.2397, be flashed on one side only on a parked or disabled vehicle or flashed as a courtesy or “do pass” signal to operators of other vehicles approaching from the rear.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 16, ch. 76-31; s. 4, ch. 83-68; s. 129, ch. 99-248; s. 4, ch. 2005-164.</History></Section>