<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.130" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pedestrians; traffic regulations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pedestrian shall obey the instructions of any official traffic control device specifically applicable to the pedestrian unless otherwise directed by a police officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pedestrians shall be subject to traffic control signals at intersections as provided in s. 316.075, but at all other places pedestrians shall be accorded the privileges and be subject to the restrictions stated in this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where sidewalks are provided, no pedestrian shall, unless required by other circumstances, walk along and upon the portion of a roadway paved for vehicular traffic.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where sidewalks are not provided, any pedestrian walking along and upon a highway shall, when practicable, walk only on the shoulder on the left side of the roadway in relation to the pedestrian’s direction of travel, facing traffic which may approach from the opposite direction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall stand in the portion of a roadway paved for vehicular traffic for the purpose of soliciting a ride, employment, or business from the occupant of any vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall stand on or in proximity to a street or highway for the purpose of soliciting the watching or guarding of any vehicle while parked or about to be parked on a street or highway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The driver of a vehicle at an intersection that has a traffic control signal in place shall stop before entering the crosswalk and remain stopped to allow a pedestrian, with a permitted signal, to cross a roadway when the pedestrian is in the crosswalk or steps into the crosswalk and is upon the half of the roadway upon which the vehicle is traveling or when the pedestrian is approaching so closely from the opposite half of the roadway as to be in danger.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The driver of a vehicle at any crosswalk where signage so indicates shall stop and remain stopped to allow a pedestrian to cross a roadway when the pedestrian is in the crosswalk or steps into the crosswalk and is upon the half of the roadway upon which the vehicle is traveling or when the pedestrian is approaching so closely from the opposite half of the roadway as to be in danger.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When traffic control signals are not in place or in operation and there is no signage indicating otherwise, the driver of a vehicle shall yield the right-of-way, slowing down or stopping if need be to so yield, to a pedestrian crossing the roadway within a crosswalk when the pedestrian is upon the half of the roadway upon which the vehicle is traveling or when the pedestrian is approaching so closely from the opposite half of the roadway as to be in danger. Any pedestrian crossing a roadway at a point where a pedestrian tunnel or overhead pedestrian crossing has been provided shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles upon the roadway.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No pedestrian shall suddenly leave a curb or other place of safety and walk or run into the path of a vehicle which is so close that it is impossible for the driver to yield.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any vehicle is stopped at a marked crosswalk or at any unmarked crosswalk at an intersection to permit a pedestrian to cross the roadway, the driver of any other vehicle approaching from the rear shall not overtake and pass such stopped vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every pedestrian crossing a roadway at any point other than within a marked crosswalk or within an unmarked crosswalk at an intersection shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles upon the roadway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Between adjacent intersections at which traffic control signals are in operation, pedestrians shall not cross at any place except in a marked crosswalk.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No pedestrian shall, except in a marked crosswalk, cross a roadway at any other place than by a route at right angles to the curb or by the shortest route to the opposite curb.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pedestrians shall move, whenever practicable, upon the right half of crosswalks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No pedestrian shall cross a roadway intersection diagonally unless authorized by official traffic control devices, and, when authorized to cross diagonally, pedestrians shall cross only in accordance with the official traffic control devices pertaining to such crossing movements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding other provisions of this chapter, every driver of a vehicle shall exercise due care to avoid colliding with any pedestrian or any person propelling a human-powered vehicle and give warning when necessary and exercise proper precaution upon observing any child or any obviously confused or incapacitated person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No pedestrian shall enter or remain upon any bridge or approach thereto beyond the bridge signal, gate, or barrier after a bridge operation signal indication has been given. No pedestrian shall pass through, around, over, or under any crossing gate or barrier at a railroad grade crossing or bridge while such gate or barrier is closed or is being opened or closed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No pedestrian may jump or dive from a publicly owned bridge. Nothing in this provision requires the state or any political subdivision of the state to post signs notifying the public of this provision. The failure to post a sign may not be construed by any court to create liability on the part of the state or any of its political subdivisions for injuries sustained as a result of jumping or diving from a bridge in violation of this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No pedestrian shall walk upon a limited access facility or a ramp connecting a limited access facility to any other street or highway; however, this subsection does not apply to maintenance personnel of any governmental subdivision.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable pursuant to chapter 318 as either a pedestrian violation or, if the infraction resulted from the operation of a vehicle, as a moving violation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; ss. 1, 8, ch. 76-31; s. 2, ch. 83-68; ss. 1, 2, ch. 83-74; s. 3, ch. 84-309; s. 306, ch. 95-148; s. 123, ch. 99-248; s. 2, ch. 2008-33.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.057.</Text></Note></Section>