<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0316.2129" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Operation of swamp buggies on public roads, streets, or highways authorized.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A swamp buggy may be operated on a public road, street, or highway if the local governmental entity, as defined in s. 334.03, having jurisdiction over the public road, street, or highway, has designated it for use by swamp buggies. Upon determining that swamp buggies may safely operate on or cross such public road, street, or highway, the local governmental entity shall post appropriate signs or otherwise inform the public that the operation of swamp buggies is allowed. This authorization does not apply to the State Highway System, as defined in s. 334.03. However, a swamp buggy may be operated on a part of the State Highway System only to cross that portion of the State Highway System which intersects a county road or municipal street that has been designated for use by swamp buggies if the Department of Transportation has reviewed and approved the location and design of the crossing and any traffic control devices needed for safety purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A swamp buggy may be operated on land managed, owned, or leased by a state or federal agency if the state or federal agency allows the operation of swamp buggies on such land, including any public road, street, or highway running through or located within the state or federal land. Upon determining that swamp buggies may safely operate on or cross a public road, street, or highway running through or located within such land, the state or federal agency shall post appropriate signs or otherwise inform the public that the operation of swamp buggies is allowed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>