<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.2045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obstruction of public streets, highways, and roads.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person or persons willfully to obstruct the free, convenient, and normal use of any public street, highway, or road by impeding, hindering, stifling, retarding, or restraining traffic or passage thereon, by standing or approaching motor vehicles thereon, or by endangering the safe movement of vehicles or pedestrians traveling thereon; and any person or persons who violate the provisions of this subsection, upon conviction, shall be cited for a pedestrian violation, punishable as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful, without proper authorization or a lawful permit, for any person or persons willfully to obstruct the free, convenient, and normal use of any public street, highway, or road by any of the means specified in subsection (1) in order to solicit. Any person who violates the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Organizations qualified under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code and registered pursuant to chapter 496, or persons or organizations acting on their behalf are exempted from the provisions of this subsection for activities on streets or roads not maintained by the state. Permits for the use of any portion of a state-maintained road or right-of-way shall be required only for those purposes and in the manner set out in s. 337.406.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permits for the use of any street, road, or right-of-way not maintained by the state may be issued by the appropriate local government. An organization that is qualified under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code and registered under chapter 496, or a person or organization acting on behalf of that organization, is exempt from local requirements for a permit issued under this subsection for charitable solicitation activities on or along streets or roads that are not maintained by the state under the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organization, or the person or organization acting on behalf of the organization, must provide all of the following to the local government:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No fewer than 14 calendar days prior to the proposed solicitation, the name and address of the person or organization that will perform the solicitation and the name and address of the organization that will receive funds from the solicitation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For review and comment, a plan for the safety of all persons participating in the solicitation, as well as the motoring public, at the locations where the solicitation will take place.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specific details of the location or locations of the proposed solicitation and the hours during which the solicitation activities will occur.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of commercial general liability insurance against claims for bodily injury and property damage occurring on streets, roads, or rights-of-way or arising from the solicitor’s activities or use of the streets, roads, or rights-of-way by the solicitor or the solicitor’s agents, contractors, or employees. The insurance shall have a limit of not less than $1 million per occurrence for the general aggregate. The certificate of insurance shall name the local government as an additional insured and shall be filed with the local government no later than 72 hours before the date of the solicitation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of registration with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services pursuant to s. 496.405 or proof that the soliciting organization is exempt from the registration requirement.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organizations or persons meeting the requirements of subparagraphs (a)1.-5. may solicit for a period not to exceed 10 cumulative days within 1 calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All solicitation shall occur during daylight hours only.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicitation activities shall not interfere with the safe and efficient movement of traffic and shall not cause danger to the participants or the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person engaging in solicitation activities shall persist after solicitation has been denied, act in a demanding or harassing manner, or use any sound or voice-amplifying apparatus or device.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons participating in the solicitation shall be at least 18 years of age and shall possess picture identification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signage providing notice of the solicitation shall be posted at least 500 feet before the site of the solicitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local government may stop solicitation activities if any conditions or requirements of this subsection are not met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to inhibit political campaigning on the public right-of-way or to require a permit for such activity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1), any commercial vehicle used solely for the purpose of collecting solid waste or recyclable or recovered materials may stop or stand on any public street, highway, or road for the sole purpose of collecting solid waste or recyclable or recovered materials. However, such solid waste or recyclable or recovered materials collection vehicle shall show or display amber flashing hazard lights at all times that it is engaged in stopping or standing for the purpose of collecting solid waste or recyclable or recovered materials. Local governments may establish reasonable regulations governing the standing and stopping of such commercial vehicles, provided that such regulations are applied uniformly and without regard to the ownership of the vehicles.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; ss. 1, 13, ch. 76-31; s. 1, ch. 87-378; s. 61, ch. 93-207; s. 29, ch. 96-350; s. 2, ch. 2007-43.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.103.</Text></Note></Section>