<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.80" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful conveyance of fuel; obtaining fuel fraudulently.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to maintain, or possess any conveyance or vehicle that is equipped with, fuel tanks, bladders, drums, or other containers that do not conform to 49 C.F.R. or have not been approved by the United States Department of Transportation for the purpose of hauling, transporting, or conveying motor or diesel fuel over any public highway. Any person who violates any provision of this subsection commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, and, in addition, is subject to the revocation of driver license privileges as provided in s. 322.26.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates subsection (1) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if he or she has attempted to or has fraudulently obtained motor or diesel fuel by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Presenting a credit card or a credit card account number in violation of ss. 817.57-817.685;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using unauthorized access to any computer network in violation of s. 815.06; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using a fraudulently scanned or lost or stolen payment access device, whether credit card or contactless device.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All conveyances or vehicles, fuel tanks, related fuel, and other equipment described in subsection (1) shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture as provided by the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law enforcement agency that seizes the motor or diesel fuel under this section shall remove and reclaim, recycle, or dispose of all associated motor or diesel fuel as soon as practicable in a safe and proper manner from the illegal containers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon conviction of the person arrested for the violation of any of the provisions of this section, the judge shall issue an order adjudging and declaring that all fuel tanks and other equipment used in violation of this section shall be forfeited and directing their destruction, with the exception of the conveyance or vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person convicted of a violation of this section shall be responsible for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All reasonable costs incurred by the investigating law enforcement agency, including costs for the towing and storage of the conveyance or vehicle, the removal and disposal of the motor or diesel fuel, and the storage and destruction of all fuel tanks and other equipment described and used in violation of subsection (1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment for the fuel to the party from whom any associated motor or diesel fuel was fraudulently obtained.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to containers of 8 gallons or less.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 71, ch. 2002-20.</History></Section>