<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.089" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Driving on roadways laned for traffic.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any roadway has been divided into two or more clearly marked lanes for traffic, the following rules, in addition to all others consistent herewith, shall apply:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vehicle shall be driven as nearly as practicable entirely within a single lane and shall not be moved from such lane until the driver has first ascertained that such movement can be made with safety.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a roadway which is divided into three lanes and provides for two-way movement of traffic, a vehicle shall not be driven in the center lane except when overtaking and passing another vehicle traveling in the same direction when such center lane is clear of traffic within a safe distance, when in preparation for making a left turn, or where such center lane is at the time allocated exclusively to traffic moving in the same direction that the vehicle is proceeding and such allocation is designated by official traffic control devices.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Official traffic control devices may be erected directing specified traffic to use a designated lane or designating those lanes to be used by traffic moving in a particular direction regardless of the center of the roadway; and drivers of vehicles shall obey the directions of every such device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Official traffic control devices may be installed prohibiting the changing of lanes on sections of roadway, and drivers of vehicles shall obey the directions of every such device.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 113, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>