<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mounting of reflectors, clearance lamps and side marker lamps.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reflectors, when required by s. 316.2225, shall be mounted at a height not less than 24 inches and not more than 60 inches above the ground on which the vehicle stands, except that if the highest part of the permanent structure of the vehicle is less than 24 inches, the reflector at such point shall be mounted as high as that part of the permanent structure will permit.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rear reflectors on a pole trailer may be mounted on each side of the bolster or load.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any required red reflector on the rear of a vehicle may be incorporated with the taillamp, but such reflector shall meet all the other reflector requirements of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clearance lamps shall, so far as is practicable, be mounted on the permanent structure of the vehicle in such a manner as to indicate the extreme height and width of the vehicle. When rear identification lamps are required and are mounted as high as is practicable, rear clearance lamps may be mounted at optional height, and when the mounting of front clearance lamps results in such lamps failing to indicate the extreme width of the trailer, such lamps may be mounted at optional height but must indicate, as nearly as practicable, the extreme width of the trailer. Clearance lamps on truck tractors shall be located so as to indicate the extreme width of the truck tractor cab. Clearance lamps and side marker lamps may be mounted in combination provided illumination is given as required herein with reference to both.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 24, ch. 76-31; s. 177, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>