<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.087" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Further limitations on driving to left of center of roadway.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No vehicle shall at any time be driven to the left side of the roadway under the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When approaching or upon the crest of a grade where the driver’s view is obstructed within such distance as to create a hazard in the event another vehicle might approach from the opposite direction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a curve in the highway where the driver’s view is obstructed within such distance as to create a hazard in the event another vehicle might approach from the opposite direction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When approaching within 100 feet of or traversing any intersection, except that this section shall not apply to any intersection on a state-maintained or county-maintained highway located outside city limits unless such intersection is marked by an official Department of Transportation or county road department traffic control device indicating an intersection either by symbol or by words and such marking is placed at least 100 feet before the intersection;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When approaching within 100 feet of or traversing any railroad grade crossing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the view is obstructed upon approaching within 100 feet of any bridge, viaduct, or tunnel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foregoing limitations shall not apply upon a one-way roadway, nor when an obstruction exists making it necessary to drive to the left of the center of the highway, nor to the driver of a vehicle turning left into or from an alley, private road or driveway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 2, ch. 86-36; s. 110, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>