<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.208" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Motorcycles and mopeds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person operating a motorcycle or moped shall be granted all of the rights and shall be subject to all of the duties applicable to the driver of any other vehicle under this chapter, except as to special regulations in this chapter and except as to those provisions of this chapter which by their nature can have no application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person operating a moped upon a roadway at less than the normal speed of traffic at the time and place and under the conditions then existing shall ride as close as practicable to the right-hand curb or edge of the roadway except under any of the following situations:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When overtaking or passing another vehicle proceeding in the same direction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When preparing for a left turn at an intersection or into a private road or driveway.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When reasonably necessary to avoid any condition, including, but not limited to, a fixed or moving object, parked or moving vehicle, bicycle, pedestrian, animal, surface hazard, or substandard-width lane, that makes it unsafe to continue along the right-hand curb or edge. For purposes of this paragraph, a “substandard-width lane” is a lane that is too narrow for a moped and another vehicle to travel safely side by side within the lane.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person operating a moped upon a one-way highway with two or more marked traffic lanes may ride as near the left-hand curb or edge of such roadway as practicable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person propelling a moped solely by human power upon and along a sidewalk, or across a roadway upon and along a crosswalk, has all the rights and duties applicable to a pedestrian under the same circumstances, except that such person shall yield the right-of-way to any pedestrian and shall give an audible signal before overtaking and passing a pedestrian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall propel a moped upon and along a sidewalk while the motor is operating.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 8, ch. 87-161; s. 163, ch. 99-248.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.127.</Text></Note></Section>