<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0316.646" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Security required; proof of security and display thereof; dismissal of cases.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person required by s. 324.022 to maintain property damage liability security, required by s. 324.023 to maintain liability security for bodily injury or death, or required by s. 627.733 to maintain personal injury protection security on a motor vehicle shall have in his or her immediate possession at all times while operating such motor vehicle proper proof of maintenance of the required security. Such proof shall be a uniform proof-of-insurance card in a form prescribed by the department, a valid insurance policy, an insurance policy binder, a certificate of insurance, or such other proof as may be prescribed by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, upon a comparison of the vehicle registration certificate or other evidence of registration or ownership with the operator’s driver’s license or other evidence of personal identity, it appears to a law enforcement officer or other person authorized to issue traffic citations that the operator is also the owner or registrant of the vehicle, upon demand of the law enforcement officer or other person authorized to issue traffic citations the operator shall display proper proof of maintenance of security as specified by subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates this section commits a nonmoving traffic infraction subject to the penalty provided in chapter 318 and shall be required to furnish proof of security as provided in this section. If any person charged with a violation of this section fails to furnish proof at or before the scheduled court appearance date that security was in effect at the time of the violation, the court shall, upon conviction, notify the department to suspend the registration and driver’s license of such person. If the court fails to order the suspension of the person’s registration and driver’s license for a conviction of this section at the time of sentencing, the department shall, upon receiving notice of the conviction from the court, suspend the person’s registration and driver’s license for the violation of this section. Such license and registration may be reinstated only as provided in s. 324.0221.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person presenting proof of insurance as required in subsection (1) who knows that the insurance as represented by such proof of insurance is not currently in force is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-182; s. 50, ch. 87-198; s. 3, ch. 88-370; s. 36, ch. 91-224; s. 332, ch. 95-148; s. 6, ch. 95-333; s. 38, ch. 96-350; s. 2, ch. 2007-150; s. 1, ch. 2007-324; s. 11, ch. 2010-223.</History>
</Section>