<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Scope and effect of regulations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a violation of this chapter for any person to drive or move, or for the owner to cause or knowingly permit to be driven or moved, on any highway any vehicle, or combination of vehicles, which is in such unsafe condition as to endanger any person, which does not contain those parts or is not at all times equipped with such lamps and other equipment in proper condition and adjustment as required in this chapter, or which is equipped in any manner in violation of this chapter, or for any person to do any act forbidden, or fail to perform any act required, under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the use of additional parts and accessories on any vehicle not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter with respect to equipment required on vehicles shall not apply to implements of husbandry, road machinery, road rollers, or farm tractors except as herein made applicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter with respect to equipment required on vehicles shall not apply to motorcycles or motor-driven cycles, except as herein made applicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter and 49 C.F.R. part 393, with respect to number, visibility, distribution of light, and mounting height requirements for headlamps, auxiliary lamps, and turn signals shall not apply to a front-end loading collection vehicle, when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The front-end loading mechanism and container or containers are in the lowered position;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vehicle is engaged in collecting solid waste or recyclable or recovered materials; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vehicle is being operated at speeds less than 20 miles per hour with the vehicular hazard-warning lights activated.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 6, ch. 97-280; s. 31, ch. 97-300; s. 170, ch. 99-248.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.059.</Text></Note></Section>