<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.076" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Flashing signals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever an illuminated flashing red or yellow signal is used in a traffic sign or signal it shall require obedience by vehicular traffic as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Flashing red (stop signal).</Font><EmDash />When a red lens is illuminated with rapid intermittent flashes, drivers of vehicles shall stop at a clearly marked stop line, but if none, before entering the crosswalk on the near side of the intersection, or if none, then at the point nearest the intersecting roadway where the driver has a view of approaching traffic on the intersecting roadway before entering the intersection, and the right to proceed shall be subject to the rules applicable after making a stop at a stop sign.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Flashing yellow (caution signal).</Font><EmDash />When a yellow lens is illuminated with rapid intermittent flashes, drivers of vehicles may proceed through the intersection or past such signal only with caution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply at railroad-highway grade crossings. Conduct of drivers of vehicles approaching such crossings shall be governed by the rules as set forth in ss. 316.1575 and 316.159.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 1, ch. 76-31; s. 5, ch. 86-243; s. 98, ch. 99-248.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 316.133.</Text></Note></Section>