<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.70" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonpublic sector buses; safety rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation shall establish and revise standards to assure the safe operation of nonpublic sector buses, as defined in s. 316.003(78), which standards shall be those contained in 49 C.F.R. parts 382, 385, and 390-397 and which shall be directed towards assuring that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonpublic sector buses are safely maintained, equipped, and operated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonpublic sector buses are carrying the insurance required by law and carrying liability insurance on the checked baggage of passengers not to exceed the standard adopted by the United States Department of Transportation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida license tags are purchased for nonpublic sector buses pursuant to s. 320.38.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The driving records of drivers of nonpublic sector buses are checked by their employers at least once each year to ascertain whether the driver has a suspended or revoked driver’s license.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department of Transportation personnel may conduct compliance reviews for the purpose of determining compliance with this section. A civil penalty not to exceed $5,000 in the aggregate may be assessed against any person who violates any provision of this section or who violates any rule or order of the Department of Transportation. A civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 in the aggregate may be assessed for violations found in a followup compliance review conducted within a 24-month period. A civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 in the aggregate may be assessed and the motor carrier may be enjoined pursuant to s. 316.3026 if violations are found after a second followup compliance review within 12 months after the first followup compliance review. Motor carriers found to be operating without insurance coverage required by s. 627.742 or 49 C.F.R. part 387 may be enjoined as provided in s. 316.3026.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School buses subject to the provisions of chapter 1006 or s. 316.615 are exempt from the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 7, ch. 81-209; s. 9, ch. 87-270; s. 9, ch. 95-247; s. 246, ch. 99-248; s. 960, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2003-90; s. 20, ch. 2003-286.</History></Section>