<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0316.235" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional lighting equipment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not more than two side cowl or fender lamps which shall emit an amber or white light without glare.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any motor vehicle may be equipped with not more than one running board courtesy lamp on each side thereof which shall emit a white or amber light without glare.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any motor vehicle may be equipped with one or more backup lamps either separately or in combination with other lamps, but any such backup lamp or lamps shall not be lighted when the motor vehicle is in forward motion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vehicle 80 inches or more in overall width, if not otherwise required by s. 316.2225, may be equipped with not more than three identification lamps showing to the front which shall emit an amber light without glare and not more than three identification lamps showing to the rear which shall emit a red light without glare. Such lamps shall be mounted as specified in this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bus, as defined in s. 316.003(3), may be equipped with a deceleration lighting system which cautions following vehicles that the bus is slowing, preparing to stop, or is stopped. Such lighting system shall consist of amber lights mounted in horizontal alignment on the rear of the vehicle at or near the vertical centerline of the vehicle, not higher than the lower edge of the rear window or, if the vehicle has no rear window, not higher than 72 inches from the ground. Such lights shall be visible from a distance of not less than 300 feet to the rear in normal sunlight. Lights are permitted to light and flash during deceleration, braking, or standing and idling of the bus. Vehicular hazard warning flashers may be used in conjunction with or in lieu of a rear-mounted deceleration lighting system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-135; s. 27, ch. 76-31; s. 3, ch. 86-23; s. 185, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>