<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0650.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Plans for coverage of employees of political subdivisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each political subdivision of the state is authorized to submit for approval by the state agency a plan for extending the benefits of Title II of the Social Security Act, in conformity with the applicable provisions of such act, to employees of such political subdivisions. Each such plan and any amendment thereof shall be approved by the state agency if it is found that such plan, or such plan as amended, is in conformity with such requirements as are provided in regulations of the state agency, except that no such plan shall be approved unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is in conformity with the requirements of the Social Security Act and with the agreement entered into under s. 650.03;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It provides that all services which constitute employment as defined in s. 650.02 are performed in the employ of the political subdivisions by employees thereof, shall be covered by the plan, except such of those services set forth in s. 650.02(2)(c) as the political subdivision specifically elects to exclude;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It specifies the source or sources from which the funds necessary to make the payments required by paragraph (3)(a) are expected to be derived and contains reasonable assurance that such sources will be adequate for such purpose;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It provides for such methods of administration of the plan by the political subdivision as are found by the state agency to be necessary for the proper and efficient administration of the plan;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It provides that the political subdivision will make such reports, in such form and containing such information, as the state agency may from time to time require, and comply with such provisions as the state agency or the Secretary of Health and Human Services may from time to time find necessary to assure the correctness and verification of such reports; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It authorizes the state agency to terminate the plan in its entirety, in the discretion of the state agency, if it finds that there has been a failure to comply substantially with any provisions contained in such plan, such termination to take effect at the expiration of such notice and on such conditions as may be provided by regulations of the state agency and may be consistent with the provisions of the Social Security Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state agency shall not finally refuse to approve a plan submitted by a political subdivision under subsection (1), and shall not terminate an approved plan, without reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the political subdivision affected thereby. Any final decision of the state agency shall be subject to proper judicial review.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each political subdivision as to which a plan has been approved under this section shall pay to the Internal Revenue Service, with respect to wages (as defined in s. 650.02), at such time or times as the Social Security Administration may prescribe, contributions in the amounts and at the rates specified in the applicable agreement entered into by the state agency under s. 650.03.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each political subdivision required to make payments under paragraph (a) is authorized, in consideration of the employee’s retention in, or entry upon, employment after enactment of this chapter, to impose upon each of its employees, as to services which are covered by an approved plan, a contribution with respect to his or her wages as defined in s. 650.02 not exceeding the amount of the employee tax which would be imposed by the Federal Insurance Contributions Act if such services constituted employment within the meaning of that act, and to deduct the amount of such contribution from his or her wages as and when paid. Contributions so collected shall be paid to the Internal Revenue Service in partial discharge of the liability of such political subdivision or instrumentality under paragraph (a). Failure to deduct such contribution shall not relieve the employee or employer of liability therefor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, effective January 1, 1972, all state political subdivisions receiving financial aid that provide social security coverage for their employees pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and the provisions of the various retirement systems as authorized by law shall, in addition to other purposes, utilize all grants-in-aid and other revenue received from the state to pay the employer’s share of social security cost.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grants-in-aid and other revenue referred to in paragraph (a) specifically include, but are not limited to, minimum foundation program grants to public school districts and community colleges; gasoline, motor fuel, cigarette, racing, and insurance premium taxes distributed to political subdivisions; and amounts specifically appropriated as grants-in-aid for mental health, mental retardation, and mosquito control programs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 26841, 1951; ss. 5, 6, 7, ch. 28246, 1953; s. 11, ch. 29824, 1955; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 1, ch. 72-109; s. 70, ch. 72-221; s. 1, ch. 72-342; s. 11, ch. 83-76; s. 506, ch. 97-102; s. 35, ch. 2004-234; s. 127, ch. 2005-2; s. 24, ch. 2006-312.</History></Section>