<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0463.0135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards of practice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed practitioner shall provide that degree of care which conforms to that level of care provided by medical practitioners in the same or similar communities. A licensed practitioner shall advise or assist her or his patient in obtaining further care when the service of another health care practitioner is required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed practitioner diagnosing angle closure, infantile, or congenital forms of glaucoma shall refer the patient to a physician skilled in diseases of the eye and licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an infectious corneal disease condition has not responded to standard methods of treatment within the scope of optometric practice, the certified optometrist shall consult with a physician skilled in diseases of the eye and licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed practitioner shall promptly advise a patient to seek evaluation by a physician skilled in diseases of the eye and licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 for diagnosis and possible treatment whenever the licensed practitioner is informed by the patient of the sudden onset of spots or “floaters” with loss of all or part of the visual field.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensed practitioner shall routinely advise a patient to immediately contact the licensed practitioner if the patient experiences an adverse drug reaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensed practitioner shall, when appropriate, refer to medical specialists or facilities patients who notify a licensed practitioner of an adverse drug reaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensed practitioner shall place in a patient’s permanent record information describing any adverse drug reaction experienced by the patient, the date of such reaction, and whether any referral was made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensed practitioner shall maintain the names of at least three physicians, physician clinics, or hospitals to whom the licensed practitioner will refer patients who experience an adverse drug reaction. At least one of these physicians shall be a physician skilled in the diagnosis and treatment of diseases of the eye and licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed practitioner who believes a patient may have glaucoma shall promptly advise the patient of the serious nature of glaucoma. The licensed practitioner shall place in the patient’s permanent record that the practitioner provided such advice to the patient.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 14, 21, ch. 86-289; s. 70, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 237, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>