<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0463.0055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration and prescription of topical ocular pharmaceutical agents; committee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified optometrists may administer and prescribe topical ocular pharmaceutical agents as provided in this section for the diagnosis and treatment of ocular conditions of the human eye and its appendages without the use of surgery or other invasive techniques. However, a licensed practitioner who is not certified may use topically applied anesthetics solely for the purpose of glaucoma examinations, but is otherwise prohibited from administering or prescribing topical ocular pharmaceutical agents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby created a committee composed of two optometrists licensed pursuant to this chapter, appointed by the Board of Optometry, two board-certified ophthalmologists licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459, appointed by the Board of Medicine, and one additional person with a doctorate degree in pharmacology who is not licensed pursuant to chapter 458, chapter 459, or this chapter, appointed by the State Surgeon General. The committee shall review requests for additions to, deletions from, or modifications of a formulary of topical ocular pharmaceutical agents for administration and prescription by certified optometrists and shall provide to the board advisory opinions and recommendations on such requests. The formulary shall consist of those topical ocular pharmaceutical agents which the certified optometrist is qualified to use in the practice of optometry. The board shall establish, add to, delete from, or modify the formulary by rule. Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 120 to the contrary, the formulary rule shall become effective 60 days from the date it is filed with the Secretary of State.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The formulary may be added to, deleted from, or modified according to the procedure described in paragraph (a). Any person who requests an addition, deletion, or modification of an authorized topical ocular pharmaceutical agent shall have the burden of proof to show cause why such addition, deletion, or modification should be made.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General shall have standing to challenge any rule or proposed rule of the board pursuant to s. 120.56. In addition to challenges for any invalid exercise of delegated legislative authority, the administrative law judge, upon such a challenge by the State Surgeon General, may declare all or part of a rule or proposed rule invalid if it:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not protect the public from any significant and discernible harm or damages;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably restricts competition or the availability of professional services in the state or in a significant part of the state; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unnecessarily increases the cost of professional services without a corresponding or equivalent public benefit.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, there shall not be created a presumption of the existence of any of the conditions cited in this subsection in the event that the rule or proposed rule is challenged.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon adoption of the formulary required by this section, and upon each addition, deletion, or modification to the formulary, the board shall mail a copy of the amended formulary to each certified optometrist and to each pharmacy licensed by the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certified optometrist shall be issued a prescriber number by the board. Any prescription written by a certified optometrist for a topical ocular pharmaceutical agent pursuant to this section shall have the prescriber number printed thereon.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 6, 21, ch. 86-289; s. 69, ch. 91-137; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 93-101; s. 223, ch. 96-410; s. 81, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>