<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0463.0057" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Optometric faculty certificate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue an optometric faculty certificate without examination to an individual who remits a nonrefundable application fee, not to exceed $100 plus the actual per applicant cost to the department, and who demonstrates to the board that she or he meets the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an accredited school or college of optometry approved by an accrediting agency recognized by the United States Office of Education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid current license to practice optometry in another jurisdiction in the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 21 years of age and of good moral character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not committed any act or offense in any jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining an optometrist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been offered and has accepted a full-time faculty appointment to teach in a program of optometry at a Florida-based college of optometry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides a certification from the dean of the college that she or he has accepted the offer of the full-time faculty appointment to teach at the Florida-based college of optometry.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate shall authorize the holder to practice only in conjunction with her or his faculty position at a Florida-based optometry school and its affiliated clinics which are registered with the board as sites at which holders of optometric faculty certificates will be practicing. Such certificates shall automatically expire upon termination of the holder’s relationship with the school or after a period of 2 years, whichever occurs first.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder of a faculty certificate may engage in the practice of optometry as permitted by this section, but may not administer or prescribe topical ocular pharmaceutical agents unless the certificateholder has satisfied the requirements of s. 463.006(1)(b)4. and 5.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (2), an optometric faculty certificate is renewable every 2 years by a holder who applies to the board on a form prescribed by the board and who continues to satisfy the requirements set forth in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 90-34; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-101; s. 233, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>