<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0463.014" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain acts prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No corporation, lay body, organization, or individual other than a licensed practitioner shall engage in the practice of optometry through the means of engaging the services, upon a salary, commission, or other means or inducement, of any person licensed to practice optometry in this state. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to prohibit the association of a licensed practitioner with a multidisciplinary group of licensed health care professionals, the primary objective of which is the diagnosis and treatment of the human body.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No licensed practitioner shall engage in the practice of optometry with any corporation, organization, group, or lay individual. This provision shall not prohibit licensed practitioners from employing, or from forming partnerships or professional associations with, licensed practitioners licensed in this state or with other licensed health care professionals, the primary objective of whom is the diagnosis and treatment of the human body.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No rule of the board shall forbid the practice of optometry in or on the premises of a commercial or mercantile establishment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No licensed practitioner may practice under practice identification names, trade names, or service names, unless any dissemination of information by the practitioner to consumers contains the name under which the practitioner is licensed or that of the professional association in which the practitioner participates. Any advertisement or other dissemination of information to consumers may contain factual information as to the geographic location of licensed practitioners or of the availability of optometric services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No licensed practitioner shall adopt and publish or cause to be published any practice identification name, trade name, or service name which is, contains, or is intended to serve as an affirmation of the quality or competitive value of the optometric services provided at the identified practice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation or labor organization may employ licensed practitioners to provide optometric services to bona fide employees of such corporation and members of their immediate families or to bona fide members of such labor organization and members of their immediate families, provided the provision of such services is incidental to the legitimate business of such corporation or labor organization. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to authorize the employment of licensed practitioners by corporations or organizations formed primarily for such purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, ordering, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, or giving any systemic drugs by a licensed practitioner is prohibited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Surgery of any kind, including the use of lasers, is expressly prohibited. Certified optometrists may remove superficial foreign bodies. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “superficial foreign bodies” means any foreign matter that is embedded in the conjunctiva or cornea but which has not penetrated the globe.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No rule of the board shall prohibit a licensed practitioner from authorizing a board-certified optician to fill, fit, adapt, or dispense a contact lens prescription as authorized under chapter 484.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-194; s. 318, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 26, ch. 83-329; ss. 15, 20, 21, ch. 86-289; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 93-101.</History></Section>