<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0463.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Optometry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed practitioner” means a person who is a primary health care provider licensed to engage in the practice of optometry under the authority of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed practitioner who is not a certified optometrist shall be required to display at her or his place of practice a sign which states, “I am a Licensed Practitioner, not a Certified Optometrist, and I am not able to prescribe topical ocular pharmaceutical agents.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All practitioners initially licensed after July 1, 1993, must be certified optometrists.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified optometrist” means a licensed practitioner authorized by the board to administer and prescribe topical ocular pharmaceutical agents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Optometry” means the diagnosis of conditions of the human eye and its appendages; the employment of any objective or subjective means or methods, including the administration of topical ocular pharmaceutical agents, for the purpose of determining the refractive powers of the human eyes, or any visual, muscular, neurological, or anatomic anomalies of the human eyes and their appendages; and the prescribing and employment of lenses, prisms, frames, mountings, contact lenses, orthoptic exercises, light frequencies, and any other means or methods, including topical ocular pharmaceutical agents, for the correction, remedy, or relief of any insufficiencies or abnormal conditions of the human eyes and their appendages.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct supervision” means supervision to an extent that the licensee remains on the premises while all procedures are being done and gives final approval to any procedures performed by an employee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General supervision” means the responsible supervision of supportive personnel by a licensee who need not be present when such procedures are performed, but who assumes legal liability therefor. Except in cases of emergency, “general supervision” shall require the easy availability or physical presence of the licensee for consultation with and direction of the supportive personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Appendages” means the eyelids, the eyebrows, the conjunctiva, and the lacrimal apparatus.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transcript-quality” means a course which is in conjunction with or sponsored by a school or college of optometry or equivalent educational entity, which course is approved by the board and requires a test and passing grade.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Clock hours” means the actual time engaged in approved coursework and clinical training.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-194; s. 315, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 20, 21, ch. 86-289; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 93-101; s. 119, ch. 94-218; s. 232, ch. 97-103; s. 63, ch. 98-166.</History></Section>