<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0259.032" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund; purpose.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the policy of the state that the citizens of this state shall be assured public ownership of natural areas for purposes of maintaining this state’s unique natural resources; protecting air, land, and water quality; promoting water resource development to meet the needs of natural systems and citizens of this state; promoting restoration activities on public lands; and providing lands for natural resource based recreation. In recognition of this policy, it is the intent of the Legislature to provide such public lands for the people residing in urban and metropolitan areas of the state, as well as those residing in less populated, rural areas. It is the further intent of the Legislature, with regard to the lands described in paragraph (3)(c), that a high priority be given to the acquisition, restoration, and management of such lands in or near counties exhibiting the greatest concentration of population and, with regard to the lands described in subsection (3), that a high priority be given to acquiring lands or rights or interests in lands that advance the goals and objectives of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission’s approved species or habitat recovery plans, or lands within any area designated as an area of critical state concern under s. 380.05 which, in the judgment of the advisory council established pursuant to s. 259.035, or its successor, cannot be adequately protected by application of land development regulations adopted pursuant to s. 380.05. Finally, it is the Legislature’s intent that lands acquired through this program and any successor programs be managed in such a way as to protect or restore their natural resource values, and provide the greatest benefit, including public access, to the citizens of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund is established within the Department of Environmental Protection. The fund shall be used as a nonlapsing, revolving fund exclusively for the purposes of this section. The fund shall be credited with proceeds from the following excise taxes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The excise taxes on documents as provided in s. 201.15; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The excise tax on the severance of phosphate rock as provided in s. 211.3103.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Department of Revenue shall credit to the fund each month the proceeds from such taxes as provided in this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall annually be transferred from the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund to the Land Acquisition Trust Fund that amount, not to exceed $20 million annually, as shall be necessary to pay the debt service on, or fund debt service reserve funds, rebate obligations, or other amounts with respect to bonds issued pursuant to s. 375.051 to acquire lands on the established priority list developed pursuant to ss. 259.101(4) and 259.105; however, no moneys transferred to the Land Acquisition Trust Fund pursuant to this paragraph, or earnings thereon, shall be used or made available to pay debt service on the Save Our Coast revenue bonds. Amounts transferred annually from the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund to the Land Acquisition Trust Fund pursuant to this paragraph shall have the highest priority over other payments or transfers from the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund, and no other payments or transfers shall be made from the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund until such transfers to the Land Acquisition Trust Fund have been made. Moneys in the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund also shall be used to manage lands and to pay for related costs, activities, and functions pursuant to the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet, sitting as the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, may allocate moneys from the fund in any one year to acquire the fee or any lesser interest in lands for the following public purposes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conserve and protect environmentally unique and irreplaceable lands that contain native, relatively unaltered flora and fauna representing a natural area unique to, or scarce within, a region of this state or a larger geographic area;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conserve and protect lands within designated areas of critical state concern, if the proposed acquisition relates to the natural resource protection purposes of the designation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conserve and protect native species habitat or endangered or threatened species, emphasizing long-term protection for endangered or threatened species designated G-1 or G-2 by the Florida Natural Areas Inventory, and especially those areas that are special locations for breeding and reproduction;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conserve, protect, manage, or restore important ecosystems, landscapes, and forests, if the protection and conservation of such lands is necessary to enhance or protect significant surface water, groundwater, coastal, recreational, timber, or fish or wildlife resources which cannot otherwise be accomplished through local and state regulatory programs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote water resource development that benefits natural systems and citizens of the state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To facilitate the restoration and subsequent health and vitality of the Florida Everglades;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide areas, including recreational trails, for natural resource based recreation and other outdoor recreation on any part of any site compatible with conservation purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To preserve significant archaeological or historic sites;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conserve urban open spaces suitable for greenways or outdoor recreation which are compatible with conservation purposes; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To preserve agricultural lands under threat of conversion to development through less-than-fee acquisitions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands acquired under this section shall be for use as state-designated parks, recreation areas, preserves, reserves, historic or archaeological sites, geologic or botanical sites, recreational trails, forests, wilderness areas, wildlife management areas, urban open space, or other state-designated recreation or conservation lands; or they shall qualify for such state designation and use if they are to be managed by other governmental agencies or nonstate entities as provided for in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees may allocate, in any year, an amount not to exceed 5 percent of the money credited to the fund in that year, such allocation to be used for the initiation and maintenance of a natural areas inventory to aid in the identification of areas to be acquired pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys in the fund not needed to meet obligations incurred under this section shall be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the fund and may be invested in the manner provided by law. Interest received on such investments shall be credited to the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees may enter into any contract necessary to accomplish the purposes of this section. The lead land managing agencies designated by the board of trustees also are directed by the Legislature to enter into contracts or interagency agreements with other governmental entities, including local soil and water conservation districts, or private land managers who have the expertise to perform specific management activities which a lead agency lacks, or which would cost more to provide in-house. Such activities shall include, but not be limited to, controlled burning, road and ditch maintenance, mowing, and wildlife assessments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lands to be considered for purchase under this section are subject to the selection procedures of s. 259.035 and related rules and shall be acquired in accordance with acquisition procedures for state lands provided for in s. 259.041, except as otherwise provided by the Legislature. An inholding or an addition to a project selected for purchase pursuant to this chapter is not subject to the selection procedures of s. 259.035 if the estimated value of such inholding or addition does not exceed $500,000. When at least 90 percent of the acreage of a project has been purchased pursuant to this chapter, the project may be removed from the list and the remaining acreage may continue to be purchased. Moneys from the fund may be used for title work, appraisal fees, environmental audits, and survey costs related to acquisition expenses for lands to be acquired, donated, or exchanged which qualify under the categories of this section, at the discretion of the board. When the Legislature has authorized the Department of Environmental Protection to condemn a specific parcel of land and such parcel has already been approved for acquisition under this section, the land may be acquired in accordance with the provisions of chapter 73 or chapter 74, and the fund may be used to pay the condemnation award and all costs, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, associated with condemnation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All lands managed under this chapter and s. 253.034 shall be:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managed in a manner that will provide the greatest combination of benefits to the public and to the resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managed for public outdoor recreation which is compatible with the conservation and protection of public lands. Such management may include, but not be limited to, the following public recreational uses: fishing, hunting, camping, bicycling, hiking, nature study, swimming, boating, canoeing, horseback riding, diving, model hobbyist activities, birding, sailing, jogging, and other related outdoor activities compatible with the purposes for which the lands were acquired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managed for the purposes for which the lands were acquired, consistent with paragraph (11)(a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Concurrent with its adoption of the annual Conservation and Recreation Lands list of acquisition projects pursuant to s. 259.035, the board of trustees shall adopt a management prospectus for each project. The management prospectus shall delineate:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The management goals for the property;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conditions that will affect the intensity of management;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An estimate of the revenue-generating potential of the property, if appropriate;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A timetable for implementing the various stages of management and for providing access to the public, if applicable;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of potential multiple-use activities as described in this section and s. 253.034;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions for protecting existing infrastructure and for ensuring the security of the project upon acquisition;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The anticipated costs of management and projected sources of revenue, including legislative appropriations, to fund management needs; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations as to how many employees will be needed to manage the property, and recommendations as to whether local governments, volunteer groups, the former landowner, or other interested parties can be involved in the management.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Concurrent with the approval of the acquisition contract pursuant to s. 259.041(3)(c) for any interest in lands except those lands being acquired under the provisions of s. 259.1052, the board of trustees shall designate an agency or agencies to manage such lands. The board shall evaluate and amend, as appropriate, the management policy statement for the project as provided by s. 259.035, consistent with the purposes for which the lands are acquired. For any fee simple acquisition of a parcel which is or will be leased back for agricultural purposes, or any acquisition of a less-than-fee interest in land that is or will be used for agricultural purposes, the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund shall first consider having a soil and water conservation district, created pursuant to chapter 582, manage and monitor such interests.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State agencies designated to manage lands acquired under this chapter except those lands acquired under s. 259.1052 may contract with local governments and soil and water conservation districts to assist in management activities, including the responsibility of being the lead land manager. Such land management contracts may include a provision for the transfer of management funding to the local government or soil and water conservation district from the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund in an amount adequate for the local government or soil and water conservation district to perform its contractual land management responsibilities and proportionate to its responsibilities, and which otherwise would have been expended by the state agency to manage the property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediately following the acquisition of any interest in lands under this chapter, the Department of Environmental Protection, acting on behalf of the board of trustees, may issue to the lead managing entity an interim assignment letter to be effective until the execution of a formal lease.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State, regional, or local governmental agencies or private entities designated to manage lands under this section shall develop and adopt, with the approval of the board of trustees, an individual management plan for each project designed to conserve and protect such lands and their associated natural resources. Private sector involvement in management plan development may be used to expedite the planning process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual management plans required by s. 253.034(5), for parcels over 160 acres, shall be developed with input from an advisory group. Members of this advisory group shall include, at a minimum, representatives of the lead land managing agency, comanaging entities, local private property owners, the appropriate soil and water conservation district, a local conservation organization, and a local elected official. The advisory group shall conduct at least one public hearing within the county in which the parcel or project is located. For those parcels or projects that are within more than one county, at least one areawide public hearing shall be acceptable and the lead managing agency shall invite a local elected official from each county. The areawide public hearing shall be held in the county in which the core parcels are located. Notice of such public hearing shall be posted on the parcel or project designated for management, advertised in a paper of general circulation, and announced at a scheduled meeting of the local governing body before the actual public hearing. The management prospectus required pursuant to paragraph (9)(d) shall be available to the public for a period of 30 days prior to the public hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once a plan is adopted, the managing agency or entity shall update the plan at least every 10 years in a form and manner prescribed by rule of the board of trustees. Such updates, for parcels over 160 acres, shall be developed with input from an advisory group. Such plans may include transfers of leasehold interests to appropriate conservation organizations or governmental entities designated by the Land Acquisition and Management Advisory Council or its successor, for uses consistent with the purposes of the organizations and the protection, preservation, conservation, restoration, and proper management of the lands and their resources. Volunteer management assistance is encouraged, including, but not limited to, assistance by youths participating in programs sponsored by state or local agencies, by volunteers sponsored by environmental or civic organizations, and by individuals participating in programs for committed delinquents and adults.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each project for which lands are acquired after July 1, 1995, an individual management plan shall be adopted and in place no later than 1 year after the essential parcel or parcels identified in the priority list developed pursuant to ss. 259.101(4) and 259.105 have been acquired. The Department of Environmental Protection shall distribute only 75 percent of the acquisition funds to which a budget entity or water management district would otherwise be entitled from the Preservation 2000 Trust Fund to any budget entity or any water management district that has more than one-third of its management plans overdue.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of subparagraph 1. do not apply to the individual management plan for the Babcock Crescent B Ranch being acquired pursuant to s. 259.1052. The management plan for the ranch shall be adopted and in place no later than 2 years following the date of acquisition by the state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual management plans shall conform to the appropriate policies and guidelines of the state land management plan and shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the purpose for which the lands were acquired, the projected use or uses as defined in s. 253.034, and the statutory authority for such use or uses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Key management activities necessary to achieve the desired outcomes, including, but not limited to, providing public access, preserving and protecting natural resources, protecting cultural and historical resources, restoring habitat, protecting threatened and endangered species, controlling the spread of nonnative plants and animals, performing prescribed fire activities, and other appropriate resource management.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A specific description of how the managing agency plans to identify, locate, protect, and preserve, or otherwise use fragile, nonrenewable natural and cultural resources.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A priority schedule for conducting management activities, based on the purposes for which the lands were acquired.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cost estimate for conducting priority management activities, to include recommendations for cost-effective methods of accomplishing those activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cost estimate for conducting other management activities which would enhance the natural resource value or public recreation value for which the lands were acquired. The cost estimate shall include recommendations for cost-effective methods of accomplishing those activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination of the public uses and public access that would be consistent with the purposes for which the lands were acquired.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of State Lands shall submit a copy of each individual management plan for parcels which exceed 160 acres in size to each member of the Acquisition and Restoration Council, which shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 60 days after receiving a plan from the division, review each plan for compliance with the requirements of this subsection and with the requirements of the rules established by the board pursuant to this subsection.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider the propriety of the recommendations of the managing agency with regard to the future use or protection of the property.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After its review, submit the plan, along with its recommendations and comments, to the board of trustees, with recommendations as to whether to approve the plan as submitted, approve the plan with modifications, or reject the plan.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees shall consider the individual management plan submitted by each state agency and the recommendations of the Acquisition and Restoration Council and the Division of State Lands and shall approve the plan with or without modification or reject such plan. The use or possession of any lands owned by the board of trustees which is not in accordance with an approved individual management plan is subject to termination by the board of trustees.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">By July 1 of each year, each governmental agency and each private entity designated to manage lands shall report to the Secretary of Environmental Protection on the progress of funding, staffing, and resource management of every project for which the agency or entity is responsible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that acquiring lands pursuant to this chapter serves the public interest by protecting land, air, and water resources which contribute to the public health and welfare, providing areas for natural resource based recreation, and ensuring the survival of unique and irreplaceable plant and animal species. The Legislature intends for these lands to be managed and maintained for the purposes for which they were acquired and for the public to have access to and use of these lands where it is consistent with acquisition purposes and would not harm the resources the state is seeking to protect on the public’s behalf.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount of not less than 1.5 percent of the cumulative total of funds ever deposited into the Florida Preservation 2000 Trust Fund and the Florida Forever Trust Fund shall be made available for the purposes of management, maintenance, and capital improvements not eligible for funding pursuant to s. 11(e), Art. VII of the State Constitution, and for associated contractual services, for lands acquired pursuant to this section, s. 259.101, s. 259.105, s. 259.1052, or previous programs for the acquisition of lands for conservation and recreation, including state forests, to which title is vested in the board of trustees and other conservation and recreation lands managed by a state agency. Of this amount, $250,000 shall be transferred annually to the Plant Industry Trust Fund within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services for the purpose of implementing the Endangered or Threatened Native Flora Conservation Grants Program pursuant to s. 581.185(11). Each agency with management responsibilities shall annually request from the Legislature funds sufficient to fulfill such responsibilities to implement individual management plans. For the purposes of this paragraph, capital improvements shall include, but need not be limited to, perimeter fencing, signs, firelanes, access roads and trails, and minimal public accommodations, such as primitive campsites, garbage receptacles, and toilets. Any equipment purchased with funds provided pursuant to this paragraph may be used for the purposes described in this paragraph on any conservation and recreation lands managed by a state agency. The funding requirement created in this paragraph is subject to an annual evaluation by the Legislature in order to ensure that such requirement does not impact the respective trust fund in a manner that would prevent the trust fund from meeting other minimum requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Land Management Uniform Accounting Council shall prepare and deliver a report on the methodology and formula for allocating land management funds to the Acquisition and Restoration Council. The Acquisition and Restoration Council shall review, modify as appropriate, and submit the report to the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund. The board of trustees shall review, modify as appropriate, and submit the report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives no later than December 31, 2008, which provides an interim management formula and a long-term management formula, and the methodologies used to develop the formulas, which shall be used to allocate land management funds provided for in paragraph (b) for interim and long-term management of all lands managed pursuant to this chapter and for associated contractual services. The methodology and formula for interim management shall be based on the estimated land acquisitions for the fiscal year in which the interim funds will be expended. The methodology and formula for long-term management shall recognize, but not be limited to, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assignment of management intensity associated with managed habitats and natural communities and the related management activities to achieve land management goals provided in s. 253.034(5) and subsection (10).</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that require minimal effort for resource preservation or restoration.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that require moderate effort for resource preservation or restoration.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that require significant effort for resource preservation or restoration.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assignment of management intensity associated with public access, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that are open to the public but offer no more than minimally developed facilities;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that have a high degree of public use and offer highly developed facilities; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that are sites that have historic significance, unique natural features, or a very high degree of public use.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that have a secondary manager contributing to the overall management effort.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The anticipated revenues generated from management of the lands.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The impacts of, and needs created or addressed by, multiple-use management strategies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acres of land that have infestations of nonnative or invasive plants, animals, or fish.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In evaluating the management funding needs of lands based on the above categories, the lead land managing agencies shall include in their considerations the impacts of, and needs created or addressed by, multiple-use management strategies. The funding formulas for interim and long-term management proposed by the agencies shall be reviewed by the Legislature during the 2009 regular legislative session. The Legislature may reject, modify, or take no action relative to the proposed funding formulas. If no action is taken, the funding formulas shall be used in the allocation and distribution of funds provided in paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All revenues generated through multiple-use management or compatible secondary-use management shall be returned to the lead agency responsible for such management and shall be used to pay for management activities on all conservation, preservation, and recreation lands under the agency’s jurisdiction. In addition, such revenues shall be segregated in an agency trust fund and shall remain available to the agency in subsequent fiscal years to support land management appropriations. For the purposes of this paragraph, compatible secondary-use management shall be those activities described in subsection (9) undertaken on parcels designated as single use pursuant to s. 253.034(2)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to one-fifth of the funds provided for in paragraph (b) shall be reserved by the board of trustees for interim management of acquisitions and for associated contractual services, to ensure the conservation and protection of natural resources on project sites and to allow limited public recreational use of lands. Interim management activities may include, but not be limited to, resource assessments, control of invasive, nonnative species, habitat restoration, fencing, law enforcement, controlled burning, and public access consistent with preliminary determinations made pursuant to paragraph (9)(g). The board of trustees shall make these interim funds available immediately upon purchase.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall set long-range and annual goals for the control and removal of nonnative, invasive plant species on public lands. Such goals shall differentiate between aquatic plant species and upland plant species. In setting such goals, the department may rank, in order of adverse impact, species that impede or destroy the functioning of natural systems. Notwithstanding paragraph (a), up to one-fourth of the funds provided for in paragraph (b) may be used by the agencies receiving those funds for control and removal of nonnative, invasive species on public lands.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 1999, the Legislature shall make available sufficient funds annually from the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund to the department for payment in lieu of taxes to qualifying counties and local governments as defined in paragraph (b) for all actual tax losses incurred as a result of board of trustees acquisitions for state agencies under the Florida Forever program or the Florida Preservation 2000 program during any year. Reserved funds not used for payments in lieu of taxes in any year shall revert to the fund to be used for land management in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment in lieu of taxes shall be available:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To all counties that have a population of 150,000 or fewer. Population levels shall be determined pursuant to s. 11.031.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To all local governments located in eligible counties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To Glades County, where a privately owned and operated prison leased to the state has recently been opened and where privately owned and operated juvenile justice facilities leased to the state have recently been constructed and opened, a payment in lieu of taxes, in an amount that offsets the loss of property tax revenue, which funds have already been appropriated and allocated from the Department of Correction’s budget for the purpose of reimbursing amounts equal to lost ad valorem taxes.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If insufficient funds are available in any year to make full payments to all qualifying counties and local governments, such counties and local governments shall receive a pro rata share of the moneys available.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment amount shall be based on the average amount of actual taxes paid on the property for the 3 years preceding acquisition. Applications for payment in lieu of taxes shall be made no later than January 31 of the year following acquisition. No payment in lieu of taxes shall be made for properties which were exempt from ad valorem taxation for the year immediately preceding acquisition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If property which was subject to ad valorem taxation was acquired by a tax-exempt entity for ultimate conveyance to the state under this chapter, payment in lieu of taxes shall be made for such property based upon the average amount of taxes paid on the property for the 3 years prior to its being removed from the tax rolls. The department shall certify to the Department of Revenue those properties that may be eligible under this provision. Once eligibility has been established, that county or local government shall receive annual payments for each tax loss until the qualifying county or local government exceeds the population threshold pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment in lieu of taxes pursuant to this subsection shall be made annually to qualifying counties and local governments after certification by the Department of Revenue that the amounts applied for are reasonably appropriate, based on the amount of actual taxes paid on the eligible property. With the assistance of the local government requesting payment in lieu of taxes, the state agency that acquired the land is responsible for preparing and submitting application requests for payment to the Department of Revenue for certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board of trustees conveys to a local government title to any land owned by the board, any payments in lieu of taxes on the land made to the local government shall be discontinued as of the date of the conveyance.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For the purposes of this subsection, “local government” includes municipalities, the county school board, mosquito control districts, and any other local government entity which levies ad valorem taxes, with the exception of a water management district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys credited to the fund each year which are not used for management, maintenance, or capital improvements pursuant to subsection (11); for payment in lieu of taxes pursuant to subsection (12); or for the purposes of subsection (5), shall be available for the acquisition of land pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees may adopt rules to further define the categories of land for acquisition under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days after receiving a certified letter from the owner of a property on the Conservation and Recreation Lands list or the priority list established pursuant to s. 259.105 objecting to the property being included in an acquisition project, where such property is a project or part of a project which has not been listed for purchase in the current year’s land acquisition work plan, the board of trustees shall delete the property from the list or from the boundary of an acquisition project on the list.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 79-255; s. 16, ch. 80-356; s. 5, ch. 81-35; s. 1, ch. 81-210; s. 165, ch. 81-259; s. 1, ch. 82-152; s. 2, ch. 83-80; s. 1, ch. 83-114; s. 10, ch. 84-330; s. 13, ch. 86-178; s. 6, ch. 86-294; s. 1, ch. 87-96; s. 1, ch. 88-387; s. 13, ch. 89-116; s. 1, ch. 89-276; s. 2, ch. 90-1; s. 8, ch. 90-217; s. 1, ch. 91-62; s. 5, ch. 91-420; s. 2, ch. 92-288; s. 45, ch. 93-206; s. 4, ch. 94-197; s. 1, ch. 94-212; s. 1, ch. 94-240; s. 65, ch. 94-356; s. 5, ch. 95-349; ss. 19, 20, ch. 95-430; s. 3, ch. 96-389; s. 19, ch. 96-420; s. 23, ch. 97-94; ss. 27, 29, ch. 97-153; s. 6, ch. 97-164; ss. 26, 38, ch. 98-46; s. 10, ch. 99-4; s. 34, ch. 99-13; ss. 28, 33, 53, ch. 99-228; s. 13, ch. 99-247; s. 20, ch. 99-292; s. 7, ch. 2000-170; s. 61, ch. 2000-171; s. 45, ch. 2001-61; s. 7, ch. 2002-2; s. 28, ch. 2002-402; s. 15, ch. 2003-6; s. 280, ch. 2003-261; s. 6, ch. 2003-394; s. 18, ch. 2004-5; ss. 42, 75, ch. 2004-269; s. 41, ch. 2005-71; ss. 31, 42, ch. 2006-26; s. 4, ch. 2006-231; s. 5, ch. 2008-5; s. 9, ch. 2008-229; s. 21, ch. 2009-21.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 253.023.</Text></Note></Section>