<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0259.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For projects and acquisitions selected for purchase pursuant to ss. 259.035, 259.101, and 259.105:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board is given the responsibility, authority, and power to develop and execute a comprehensive, statewide 5-year plan to conserve, restore, and protect environmentally endangered lands, ecosystems, lands necessary for outdoor recreational needs, and other lands as identified in ss. 259.032, 259.101, and 259.105. This plan shall be kept current through continual reevaluation and revision. The advisory council or its successor shall assist the board in the development, reevaluation, and revision of the plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter into contracts with the government of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof; the state or any county, municipality, district authority, or political subdivision; or any private corporation, partnership, association, or person providing for or relating to the conservation or protection of certain lands in accomplishing the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 45 days after the advisory council or its successor submits the lists of projects to the board, the board shall approve, in whole or in part, the lists of projects in the order of priority in which such projects are presented. To the greatest extent practicable, projects on the lists shall be acquired in their approved order of priority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board is authorized to acquire, by purchase, gift, or devise or otherwise, the fee title or any lesser interest of lands, water areas, and related resources for environmentally endangered lands.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For state capital projects for outdoor recreation lands, the provisions of chapter 375 and s. 253.025 shall also apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-300; s. 15, ch. 79-255; s. 4, ch. 81-210; s. 4, ch. 83-114; s. 12, ch. 89-116; s. 6, ch. 92-288; s. 16, ch. 94-240; s. 18, ch. 99-247; s. 29, ch. 2000-152.</History></Section>