<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0901.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Strip searches of persons arrested; body cavity search.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “strip search” means having an arrested person remove or arrange some or all of his or her clothing so as to permit a visual or manual inspection of the genitals; buttocks; anus; breasts, in the case of a female; or undergarments of such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person arrested for a traffic, regulatory, or misdemeanor offense, except in a case which is violent in nature, which involves a weapon, or which involves a controlled substance, shall be strip searched unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is probable cause to believe that the individual is concealing a weapon, a controlled substance, or stolen property; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A judge at first appearance has found that the person arrested cannot be released either on recognizance or bond and therefore shall be incarcerated in the county jail.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each strip search shall be performed by a person of the same gender as the arrested person and on premises where the search cannot be observed by persons not physically conducting or observing the search pursuant to this section. Any observer shall be of the same gender as the arrested person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any body cavity search must be performed under sanitary conditions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No law enforcement officer shall order a strip search within the agency or facility without obtaining the written authorization of the supervising officer on duty.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting any statutory or common-law right of any person for purposes of any civil action or injunctive relief.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 81-313; s. 171, ch. 83-216; s. 1, ch. 83-254.</History></Section>