<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Officers and employees prohibited from being employed by or engaging in beverage business; penalties; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No officer or employee of the division, and no sheriff or other state, county, or municipal officer with state police power granted by the Legislature, shall be permitted to engage in the sale of alcoholic beverages under the Beverage Law; or shall be employed, directly or indirectly, in connection with the operation of any business licensed under the Beverage Law; or shall be permitted to own any stock or interest in any firm, partnership, or corporation dealing wholly or partly in the sale or distribution of alcoholic beverages, except as provided in this section. The provisions of this subsection shall not be construed to prevent any certified law enforcement officer, except members of the Florida Highway Patrol or its auxiliary, or employees of the division, from being employed in businesses which have obtained licenses only to sell beer or beer and wine for consumption off the premises. However, the written approval of the chief of police, sheriff, or other appropriate department head must be obtained for any such employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person violating this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, and shall be automatically removed or suspended from office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing herein may be construed to prohibit any sheriff or other state, county, or municipal officer with state police power granted by the Legislature from owning, negotiating, or trading any shares of stock, bonds, or other securities which are regulated by and registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission, and which are customarily traded on the major stock exchanges of the United States, or from being employed as an entertainer or from rendering security services when off duty in any business establishment licensed under the beverage laws to sell beverages, provided the written approval of the chief of police, sheriff, or other appropriate department head is obtained for the place and hours of such employment or service. Any officer employed for the purposes of rendering private security services as permitted under this section shall not be paid less than the established prevailing wage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 16774, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(229), 7648(4); s. 6, ch. 22663, 1945; s. 20, ch. 57-420; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-346; s. 560, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 72-93; s. 1, ch. 72-230; s. 144, ch. 73-333; s. 1, ch. 77-471; s. 1, ch. 79-349; s. 2, ch. 88-404; s. 148, ch. 91-224.</History></Section>