<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensing of manufacturers and distributors as vendors and of vendors as manufacturers; conditions and limitations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in s. 561.22, s. 561.42, or any other provision of the Beverage Law prohibits the ownership, management, operation, or control of not more than three vendor’s licenses for the sale of alcoholic beverages by a manufacturer of wine who is licensed and engaged in the manufacture of wine in this state, even if such manufacturer is also licensed as a distributor; provided that no such vendor’s license shall be owned, managed, operated, or controlled by any licensed manufacturer of wine unless the licensed premises of the vendor are situated on property contiguous to the manufacturing premises of the licensed manufacturer of wine.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco shall issue permits to a certified Florida Farm Winery to conduct tasting and sales of wine produced by certified Florida Farm Wineries at Florida fairs, trade shows, expositions, and festivals. The certified Florida Farm Winery shall pay all entry fees and shall have a winery representative present during the event. The permit is limited to the length of the event.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to issue vendor’s licenses to a manufacturer of malt beverages, even if such manufacturer is also licensed as a distributor, for the sale of alcoholic beverages on property consisting of a single complex, which property shall include a brewery and such other structures which promote the brewery and the tourist industry of the state. However, such property may be divided by no more than one public street or highway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding other provisions of the Beverage Law, any vendor licensed in this state may be licensed as a manufacturer of malt beverages upon a finding by the division that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vendor will be engaged in brewing malt beverages at a single location and in an amount which will not exceed 10,000 kegs per year. For purposes of this subsection, the term “keg” means 15.5 gallons.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The malt beverages so brewed will be sold to consumers for consumption on the vendor’s licensed premises or on contiguous licensed premises owned by the vendor.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vendor which is also licensed as a manufacturer of malt beverages pursuant to this subsection shall be responsible for applicable reports pursuant to ss. 561.50 and 561.55 with respect to the amount of beverage manufactured each month and shall pay applicable excise taxes thereon to the division by the 10th day of each month for the previous month.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any licensed distributor of malt beverages or any officer, agent, or other representative thereof to discourage or prohibit any vendor licensed as a manufacturer under this subsection from offering malt beverages brewed for consumption on the licensed premises of the vendor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any manufacturer of malt beverages or any officer, agent, or other representative thereof to take any action to discourage or prohibit any distributor of the manufacturer’s product from distributing such product to a licensed vendor which is also licensed as a manufacturer of malt beverages pursuant to this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-11; s. 1, ch. 67-511; s. 1, ch. 72-230; s. 1, ch. 78-187; s. 1, ch. 79-54; s. 1, ch. 84-142; s. 1, ch. 87-63; s. 8, ch. 92-151; s. 1, ch. 94-296.</History></Section>