<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.43" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dry counties; manufacturers’ or distributors’ licenses; exporters’ registrations; exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license may not be issued to a manufacturer or distributor, and a registration may not be issued to an exporter, for the operation of a manufacturing or distributing plant or exporting establishment in any county where the sale of intoxicating liquors, wines, and beers is prohibited, except:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To manufacturers of wines or wines and cordials;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To distillers of alcoholic or spirituous liquors made exclusively from citrus fruits, citrus fruit products or citrus fruit byproducts, agricultural products and byproducts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To manufacturers of beer whose plants are licensed at the time the county in which such plants are located votes to prohibit the sale of intoxicating beverages therein under the local option provisions of the Constitution of Florida.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To rectifiers and blenders of alcoholic or spirituous liquors mixed exclusively with citrus fruit products or citrus fruit byproducts, agricultural products, or agricultural byproducts.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be lawful for any manufacturer or distiller authorized to be licensed under the provisions of this section to sell its products from its plants only for transportation out of the county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 16774, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(231); s. 2, ch. 19301, 1939; s. 8, ch. 22663, 1945; s. 7, ch. 23746, 1947; s. 1, ch. 57-1969; s. 1, ch. 61-438; s. 9, ch. 63-562; s. 1, ch. 72-230; s. 16, ch. 91-60.</History></Section>