<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.695" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Stand-alone bar enforcement; qualification; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall designate as a stand-alone bar the licensed premises of a vendor that operates a business that meets the definition of a stand-alone bar in s. 386.203(11) upon receipt of the vendor’s election to permit tobacco smoking in the licensed premises.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon this act becoming a law and until the annual renewal of a vendor’s license, a licensed vendor who makes the required election under subsection (1) may permit tobacco smoking on the licensed premises and must post a notice of such intention at the same location at which the vendor’s current alcoholic beverage license is posted. The notice shall affirm the vendor’s intent to comply with the conditions and qualifications of a stand-alone bar imposed pursuant to part II of chapter 386 and the Beverage Law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only the licensed vendor may provide or serve food on the licensed premises of a stand-alone bar. Other than customary bar snacks as defined by rule of the division, the licensed vendor may not provide or serve food to a person on the licensed premises without requiring the person to pay a separately stated charge for the food that reasonably approximates the retail value of the food.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed vendor operating a stand-alone bar must conspicuously post signs at each entrance to the establishment stating that smoking is permitted in the establishment. The color and design of such signs shall be left to the discretion of the person in charge of the premises.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the initial designation, to continue to qualify as a stand-alone bar the licensee must provide to the division annually, on or before the licensee’s annual renewal date, an affidavit that certifies, with respect to the preceding 12-month period, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 10 percent of the gross revenue of the business is from the sale of food consumed on the licensed premises as defined in s. 386.203(11).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other than customary bar snacks as defined by rule of the division, the licensed vendor does not provide or serve food to a person on the licensed premises without requiring the person to pay a separately stated charge for food that reasonably approximates the retail value of the food.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensed vendor conspicuously posts signs at each entrance to the establishment stating that smoking is permitted in the establishment.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The division shall establish by rule the format of the affidavit required by this subsection. A licensed vendor shall not knowingly make a false statement on the affidavit required by this subsection. In addition to the penalties provided in subsection (7), a licensed vendor who knowingly makes a false statement on the affidavit required by this subsection may be subject to suspension or revocation of the vendor’s alcoholic beverage license under s. 561.29.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco shall have the power to enforce the provisions of part II of chapter 386 and to audit a licensed vendor that operates a business that meets the definition of a stand-alone bar as provided in s. 386.203(11) for compliance with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vendor that operates a business that meets the definition of a stand-alone bar as provided in s. 386.203(11) who violates the provisions of this section or part II of chapter 386 shall be subject to the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the first violation, the vendor shall be subject to a warning or a fine of up to $500, or both;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the second violation within 2 years after the first violation, the vendor shall be subject to a fine of not less than $500 or more than $2,000;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the third or subsequent violation within 2 years after the first violation, the vendor shall receive a suspension of the right to maintain a stand-alone bar in which tobacco smoking is permitted, not to exceed 30 days, and shall be subject to a fine of not less than $500 or more than $2,000; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the fourth or subsequent violation, the vendor shall receive a 60-day suspension of the right to maintain a stand-alone bar in which tobacco smoking is permitted and shall be subject to a fine of not less than $500 or more than $2,000 or revocation of the right to maintain a stand-alone bar in which tobacco smoking is permitted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall adopt rules governing the designation process, criteria for qualification, required recordkeeping, auditing, and all other rules necessary for the effective enforcement and administration of this section and part II of chapter 386. The division is authorized to adopt emergency rules pursuant to s. 120.54(4) to implement the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 2003-398; s. 1, ch. 2006-130.</History></Section>