<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in the Beverage Law:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State bonded warehouse” means any licensed warehouse used to store alcoholic beverages.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alcoholic beverages” means distilled spirits and all beverages containing one-half of 1 percent or more alcohol by volume.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage of alcohol by volume shall be determined by measuring the volume of the standard ethyl alcohol in the beverage and comparing it with the volume of the remainder of the ingredients as though said remainder ingredients were distilled water.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intoxicating beverage” and “intoxicating liquor” mean only those alcoholic beverages containing more than 4.007 percent of alcohol by volume.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“The Beverage Law” means this chapter and chapters 562, 563, 564, 565, 567, and 568.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer” means all persons who make alcoholic beverages except those who make beer or wine for personal or family consumption pursuant to s. 562.165.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tax” means all taxes or payments required under the Beverage Law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“There shall be paid” means “there is hereby levied and imposed and shall be paid.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sale” and “sell” mean any transfer of an alcoholic beverage for a consideration, any gift of an alcoholic beverage in connection with, or as a part of, a transfer of property other than an alcoholic beverage for a consideration, or the serving of an alcoholic beverage by a club licensed under the Beverage Law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Discount in the usual course of business” means a cash or spirituous or vinous beverage merchandise discount given pursuant to an agreement made at the time of sale. However, such agreement shall not result in an accrued, accumulated, or retroactive discount. The same discounts shall be offered to all vendors of the same license series or type buying similar quantities. Any discount which is in violation of this section shall be considered an arrangement for financial assistance by gift.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed premises” means not only rooms where alcoholic beverages are stored or sold by the licensee, but also all other rooms in the building which are so closely connected therewith as to admit of free passage from drink parlor to other rooms over which the licensee has some dominion or control and shall also include all of the area embraced within the sketch, appearing on or attached to the application for the license involved and designated as such on said sketch, in addition to that included or designated by general law. The area embraced within the sketch may include a sidewalk or other outside area which is contiguous to the licensed premises. When the sketch includes a sidewalk or other outside area, written approval from the county or municipality attesting to compliance with local ordinances must be submitted to the division to authorize inclusion of sidewalks and outside areas in licensed premises. The division may approve applications for temporary expansion of the licensed premises to include a sidewalk or other outside area for special events upon the payment of a $100 application fee, stipulation of the timeframe for the special event, and submission of a sketch outlining the expanded premises and accompanied by written approval from the county or municipality as required in this subsection. All moneys collected from the fees assessed under this subsection shall be deposited into the Alcoholic Beverage and Tobacco Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Special airport license” means a vendor license to sell certain alcoholic beverages only on those airport premises which have been designated in the <Reference Number="1" />United States National Airport System Plan, 49 U.S.C. s. 1711, as air carrier airports, commuter airports, and reliever airports.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Airport terminal” means the airport passenger handling facilities or premises publicly owned or leased by a county, municipality, or public authority at airports which have been designated in the <Reference Number="1" />United States National Airport System Plan, 49 U.S.C. s. 1711, as air carrier airports, commuter airports, and reliever airports.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means a legal or business entity, person, or persons that hold a license issued by the division and meet the qualifications set forth in s. 561.15.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bottle club” means a commercial establishment, operated for a profit, whether or not a profit is actually made, wherein patrons consume alcoholic beverages which are brought onto the premises and not sold or supplied to the patrons by the establishment, whether the patrons bring in and maintain custody of their own alcoholic beverages or surrender custody to the establishment for dispensing on the premises, and which is located in a building or other enclosed permanent structure. This definition does not apply to sporting facilities where events sanctioned by nationally recognized regulatory athletic or sports associations are held, bona fide restaurants licensed by the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation whose primary business is the service of full course meals, or hotels and motels licensed by the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exporter” means any person that sells alcoholic beverages to persons for use outside the state and includes a ship’s chandler and a duty-free shop.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Performing arts center” means a facility consisting of not less than 200 seats, owned and operated by a not-for-profit corporation qualified as an exempt organization under the provisions of s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or of the corresponding section of a subsequently enacted federal revenue act, which is used and occupied to promote development of any or all of the performing, visual, or fine arts or any or all matters relating thereto and to encourage and cultivate public and professional knowledge and appreciation of the arts through:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preparation, production, public presentation, or public exhibition of dramatic or musical works, dance, opera, motion pictures, television, music, recordings, or works of fine, performing, or visual arts of any nature;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conducting of lectures, seminars, classes, or workshops for development of skills or techniques related to the practice or appreciation of any or all of these arts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The broadcast or telecast of the performing or visual arts through whatever means is desirable, including, but not limited to, television, radio, cable, or the latest state-of-the-art media, equipment, or techniques;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reproduction of the performing, visual, or fine arts through motion pictures, videotapes, video disks, delayed presentations, sound recordings, or whatever in the future becomes a viable means or state-of-the-art;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of banquet, concession, or other on-premises food and alcoholic and nonalcoholic beverage activities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct of retail activities reasonably related to the other uses of the facility;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct of fundraising activities reasonably related to the arts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of auxiliary services for performing or visual artists, educators, students, or the public which are necessary or desirable to promote or facilitate the foregoing uses, including, but not limited to, the publication and dissemination of any or all materials related to the foregoing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct of rehearsals, conventions, meetings, or commercial or other activities; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other activities for the promotion and development of the arts not described in paragraphs (a)-(i) as the not-for-profit corporation determines, provided that no such activity is inconsistent with or otherwise violates any applicable statute, ordinance, or regulation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Entertainment/resort complex” means a theme park comprised of at least 25 acres of land with permanent exhibitions and a variety of recreational activities, which has at least 1 million visitors annually who pay admission fees thereto, together with any lodging, dining, and recreational facilities located adjacent to, contiguous to, or in close proximity to the theme park, as long as the owner(s)/operators(s) of the theme park, or a parent or related company or subsidiary thereof, has an equity interest in the lodging, dining, or recreational facilities or is in privity therewith. Close proximity shall include an area within a 5-mile radius of the theme park complex.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Common carrier” means any person, firm, or corporation that undertakes for hire, as a regular business, the transportation of persons or commodities from place to place, offering its services to all who choose to employ it and pay its charges.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permit carrier” means a licensee authorized to make deliveries as provided in s. 561.57.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of license qualification pursuant to s. 561.20(2)(a)1. the term “historic structure” means a structure that is listed on the National Register of Historic Places pursuant to the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, or is within and contributes to a registered historic district pursuant to 26 U.S.C. s. 48(g)(3)(B), or has been found to meet the criteria of historical significance of the Division of Historical Resources of the Department of State, as certified by that division or by a locally established historic preservation board or commission, or like body, which has been granted authority to designate historically significant properties by the jurisdiction within which the hotel or motel is located.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 16774, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(239); s. 1, ch. 18015, 1937; ss. 1, 3A, ch. 19301, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(271a,n); s. 1, ch. 21839, 1943; s. 1, ch. 25359, 1949; s. 4, ch. 28149, 1953; s. 1, ch. 29786, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-420; s. 1, ch. 63-32; s. 1, ch. 67-73; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 213, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 72-230; s. 4, ch. 77-421; s. 1, ch. 78-133; s. 27, ch. 79-4; s. 1, ch. 80-339; s. 2, ch. 80-365; s. 1, ch. 81-158; s. 1, ch. 86-269; s. 1, ch. 90-233; s. 5, ch. 91-60; s. 1, ch. 92-176; s. 1, ch. 92-205; s. 7, ch. 93-220; s. 1, ch. 97-165; s. 7, ch. 97-213; s. 1, ch. 99-216; s. 1, ch. 99-362; s. 3, ch. 2000-191.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">49 U.S.C. ss. 1711 et seq., were repealed by Pub. L. No. 97-248, Title V, s. 523(a), 96 Stat. 695.</Text></Note></Section>