<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation and duties of Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Business and Professional Regulation the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco, which shall supervise the conduct, management, and operation of the manufacturing, packaging, distribution, and sale within the state of all alcoholic beverages and shall enforce the provisions of the Beverage Law and the <Reference Number="1" />tobacco law and rules and regulations of the division in connection therewith. It is the express legislative intent that the state retain primary regulatory authority over the activities of licensees under the Beverage Law within the power of the state and the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation. However, none of the provisions of the Beverage Law shall apply to ethyl alcohol intended for use or used for the following purposes:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Scientific, chemical, mechanical, industrial, or medicinal purposes;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Patented, patent, proprietary, medicinal, pharmaceutical, antiseptic, toilet, scientific, chemical, mechanical or industrial preparations, or products unfit for beverage purposes;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Flavoring extracts and syrups, unfit for beverage purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 16774, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(227); s. 1A, ch. 19301, 1939; s. 2, ch. 57-420; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-230; s. 5, ch. 77-421; s. 212, ch. 94-218; s. 2, ch. 97-165.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As enacted by s. 5, ch. 77-421. There is no provision designated as the “tobacco law” in the Florida Statutes.</Text></Note></Section>