<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.68" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure; distributor’s salespersons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before any person may solicit or sell to vendors or become employed as a salesperson of spirituous or vinous beverages for a licensed Florida distributor in accordance with the provisions of this section, such person shall file with the district supervisor of the district of the Division of Alcoholic Beverage and Tobacco in which the distributor’s premises is located a sworn application for a license on forms provided by the division. Prior to any application being approved, the division shall require the applicant to file a fee of $50 and file a set of fingerprints on regular United States Department of Justice forms. The licensure requirement provided in this paragraph does not apply to the solicitation or sale of cider.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person employed as a salesperson of spirituous or vinous beverages for a licensed Florida distributor on October 1, 1986, shall not be required to submit a set of fingerprints to the division with his or her application for licensure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the application has been filed, the district supervisor shall cause the application to be fully investigated. Upon the completion of the investigation the division shall approve or disapprove the application. If approved the license shall be issued. Licenses shall be issued only to persons meeting the qualifications of s. 561.15 and any other requirements of the Beverage Law. Upon issuance, the salesperson’s license shall be valid and remain in effect unless the salesperson has a break in employment. If a licensee salesperson has a break in employment longer than 90 days during which time the salesperson is not employed by any Florida distributor, the salesperson must obtain a new salesperson’s license by complying with the requirements for original issuance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed salesperson is required to comply with all aspects of the Beverage Law to the same extent as all licensees and any violation of the Beverage Law shall cause the license to be subject to suspension or revocation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall have the authority to promulgate rules to carry out the purposes of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee collected for a salesperson’s license pursuant to this section shall go directly to the Department of Business and Professional Regulation to provide funds to administer the provisions contained herein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 86-268; s. 47, ch. 91-220; s. 218, ch. 94-218; s. 853, ch. 97-103; s. 10, ch. 97-213.</History></Section>