<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.181" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary initial licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any person has filed a properly completed application which does not on its face disclose any reason for denying an alcoholic beverage license, the division shall issue to such person a temporary initial license of the same type and series for which the application has been submitted, to be valid for all purposes under the Beverage Law, except as provided in paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license issued under this section entitles a vendor to purchase alcoholic beverages for cash only. This paragraph does not apply:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the entity holding the temporary initial license is also the holder of a beverage license authorizing the purchase of the same type of alcoholic beverages as is authorized under the temporary license.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To purchases made as part of a single-transaction cooperative purchase placed by a pool buying agent.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary initial license shall expire and shall not be continued or extended beyond the date the division denies the application for license, beyond 14 days after the date the division approves the application for license, or beyond the date the applicant pays the license fee for and the division issues the license applied for, whichever date occurs first. If the department issues a notice of intent to deny the license application for failure of the applicant to disclose the information required by s. 561.15(2) or (4), the initial temporary license expires and shall not be extended during any proceeding for administrative or judicial review pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant seeking a temporary initial license shall pay to the division for such license a fee equal to one-fourth of the annual license fee for the type and series of license being applied for or $100, whichever is greater, which fee shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 84-262; s. 5, ch. 95-346; s. 5, ch. 2000-191.</History></Section>