<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">One state tax payment; reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be only one state tax paid as to each gallon or fraction thereof of beverage sold under the Beverage Law, and no other excise tax shall be levied directly or indirectly. Such tax shall be computed from the reports, books, and records of manufacturers and distributors; and the amount so computed shall be remitted with the report required by s. 561.55 to the division at intervals of 1 month, on or before the 10th of each month, for all beverages sold during the previous calendar month, and such payment of tax shall accompany the report required by s. 561.55. If the monthly tax liability of a manufacturer or distributor exceeds the amount of the bond furnished for payment of taxes, the division, upon a finding based upon substantial and competent evidence that the security of the tax revenue involved is in jeopardy, may require a bond equal to the anticipated tax liability of the manufacturer or distributor. Additionally, the division may increase the frequency of the remittance of the tax when the security of the tax involved is in immediate jeopardy or the financial condition of the manufacturer or distributor is unstable and the potential tax liability exceeds the bond furnished under the Beverage Law. In arriving at a conclusion that the security of the tax revenue involved is in jeopardy, the division shall consider and be guided by the prior history, if any, of the compliance or noncompliance by the manufacturer or distributor with beverage tax obligations; the transient or nontransient nature of the manufacturer or distributorship; the type of inventory, the equity of the manufacturer or distributor therein, and the mobility of such inventory; the financial status of the manufacturer or distributor; and the anticipated tax obligation of the manufacturer or distributor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the tax on alcoholic beverages under the Beverage Law is expressed in gallons, the conversion factor of 1 liter being the equivalent of 0.26417 gallons shall be used in determining the applicable tax.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of the word “sold” in subsection (1) shall include alcoholic beverages lost, stolen, or other unaccounted for shortages occurring after entry into the state. All lost, stolen, or other unaccounted for shortages occurring outside this state and supported by documentation shall not be subject to the Florida excise tax upon such alcoholic beverages.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 16774, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(235); s. 10, ch. 18015, 1937; s. 2, ch. 20830, 1941; s. 30, ch. 57-420; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-230; s. 20, ch. 81-158; s. 5, ch. 88-308.</History></Section>