<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.67" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reclamation by distributor of beverages not paid for by licensed vendors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall issue to the distributor a written statement of reclamation, upon written request by such licensed distributor of spirituous, vinous, or malt beverages, to authorize reclamation by the distributor of such beverages delivered to and in possession of a licensed vendor pursuant to unpaid invoices. At the time the division issues a written statement of reclamation to the distributor, the division shall mail a copy of the statement to any financial institution or third party which has, according to the records of the Secretary of State, a perfected security interest in the spirituous, vinous, or malt beverages inventory of the licensed vendor. Reclamation by the distributor is authorized when such transaction is the cause of an unpaid account, for which the vendor has been notified pursuant to the Beverage Law, and the excise tax has been paid or is due and payable by the distributor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If reclamation wholly satisfies the unpaid invoices, the distributor shall notify the division in writing, and such vendor shall be considered to have fully paid for all beverages previously purchased from that distributor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the division, nor any employee of the division, shall be liable to any person for any cause whatsoever arising out of, or from, any acts by the division, by the division director, or by any employee of the division under the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall promulgate rules to assist in the enforcement of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-228; s. 2, ch. 92-91; s. 347, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>