<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.424" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Vinous beverages; in-store servicing authorized.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the finding of the Legislature that the in-store servicing of wine by a distributor is a necessary part of a distributor’s function and responsibility to a vendor. It is further the finding of the Legislature that the in-store servicing of wine by a distributor is not intended by the distributor to induce a vendor to purchase wine from the distributor nor does the distributor intend to provide any financial assistance to a vendor by providing such in-store servicing to the vendor. In addition, it is the finding of the Legislature that in-store servicing of wine by a distributor is a normal trade or business practice which has substantially contributed to the increase in sales of wine resulting in a substantial benefit to the state by increased tax revenues resulting from the increased sales, and therefore is not a rendering of financial assistance to a vendor or an inducement to purchase wine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in s. 561.42 or any other provision of the alcoholic beverage law shall prohibit a distributor of wine from providing in-store servicing of wine sold by such distributor to a vendor. “In-store servicing” as used herein means: placing the wine on the vendor’s shelves and maintaining the appearance and display of said wine on the vendor’s shelves in the vendor’s licensed premises; placing the wine not so shelved or displayed in a storage area designated by the vendor, which is located in the vendor’s licensed premises; rotation of vinous beverages; and price stamping of vinous beverages in vendor’s licensed premises. This section shall not apply to distilled spirits.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 77-192.</History></Section>