<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.55" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Manufacturers’, distributors’, brokers’, sales agents’, importers’, vendors’, and exporters’ records and reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manufacturer, distributor, broker, sales agent, importer, and exporter shall keep a complete and accurate record and make reports showing the amount of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beverages manufactured or sold within the state and to whom sold;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beverages imported from beyond the limits of the state and to whom sold;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beverages exported beyond the limits of the state, to whom sold, the place where sold, and the address of the person to whom sold.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manufacturer, distributor, broker, sales agent, and importer shall make a full and complete report by the 10th day of each month for the previous calendar month. The report shall be made out in triplicate; two copies shall be sent to the division, and the third copy shall be retained for the manufacturer’s, distributor’s, broker’s, sales agent’s, or importer’s record. Reports shall be made on forms prepared and furnished by the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manufacturer, distributor, broker, agent, and importer licensed under the Beverage Law shall maintain and keep for a period of 3 years at the licensed place of business such records of alcoholic beverages received, sold, or delivered within or without this state as may be required by the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each vendor shall keep records of all purchases and other acquisitions of alcoholic beverages for a period of 3 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each registered exporter shall supply to the division copies of all certified reports pertaining to transporting, warehousing, and exporting alcoholic beverages prepared for the Federal Government with all supporting documents.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 16774, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 4151(230); s. 31, ch. 57-420; s. 3, ch. 61-219; s. 12, ch. 63-562; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-230; s. 17, ch. 81-158; s. 17, ch. 91-60.</History></Section>