<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0561.545" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain shipments of beverages prohibited; penalties; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the direct shipment of alcoholic beverages by persons in the business of selling alcoholic beverages to residents of this state in violation of the Beverage Law poses a serious threat to the public health, safety, and welfare; to state revenue collections; and to the economy of the state. The Legislature further finds that the penalties for illegal direct shipment of alcoholic beverages to residents of this state should be made adequate to ensure compliance with the Beverage Law and that the measures provided for in this section are fully consistent with the powers conferred upon the state by the Twenty-first Amendment to the United States Constitution.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person in the business of selling alcoholic beverages who knowingly and intentionally ships, or causes to be shipped, any alcoholic beverage from an out-of-state location directly to any person in this state who does not hold a valid manufacturer’s or wholesaler’s license or exporter’s registration issued by the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco or who is not a state-bonded warehouse is in violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any common carrier or permit carrier or any operator of a privately owned car, truck, bus, or other conveyance who knowingly and intentionally transports any alcoholic beverage from an out-of-state location directly to any person in this state who does not hold a valid manufacturer’s or wholesaler’s license or exporter’s registration or who is not a state-bonded warehouse is in violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person found by the division to be in violation of subsection (1) shall be issued a notice, by certified mail, to show cause why a cease and desist order should not be issued. Any person who violates subsection (1) within 2 years after receiving a cease and desist order or within 2 years after a prior conviction for violating subsection (1) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any common carrier or permit carrier, or any operator of a privately owned car, truck, bus, or other conveyance found by the division to be in violation of subsection (2) as a result of a second or subsequent delivery from the same source and location, within a 2-year period after the first delivery shall be issued a notice, by certified mail, to show cause why a cease and desist order should not be issued. Any person who violates subsection (2) within 2 years after receiving the cease and desist order or within 2 years after a prior conviction for violating subsection (2) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to the direct shipment of sacramental alcoholic beverages to bona fide religious organizations as authorized by the division or to possession of alcoholic beverages in accordance with s. 562.15(2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 97-213.</History></Section>