<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0571.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful acts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To remove or dispose of any hold order or any detained agricultural product or article by sale or otherwise without permission of the department or by order of court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To reproduce or use any seal of quality without license or in violation of the provisions of this part or rules adopted hereunder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To supply any seal of quality or reproduction of same to any unauthorized person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make, reproduce, or use any seal of quality that is an imitation or counterfeit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To market any agricultural product with which an imitation or counterfeit seal of quality is used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To market any agricultural product with which a seal of quality is used unless the container of such product is labeled to indicate the name of the licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fail to report the volume and kind of agricultural product on which a seal of quality has been used and make remittance of advertising and promotion fee when due as provided by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To mislead or deceive, use any imitation, counterfeit, or likeness of the seal of quality on any label, tag, seal, container, sign, or otherwise of any agricultural product of any kind or description for any purpose whatsoever or to mislead or deceive, use any emblem or counterfeit likeness thereof upon or in connection with any offer to sell or advertise for sale or use of any agricultural product of any kind or description which does not in fact lawfully bear a seal of quality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fail to do any act required or to do any act prohibited by this part or rules adopted hereunder.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-378; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 13, ch. 90-323.</History></Section>