<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0317.0003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“ATV” means any motorized off-highway or all-terrain vehicle 50 inches or less in width, having a dry weight of 1,200 pounds or less, designed to travel on three or more nonhighway tires, having a seat designed to be straddled by the operator and handlebars for steering control, and intended for use by a single operator and with no passenger.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” means any person authorized by the Department of Revenue to buy, sell, resell, or otherwise distribute off-highway vehicles. Such person must have a valid sales tax certificate of registration issued by the Department of Revenue and a valid commercial or occupational license required by any county, municipality, or political subdivision of the state in which the person operates.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Florida resident” means a person who has had a principal place of domicile in this state for a period of more than 6 consecutive months, who has registered to vote in this state, who has made a statement of domicile pursuant to s. 222.17, or who has filed for homestead tax exemption on property in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“OHM” or “off-highway motorcycle” means any motor vehicle used off the roads or highways of this state that has a seat or saddle for the use of the rider and is designed to travel with not more than two wheels in contact with the ground, but excludes a tractor or a moped.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Off-highway vehicle” means any ATV, two-rider ATV, ROV, or OHM that is used off the roads or highways of this state and that is not registered and licensed for highway use pursuant to chapter 320.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means a person, other than a lienholder, having the property in or title to an off-highway vehicle, including a person entitled to the use or possession of an off-highway vehicle subject to an interest held by another person, reserved or created by agreement and securing payment of performance of an obligation, but the term excludes a lessee under a lease not intended as security.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public lands” means lands within the state that are available for public use and that are owned, operated, or managed by a federal, state, county, or municipal governmental entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“ROV” means any motorized recreational off-highway vehicle 64 inches or less in width, having a dry weight of 2,000 pounds or less, designed to travel on four or more nonhighway tires, having nonstraddle seating and a steering wheel, and manufactured for recreational use by one or more persons. The term “ROV” does not include a golf cart as defined in ss. 320.01(22) and 316.003(68) or a low-speed vehicle as defined in s. 320.01(42).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Two-rider ATV” means any ATV that is specifically designed by the manufacturer for a single operator and one passenger.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 2002-295; s. 43, ch. 2005-164; s. 3, ch. 2009-137; s. 2, ch. 2010-198; s. 43, ch. 2010-223.</History>
</Section>