<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0317.0018" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transfer without delivery of certificate; operation or use without certificate; failure to surrender; other violations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, any person who:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purports to sell or transfer an off-highway vehicle without delivering to the purchaser or transferee of the vehicle a certificate of title to the vehicle duly assigned to the purchaser as provided in this chapter;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operates or uses in this state an off-highway vehicle for which a certificate of title is required without the certificate having been obtained in accordance with this chapter, or upon which the certificate of title has been canceled;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails to surrender a certificate of title upon cancellation of the certificate by the department and notice thereof as prescribed in this chapter;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails to surrender the certificate of title to the department as provided in this chapter in the case of the destruction, dismantling, or change of an off-highway vehicle in such respect that it is not the off-highway vehicle described in the certificate of title; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violates any other provision of this chapter or a lawful rule adopted pursuant to this chapter;</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall be fined not more than $500 or imprisoned for not more than 6 months, or both, for each offense, unless otherwise specified.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 56, ch. 2005-164.</History></Section>