<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0193.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lands subject to tax sale certificates; assessments; taxes not extended.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All lands against which the state holds any tax sale certificate or other lien for delinquent taxes assessed for the year 1940 or prior years shall be assessed for the year 1941 and subsequent years in like manner and to the same effect as if no taxes against such lands were delinquent. Should the taxes on such lands not be paid as required by law, such lands shall be sold or the title thereto shall become vested in the county, in like manner and to the same effect as other lands upon which taxes are delinquent are sold or the title to which becomes vested in the county under this law. Such lands upon which tax certificates have been issued to this state, when sold by the county for delinquent taxes, may be redeemed in the manner prescribed by this law; provided, that all tax certificates held by the state on such lands shall be redeemed at the same time, and the clerk of the circuit court shall disburse the money as provided by law. After the title to any such lands against which the state holds tax certificates becomes vested in the county as provided by this law, the county may sell such lands in the same manner as provided in s. 197.592, and the clerk of the circuit court shall distribute the proceeds from the sale of such lands by the board of county commissioners in proportion to the interest of the state, the several taxing units, and the funds of such units, as may be calculated by the clerk.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property appraisers, in making up their assessment rolls, shall place thereon the lands upon which taxes have been sold to the county, enter their valuation of the same on the roll, and extend the taxes upon such lands.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 4322, 1895; GS 512; s. 13, ch. 5596, 1907; s. 1, ch. 6158, 1911; RGS 712, 769; CGL 914, 984; ss. 4, 23, ch. 20722, 1941; ss. 3<Fraction>1/2</Fraction>, 10, ch. 22079, 1943; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-55; s. 1, ch. 69-300; s. 16, ch. 70-243; s. 32, ch. 73-332; s. 5, ch. 75-103; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 205, 221, ch. 85-342.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 193.16, 193.171, 193.63, 193.181.</Text></Note></Section>