<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0193.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mobile homes and recreational vehicles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home shall be taxed as real property if the owner of the mobile home is also the owner of the land on which the mobile home is permanently affixed. A mobile home shall be considered permanently affixed if it is tied down and connected to the normal and usual utilities. However, this provision does not apply to a mobile home, or any appurtenance thereto, that is being held for display by a licensed mobile home dealer or a licensed mobile home manufacturer and that is not rented or occupied. A mobile home that is taxed as real property shall be issued an “RP” series sticker as provided in s. 320.0815.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home that is not taxed as real property shall have a current license plate properly affixed as provided in s. 320.08(11). Any such mobile home without a current license plate properly affixed shall be presumed to be tangible personal property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recreational vehicle shall be taxed as real property if the owner of the recreational vehicle is also the owner of the land on which the vehicle is permanently affixed. A recreational vehicle shall be considered permanently affixed if it is connected to the normal and usual utilities and if it is tied down or it is attached or affixed in such a way that it cannot be removed without material or substantial damage to the recreational vehicle. Except when the mode of attachment or affixation is such that the recreational vehicle cannot be removed without material or substantial damage to the recreational vehicle or the real property, the intent of the owner to make the recreational vehicle permanently affixed shall be determinative. A recreational vehicle that is taxed as real property must be issued an “RP” series sticker as provided in s. 320.0815.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recreational vehicle that is not taxed as real property must have a current license plate properly affixed as provided in s. 320.08(9). Any such recreational vehicle without a current license plate properly affixed is presumed to be tangible personal property.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-234; s. 10, ch. 88-216; s. 1, ch. 91-241; s. 6, ch. 93-132; s. 30, ch. 94-353; s. 3, ch. 95-404; s. 1, ch. 98-139.</History></Section>