<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0193.481" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assessment of mineral, oil, gas, and other subsurface rights.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the mineral, oil, gas, and other subsurface rights in or to real property in this state shall have been sold or otherwise transferred by the owner of such real property, or retained or acquired through reservation or otherwise, such subsurface rights shall be taken and treated as an interest in real property subject to taxation separate and apart from the fee or ownership of the fee or other interest in the fee. Such mineral, oil, gas, and other subsurface rights, when separated from the fee or other interest in the fee, shall be subject to separate taxation. Such taxation shall be against such subsurface interest and not against the owner or owners thereof or against separate interests or rights in or to such subsurface rights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The property appraiser shall, upon request of the owner of real property who also owns mineral, oil, gas, or other subsurface mineral rights to the same property, separately assess the subsurface mineral right and the remainder of the real estate as separate items on the tax roll.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such subsurface rights shall be assessed on the basis of a just valuation, as required by s. 4, Art. VII of the State Constitution, which valuation, when combined with the value of the remaining surface and undisposed of subsurface interests, shall not exceed the full just value of the fee title of the lands involved, including such subsurface rights.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Statutes and regulations, not in conflict with the provisions herein, relating to the assessment and collection of ad valorem taxes on real property, shall apply to the separate assessment and taxation of such subsurface rights, insofar as they may be applied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tax certificates and tax liens encumbering subsurface rights, as aforesaid, may be acquired, purchased, transferred, and enforced as are tax certificates and tax liens encumbering real property generally, including the issuance of a tax deed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in chapter 69-60, Laws of Florida, amending subsections (1) and (3) of this section and creating former s. 197.083 shall be construed to affect any contractual obligation existing on June 4, 1969.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 57-150; s. 1, ch. 63-355; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-55; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-60; s. 13, ch. 69-216; s. 2, ch. 71-105; ss. 33, 35, ch. 73-332; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 29, ch. 95-280.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 193.221.</Text></Note></Section>