<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0193.092" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assessment of property for back taxes.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When it shall appear that any ad valorem tax might have been lawfully assessed or collected upon any property in the state, but that such tax was not lawfully assessed or levied, and has not been collected for any year within a period of 3 years next preceding the year in which it is ascertained that such tax has not been assessed, or levied, or collected, then the officers authorized shall make the assessment of taxes upon such property in addition to the assessment of such property for the current year, and shall assess the same separately for such property as may have escaped taxation at and upon the basis of valuation applied to such property for the year or years in which it escaped taxation, noting distinctly the year when such property escaped taxation and such assessment shall have the same force and effect as it would have had if it had been made in the year in which the property shall have escaped taxation, and taxes shall be levied and collected thereon in like manner and together with taxes for the current year in which the assessment is made. But no property shall be assessed for more than 3 years’ arrears of taxation, and all property so escaping taxation shall be subject to such taxation to be assessed in whomsoever’s hands or possession the same may be found, except that property acquired by a bona fide purchaser who was without knowledge of the escaped taxation shall not be subject to assessment for taxes for any time prior to the time of such purchase, but it is the duty of the property appraiser making such assessment to serve upon the previous owner a notice of intent to record in the public records of the county a notice of tax lien against any property owned by that person in the county. Any property owned by such previous owner which is situated in this state is subject to the lien of such assessment in the same manner as a recorded judgment. Before any such lien may be recorded, the owner so notified must be given 30 days to pay the taxes, penalties, and interest. Once recorded, such lien may be recorded in any county in this state and shall constitute a lien on any property of such person in such county in the same manner as a recorded judgment, and may be enforced by the tax collector using all remedies pertaining to same; provided, that the county property appraiser shall not assess any lot or parcel of land certified or sold to the state for any previous years unless such lot or parcel of lands so certified or sold shall be included in the list furnished by the Chief Financial Officer to the county property appraiser as provided by law; provided, if real or personal property be assessed for taxes, and because of litigation delay ensues and the assessment be held invalid the taxing authorities, may reassess such property within the time herein provided after the termination of such litigation; provided further, that personal property acquired in good faith by purchase shall not be subject to assessment for taxes for any time prior to the time of such purchase, but the individual or corporation liable for any such assessment shall continue personally liable for same. As used in this subsection, the term “bona fide purchaser” means a purchaser for value, in good faith, before certification of such assessment of back taxes to the tax collector for collection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to property of every class and kind upon which ad valorem tax is assessable by any state or county authority under the laws of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (2), the provisions of this section requiring the retroactive assessment and collection of ad valorem taxes shall not apply if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of a building, structure, or other improvement to land that has not been previously assessed complied with all necessary permitting requirements when the improvement was completed; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of real property that has not been previously assessed voluntarily discloses to the property appraiser the existence of such property before January 1 of the year the property is first assessed. The disclosure must be made on a form provided by the property appraiser.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 4322, 1895; s. 1, ch. 4663, 1899; GS 524; s. 22, ch. 5596, 1907; RGS 722; ss. 1, 2, ch. 9180, 1923; CGL 924-926; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-55; s. 15, ch. 70-243; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 9, ch. 2002-18; s. 174, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2010-66.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 193.23, 193.151.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>