<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0193.114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preparation of assessment rolls.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each property appraiser shall prepare the following assessment rolls:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real property assessment roll.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tangible personal property assessment roll. This roll shall include taxable household goods and all other taxable tangible personal property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Reference Number="1" />
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The real property assessment roll shall include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The just value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The school district assessed value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonschool district assessed value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The difference between just value and school district and nonschool district assessed value for each statutory provision resulting in such difference.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The school taxable value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonschool taxable value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of each exemption or discount causing a difference between assessed and taxable value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of new construction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of any deletion from the property causing a reduction in just value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land characteristics, including the land use code, land value, type and number of land units, land square footage, and a code indicating a combination or splitting of parcels in the previous year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improvement characteristics, including improvement quality, construction class, effective year built, actual year built, total living or usable area, number of buildings, number of residential units, value of special features, and a code indicating the type of special feature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The market area code, according to department guidelines.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The neighborhood code, if used by the property appraiser.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recorded selling price, ownership transfer date, and official record book and page number or clerk instrument number for each deed or other instrument transferring ownership of real property and recorded or otherwise discovered during the period beginning 1 year before the assessment date and up to the date the assessment roll is submitted to the department. The assessment roll shall also include the basis for qualification or disqualification of a transfer as an arms-length transaction. A decision qualifying or disqualifying a transfer of property as an arms-length transaction must be recorded on the assessment roll within 3 months after the date that the deed or other transfer instrument is recorded or otherwise discovered. If, subsequent to the initial decision qualifying or disqualifying a transfer of property, the property appraiser obtains information indicating that the initial decision should be changed, the property appraiser may change the qualification decision and, if so, must document the reason for the change in a manner acceptable to the executive director or the executive director’s designee. Sale or transfer data must be current on all tax rolls submitted to the department. As used in this paragraph, the term “ownership transfer date” means the date that the deed or other transfer instrument is signed and notarized or otherwise executed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A code indicating that the physical attributes of the property as of January 1 were significantly different than that at the time of the last sale.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the owner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state of domicile of the owner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physical address of the property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States Census Bureau block group in which the parcel is located.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specific to the homestead property, including the social security number of the homestead applicant and the applicant’s spouse, if any, and, for homestead property to which a homestead assessment difference was transferred in the previous year, the number of owners among whom the previous homestead was split, the assessment difference amount, the county of the previous homestead, the parcel identification number of the previous homestead, and the year in which the difference was transferred.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A code indicating confidentiality pursuant to s. 119.071.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The millage for each taxing authority levying tax on the property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For tax rolls submitted subsequent to the tax roll submitted pursuant to s. 193.1142, a notation indicating any change in just value from the tax roll initially submitted pursuant to s. 193.1142 and a code indicating the reason for the change.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Reference Number="2" />
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tangible personal property roll shall include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An industry code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A code reference to tax returns showing the property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The just value of furniture, fixtures, and equipment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The just value of leasehold improvements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assessed value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The difference between just value and school district and nonschool district assessed value for each statutory provision resulting in such difference.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxable value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of each exemption or discount causing a difference between assessed and taxable value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalty rate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the owner or fiduciary responsible for the payment of taxes on the property and an indicator of fiduciary capacity, as appropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state of domicile of the owner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physical address of the property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The millage for each taxing authority levying tax on the property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For every change made to the assessed or taxable value of a parcel on an assessment roll subsequent to the mailing of the notice provided for in s. 200.069, the property appraiser shall document the reason for such change in the public records of the office of the property appraiser in a manner acceptable to the executive director or the executive director’s designee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For every change that decreases the assessed or taxable value of a parcel on an assessment roll between the time of complete submission of the tax roll pursuant to s. 193.1142(3) and mailing of the notice provided for in s. 200.069, the property appraiser shall document the reason for such change in the public records of the office of the property appraiser in a manner acceptable to the executive director or the executive director’s designee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Changes made by the value adjustment board are not subject to the requirements of this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For proprietary purposes, including the furnishing or sale of copies of the tax roll under s. 119.07(1), the property appraiser is the custodian of the tax roll and the copies of it which are maintained by any state agency. The department or any state or local agency may use copies of the tax roll received by it for official purposes and shall permit inspection and examination thereof under s. 119.07(1), but is not required to furnish copies of the records. A social security number submitted under s. 196.011(1) is confidential and exempt from s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution and the provisions of s. 119.07(1). A copy of documents containing the numbers furnished or sold by the property appraiser, except a copy furnished to the department, or a copy of documents containing social security numbers provided by the department or any state or local agency for inspection or examination by the public, must exclude those social security numbers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Reference Number="2" />
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rolls shall be prepared in the format and contain the data fields specified pursuant to s. 193.1142.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 70-243; ss. 10, 21, ch. 73-172; s. 21, ch. 74-234; s. 1, ch. 77-102; ss. 45, 46, ch. 77-104; s. 8, ch. 80-274; s. 4, ch. 81-308; s. 5, ch. 82-208; ss. 19, 64, 80, ch. 82-226; s. 130, ch. 91-112; s. 2, ch. 93-132; s. 1, ch. 94-130; s. 1466, ch. 95-147; s. 50, ch. 96-406; s. 7, ch. 2006-312; s. 4, ch. 2007-339; s. 1, ch. 2008-173; s. 4, ch. 2012-193.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 1, ch. 2007-339, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) In anticipation of implementing this act, the executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of making necessary changes and preparations so that forms, methods, and data records, electronic or otherwise, are ready and in place if sections 3 through 9 and sections 10, 12, and 14 . . . of this act become law.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 18 months after the date of adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 13, ch. 2008-173, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 18 months after the date of adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 13, ch. 2008-173, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 18 months after the date of adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of provisions of former ss. 193.041, 193.051, 193.061, 193.071, 193.113, 193.131, 193.251, 193.261, 193.361-193.381, 193.392.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>