<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0205.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions allowed disabled veterans of any war or their unremarried spouses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bona fide, permanent resident elector of the state who served as an officer or enlisted person during any of the periods specified in s. 1.01(14) in the Armed Forces of the United States, National Guard, or United States Coast Guard or Coast Guard Reserve, or any temporary member thereof, who has actually been, or may hereafter be, reassigned by the air force, army, navy, coast guard, or marines to active duty during any war, declared or undeclared, armed conflicts, crises, etc., who was honorably discharged from the service of the United States, and who at the time of his or her application for a business tax receipt is disabled from performing manual labor shall, upon sufficient identification, proof of being a permanent resident elector in the state, and production of an honorable discharge from the service of the United States:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be granted a receipt to engage in any business or occupation in the state which may be carried on mainly through the personal efforts of the receiptholder as a means of livelihood and for which the state license or county or municipal receipt does not exceed the sum of $50 for each without payment of any business tax otherwise provided for by law; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be entitled to an exemption to the extent of $50 on any receipt to engage in any business or occupation in the state which may be carried on mainly through the personal efforts of the receiptholder as a means of livelihood when the state license or county or municipal receipt for such business or occupation is more than $50. The exemption shall extend to and include the right of the receiptholder to operate an automobile-for-hire of not exceeding five-passenger capacity, including the driver, when such automobile is owned or contracted to be purchased by the receiptholder and is being operated by him or her as a means of livelihood and that the proper business tax for the operation of such motor vehicle for private use has been applied for and attached to the motor vehicle and the proper fees paid by the receiptholder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When such person applies for a receipt to conduct any business or occupation for which the county or municipal business tax exceeds $50, the remainder of such tax in excess of $50 shall be paid in cash.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each tax collecting authority of this state and of each county and each municipality shall issue to such persons as may be entitled hereunder a receipt pursuant to the foregoing provision and subject to the conditions thereof. Such receipt when issued shall be marked across the face “Veterans Exempt Receipt” <EmDash /> “Not Transferable.” Before issuing the receipt, proof shall be duly made that the applicant is entitled under this law to receive the exemption. The proof may be made by establishing to the satisfaction of such tax collecting authority by means of certificate of honorable discharge or certified copy thereof that the applicant is a veteran within the purview of this section and by exhibiting:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of government-rated disability to an extent of 10 percent or more;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The affidavit or testimony of a reputable physician who personally knows the applicant and who makes oath that the applicant is disabled from performing manual labor as a means of livelihood;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate of the veteran’s service officer of the county in which applicant lives, duly executed under the hand and seal of the chief officer and secretary thereof, attesting the fact that the applicant is disabled and entitled to receive a receipt within the meaning and intent of this section;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pension certificate issued to him or her by the United States by reason of such disability; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other reasonable proof as may be required by the tax collecting authority to establish the fact that such applicant is disabled.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All receipts issued under this section shall be in the same general form as other state, county, and municipal licenses and shall expire at the same time as such other licenses are fixed by law to expire.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receipts obtained by the commission of fraud upon any issuing authority are void. Any person who has fraudulently obtained a receipt, or who has fraudulently received any transfer of a receipt issued to another, and has thereafter engaged in any business or occupation requiring a receipt under color thereof is subject to prosecution for engaging in a business or occupation without having the required receipt under the laws of the state. Such receipt may not be issued in any county other than the county where the veteran is a resident citizen elector, unless such veteran produces a certificate of the tax collector of his or her home county to the effect that no exemption from taxation has been granted to such veteran in his or her home county under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither this nor any other law exempts any person from the payment of any amount required by law for the issuance of a license to sell intoxicating liquors or malt and vinous beverages.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unremarried spouse of a deceased disabled veteran of any war in which the United States Armed Forces participated is entitled to the same exemptions as the disabled veteran.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-433; s. 38, ch. 71-355; s. 1, ch. 77-163; s. 93, ch. 79-400; s. 2, ch. 85-159; s. 1057, ch. 95-147; s. 32, ch. 95-280; s. 20, ch. 2006-152.</History>
</Section>