<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0205.0535" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reclassification and rate structure revisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By October 1, 2008, any municipality that has adopted by ordinance a local business tax after October 1, 1995, may by ordinance reclassify businesses, professions, and occupations and may establish new rate structures, if the conditions specified in subsections (2) and (3) are met. A person who is engaged in the business of providing local exchange telephone service or a pay telephone service in a municipality or in the unincorporated area of a county and who pays the business tax under the category designated for telephone companies or a pay telephone service provider certified pursuant to s. 364.3375 is deemed to have but one place of business or business location in each municipality or unincorporated area of a county. Pay telephone service providers may not be assessed a business tax on a per-instrument basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before adopting a reclassification and revision ordinance, the municipality or county must establish an equity study commission and appoint its members. Each member of the study commission must be a representative of the business community within the local government’s jurisdiction. Each equity study commission shall recommend to the appropriate local government a classification system and rate structure for business taxes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the reclassification and rate structure revisions have been transmitted to and considered by the appropriate local governing body, it may adopt by majority vote a new business tax ordinance. Except that a minimum tax of up to $25 is permitted, the reclassification may not increase the tax by more than the following: for receipts costing $150 or less, 200 percent; for receipts costing more than $150 but not more than $500, 100 percent; for receipts costing more than $500 but not more than $2,500, 75 percent; for receipts costing more than $2,500 but not more than $10,000, 50 percent; and for receipts costing more than $10,000, 10 percent; however, in no case may the tax on any receipt be increased more than $5,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total annual revenue generated by the new rate structure for the fiscal year following the fiscal year during which the rate structure is adopted may not exceed:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For municipalities, the sum of the revenue base and 10 percent of that revenue base. The revenue base is the sum of the business tax revenue generated by receipts issued for the most recently completed local fiscal year or the amount of revenue that would have been generated from the authorized increases under s. 205.043(1)(b), whichever is greater, plus any revenue received from the county under s. 205.033(4).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For counties, the sum of the revenue base, 10 percent of that revenue base, and the amount of revenue distributed by the county to the municipalities under s. 205.033(4) during the most recently completed local fiscal year. The revenue base is the business tax revenue generated by receipts issued for the most recently completed local fiscal year or the amount of revenue that would have been generated from the authorized increases under s. 205.033(1)(b), whichever is greater, but may not include any revenues distributed to municipalities under s. 205.033(4).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the revenue increases authorized by paragraph (b), revenue increases attributed to the increases in the number of receipts issued are authorized.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the conditions specified in subsections (2) and (3) are met, municipalities and counties may, every other year thereafter, increase or decrease by ordinance the rates of business taxes by up to 5 percent. An increase, however, may not be enacted by less than a majority plus one vote of the governing body. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit a municipality or county from decreasing or repealing any business tax authorized under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A receipt may not be issued unless the federal employer identification number or social security number is obtained from the person to be taxed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 93-180; s. 60, ch. 98-419; s. 12, ch. 2006-152; s. 2, ch. 2007-97.</History></Section>