<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0415.1071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Release of confidential information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or organization, including the Department of Children and Family Services, may petition the court for an order making public the records of the Department of Children and Family Services which pertain to investigations of alleged abuse, neglect, or exploitation of a vulnerable adult. The court shall determine whether good cause exists for public access to the records sought or a portion thereof. In making this determination, the court shall balance the best interests of the vulnerable adult who is the focus of the investigation together with the privacy right of other persons identified in the reports against the public interest. The public interest in access to such records is reflected in s. 119.01(1), and includes the need for citizens to know of and adequately evaluate the actions of the Department of Children and Family Services and the court system in providing vulnerable adults of this state with the protections enumerated in s. 415.101. However, this subsection does not contravene s. 415.107, which protects the name of any person reporting the abuse, neglect, or exploitation of a vulnerable adult.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cases involving serious bodily injury to a vulnerable adult, the Department of Children and Family Services may petition the court for an order for the immediate public release of records of the department which pertain to the protective investigation. The petition must be personally served upon the vulnerable adult, the vulnerable adult’s legal guardian, if any, and any person named as an alleged perpetrator in the report of abuse, neglect, or exploitation. The court must determine whether good cause exists for the public release of the records sought no later than 24 hours, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after the date the department filed the petition with the court. If the court does not grant or deny the petition within the 24-hour time period, the department may release to the public summary information including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A confirmation that an investigation has been conducted concerning the alleged victim.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dates and brief description of procedural activities undertaken during the department’s investigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of each judicial proceeding, a summary of each participant’s recommendations made at the judicial proceeding, and the ruling of the court.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The summary information shall not include the name of, or other identifying information with respect to, any person identified in any investigation. In making a determination to release confidential information, the court shall balance the best interests of the vulnerable adult who is the focus of the investigation together with the privacy rights of other persons identified in the reports against the public interest for access to public records. However, this subsection does not contravene s. 415.107, which protects the name of any person reporting abuse, neglect, or exploitation of a vulnerable adult.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the court determines that good cause for public access exists, the court shall direct that the department redact the name of and other identifying information with respect to any person identified in any protective investigation report until such time as the court finds that there is probable cause to believe that the person identified committed an act of alleged abuse, neglect, or exploitation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2004-335.</History></Section>