<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0415.106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation by the department and criminal justice and other agencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All criminal justice agencies have a duty and responsibility to cooperate fully with the department so as to enable the department to fulfill its responsibilities under ss. 415.101-415.113. Such duties include, but are not limited to, forced entry, emergency removal, emergency transportation, and the enforcement of court orders obtained under ss. 415.101-415.113.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To ensure coordination, communication, and cooperation with the investigation of abuse, neglect, or exploitation of vulnerable adults, the department shall develop and maintain interprogram agreements or operational procedures among appropriate departmental programs and the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman Council, the Florida Statewide Advocacy Council, and other agencies that provide services to vulnerable adults. These agreements or procedures must cover such subjects as the appropriate roles and responsibilities of the department in identifying and responding to reports of abuse, neglect, or exploitation of vulnerable adults; the provision of services; and related coordinated activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the fullest extent possible, the department shall cooperate with and seek cooperation from all appropriate public and private agencies, including health agencies, educational agencies, social service agencies, courts, organizations, or programs providing or concerned with human services related to the prevention, identification, or treatment of abuse, neglect, or exploitation of vulnerable adults.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, ch. 73-176; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 3, 5, ch. 79-287; s. 15, ch. 79-298; s. 1, ch. 80-293; s. 1, ch. 83-82; s. 32, ch. 86-220; s. 27, ch. 93-177; s. 104, ch. 95-418; s. 24, ch. 2000-263; s. 37, ch. 2000-349.</History></Section>