<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0164.1053" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conflict assessment phase.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the initiation of the conflict resolution procedure, and after proper notice by certified letter has been given, a conflict assessment meeting shall occur. The meeting shall be scheduled to occur within 30 days of the receipt of the letter initiating the conflict resolution procedure. Public notice shall be given for this meeting in accordance with s. 164.1031(7). The conflict assessment meeting shall be scheduled to allow the attendance by the appropriate personnel from each primary conflicting governmental entity. The chief administrator, or his or her designee, for each governmental entity that is a primary conflicting governmental entity in the conflict resolution procedure shall be present at this meeting. If the entities in conflict agree, the assistance of a facilitator may be enlisted for the conflict assessment meeting. During the conflict assessment meeting, the governmental entities shall discuss the issues pertaining to the conflict and an assessment of the conflict from the perspective of each governmental entity involved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a tentative resolution to the conflict can be agreed upon by the representatives of the primary conflicting governmental entities at the conflict assessment meeting, the primary conflicting governmental entities may proceed with whatever steps they deem appropriate to fully resolve the conflict, including, but not limited to, the scheduling of additional meetings for informal negotiations or proposing a resolution to the governing bodies of the primary conflicting governmental entities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that no tentative resolution can be agreed upon, the primary conflicting governmental entities shall schedule a joint public meeting as described in s. 164.1055, which meeting shall occur within 50 days of the receipt of the first letter initiating the conflict resolution process from the initiating governmental entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the conclusion of the conflict assessment meeting, any primary conflicting governmental entity may request mediation as provided in s. 164.1055(2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 99-279.</History></Section>