<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0164.1055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Joint public meeting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to resolve a conflict after following authorized procedures as specified in s. 164.1053 shall require the scheduling of a joint public meeting between the primary conflicting governmental entities. The governmental entity first initiating the conflict resolution process shall have the responsibility to schedule the joint public meeting and arrange a location. If the entities in conflict agree, the assistance of a facilitator may be enlisted to assist them in conducting the meeting. In this meeting, the governing bodies of the primary conflicting governmental entities shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider the statement of issues prepared in the conflict assessment phase.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek an agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Schedule additional meetings of the entities in conflict, or of their designees, to continue to seek resolution of the conflict.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no agreement is reached, the primary conflicting governmental entities shall participate in mediation, the costs of which shall be equally divided between the primary conflicting governmental entities. The primary conflicting governmental entities shall endeavor in good faith to select a mutually acceptable mediator. If the primary conflicting governmental entities are unable to mutually agree on a mediator within 14 days after the joint public meeting, the primary conflicting governmental entities shall arrange for a mediator to be selected or recommended by an independent conflict resolution organization, such as the Florida Conflict Resolution Consortium, and shall agree to accept the recommendation of that independent organization, or shall agree upon an alternate method for selection of a mediator, within 7 business days after the close of that 14-day period. Upon the selection of a mediator, the conflicting governmental entities shall schedule mediation to occur within 14 days, and shall issue a written agreement on the issues in conflict within 10 days of the conclusion of the mediation proceeding. The written agreement shall not be admissible in any court proceeding concerning the conflict, except for proceedings to award attorney’s fees under s. 164.1058, where the agreement may be used to demonstrate an entity’s refusal to participate in the process in good faith.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 99-279.</History></Section>