<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0164.1052" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Initiation of conflict resolution procedure; duty to give notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a governmental entity shall initiate the conflict resolution procedures provided by this act through passage of a resolution by its members. The resolution shall state that it is the intention of the governing body to initiate the conflict resolution procedures provided by this act prior to initiating court proceedings or prosecuting action on a previously filed court proceeding to resolve the conflict and shall specify the issues of conflict and the governmental entity or entities with which the governing body has a conflict. Within 5 days after the passage of the resolution, a letter and a certified copy of the resolution shall be provided to the chief administrator of the governmental entity or entities with which the governing body has a conflict by certified mail, return receipt requested. The letter shall state, at a minimum, the conflict, other governmental entities in conflict with the initiating governmental entity, the justification for initiating the conflict resolution process, the proposed date and location for the conflict assessment meeting to be held pursuant to s. 164.1053, and suggestions regarding the officials who should be present at the conflict assessment meeting. The initiating governmental entity also shall mail a copy of the letter and resolution to any state, regional, or local governmental entities which, in the determination of the initiating governmental entity, may have a role in approving or implementing a particular element or aspect of any settlement of the conflict or whose substantial interests may be affected by the resolution of the conflict, and any other governmental entity deemed appropriate by the initiating governmental entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 days after receiving a copy of a certified letter noticing the initiation of the conflict resolution procedure, other governmental entities receiving the notice may elect to participate in the conflict resolution process, but are not entitled by virtue of that participation to control the timing or progress of the conflict resolution process, which at all times shall remain in the discretion of the primary conflicting governmental entities. However, a governmental entity which receives notice of a conflict may, by passage of its own resolution and by otherwise following the procedures set forth in subsection (1), join the conflict resolution process as a primary conflicting governmental entity. The intent of a governmental entity to join in the conflict resolution process shall be communicated to the initiating governmental entity by certified mail. The joining governmental entity also shall mail a copy of the letter to any state, regional, or local governmental entities which, in the determination of the joining governmental entity, may have a role in approving or implementing a particular element or aspect of any settlement of the conflict or whose substantial interests may be affected by the resolution of the conflict, and any other governmental entity deemed appropriate by the joining governmental entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this act, the date of initiation of the conflict resolution procedure shall be the date of the passage of a resolution by a governmental entity.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 99-279.</History></Section>