<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0404.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensing of naturally occurring, accelerator-produced, byproduct, source, and special nuclear materials.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor is authorized to enter into agreements with the Federal Government which provide for discontinuance of certain of the responsibilities of the Federal Government with respect to sources of ionizing radiation and the assumption thereof by this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the signing of an agreement as provided in subsection (1), the department shall provide by rule for general or specific licensing of persons to use, manufacture, produce, transport, transfer, receive, acquire, own, or possess naturally occurring, accelerator-produced, byproduct, source, or special nuclear materials or devices, installations, or equipment utilizing such materials. Such rule shall provide for amendment, modification, suspension, denial, or revocation of licenses. Each application for a specific license shall be in writing, on forms prescribed and furnished by the department, and shall state such information, and be accompanied by such documents, including, but not limited to, plans, specifications, and reports for new construction or material alterations, as the department determines to be reasonable and necessary to decide the qualifications of the applicant and to protect the public health and safety. The department may make or cause to be made such inspections and investigations, and require the submission of such written statements, as it deems necessary. The department may require all applications or statements to be made under oath or affirmation. Each license shall be in such form and contain such terms and conditions as the department deems necessary. The terms and conditions of all licenses shall be subject to amendment, revision, or modification by rules or orders issued in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each license shall be valid only for the persons to whom it is issued and shall not be subject to sale, assignment, or other transfer, voluntary or involuntary; and a license shall not be valid for any premises or authorize any possession or use other than that for which it was originally issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a new license is required when:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the ownership or controlling interest of a license has been transferred or assigned; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lessee has agreed to undertake or provide services to the extent that the legal liability for the possession or use of sources of radiation rests with the lessee.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this chapter authorizes any regulatory or licensing activities which are regulated by the Federal Government unless the Federal Government delegates appropriate authority for such activities to this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-373; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 22, ch. 82-186; ss. 3, 17, 18, ch. 84-190; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 290.061.</Text></Note></Section>