<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0404.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agreement materials” means those materials licensed by the state, under agreement with the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission or its successor agency, which include byproduct, source, or special nuclear materials in a quantity not sufficient to form a critical mass, as defined by the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agreement state” means any state which has consummated an agreement with the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission under the authority of s. 274 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended, as authorized by compatible state legislation providing for acceptance by that state of licensing authority for agreement materials and the discontinuance of such activities by the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Byproduct material” means any radioactive material, except special nuclear material, yielded in or made radioactive by exposure to the radiation incident to the process of producing or utilizing special nuclear material.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial low-level radioactive waste management facility” means a parcel of land, together with the structures, equipment, and improvements thereon or appurtenant thereto, which is used or is being developed by a person for the treatment, storage, or disposal of low-level radioactive waste other than that person’s own generated waste.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial low-level radioactive waste management license” means a specific license issued, after application, to a person to construct, operate, or provide for the closure and stabilization of a treatment, storage, or disposal facility in order to treat, store, or dispose of low-level radioactive waste other than that person’s own generated waste.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Emergency” means any condition existing outside the bounds of nuclear operating sites owned or licensed by a federal agency, and further means any condition existing within or outside the jurisdictional confines of a facility licensed by the department and arising from byproduct material, source material, special nuclear materials, or other radioactive materials, which is endangering, or could reasonably be expected to endanger, the health and safety of the public or to contaminate the environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General license” means a license effective pursuant to rules promulgated under the provisions of this chapter without the filing of an application to transfer, acquire, own, possess, or use quantities of, or devices or equipment utilizing, byproduct, source, or special nuclear materials or other radioactive materials occurring naturally or produced artificially.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ionizing radiation” means gamma rays and X rays, alpha and beta particles, high-speed electrons, protons, neutrons, and other nuclear particles, but not sound or radio waves or infrared, ultraviolet, or visible light.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, corporation, partnership, firm, association, trust, estate, public or private institution, group, agency, political subdivision of this state, any other state, or political subdivision or agency thereof, and any legal successor, representative, agent, or agency of the foregoing, other than the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission, or any successor thereto, and other than Federal Government agencies licensed by the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission, or any successors thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiation” means ionizing radiation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiation machine” means any device designed to produce, or which produces, radiation or nuclear particles when the associated control devices of the machine are operated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radioactive material” means any solid, liquid, or gas which emits ionizing radiation spontaneously; however, this definition does not include radioactive wastes regulated pursuant to the hazardous waste management sections of the federal Resource Conservation and Recovery Act of 1976 or the Department of Environmental Protection’s assumption of that program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radioactive waste” means any equipment or materials which are radioactive or have radioactive contamination and which are required pursuant to any governing laws, regulations, or licenses to be stored, treated, or disposed of as radioactive waste. The term “radioactive waste” is further defined as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“High-level waste” means irradiated reactor fuel, liquid wastes from reprocessing irradiated reactor fuel, and solids into which such liquid wastes have been converted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Low-level waste” means radioactive waste not classified as high-level radioactive waste, transuranic waste, spent nuclear fuel, or byproduct material as defined in s. 11(e)(2) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transuranic waste” means waste material containing transuranic elements with contamination levels greater than 10 nanocuries per gram of waste.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registration” means the registering of a radiation machine with the department in accordance with the rules promulgated pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Source material” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uranium, thorium, or any other material which the department declares to be source material after the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission, or any successor thereto, has determined the material to be such; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ores containing one or more of the foregoing materials in such concentration to be source material.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sources of radiation” means, collectively, radioactive material and radiation machines.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Special nuclear material” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plutonium, uranium 233, uranium 235, uranium enriched in the isotope 233 or in the isotope 235, and any other material which the department declares to be a special nuclear material after the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission, or any successor thereto, has determined the material to be such, but does not include source material; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any material artificially enriched by any of the foregoing, but does not include source material.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Specific license” means a license, issued after application, to use, manufacture, produce, transfer, receive, acquire, own, or possess quantities of, or devices or equipment utilizing, byproduct material, source material, special nuclear material, or other radioactive material occurring naturally or produced artificially.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission” means the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission or its successor agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-373; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 22, ch. 82-186; ss. 1, 17, 18, ch. 84-190; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 452, ch. 94-356; s. 55, ch. 97-237.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 290.031.</Text></Note></Section>