<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0404.131" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to charge and collect reasonable fees for specific and general licenses and for the registration of radiation machines. The fees shall not exceed the estimated costs to the department of performing licensing, registration, inspection, and other regulatory duties. Unless otherwise provided by law, such fees shall be deposited to the credit of the Radiation Protection Trust Fund, to be held and applied solely for salaries and expenses of the department incurred in implementing and enforcing the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require that each person who possesses a specific license to use, manufacture, produce, transport, transfer, receive, acquire, own, or possess radioactive material annually pay to the department an additional 5 percent of his or her annual licensing and inspection fee for the purposes of s. 404.122. All fees collected as specified in this subsection shall be deposited in the Radiation Protection Trust Fund. These fees are not refundable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to charge and collect reasonable fees from department licensees and nuclear power plant licensees of the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission who ship low-level radioactive waste to commercial low-level radioactive waste management facilities. Such fees shall be levied according to the cubic foot amount of low-level radioactive waste shipped quarterly by each department licensee and nuclear power plant licensee of the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission and shall be set by the department to provide an amount no greater than the costs to the department of surveying the external radiation levels of a vehicle carrying low-level radioactive waste, inspection of the package bracing of a vehicle carrying low-level radioactive waste, verification of required marking and placarding of a vehicle carrying low-level radioactive waste, examination of required shipping papers, routing of low-level radioactive waste shipments to their final destinations, and ensuring compliance with the provisions of the Southeast Interstate Low-Level Radioactive Waste Compact. Fees shall be $1.25 per cubic foot for the first year and shall be determined by department rule for succeeding years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected by the department shall be deposited in the Radiation Protection Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to charge and collect reasonable fees in an amount no greater than the costs to the department of issuing a permit to a person to transport low-level radioactive waste into or through the borders of the state which is destined to a commercial low-level radioactive waste management facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected by the department shall be deposited in the Radiation Protection Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to collect reasonable fees from industries extracting solid minerals as defined in s. 211.30(1), licensees, and nuclear power plants to meet the actual costs of surveillance activities performed for the purpose of monitoring the radiological environmental impact of activities conducted by such solid mineral extraction industries, licensees, and nuclear power plants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected by the department shall be deposited into the Radiation Protection Trust Fund and used for environmental surveillance activities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-373; s. 2, ch. 80-187; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 13, 22, ch. 82-186; ss. 8, 10, 17, 18, ch. 84-190; s. 58, ch. 85-81; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 21, ch. 93-120; s. 20, ch. 96-418; s. 1014, ch. 97-103; s. 59, ch. 97-237.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 290.131.</Text></Note></Section>