<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0404.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Radiation machines and components; inspection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and its duly authorized agents may inspect in a lawful manner at all reasonable hours any hospital or other health care facility or other place in the state in which a radiation machine is installed for the purpose of determining whether the facility, the radiation machine and its components, the film and film processing equipment, the techniques and procedures, any mechanical holding devices, the warning labels and signs, the written safety procedures, and the resultant image produced meet the standards of the department as set forth in this chapter and rules adopted pursuant to this chapter. Such rules may include standards for radiation machine performance, surveys, calibrations, and spot checks; requirements for quality assurance programs and quality control programs; standards for facility electrical systems, safety alarms, radiation-monitoring equipment, and dosimetry systems; requirements for visual and aural communication with patients; procedures for establishing radiation safety committees for a facility; and qualifications of persons who cause a radiation machine to be used, who operate a radiation machine, and who ensure that a radiation machine complies with the requirements of this chapter and with rules of the department. If, in the opinion of the department, a radiation machine that fails to meet such standards can be made to meet the standards through an adjustment or limitation upon the stations or range of the radiation machine or through the purchase of a component meeting the standards, the department shall order the owner of the radiation machine to make the necessary adjustment or to purchase the necessary component within 90 days after the date or receipt of the order. However, if the radiation machine cannot be made to meet the standards, the department shall order the owner to cease the use of the radiation machine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who enters the state with a radiation machine or component owned by him or her for the purpose of installing and utilizing the radiation machine shall register the radiation machine with the department. The department shall inspect the radiation machine to determine its compliance with the standards and shall approve or disapprove the radiation machine or shall order adjustments to the radiation machine in accordance with the provisions of subsection (1). Each person who installs or offers to install or service radiation machines must register with the department and must apply to the department, on forms furnished by the department, before furnishing or offering to furnish any such service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall sell or offer to sell in this state any radiation machine or component thereof which does not meet the standards of the department or which cannot be adjusted to meet such standards in accordance with the provisions of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall enforce the provisions of this section and may impose an administrative fine, in addition to all other fines and penalties imposed by law, in an amount of $1,000 for each violation of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may charge and collect reasonable fees annually for the registration and inspection of radiation machines pursuant to this section. Such fees shall include the registration fee provided in s. 404.131 and shall be deposited into the Radiation Protection Trust Fund. Registration shall be on an annual basis. Registration shall consist of having the registrant file, on forms prescribed and furnished by the department, information which includes, but is not limited to: type and number of radiation machines, location of radiation machines, and changes in ownership. The department shall establish by rule a fee schedule based upon the actual costs incurred by the department in carrying out its registration and inspection responsibilities, including the salaries, expenses, and equipment of inspectors, but excluding costs of supervision and program administration. The fee schedule shall reflect differences in the frequency and complexity of inspections necessary to ensure that the radiation machines are functioning in accordance with the applicable standards developed pursuant to this chapter and rules adopted pursuant hereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee schedule and frequency of inspections shall be determined as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Radiation machines which are used in the practice of medicine, chiropractic medicine, osteopathic medicine, or naturopathic medicine shall be inspected at least once every 2 years, but not more than annually, for an annual fee which is not less than $83 or more than $145 for the first radiation machine within an office or facility and not less than $36 or more than $85 for each additional radiation machine therein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Radiation machines which are used in the practice of veterinary medicine shall be inspected at least once every 3 years for an annual fee which is not less than $28 or more than $50 for the first radiation machine within an office or facility and not less than $19 or more than $34 for each additional radiation machine therein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Radiation machines which are used for educational or industrial purposes shall be inspected at least once every 3 years for an annual fee which is not less than $26 or more than $47 for the first radiation machine within an office or facility and not less than $12 or more than $23 for each additional radiation machine therein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Radiation machines which are used in the practice of dentistry or podiatric medicine shall be inspected at least once every 5 years but not more often than once every 4 years for an annual fee which is not less than $16 or more than $31 for the first radiation machine within an office or facility and not less than $5 or more than $11 for each additional radiation machine therein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Radiation machines which accelerate particles and are used in the healing arts shall be inspected at least annually for an annual fee which is not less than $153 or more than $258 for the first radiation machine within an office or facility and not less than $87 or more than $148 for each additional radiation machine therein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Radiation machines which accelerate particles and are used for educational or industrial purposes shall be inspected at least once every 2 years for an annual fee which is not less than $46 or more than $81 for the first radiation machine within an office or facility and not less than $26 or more than $48 for each additional radiation machine therein.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a radiation machine fails to meet the applicable standards upon initial inspection, the department may reinspect the radiation machine and charge a reinspection fee in accordance with the same schedule of fees as in subparagraphs 1.-6.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, “mammography” means radiography of the breast for the purpose of enabling a physician to determine the presence, size, location, and extent of cancerous or potentially cancerous tissue in the breast.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All radiation machines used for mammography shall meet the accreditation criteria of the American College of Radiology or similar criteria established by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All radiation machines used for mammography shall be specifically designed to perform mammography.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All radiation machines used for mammography shall be used exclusively to perform mammography.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department shall adopt rules to implement the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-187; s. 2, ch. 81-133; s. 40, ch. 83-218; ss. 16, 18, ch. 84-190; s. 1, ch. 91-76; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 23, ch. 97-103; s. 61, ch. 97-237; s. 25, ch. 98-151; s. 184, ch. 98-166; s. 30, ch. 2000-242; s. 1, ch. 2000-326.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.507.</Text></Note></Section>