<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0404.0617" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Siting of commercial low-level radioactive waste management facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, within 30 days of receipt of a complete application for a commercial low-level radioactive waste management license, shall notify the governing body of each municipality or county within 3 miles of the proposed facility and the municipality and county in which the proposed facility is located that a complete license application has been received and shall publish notice in a newspaper of general circulation in the area of the proposed facility that a complete license application has been received.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon notification of receipt of a complete license application by the department as required by subsection (1), the municipality or county having jurisdiction over the proposed site shall, within 90 days of such notification, determine whether or not the proposed site is consistent and in compliance with adopted local government comprehensive plans, local land use ordinances, local zoning ordinances or regulations, and other local ordinances in effect at the time a complete license application is made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the municipality or county fails to make a determination pursuant to subsection (2) within 90 days of department notification of receipt of a complete license application or determines within 90 days of such notification that a proposed facility does not comply with such plans, ordinances, or regulations, the applicant may request the Governor and Cabinet to grant a variance from such plans, ordinances, or regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet shall consider the following when determining whether to grant a petition for a variance from local ordinances, regulations, or plans:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any interstate contractual obligations to create the commercial low-level radioactive waste management facility;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such studies, reports, and information as the Governor and Cabinet may request of the department addressing the effect a proposed facility would have on the groundwater, surface water, land, and air; the feasibility of alternative methods of storage, treatment, or disposal of the low-level radioactive waste to be handled at the proposed facility; the need for the commercial low-level radioactive waste management facility based on the amount of low-level radioactive waste being generated in this state; the availability of possible suitable locations for the commercial low-level radioactive waste management facility elsewhere in this state; and the economics of transporting the low-level radioactive waste to be disposed of, stored, or treated at the proposed facility to alternative existing facilities in or out of this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional information from the department deemed necessary by the Governor and Cabinet to determine whether to grant a petition for a variance from local ordinances, regulations, or plans; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such studies, reports, and information as the Governor and Cabinet may request of the Department of Economic Opportunity addressing whether or not the proposed facility unreasonably interferes with the achievement of the goals and objectives of any adopted state or local comprehensive plan and any other matter within its jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor and Cabinet may attach conditions and restrictions to any variance granted pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 20, 22, ch. 82-186; s. 44, ch. 83-55; ss. 17, 18, ch. 84-190; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 298, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>