<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0404.121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Perpetual care trust funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require a licensee to deposit funds quarterly into a trust fund known as the Perpetual Care Trust Fund when it is deemed that there is a reasonable possibility that the licensed facility may eventually cease to operate although still containing, or having associated with the facility property, licensable radioactive material, including low-level radioactive waste, which will require maintenance, monitoring, surveillance, or other care on a continuing and perpetual basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require a person possessing a commercial low-level radioactive waste management license to deposit in a trust fund, quarterly, funds sufficient to provide for maintenance, monitoring, and surveillance of a facility, to be used after the person possessing such license completes the closure and postclosure observation and maintenance duties required by applicable federal and state laws and rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to provide for the proper care and surveillance of facilities subject to subsections (1) and (2), the state may acquire, by gift or transfer from another government agency or private person, any and all lands, buildings, and grounds necessary to fulfill the purposes of this section. Any such gift or transfer is subject to approval and acceptance by the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, by lease or license with any person, provide for the operation of a site or facility subject to this section for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter. Any lessee or licensee operating under the provisions of this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds required by subsections (1) and (2) shall be established at such rate that interest on the sum of all funds reasonably anticipated as payable shall provide an annual amount equal to the anticipated reasonable costs necessary to maintain, monitor, and otherwise supervise and care for the lands and facilities as required in the interest of public health and safety. The department shall adopt and promulgate rules for the length of time and the amount of funds required to implement a program of maintenance, monitoring, and surveillance of a commercial low-level radioactive waste management facility, to be used after the operator completes the closure and postclosure observation and maintenance duties required by applicable federal and state laws and rules. In arriving at the rate of funds to be deposited, the department shall consider the nature of the radioactive material, including low-level radioactive waste, size and type of facility, estimated future receipts, and estimated future expenses of maintenance, monitoring, and supervision.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognizing the uncertainty of the existence of a person or corporation in perpetuity, and that ultimate responsibility to protect the public health and safety must be reposed in a solvent government, without regard to the existence of any particular agency or department thereof, all lands, buildings, and grounds acquired by the state under subsection (3) shall be owned in fee simple absolute by the state and dedicated in perpetuity to the purposes stated in subsection (3). All radioactive material, including low-level radioactive waste, received at such facility and located therein at time of acquisition of ownership by the state becomes the property of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event a person licensed by any governmental agency other than this state desires to transfer a facility to the state for the purpose of administering or providing perpetual care, a lump-sum deposit shall be made to a trust fund. The amount of such deposit shall be determined by the department, taking into consideration the factors stated in subsection (5).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state and local government agencies are exempt from this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 78-373; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 12, 22, ch. 82-186; ss. 8, 9, 17, 18, ch. 84-190; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 290.121.</Text></Note></Section>