<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0404.056" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Environmental radiation standards and projects; certification of persons performing measurement or mitigation services; mandatory testing; notification on real estate documents; rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STANDARDS.<EmDash />To preserve and protect the public health, the department is authorized to establish, by rule, environmental radiation standards for buildings, and to conduct programs designed to reduce human exposure to such harmful environmental radiation. In the establishment of such standards, the department shall consider:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Existing federal standards or guidelines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recommendations of nationally recognized bodies which are expert in the field of radiation protection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The radiation effect of water supplies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use made, or to be made, of the land for residential dwellings, public or private schools, health care facilities, or other purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The availability of measures to mitigate the effect of the radiation.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For the purposes of this section, “building” means any structure that encloses space used for sheltering any occupancy. Each portion of a building separated from other portions by a firewall shall be considered a separate building.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CERTIFICATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may certify persons who perform radon gas or radon progeny measurements, including sample collection, analysis, or interpretation of such measurements, and who perform mitigation of buildings for radon gas or radon progeny, and shall collect a fee for such certification. Before performing radon measurement or radon mitigation services, including collecting samples, performing analysis, or interpreting measurement results, a certified individual must own, be employed by, or be retained as a consultant to a certified radon measurement or certified radon mitigation business. The department may establish criteria for the application, certification, and annual renewal of basic and advanced levels of certification for individuals, which may include requirements for education and experience, approved training, examinations, and reporting. The department may approve training courses for certification and establish criteria for training courses and instructors. The department may observe and evaluate training sessions, instructors, and course material without charge.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not participate in performing radon gas or radon progeny measurements, including sample collection, analysis, or interpretation of such measurements, or perform mitigation of buildings for radon gas or radon progeny, and charge a fee or obtain other remuneration as benefit for such services or devices, unless that person is certified by the department. A certification issued in accordance with this section automatically expires at the end of the certification period stated on the certificate. An uncertified commercial business may subcontract radon measurements to a certified radon business. The uncertified commercial business must provide the complete radon report from the certified radon business to the client and direct all the client’s questions about the measurements or radon report to the certified radon business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The results of measurements of radon gas or radon progeny performed by persons certified under the provisions of this subsection shall be reported to the department and persons contracting for the service. Upon request, the results of measurements of radon gas or radon progeny which are performed to evaluate the effectiveness of a radon mitigation system shall be reported to the certified business that installed the mitigation system. The report must include the radon levels detected; the location, age, and description of the building; the name and certification numbers of the certified radon measurement business and individual who performed the measurements; and other information determined by the department to meet the requirements of the protocols and procedures for the type of measurement performed. Each installation of a radon mitigation system performed by a person certified under this section must be reported to the department according to the schedule set by the department. The report must include the premitigation and postmitigation radon levels; the type or types of systems installed; the location, age, and description of the building; and the name and certification number of the certified mitigation business that performed the mitigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorized representatives of the department may inspect the business and records of any person certified under the provisions of this subsection, at all reasonable times, to examine records and test procedures to determine compliance with or violation of the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who practices fraud, deception, or misrepresentation in performing radon gas or radon progeny measurements or in performing mitigation of buildings for radon gas or radon progeny is subject to the penalties provided in s. 404.161.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may charge and collect nonrefundable fees for the certification and annual recertification of persons who perform radon gas or radon progeny measurements or who perform mitigation of buildings for radon gas or radon progeny. The amount of the initial application fee and certification shall be not less than $200 or more than $900. The amount of the annual recertification fee shall be not less than $200 or more than $900. The fee amounts shall be the minimum fee prescribed in this paragraph, and such fee amounts shall remain in effect until the effective date of a fee schedule promulgated by rule by the department. The fees collected shall be deposited in the Radiation Protection Trust Fund and shall be used only to implement the provisions of this section. The surcharge established pursuant to s. 553.721 may be used to supplement the fees established in this paragraph in carrying out the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish enforcement procedures; deny an application for initial or renewal certification; deny, suspend, or revoke a certification; or impose an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 per violation per day, for the violation of any provision of this section or rule adopted under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificateholder in good standing remains in good standing when he or she becomes a member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty without payment of renewal fees as long as he or she is a member of the Armed Forces on active duty and for a period of 6 months after his or her discharge from active duty, if he or she is not engaged in practicing radon measurement or radon mitigation in the private sector for profit. The certificateholder must pay a renewal fee to renew the certificate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificateholder who is in good standing remains in good standing if he or she is absent from the state because of his or her spouse’s active duty with the Armed Forces of the United States. The certificateholder remains in good standing without payment of renewal fees as long as his or her spouse is a member of the Armed Forces on active duty and for a period of 6 months after the spouse’s discharge from active duty, if the certificateholder is not engaged in practicing radon measurement or radon mitigation in the private sector for profit. The certificateholder must pay a renewal fee to renew the certificate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may set criteria and requirements for the application, certification, and annual renewal of certification for radon measurement and mitigation businesses, which may include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for measurement devices and measurement procedures, including the disclosure of mitigation materials, systems, and other mitigation services offered.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification of certified specialists and technicians employed by the business and requirements for specialist staffing and duties.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The analysis of measurement devices by proficient analytical service providers.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for a quality assurance and quality control program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclosure of client measurement reporting forms and warranties and operating instructions for mitigation systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for radon services publications and the identification of the radon business certification number in advertisements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for a worker health and safety program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for maintaining radon records.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation of branch office locations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for supervising subcontractors who install mitigation systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for building code inspections and evaluation and standards for the design and installation of mitigation systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing conditions of premitigation and postmitigation measurements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for renewals received after the automatic expiration date of certification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for obtaining a duplicate or replacement certificate, including a fee not to exceed the cost of producing the duplicate or replacement certificate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for reporting, including timeframes and content.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change in the information provided to the department in the original business application to be reported within 10 days after the change.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PUBLIC INFORMATION.<EmDash />The department shall initiate and administer a program designed to educate and inform the public concerning radon gas and radon progeny, which program shall include, but not be limited to, the origin and health effects of radon, how to measure radon, and construction and mitigation techniques to reduce exposure to radon. The surcharge established pursuant to s. 553.721 may be used to supplement the fees established in paragraph (2)(f) in carrying out the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MANDATORY TESTING.<EmDash />All public and private school buildings or school sites housing students in kindergarten through grade 12; all state-owned, state-operated, state-regulated, or state-licensed 24-hour care facilities; and all state-licensed day care centers for children or minors which are located in counties designated within the Department of Business and Professional Regulation’s Florida Radon Protection Map Categories as “Intermediate” or “Elevated Radon Potential” shall be measured to determine the level of indoor radon, using measurement procedures established by the department. Initial measurements shall be conducted in 20 percent of the habitable first floor spaces within any of the regulated buildings and shall be completed and reported to the department within 1 year after the date the building is opened for occupancy or within 1 year after license approval for the entity residing in the existing building. Followup testing must be completed in 5 percent of the habitable first floor spaces within any of the regulated buildings after the building has been occupied for 5 years, and results must be reported to the department by the first day of the 6th year of occupancy. After radon measurements have been made twice, regulated buildings need not undergo further testing unless significant structural changes occur. No funds collected pursuant to s. 553.721 shall be used to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTIFICATION ON REAL ESTATE DOCUMENTS.<EmDash />Notification shall be provided on at least one document, form, or application executed at the time of, or prior to, contract for sale and purchase of any building or execution of a rental agreement for any building. Such notification shall contain the following language:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">“RADON GAS: Radon is a naturally occurring radioactive gas that, when it has accumulated in a building in sufficient quantities, may present health risks to persons who are exposed to it over time. Levels of radon that exceed federal and state guidelines have been found in buildings in Florida. Additional information regarding radon and radon testing may be obtained from your county health department.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">The requirements of this subsection do not apply to any residential transient occupancy, as described in s. 509.013(12), provided that such occupancy is 45 days or less in duration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULES.<EmDash />The department shall have the authority to promulgate rules necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, including the definition of terms.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 18, ch. 84-190; ss. 1, 3, ch. 88-285; s. 15, ch. 91-40; s. 3, ch. 91-145; s. 1, ch. 91-222; ss. 4, 5, ch. 91-429; s. 28, ch. 92-173; s. 19, ch. 93-120; s. 33, ch. 93-166; s. 2, ch. 94-284; s. 31, ch. 95-269; s. 1, ch. 95-339; s. 106, ch. 97-101; s. 21, ch. 97-103; s. 57, ch. 97-237; s. 24, ch. 98-151; s. 14, ch. 99-329; s. 41, ch. 2000-153; s. 29, ch. 2000-242; s. 27, ch. 2000-372; s. 19, ch. 2001-53; s. 29, ch. 2001-89; s. 66, ch. 2002-1; s. 37, ch. 2004-350; s. 47, ch. 2006-1; s. 297, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>