<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0029.007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court-appointed counsel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of implementing s. 14, Art. V of the State Constitution, the elements of court-appointed counsel to be provided from state revenues appropriated by general law are as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Private attorneys appointed by the court to handle cases where the defendant is indigent and cannot be represented by the public defender or the office of criminal conflict and civil regional counsel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the office of criminal conflict and civil regional counsel has a conflict of interest, private attorneys appointed by the court to represent indigents or other classes of litigants in civil proceedings requiring court-appointed counsel in accordance with state and federal constitutional guarantees and federal and state statutes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable court reporting and transcription services necessary to meet constitutional or statutory requirements, including the cost of transcribing and copying depositions of witnesses and the cost of foreign language and sign-language interpreters and translators.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Witnesses, including expert witnesses, summoned to appear for an investigation, preliminary hearing, or trial in a case when the witnesses are summoned on behalf of an indigent, and any other expert witnesses approved by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mental health professionals appointed pursuant to s. 394.473 and required in a court hearing involving an indigent, mental health professionals appointed pursuant to s. 916.115(2) and required in a court hearing involving an indigent, and any other mental health professionals required by law for the full adjudication of any civil case involving an indigent person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable pretrial consultation fees and costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Travel expenses reimbursable under s. 112.061 reasonably necessary in the performance of constitutional and statutory responsibilities.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Subsections (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7) apply when court-appointed counsel is appointed; when the court determines that the litigant is indigent for costs; or when the litigant is acting pro se and the court determines that the litigant is indigent for costs at the trial or appellate level. This section applies in any situation in which the court appoints counsel to protect a litigant’s due process rights. The Justice Administrative Commission shall approve uniform contract forms for use in processing payments for due process services under this section. In each case in which a private attorney represents a person determined by the court to be indigent for costs, the attorney shall execute the commission’s contract for private attorneys representing persons determined to be indigent for costs.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2000-237; s. 43, ch. 2003-402; s. 16, ch. 2005-236; s. 18, ch. 2007-62.</History></Section>