<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0200.185" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Maximum millage rates for the 2007-2008 and 2008-2009 fiscal years.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“County of special financial concern” means a county considered fiscally constrained pursuant to s. 218.67 and for which 1 mill will raise less than $100 per capita.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Municipality of special financial concern” means a municipality within a county of special financial concern or a municipality that has been at any time since June 30, 2002, in a state of financial emergency pursuant to s. 218.503.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate that a county, a municipal service taxing unit of that county, or a special district dependent to that county may levy by a majority vote of the governing body for the 2007-2008 fiscal year shall be determined as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any county of special financial concern for which the compound annual growth rate in total county ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was no more than 5 percent, 100 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any county not included in subparagraph 1. for which the compound annual growth in total county ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was no more than 7 percent, or, notwithstanding subparagraphs 3., 4., and 5., any county that is a county of special financial concern not included in subparagraph 1., 97 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any county for which the compound annual growth in total county ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was greater than 7 percent but no more than 9 percent, 95 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any county for which the compound annual growth in total county ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was greater than 9 percent but no more than 11 percent, 93 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any county for which the compound annual growth in total county ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was greater than 11 percent, 91 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a county authorized to levy a county public hospital surtax under s. 212.055, the maximum millage rate shall exclude the revenues required to be contributed to the county public general hospital for the purposes of making the maximum millage rate calculation, but shall be added back to the maximum millage rate allowed after the applicable percentage of the rolled-back rate as provided in subparagraphs 1.-5. has been applied.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate that may be levied under paragraph (a) may be increased to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065, if approved by a two-thirds vote of the governing body of the county or special district dependent thereto; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonvoted millage rate that was levied in the 2006-2007 fiscal year, if approved by a unanimous vote of the governing body of the county or special district dependent thereto or by a three-fourths vote if the governing body has nine or more members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of a maximum rate as provided in paragraph (b), a higher rate may be levied if approved by a referendum of the voters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate that a municipality or a special district dependent to a municipality may levy by a majority vote of the governing body for the 2007-2008 fiscal year shall be determined as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality of special financial concern or any municipality for which the compound annual growth in total municipal ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was no more than 6 percent, or, for a municipality that first levied ad valorem taxes in the 2002-2003 fiscal year, 100 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality for which the compound annual growth in total municipal ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was greater than 6 percent but no more than 7.5 percent, 97 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality for which the compound annual growth in total municipal ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was greater than 7.5 percent but no more than 10.5 percent, 95 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality for which the compound annual growth in total municipal ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was greater than 10.5 percent but no more than 12.4 percent, 93 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any municipality for which the compound annual growth in total municipal ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, per capita from fiscal year 2001-2002 to fiscal year 2006-2007 was greater than 12.4 percent, 91 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate that may be levied under paragraph (a) may be increased to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065, if approved by a two-thirds vote of the governing body of the municipality or special district dependent thereto; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonvoted millage rate that was levied in the 2006-2007 fiscal year, if approved by a unanimous vote of the governing body of the municipality or special district dependent thereto or by a three-fourths vote if the governing body has nine or more members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of a maximum rate as provided in paragraph (b), a higher rate may be levied if approved by a referendum of the voters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate that an independent special district may levy by a majority vote of the governing body for the 2007-2008 fiscal year is 97 percent of the rolled-back rate, as calculated under s. 200.065.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate specified in this subsection may be increased to the rolled-back rate if approved by a two-thirds vote of the governing body of the independent special district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate specified in this subsection may be increased to the nonvoted millage rate that was levied in the 2006-2007 fiscal year, if approved by a unanimous vote of the governing body of the independent special district or by a three-fourths vote if the governing body has nine or more members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of a maximum rate in paragraph (b), a higher rate may be levied if approved by a referendum of the voters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of calculating maximum millage rates for the 2007-2008 fiscal year under this section, municipal service taxing units and special districts dependent to a county or municipality, the predominant function of which is to provide emergency medical or fire rescue services, shall be considered independent special districts and shall not be included for purposes of calculating the maximum millage rate under subsections (2) and (3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Reference Number="1" />
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the 2008-2009 fiscal year, a county, municipal service taxing units of that county, and special districts dependent to that county; a municipality and special districts dependent to that municipality; and an independent special district may levy a maximum millage determined as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate that may be levied shall be the rolled-back rate calculated pursuant to s. 200.065 and adjusted for change in per capita Florida personal income, except that:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ad valorem tax revenue levied in the 2007-2008 fiscal year and used in the calculation of the rolled-back rate shall be reduced by any tax revenue resulting from a millage rate approved by a super majority vote of the governing board of the taxing authority in excess of the maximum rate that could have been levied by a majority vote as provided in this section.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The taxable value within the jurisdiction of each taxing authority used in the calculation of the rolled-back rate shall be increased by an amount equal to the reduction in taxable value occurring as a result of the amendments to the State Constitution contained in SJR 2-D (2007) providing an additional homestead exemption, providing portability of the Save-Our-Homes differential, providing an exemption from ad valorem taxation for tangible personal property, and providing a 10-percent limitation on assessment increases for certain properties.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a county authorized to levy a county public hospital surtax under s. 212.055 that did so in fiscal year 2007, the maximum millage rate shall exclude the revenues required to be contributed to the county public general hospital in the current fiscal year for the purposes of making the maximum millage rate calculation but shall be added back to the maximum millage rate allowed after the rolled-back rate has been applied, the total of which shall be considered the maximum millage rate for such a county for purposes of this subsection. The revenue required to be contributed to the county public general hospital for the upcoming fiscal year shall be calculated by multiplying 11.873 percent by the millage rate levied for countywide purposes in fiscal year 2007 and multiplying the result by 95 percent of the preliminary tax roll for the upcoming fiscal year. For a downtown development authority established before the effective date of the 1968 State Constitution which has a millage that must be approved by a municipality, the governing body of that municipality shall be considered the governing body of the downtown development authority for purposes of this subsection.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rate in excess of the maximum millage rate allowed under paragraph (a), but not more than 110 percent of the rate in paragraph (a) determined without taking into account the adjustment in sub-subparagraph (a)1.b., may be levied if approved by a two-thirds vote of the membership of the governing body of the county, municipality, or independent district.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rate in excess of the millage rate allowed in paragraph (b) may be levied if approved by a unanimous vote of the membership of the governing body of the county, municipality, or independent district or by a three-fourths vote of the membership of the governing body if the governing body has nine or more members, or if approved by a referendum of the voters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or municipality that is in violation of this section shall forfeit the distribution of the local government half-cent sales tax revenues during the 12 months following a determination of noncompliance by the Department of Revenue, subject to the conditions provided in ss. 200.065 and 218.63.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before June 25, 2007, the executive director of the Department of Revenue shall notify each property appraiser and the chair of the governing body of each county and municipality of the amount of the tax levies that will be used to calculate each jurisdiction’s compound annual growth rate as determined in this subsection. On or before July 2, 2007, each property appraiser and the chair of each such governing body, or his or her designee, shall report to the executive director whether the information that was provided is correct and, if incorrect, provide corrected information along with the basis for any correction. The Governor may consider failure to report as required in this subsection as sufficient grounds to constitute malfeasance or neglect of duty by any person required to report under this subsection. On or before July 13, 2007, the executive director of the Department of Revenue, after consultation with the Revenue Estimating Conference, shall determine and publish on the Department of Revenue’s website the compound annual growth rate in per capita property tax levies for each county and municipality, exclusive of voted levies, calculated from fiscal year 2001-2002 through fiscal year 2006-2007, based on the April 1 official population estimates of 2001 and 2006, respectively, for each jurisdiction pursuant to s. 186.901, exclusive of inmate and patient populations. The determination and publication made pursuant to this subsection is not subject to the provisions of chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Reference Number="1" />
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The millage rate of a county or municipality, municipal service taxing unit of that county, and any special district dependent to that county or municipality may exceed in any year the maximum millage rate calculated pursuant to this section if the total county ad valorem taxes levied or total municipal ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, do not exceed the maximum total county ad valorem taxes levied or maximum total municipal ad valorem taxes levied, as defined in s. 200.001, respectively. Voted millage, as defined in s. 200.001, and taxes levied by a municipality or independent special district that has levied ad valorem taxes for less than 5 years are not subject to the limitation on millage rates provided by this section. Total taxes levied may exceed the maximum calculated pursuant to this section as a result of an increase in taxable value above that certified in s. 200.065(1) if such increase is less than the percentage amounts contained in s. 200.065(6) or if the administrative adjustment cannot be made because the value adjustment board is still in session at the time the tax roll is extended; otherwise, millage rates subject to this section may be reduced so that total taxes levied do not exceed the maximum. Any unit of government operating under a home rule charter adopted pursuant to ss. 10, 11, and 24, Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1885, as preserved by s. 6(e), Art. VIII of the State Constitution of 1968, which is granted the authority in the State Constitution to exercise all the powers conferred now or hereafter by general law upon municipalities and which exercises such powers in the unincorporated area shall be recognized as a municipality under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2007-321; s. 1, ch. 2007-323; s. 12, ch. 2008-173.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 13, ch. 2008-173, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 18 months after the date of adoption and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>