<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0286.29" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Climate-friendly public business.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes the importance of leadership by state government in the area of energy efficiency and in reducing the greenhouse gas emissions of state government operations. The following shall pertain to all state agencies when conducting public business:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall develop the “Florida Climate-Friendly Preferred Products List.” In maintaining that list, the department, in consultation with the Department of Environmental Protection, shall continually assess products currently available for purchase under state term contracts to identify specific products and vendors that offer clear energy efficiency or other environmental benefits over competing products. When procuring products from state term contracts, state agencies shall first consult the Florida Climate-Friendly Preferred Products List and procure such products if the price is comparable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2008, state agencies shall contract for meeting and conference space only with hotels or conference facilities that have received the “Green Lodging” designation from the Department of Environmental Protection for best practices in water, energy, and waste efficiency standards, unless the responsible state agency head makes a determination that no other viable alternative exists. The Department of Environmental Protection is authorized to adopt rules to implement the “Green Lodging” program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state agency shall ensure that all maintained vehicles meet minimum maintenance schedules shown to reduce fuel consumption, which include: ensuring appropriate tire pressures and tread depth; replacing fuel filters and emission filters at recommended intervals; using proper motor oils; and performing timely motor maintenance. Each state agency shall measure and report compliance to the Department of Management Services through the Equipment Management Information System database.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When procuring new vehicles, all state agencies, state universities, community colleges, and local governments that purchase vehicles under a state purchasing plan shall first define the intended purpose for the vehicle and determine which of the following use classes for which the vehicle is being procured:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State business travel, designated operator;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State business travel, pool operators;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construction, agricultural, or maintenance work;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conveyance of passengers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conveyance of building or maintenance materials and supplies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Off-road vehicle, motorcycle, or all-terrain vehicle;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency response; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Vehicles described in paragraphs (a) through (h), when being processed for purchase or leasing agreements, must be selected for the greatest fuel efficiency available for a given use class when fuel economy data are available. Exceptions may be made for individual vehicles in paragraph (g) when accompanied, during the procurement process, by documentation indicating that the operator or operators will exclusively be emergency first responders or have special documented need for exceptional vehicle performance characteristics. Any request for an exception must be approved by the purchasing agency head and any exceptional performance characteristics denoted as a part of the procurement process prior to purchase.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state agencies shall use ethanol and biodiesel blended fuels when available. State agencies administering central fueling operations for state-owned vehicles shall procure biofuels for fleet needs to the greatest extent practicable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>