<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0286.001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reports statutorily required; filing, maintenance, retrieval, and provision of copies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise specifically provided by law, any agency or officer of the executive, legislative, or judicial branches of state government, the State Board of Education, the Board of Governors of the State University System, or the Public Service Commission required or authorized by law to make reports regularly or periodically shall fulfill such requirement by filing an abstract of the report with the statutorily or administratively designated recipients of the report and an abstract and one copy of the report with the Division of Library and Information Services of the Department of State, unless the head of the reporting entity makes a determination that the additional cost of providing the entire report to the statutorily or administratively designated recipients is justified. A one-page summary justifying the determination shall be submitted to the chairs of the governmental operations committees of both houses of the Legislature. The abstract of the contents of such report shall be no more than one-half page in length. The actual report shall be retained by the reporting agency or officer, and copies of the report shall be provided to interested parties and the statutorily or administratively designated recipients of the report upon request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to reports statutorily required of agencies or officers within the executive, legislative, or judicial branches of state government, the State Board of Education, the Board of Governors of the State University System, or the Public Service Commission, it is the duty of the division, in addition to its duties under s. 257.05, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regularly compile and update bibliographic information on such reports for distribution as provided in paragraph (b). Such bibliographic information may be included in the bibliographies prepared by the division pursuant to s. 257.05(3)(c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for at least quarterly distribution of bibliographic information on reports to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agencies and officers within the executive, legislative, and judicial branches of state government, the State Board of Education, the Board of Governors of the State University System, and the Public Service Commission, free of charge; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other interested parties upon request properly made and upon payment of the actual cost of duplication pursuant to s. 119.07(1).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As soon as practicable, the administrative head of each executive, legislative, or judicial agency and each agency of the State Board of Education, the Board of Governors of the State University System, and the Public Service Commission required by law to make reports periodically shall ensure that those reports are created, stored, managed, updated, retrieved, and disseminated through electronic means.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to waive or modify the requirement in s. 257.05(2) pertaining to the provision of copies of public documents to the division.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 26, 28, 29, ch. 84-254; s. 12, ch. 92-98; s. 104, ch. 92-142; s. 29, ch. 95-196; s. 34, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>