<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0550.26165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Breeders’ awards.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to encourage the agricultural activity of breeding and training racehorses in this state. Moneys dedicated in this chapter for use as breeders’ awards and stallion awards are to be used for awards to breeders of registered Florida-bred horses winning horseraces and for similar awards to the owners of stallions who sired Florida-bred horses winning stakes races, if the stallions are registered as Florida stallions standing in this state. Such awards shall be given at a uniform rate to all winners of the awards, shall not be greater than 20 percent of the announced gross purse, and shall not be less than 15 percent of the announced gross purse if funds are available. In addition, no less than 17 percent nor more than 40 percent, as determined by the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, of the moneys dedicated in this chapter for use as breeders’ awards and stallion awards for thoroughbreds shall be returned pro rata to the permitholders that generated the moneys for special racing awards to be distributed by the permitholders to owners of thoroughbred horses participating in prescribed thoroughbred stakes races, nonstakes races, or both, all in accordance with a written agreement establishing the rate, procedure, and eligibility requirements for such awards entered into by the permitholder, the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, and the Florida Horsemen’s Benevolent and Protective Association, Inc., except that the plan for the distribution by any permitholder located in the area described in s. 550.615(9) shall be agreed upon by that permitholder, the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, and the association representing a majority of the thoroughbred racehorse owners and trainers at that location. Awards for thoroughbred races are to be paid through the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, and awards for standardbred races are to be paid through the Florida Standardbred Breeders and Owners Association. Among other sources specified in this chapter, moneys for thoroughbred breeders’ awards will come from the 0.955 percent of handle for thoroughbred races conducted, received, broadcast, or simulcast under this chapter as provided in s. 550.2625(3). The moneys for quarter horse and harness breeders’ awards will come from the breaks and uncashed tickets on live quarter horse and harness racing performances and 1 percent of handle on intertrack wagering. The funds for these breeders’ awards shall be paid to the respective breeders’ associations by the permitholders conducting the races.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each breeders’ association shall develop a plan each year that will provide for a uniform rate of payment and procedure for breeders’ and stallion awards. The plan for payment of breeders’ and stallion awards may set a cap on winnings and may limit, exclude, or defer payments on certain classes of races, such as the Florida stallion stakes races, in order to assure that there are adequate revenues to meet the proposed uniform rate. Priority shall be placed on imposing such restrictions in lieu of allowing the uniform rate for breeders’ and stallion awards to be less than 15 percent of the total purse payment. The plan must provide for the maximum possible payments within revenues.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Breeders’ associations shall submit their plans to the division at least 60 days before the beginning of the payment year. The payment year may be a calendar year or any 12-month period, but once established, the yearly base may not be changed except for compelling reasons. Once a plan is approved, the division may not allow the plan to be amended during the year, except for the most compelling reasons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is not intended that the funds in the breeders’ association special payment account be allowed to grow excessively, although there is no intent to require that payment each year equal receipts each year. The rate each year shall be adjusted to compensate for changing revenues from year to year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The awards programs in this chapter, which are intended to encourage thoroughbred breeding and training operations to locate in this state, must be responsive to rapidly changing incentive programs in other states. To attract such operations, it is appropriate to provide greater flexibility to thoroughbred industry participants in this state so that they may design competitive awards programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, as part of its annual plan, may:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay breeders’ awards on horses finishing in first, second, or third place in thoroughbred horse races; pay breeders’ awards that are greater than 20 percent and less than 15 percent of the announced gross purse; and vary the rates for breeders’ awards, based upon the place of finish, class of race, state or country in which the race took place, and the state in which the stallion siring the horse was standing when the horse was conceived;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay stallion awards on horses finishing in first, second, or third place in thoroughbred horse races; pay stallion awards that are greater than 20 percent and less than 15 percent of the announced gross purse; reduce or eliminate stallion awards to enhance breeders’ awards or awards under subparagraph 3.; and vary the rates for stallion awards, based upon the place of finish, class of race, and state or country in which the race took place; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay awards from the funds dedicated for breeders’ awards and stallion awards to owners of registered Florida-bred horses finishing in first, second, or third place in thoroughbred horse races in this state, without regard to any awards paid pursuant to s. 550.2625(6).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Breeders’ awards or stallion awards under this chapter may not be paid on thoroughbred horse races taking place in other states or countries unless agreed to in writing by all thoroughbred permitholders in this state, the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, and the Florida Horsemen’s Benevolent and Protective Association, Inc.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 92-348; s. 25, ch. 2000-354; s. 1, ch. 2003-295; s. 12, ch. 2009-170; ss. 4, 5, ch. 2010-29.</History>
</Section>