<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0550.334" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Quarter horse racing; substitutions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator of any licensed racetrack is authorized to lease such track to any quarter horse racing permitholder located within 35 miles of such track for the conduct of quarter horse racing under this chapter. However, a quarter horse facility located in a county where a referendum was conducted to authorize slot machines pursuant to s. 23, Art. X of the State Constitution is not subject to the mileage restriction if they lease from a licensed racetrack located within a county where a referendum was conducted to authorize slot machines pursuant to s. 23, Art. X of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other provisions of this chapter, including s. 550.054, apply to, govern, and control such racing, and the same must be conducted in compliance therewith.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Quarter horses participating in such races must be duly registered by the American Quarter Horse Association, and before each race such horses must be examined and declared in fit condition by a qualified person designated by the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any quarter horse racing days permitted under this chapter are in addition to any other racing permitted under the license issued the track where such quarter horse racing is conducted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any quarter horse racing permitholder operating under a valid permit issued by the division is authorized to substitute races of other breeds of horses which are, respectively, registered with the American Paint Horse Association, Appaloosa Horse Club, Arabian Horse Registry of America, Palomino Horse Breeders of America, United States Trotting Association, Florida Cracker Horse Association, or Jockey Club for no more than 50 percent of the quarter horse races during its meet.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 550.3345, a quarter horse permit issued pursuant to this section is not eligible for transfer or conversion to another type of pari-mutuel operation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nonprofit corporation, including, but not limited to, an agricultural cooperative marketing association, organized and incorporated under the laws of this state may apply for a quarter horse racing permit and operate racing meets under such permit, provided all pari-mutuel taxes and fees applicable to such racing are paid by the corporation. However, insofar as its pari-mutuel operations are concerned, the corporation shall be considered to be a corporation for profit and is subject to taxation on all property used and profits earned in connection with its pari-mutuel operations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible to conduct intertrack wagering, a quarter horse racing permitholder must have conducted a full schedule of live racing in the preceding year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 92-348; s. 11, ch. 95-390; s. 789, ch. 97-103; s. 3, ch. 2005-288; s. 14, ch. 2009-170; ss. 4, 5, ch. 2010-29; s. 41, ch. 2011-4.</History>
</Section>