<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Uniform reporting system; bond requirement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that a uniform reporting system should be developed to provide acceptable uniform financial data and statistics.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each permitholder that conducts race meetings or jai alai exhibitions under this chapter shall keep records that clearly show the total number of admissions and the total amount of money contributed to each pari-mutuel pool on each race or exhibition separately and the amount of money received daily from admission fees and, within 120 days after the end of its fiscal year, shall submit to the division a complete annual report of its accounts, audited by a certified public accountant licensed to practice in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall adopt rules specifying the form and content of such reports, including, but not limited to, requirements for a statement of assets and liabilities, operating revenues and expenses, and net worth, which statement must be audited by a certified public accountant licensed to practice in this state, and any supporting informational schedule found necessary by the division to verify the foregoing financial statement, which informational schedule must be attested to under oath by the permitholder or an officer of record, to permit the division to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assess the profitability and financial soundness of permitholders, both individually and as an industry;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan and recommend measures necessary to preserve and protect the pari-mutuel revenues of the state; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completely identify the holdings, transactions, and investments of permitholders with other business entities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General and the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability may, pursuant to their own authority or at the direction of the Legislative Auditing Committee, audit, examine, and check the books and records of any permitholder. These audit reports shall become part of, and be maintained in, the division files.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall annually review the books and records of each permitholder and verify that the breaks and unclaimed ticket payments made by each permitholder are true and correct.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each permitholder to which a license is granted under this chapter, at its own cost and expense, must, before the license is delivered, give a bond in the penal sum of $50,000 payable to the Governor of the state and her or his successors in office, with a surety or sureties to be approved by the division and the Chief Financial Officer, conditioned to faithfully make the payments to the Chief Financial Officer in her or his capacity as treasurer of the division; to keep its books and records and make reports as provided; and to conduct its racing in conformity with this chapter. When the greatest amount of tax owed during any month in the prior state fiscal year, in which a full schedule of live racing was conducted, is less than $50,000, the division may assess a bond in a sum less than $50,000. The division may review the bond for adequacy and require adjustments each fiscal year. The division has the authority to adopt rules to implement this paragraph and establish guidelines for such bonds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter concerning bonding do not apply to nonwagering licenses issued pursuant to s. 550.505.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 92-348; s. 785, ch. 97-103; s. 122, ch. 2001-266; s. 655, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>