<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.1815" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain persons prohibited from holding racing or jai alai permits; suspension and revocation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation, general or limited partnership, sole proprietorship, business trust, joint venture, or unincorporated association, or other business entity may not hold any horseracing or dogracing permit or jai alai fronton permit in this state if any one of the persons or entities specified in paragraph (a) has been determined by the division not to be of good moral character or has been convicted of any offense specified in paragraph (b).</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee of the permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sole proprietor of the permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporate officer or director of the permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general partner of the permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trustee of the permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of an unincorporated association permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A joint venturer of the permitholder;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of more than 5 percent of any equity interest in the permitholder, whether as a common shareholder, general or limited partner, voting trustee, or trust beneficiary; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner of any interest in the permit or permitholder, including any immediate family member of the owner, or holder of any debt, mortgage, contract, or concession from the permitholder, who by virtue thereof is able to control the business of the permitholder.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony in this state;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any felony in any other state which would be a felony if committed in this state under the laws of this state;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any felony under the laws of the United States;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony under the laws of another state if related to gambling which would be a felony under the laws of this state if committed in this state; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bookmaking as defined in s. 849.25.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant for permit as specified under subsection (1) or a permitholder as specified in paragraph (1)(a) has received a full pardon or a restoration of civil rights with respect to the conviction specified in paragraph (1)(b), the conviction does not constitute an absolute bar to the issuance or renewal of a permit or a ground for the revocation or suspension of a permit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation that has been convicted of a felony is entitled to apply for and receive a restoration of its civil rights in the same manner and on the same grounds as an individual.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After notice and hearing, the division shall refuse to issue or renew or shall suspend, as appropriate, any permit found in violation of subsection (1). The order shall become effective 120 days after service of the order upon the permitholder and shall be amended to constitute a final order of revocation unless the permitholder has, within that period of time, either caused the divestiture, or agreed with the convicted person upon a complete immediate divestiture, of her or his holding, or has petitioned the circuit court as provided in subsection (4) or, in the case of corporate officers or directors of the holder or employees of the holder, has terminated the relationship between the permitholder and those persons mentioned. The division may, by order, extend the 120-day period for divestiture, upon good cause shown, to avoid interruption of any jai alai or race meeting or to otherwise effectuate this section. If no action has been taken by the permitholder within the 120-day period following the issuance of the order of suspension, the division shall, without further notice or hearing, enter a final order of revocation of the permit. When any permitholder or sole proprietor of a permitholder is convicted of an offense specified in paragraph (1)(b), the department may approve a transfer of the permit to a qualified applicant, upon a finding that revocation of the permit would impair the state’s revenue from the operation of the permit or otherwise be detrimental to the interests of the state in the regulation of the industry of pari-mutuel wagering. In such approval, no public referendum is required, notwithstanding any other provision of law. A petition for transfer after conviction must be filed with the department within 30 days after service upon the permitholder of the final order of revocation. The timely filing of such a petition automatically stays any revocation order until further order of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit courts have jurisdiction to decide a petition brought by a holder of a pari-mutuel permit that shows that its permit is in jeopardy of suspension or revocation under subsection (3) and that it is unable to agree upon the terms of divestiture of interest with the person specified in subparagraphs (1)(a)3.-9. who has been convicted of an offense specified in paragraph (1)(b). The court shall determine the reasonable value of the interest of the convicted person and order a divestiture upon such terms and conditions as it finds just. In determining the value of the interest of the convicted person, the court may consider, among other matters, the value of the assets of the permitholder, its good will and value as a going concern, recent and expected future earnings, and other criteria usual and customary in the sale of like enterprises.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall make such rules for the photographing, fingerprinting, and obtaining of personal data of individuals described in paragraph (1)(a) and the obtaining of such data regarding the business entities described in paragraph (1)(a) as is necessary to effectuate the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 92-348; s. 29, ch. 97-98; s. 788, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>