<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.495" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Totalisator licensing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A totalisator may not be operated at a pari-mutuel facility in this state, or at a facility located in or out of this state which is used as the primary totalisator for a race or game conducted in this state, unless the totalisator company possesses a business license issued by the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each totalisator company must apply to the division for an annual business license. The application must include such information as the division by rule requires.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a part of its license application, each totalisator company must agree in writing to pay to the division an amount equal to the loss of any state revenues from missed or canceled races, games, or performances due to acts of the totalisator company or its agents or employees or failures of the totalisator system, except for circumstances beyond the control of the totalisator company or agent or employee, as determined by the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each totalisator company must file with the division a performance bond, acceptable to the division, in the sum of $250,000 issued by a surety approved by the division or must file proof of insurance, acceptable to the division, against financial loss in the amount of $250,000, insuring the state against such a revenue loss.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of a loss of state tax revenues, the division shall determine:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated revenue lost as a result of missed or canceled races, games, or performances;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of races, games, or performances which is practicable for the permitholder to conduct in an attempt to mitigate the revenue loss; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the revenue loss which the makeup races, games, or performances will not recover and for which the totalisator company is liable.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the making of such determinations, the division shall issue to the totalisator company and to the affected permitholder an order setting forth the determinations of the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the order is contested by either the totalisator company or any affected permitholder, the provisions of chapter 120 apply. If the totalisator company contests the order on the grounds that the revenue loss was due to circumstances beyond its control, the totalisator company has the burden of proving that circumstances vary in fact beyond its control. For purposes of this paragraph, strikes and acts of God are beyond the control of the totalisator company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the failure of the totalisator company to make the payment found to be due the state, the division may cause the forfeiture of the bond or may proceed against the insurance contract, and the proceeds of the bond or contract shall be deposited into the Pari-mutuel Wagering Trust Fund. If that bond was not posted or insurance obtained, the division may proceed against any assets of the totalisator company to collect the amounts due under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant meets the requirements of this section and division rules and pays the license fee, the division shall issue the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each totalisator company shall conduct operations in accordance with rules adopted by the division, in such form, content, and frequency as the division by rule determines.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division and its representatives may enter and inspect any area of the premises of a licensed totalisator company, and may examine totalisator records, during the licensee’s regular business or operating hours.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 92-348; s. 13, ch. 95-390.</History></Section>