<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Intertrack wagering; purses; breeders’ awards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a host track is a horse track:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A host track racing under either a thoroughbred or quarter horse permit shall pay an amount equal to 7.0 percent of all wagers placed pursuant to the provisions of s. 550.615, as purses during its current race meet. However, up to 0.50 percent of all wagers placed pursuant to s. 550.615 may, at the option of the host track, be deducted from the amount retained by the host track for purses to supplement the awards program for owners of Florida-bred horses as set forth in s. 550.2625(6). A host track racing under a harness permit shall pay an amount equal to 7 percent of all wagers placed pursuant to the provisions of s. 550.615, as purses during its current race meet. If a host track underpays or overpays purses required by this section and s. 550.2625, the provisions of s. 550.2625 apply to the overpayment or underpayment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of all wagers placed pursuant to the provisions of s. 550.615:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the host track is a thoroughbred track, an amount equal to 0.75 percent shall be paid to the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, Inc., for the payment of breeders’ awards;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the host track is a harness track, an amount equal to 1 percent shall be paid to the Florida Standardbred Breeders and Owners Association, Inc., for the payment of breeders’ awards, stallion awards, stallion stakes, additional purses, and prizes for, and the general promotion of owning and breeding, Florida-bred standardbred horses; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the host track is a quarter horse track, an amount equal to 1 percent shall be paid to the Florida Quarter Horse Breeders and Owners Association, Inc., for the payment of breeders’ awards and general promotion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment to a breeders’ organization shall be combined with any other amounts received by the respective breeders’ and owners’ associations as so designated. Each breeders’ and owners’ association receiving these funds shall be allowed to withhold the same percentage as set forth in s. 550.2625 to be used for administering the payment of awards and for the general promotion of their respective industries. If the total combined amount received for thoroughbred breeders’ awards exceeds 15 percent of the purse required to be paid under subsection (1), the breeders’ and owners’ association, as so designated, notwithstanding any other provision of law, shall submit a plan to the division for approval which would use the excess funds in promoting the breeding industry by increasing the purse structure for Florida-breds. Preference shall be given to the track generating such excess.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 48, ch. 92-348; s. 17, ch. 2000-354.</History></Section>