<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.1647" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Greyhound permitholders; unclaimed tickets; breaks.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All money or other property represented by any unclaimed, uncashed, or abandoned pari-mutuel ticket which has remained in the custody of or under the control of any permitholder authorized to conduct greyhound racing pari-mutuel pools in this state for a period of 1 year after the date the pari-mutuel ticket was issued, if the rightful owner or owners thereof have made no claim or demand for such money or other property within that period of time, shall, with respect to live races conducted by the permitholder, be remitted to the state pursuant to s. 550.1645; however, such permitholder shall be entitled to a credit in each state fiscal year in an amount equal to the actual amount remitted in the prior state fiscal year which may be applied against any taxes imposed pursuant to this chapter. In addition, each permitholder shall pay, from any source, including the proceeds from performances conducted pursuant to s. 550.0351, an amount not less than 10 percent of the amount of the credit provided by this section to any bona fide organization that promotes or encourages the adoption of greyhounds. As used in this chapter, the term “bona fide organization that promotes or encourages the adoption of greyhounds” means any organization that provides evidence of compliance with chapter 496 and possesses a valid exemption from federal taxation issued by the Internal Revenue Service. Such bona fide organization, as a condition of adoption, must provide sterilization of greyhounds by a licensed veterinarian before relinquishing custody of the greyhound to the adopter. The fee for sterilization may be included in the cost of adoption.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2000-354; s. 2, ch. 2004-23.</History></Section>