<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.1645" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Escheat to state of abandoned interest in or contribution to pari-mutuel pools.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the public policy of the state, while protecting the interest of the owners, to possess all unclaimed and abandoned interest in or contribution to certain pari-mutuel pools conducted in this state under this chapter, for the benefit of all the people of the state; and this law shall be liberally construed to accomplish such purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, all money or other property represented by any unclaimed, uncashed, or abandoned pari-mutuel ticket which has remained in the custody of or under the control of any licensee authorized to conduct pari-mutuel pools in this state for a period of 1 year after the date the pari-mutuel ticket was issued, if the rightful owner or owners thereof have made no claim or demand for such money or other property within the aforesaid period of time, is hereby declared to have escheated to or to escheat to, and to have become the property of, the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All money or other property that has escheated to and become the property of the state as provided herein, and which is held by such licensee authorized to conduct pari-mutuel pools in this state, shall be paid by such licensee to the Chief Financial Officer annually within 60 days after the close of the race meeting of the licensee. Such moneys so paid by the licensee to the Chief Financial Officer shall be deposited in the State School Fund to be used for the support and maintenance of public free schools as required by s. 6, Art. IX of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 92-348; s. 11, ch. 2000-354; s. 657, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>