<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.912" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rights and responsibilities of each party state.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By enacting this compact, each party state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agrees to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept the decisions of the compact committee regarding the issuance of compact committee licenses to participants in pari-mutuel wagering pursuant to the committee’s licensure requirements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reimburse or otherwise pay the expenses of its official representative on the compact committee or her or his alternate.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agrees not to treat a notification to an applicant by the compact committee described in s. 550.908 as the denial of a license, or to penalize such an applicant in any other way based solely on such a decision by the compact committee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves the right to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply its own standards in determining whether, on the facts of a particular case, a compact committee license should be suspended or revoked. Any party state that suspends or revokes a compact committee license shall, through its racing commission or the equivalent thereof, or otherwise, promptly notify the compact committee of that suspension or revocation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply its own standards in determining licensure eligibility, under the laws of that party state, for categories of participants in pari-mutuel wagering which the compact committee decides not to license and for individual participants in pari-mutuel wagering who do not meet the licensure requirements of the compact committee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish its own licensure standards for those who are not covered by the compact committee license.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party state may not be held liable for the debts or other financial obligations incurred by the compact committee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 42, ch. 2000-354; s. 29, ch. 2001-63.</History></Section>