<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.0745" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conversion of pari-mutuel permit to summer jai alai permit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or operator of a pari-mutuel permit who is authorized by the division to conduct pari-mutuel pools on exhibition sports in any county having five or more such pari-mutuel permits and whose mutuel play from the operation of such pari-mutuel pools for the 2 consecutive years next prior to filing an application under this section has had the smallest play or total pool within the county may apply to the division to convert its permit to a permit to conduct a summer jai alai fronton in such county during the summer season commencing on May 1 and ending on November 30 of each year on such dates as may be selected by such permittee for the same number of days and performances as are allowed and granted to winter jai alai frontons within such county. If a permittee who is eligible under this section to convert a permit declines to convert, a new permit is hereby made available in that permittee’s county to conduct summer jai alai games as provided by this section, notwithstanding mileage and permit ratification requirements. If a permittee converts a quarter horse permit pursuant to this section, nothing in this section prohibits the permittee from obtaining another quarter horse permit. Such permittee shall pay the same taxes as are fixed and required to be paid from the pari-mutuel pools of winter jai alai permittees and is bound by all of the rules and provisions of this chapter which apply to the operation of winter jai alai frontons. Such permittee shall only be permitted to operate a jai alai fronton after its application has been submitted to the division and its license has been issued pursuant to the application. The license is renewable from year to year as provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such permittee is entitled to the issuance of a license for the operation of a jai alai fronton during the summer season as fixed in this section. A permittee granted a license under this section may not conduct pari-mutuel pools during the summer season except at a jai alai fronton as provided in this section. Such license authorizes the permittee to operate at any jai alai permittee’s plant it may lease or build within such county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such license for the operation of a jai alai fronton shall never be permitted to be operated during the jai alai winter season; and neither the jai alai winter licensee or the jai alai summer licensee shall be permitted to operate on the same days or in competition with each other. This section does not prevent the summer jai alai permittee from leasing the facilities of the winter jai alai permittee for the operation of the summer meet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter which prohibit the location and operation of jai alai frontons within a specified distance from the location of another jai alai fronton or other permittee and which prohibit the division from granting any permit at a location within a certain designated area do not apply to the provisions of this section and do not prevent the issuance of a license under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 92-348.</History></Section>