<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.2633" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Horseracing; distribution of abandoned interest in or contributions to pari-mutuel pools.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys or other property represented by any unclaimed, uncashed, or abandoned pari-mutuel ticket which has remained in the custody of or under the control of any horseracing permitholder authorized to conduct pari-mutuel pools in this state for a period of 1 year after the date the pari-mutuel ticket was issued, when the rightful owner or owners thereof have made no claim or demand for such money or other property within that period, is hereby declared to have escheated to or to escheat to, and to have become the property of, the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys or other property which has escheated to and become the property of the state as provided herein and which is held by a permitholder authorized to conduct pari-mutuel pools in this state shall be paid annually by the permitholder to the recipient designated in this subsection within 60 days after the close of the race meeting of the permitholder. Section 550.1645 notwithstanding, the moneys shall be paid by the permitholder as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds from any harness horse races shall be paid to the Florida Standardbred Breeders and Owners Association and shall be used for the payment of breeders’ awards, stallion awards, stallion stakes, additional purses, and prizes for, and for the general promotion of owning and breeding of, Florida-bred standardbred horses, as provided for in s. 550.2625.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (c), funds from quarter horse races shall be paid to the Florida Quarter Horse Breeders and Owners Association and shall be allocated solely for supplementing and augmenting purses and prizes and for the general promotion of owning and breeding of racing quarter horses in this state, as provided for in s. 550.2625.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds for Arabian horse races conducted under a quarter horse racing permit shall be deposited into the General Inspection Trust Fund in a special account to be known as the “Florida Arabian Horse Racing Promotion Account” and shall be used for the payment of breeders’ awards and stallion awards as provided for in s. 570.382.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uncashed tickets and breaks on live racing conducted by thoroughbred permitholders shall be retained by the permitholder conducting the live race.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 92-348; s. 26, ch. 2001-63; s. 21, ch. 2001-279; s. 84, ch. 2002-1; s. 6, ch. 2006-79.</History></Section>