<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.6308" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited intertrack wagering license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In recognition of the economic importance of the thoroughbred breeding industry to this state, its positive impact on tourism, and of the importance of a permanent thoroughbred sales facility as a key focal point for the activities of the industry, a limited license to conduct intertrack wagering is established to ensure the continued viability and public interest in thoroughbred breeding in Florida.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application to the division on or before January 31 of each year, any person that is licensed to conduct public sales of thoroughbred horses pursuant to s. 535.01, that has conducted at least 15 days of thoroughbred horse sales at a permanent sales facility in this state for at least 3 consecutive years, and that has conducted at least 1 day of nonwagering thoroughbred racing in this state, with a purse structure of at least $250,000 per year for 2 consecutive years before such application, shall be issued a license, subject to the conditions set forth in this section, to conduct intertrack wagering at such a permanent sales facility during the following periods:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 21 days in connection with thoroughbred sales;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Between November 1 and May 8;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Between May 9 and October 31 at such times and on such days as any thoroughbred, jai alai, or a greyhound permitholder in the same county is not conducting live performances; provided that any such permitholder may waive this requirement, in whole or in part, and allow the licensee under this section to conduct intertrack wagering during one or more of the permitholder’s live performances; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the weekend of the Kentucky Derby, the Preakness, the Belmont, and a Breeders’ Cup Meet that is conducted before November 1 and after May 8.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">No more than one such license may be issued, and no such license may be issued for a facility located within 50 miles of any thoroughbred permitholder’s track.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If more than one application is submitted for such license, the division shall determine which applicant shall be granted the license. In making its determination, the division shall grant the license to the applicant demonstrating superior capabilities, as measured by the length of time the applicant has been conducting thoroughbred sales within this state or elsewhere, the applicant’s total volume of thoroughbred horse sales, within this state or elsewhere, the length of time the applicant has maintained a permanent thoroughbred sales facility in this state, and the quality of the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must comply with the provisions of ss. 550.125 and 550.1815.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intertrack wagering under this section may be conducted only on thoroughbred horse racing, except that intertrack wagering may be conducted on any class of pari-mutuel race or game conducted by any class of permitholders licensed under this chapter if all thoroughbred, jai alai, and greyhound permitholders in the same county as the licensee under this section give their consent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall be considered a guest track under this chapter. The licensee shall pay 2.5 percent of the total contributions to the daily pari-mutuel pool on wagers accepted at the licensee’s facility on greyhound races or jai alai games to the thoroughbred permitholder that is conducting live races for purses to be paid during its current racing meet. If more than one thoroughbred permitholder is conducting live races on a day during which the licensee is conducting intertrack wagering on greyhound races or jai alai games, the licensee shall allocate these funds between the operating thoroughbred permitholders on a pro rata basis based on the total live handle at the operating permitholders’ facilities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 98-190; s. 4, ch. 98-217; s. 28, ch. 2000-354.</History></Section>