<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0550.908" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of compact committee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to carry out the purposes of this compact, the compact committee has the power and duty to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine which categories of participants in pari-mutuel wagering, including, but not limited to, owners, trainers, jockeys, jai alai players, drivers, grooms, mutuel clerks, racing officials, veterinarians, and farriers, should be licensed by the committee, and to establish the requirements for the initial licensure of applicants in each category, the term of the license for each category, and the requirements for renewal of licenses in each category.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With regard to requests for criminal history record information on each applicant for a license, and with regard to the effect of a criminal record on the issuance or renewal of a license, determine for each category of participants in pari-mutuel wagering which licensure requirements for that category are, in its judgment, the most restrictive licensure requirements of any party state for that category and to adopt licensure requirements for that category which are, in its judgment, comparable to those most restrictive requirements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigate applicants for licensure by the compact committee and, as permitted by federal and state law, gather information on such applicants, including criminal history record information from the Federal Bureau of Investigation and relevant state and local law enforcement agencies, and, where appropriate, from the Royal Canadian Mounted Police and law enforcement agencies of other countries, which is necessary to determine whether a license should be issued under the licensure requirements established by the committee under subsection (1). The fingerprints of each applicant for licensure by the compact committee shall be taken by the compact committee, its employees, or its designee, and, pursuant to Pub. L. No. 92-544 or Pub. L. No. 100-413, shall be forwarded to a state identification bureau or to the Association of Racing Commissioners International, Inc., for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a criminal history record check. Such fingerprints may be submitted on a fingerprint card or by electronic or other means authorized by the Federal Bureau of Investigation or other receiving law enforcement agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue licenses to, and renew the licenses of, participants in pari-mutuel wagering who are found by the committee to have met the licensure and renewal requirements established by the committee under subsection (1). The compact committee shall not have the power or authority to deny a license. If the compact committee determines that an applicant is not eligible for the issuance or renewal of a compact committee license, the compact committee shall notify the applicant that her or his application will not be processed further. Such notification does not constitute and shall not be considered to be the denial of a license. Any such applicant shall have the right to present additional evidence to, and be heard by, the compact committee, but the final decision on issuance or renewal of the license shall be made by the compact committee using the requirements established under subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into contracts or agreements with governmental agencies and nongovernmental persons to provide personal services for its activities and such other services as are necessary to effectuate the purposes of this compact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create, appoint, and abolish those offices, employments, and positions, including that of executive director, that it considers necessary for the purposes of this compact; prescribe the powers, duties, and qualifications of, and hire persons to fill, such offices, employments, and positions; and provide for the removal, term, tenure, compensation, fringe benefits, retirement benefits, and other conditions of employment of persons filling such offices, employments, and positions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Borrow, accept, or contract for the services of personnel from any state, the United States, or any other governmental agency, or from any person, firm, association, corporation, or other entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire, hold, and dispose of real and personal property by gift, purchase, lease, or license, or in other similar manner, in furtherance of the purposes of this compact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Charge a fee to each applicant for an initial license or renewal of a license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive other funds through gifts, grants, and appropriations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 38, ch. 2000-354.</History></Section>