<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0550.3345" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conversion of quarter horse permit to a limited thoroughbred permit.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In recognition of the important and long-standing economic contribution of the thoroughbred horse breeding industry to this state and the state’s vested interest in promoting the continued viability of this agricultural activity, the state intends to provide a limited opportunity for the conduct of live thoroughbred horse racing with the net revenues from such racing dedicated to the enhancement of thoroughbred purses and breeders’, stallion, and special racing awards under this chapter; the general promotion of the thoroughbred horse breeding industry; and the care in this state of thoroughbred horses retired from racing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the holder of a quarter horse racing permit issued under s. 550.334 may, within 1 year after the effective date of this section, apply to the division for a transfer of the quarter horse racing permit to a not-for-profit corporation formed under state law to serve the purposes of the state as provided in subsection (1). The board of directors of the not-for-profit corporation must be comprised of 11 members, 4 of whom shall be designated by the applicant, 4 of whom shall be designated by the Florida Thoroughbred Breeders’ Association, and 3 of whom shall be designated by the other 8 directors, with at least 1 of these 3 members being an authorized representative of another thoroughbred permitholder in this state. The not-for-profit corporation shall submit an application to the division for review and approval of the transfer in accordance with s. 550.054. Upon approval of the transfer by the division, and notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the not-for-profit corporation may, within 1 year after its receipt of the permit, request that the division convert the quarter horse racing permit to a permit authorizing the holder to conduct pari-mutuel wagering meets of thoroughbred racing. Neither the transfer of the quarter horse racing permit nor its conversion to a limited thoroughbred permit shall be subject to the mileage limitation or the ratification election as set forth under s. 550.054(2) or s. 550.0651. Upon receipt of the request for such conversion, the division shall timely issue a converted permit. The converted permit and the not-for-profit corporation shall be subject to the following requirements:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All net revenues derived by the not-for-profit corporation under the thoroughbred horse racing permit, after the funding of operating expenses and capital improvements, shall be dedicated to the enhancement of thoroughbred purses and breeders’, stallion, and special racing awards under this chapter; the general promotion of the thoroughbred horse breeding industry; and the care in this state of thoroughbred horses retired from racing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From December 1 through April 30, no live thoroughbred racing may be conducted under the permit on any day during which another thoroughbred permitholder is conducting live thoroughbred racing within 125 air miles of the not-for-profit corporation’s pari-mutuel facility unless the other thoroughbred permitholder gives its written consent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the conversion of the quarter horse racing permit and the issuance of its initial license to conduct pari-mutuel wagering meets of thoroughbred racing, the not-for-profit corporation shall annually apply to the division for a license pursuant to s. 550.5251.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Racing under the permit may take place only at the location for which the original quarter horse racing permit was issued, which may be leased by the not-for-profit corporation for that purpose; however, the not-for-profit corporation may, without the conduct of any ratification election pursuant to s. 550.054(13) or s. 550.0651, move the location of the permit to another location in the same county provided that such relocation is approved under the zoning and land use regulations of the applicable county or municipality.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No permit converted under this section is eligible for transfer to another person or entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in this section, after conversion, the permit and the not-for-profit corporation shall be treated under the laws of this state as a thoroughbred permit and as a thoroughbred permitholder, respectively, with the exception of s. 550.09515(3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2009-170; ss. 4, 5, ch. 2010-2; s. 42, ch. 2011-4.</History>
</Section>