<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0660.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Establishment of common trust funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any trust company or trust department may establish one or more common trust funds for the exclusive purpose of furnishing investments to itself as fiduciary, including estates, guardianships, managing agencies, and all other fiduciary relationships, now in existence or hereafter created, requiring or authorizing investment of funds held as fiduciary including managing agencies, or to itself and others, as cofiduciaries. It may, as such fiduciary or cofiduciary, invest funds which it lawfully holds for investment in interests in such common trust funds if such investment is not prohibited by the instrument, judgment, decree, or order creating such fiduciary relationship and if, in the case of cofiduciaries, the trust company or trust department procures the consent of its cofiduciary or cofiduciaries to such investment, which consent such cofiduciary is hereby authorized to grant. The full management of the fund shall at all times be in full charge of such trust company or trust department, and no cofiduciary shall have any right to interfere in the management of such common trust funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “trust company or trust department” includes two or more trust companies or trust departments which are members of the same affiliated group as defined in s. 1504 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, as amended, of which any of such trust companies or trust departments is trustee or of which two or more of such trust companies or trust departments are cotrustees. The fiduciary relationship that exists between an individual trust company or trust department and its customer is not altered due to the fact of the enactment of this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 28016, 1953; s. 1, ch. 67-365; s. 3, ch. 76-168; ss. 1, 2, ch. 77-42; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 140, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 148, ch. 92-303.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 660.11.</Text></Note></Section>