<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0660.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trust department licensing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When authorized by the office as provided in this section, a state bank or association may establish a trust department for the purpose of conducting trust business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written application for trust powers shall be filed with the office in such form as the commission prescribes and containing such information as the commission and office reasonably require. The application shall be accompanied by the required nonrefundable fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of an application, the office shall investigate and consider:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The general character and management ability of the principal executive officers of the applicant bank or association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The quality of the supervision to be given to the fiduciary activities, including the qualifications, experience, and character of the proposed principal officers of the trust department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The general condition of the applicant bank or association, and the sufficiency of earnings and earning prospects of the applicant bank or association, including the proposed trust department, to support the anticipated expenses and any anticipated operating losses of the trust department during its formative or initial years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other matters relevant to the application and the establishment and operation of the proposed trust department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses necessarily incurred by the office in the conduct of investigations required by this section shall, in the case of applications which require investigations by the office outside the state, be assessed against the applicant bank or association on an actual-cost-incurred basis and shall be in addition to other fees required by law. Failure to promptly reimburse the office upon its demand shall be grounds for denial of such application or revocation of any approval thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall approve the application if it finds that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The general condition of the applicant bank or association is sufficient to support the proposed trust department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The earnings and earning prospects of the applicant bank or association, including the earning prospects of the proposed trust department, are sufficient to support the anticipated expenses and any anticipated operating losses of the trust department during its formative or initial years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The capital structure of the bank or association is adequate to support the trust department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed trust officers have or will be supplied with sufficient trust and related investment, financial, and managerial experience, ability, and standing to operate the trust department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision has been made for the trust department to occupy suitable quarters at the location specified in the application.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable federal law requires the approval of a federal regulatory agency for the establishment of a trust department by the applicant bank or association, approval by the office, by final order or otherwise, shall be deemed subject to approval by such federal regulatory agency, and a final order of denial by such federal regulatory agency will terminate and revoke the final or other order issued by the office approving the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval of an application by the office and such federal regulatory agency, if required, the office shall issue and deliver to the applicant a certificate or other document granting trust powers to the applicant and authorizing it to establish a trust department and engage in trust business.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 131, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 32, 51, ch. 84-216; s. 1, ch. 91-307; s. 1, ch. 92-303; s. 1807, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>