<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1003.48" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Instruction in operation of motor vehicles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A course of study and instruction in the safe and lawful operation of a motor vehicle shall be made available by each district school board to students in the secondary schools in the state. As used in this section, the term “motor vehicle” shall have the same meaning as in s. 320.01(1)(a) and shall include motorcycles and mopeds. Instruction in motorcycle or moped operation may be limited to classroom instruction. The course shall not be made a part of, or a substitute for, any of the minimum requirements for graduation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to make such a course available to any secondary school student, the district school board may use any one of the following procedures or any combination thereof:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Utilize instructional personnel employed by the district school board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract with a commercial driving school licensed under the provisions of chapter 488.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract with an instructor certified under the provisions of chapter 488.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">District school boards shall earn funds on full-time equivalent students at the appropriate basic program cost factor, regardless of the method by which such courses are offered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of financing the Driver Education Program in the secondary schools, there shall be levied an additional 50 cents per year to the driver’s license fee required by s. 322.21. The additional fee shall be promptly remitted to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, which shall transmit the fee to the Chief Financial Officer to be deposited in the General Revenue Fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board shall prescribe standards for the course required by this section and for instructional personnel directly employed by the district school board. Any certified instructor or licensed commercial driving school shall be deemed sufficiently qualified and shall not be required to meet any standards in lieu of or in addition to those prescribed under chapter 488.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 141, ch. 2002-387; s. 1947, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>