<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1003.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">English language instruction for limited English proficient students.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instruction in the English language shall be provided to limited English proficient students. Such instruction shall be designed to develop the student’s mastery of the four language skills, including listening, speaking, reading, and writing, as rapidly as possible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited English proficient” or “limited English proficiency,” when used with reference to an individual, means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who was not born in the United States and whose native language is a language other than English;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who comes from a home environment where a language other than English is spoken in the home; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who is an American Indian or Alaskan native and who comes from an environment where a language other than English has had a significant impact on his or her level of English language proficiency; and</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who, by reason thereof, has sufficient difficulty speaking, reading, writing, or listening to the English language to deny such individual the opportunity to learn successfully in classrooms where the language of instruction is English.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home language” or “native language,” when used with reference to an individual of limited English proficiency, means the language normally used by such individual or, in the case of a student, the language normally used by the parents of the student.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“ESOL” means English for Speakers of Other Languages and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When modifying instruction, the strategy used to teach limited English proficient students; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When modifying program, the program funded in the Florida Education Finance Program, listed under English for Speakers of Other Languages in s. 1011.62.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall implement the following procedures:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and submit a plan for providing English language instruction for limited English proficient students to the Department of Education for review and approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify limited English proficient students through assessment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for student exit from and reclassification into the program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide limited English proficient students ESOL instruction in English and ESOL instruction or home language instruction in the basic subject areas of reading, mathematics, science, social studies, and computer literacy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a student plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide qualified teachers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide equal access to other programs for eligible limited English proficient students based on need.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for parental involvement in the program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board’s program for limited English proficient students shall be evaluated and monitored periodically.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt rules for the purpose of implementing this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 150, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>