<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1003.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Classroom placement of multiple birth siblings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “multiple birth siblings” means twins, triplets, quadruplets, or other siblings resulting from a multiple birth.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent of multiple birth siblings who are assigned to the same grade level and school may request in writing that the school place the siblings in the same classroom or in separate classrooms. The request must be made no later than 5 days before the first day of each school year or 5 days after the first day of attendance of students during the school year if the students are enrolled in the school after the school year commences.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The school may recommend to the parent the appropriate classroom placement for multiple birth siblings and may provide professional educational advice to assist the parent with the decision regarding appropriate classroom placement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (4) or subsection (5), a school shall provide the multiple birth siblings with the classroom placement requested by the parent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A school is not required to place multiple birth siblings in the same classroom if factual evidence of performance shows proof that the multiple birth siblings should be separated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A school is not required to place multiple birth siblings in separate classrooms if the request would require the school district to add an additional class to the grade level of the multiple birth siblings.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the end of the first grading period following the multiple birth siblings’ enrollment in the school, if the principal of the school, in consultation with the teacher of each classroom in which the multiple birth siblings are placed, determines that the requested classroom placement is disruptive to the school, the principal may determine the appropriate classroom placement for the siblings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent may appeal the principal’s classroom placement of multiple birth siblings in the manner provided by school district policy. During an appeal, the multiple birth siblings shall remain in the classroom chosen by the parent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A right or obligation under s. 1003.57 or under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, 20 U.S.C. ss. 1400 et seq., regarding the individual placement decisions of the school district; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of a school district, principal, or teacher to remove a student from a classroom pursuant to school district student discipline policies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2008-210.</History></Section>