<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1003.436" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definition of “credit”.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of requirements for high school graduation, one full credit means a minimum of 135 hours of bona fide instruction in a designated course of study that contains student performance standards. One full credit means a minimum of 120 hours of bona fide instruction in a designated course of study that contains student performance standards for purposes of meeting high school graduation requirements in a district school that has been authorized to implement block scheduling by the district school board. The State Board of Education shall determine the number of postsecondary credit hours earned through dual enrollment pursuant to s. 1007.271 that satisfy the requirements of a dual enrollment articulation agreement according to s. 1007.271(21) and that equal one full credit of the equivalent high school course identified pursuant to s. 1007.271(9).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The hourly requirements for one-half credit are one-half the requirements specified in paragraph (a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In awarding credit for high school graduation, each district school board shall maintain a one-half credit earned system that shall include courses provided on a full-year basis. A student enrolled in a full-year course shall receive one-half credit if the student successfully completes either the first half or the second half of a full-year course but fails to successfully complete the other half of the course and the averaging of the grades obtained in each half would not result in a passing grade. A student enrolled in a full-year course shall receive a full credit if the student successfully completes either the first half or the second half of a full-year course but fails to successfully complete the other half of the course and the averaging of the grades obtained in each half would result in a passing grade, provided that such additional requirements specified in district school board policies, such as class attendance, homework, participation, and other indicators of performance, shall be successfully completed by the student.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 134, ch. 2002-387; s. 14, ch. 2003-391; s. 11, ch. 2012-191.</History>
</Section>