<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1003.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District school board” means the members who are elected by the voters of a school district created and existing pursuant to s. 4, Art. IX of the State Constitution to operate and control public K-12 education within the school district.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“School” means an organization of students for instructional purposes on an elementary, middle or junior high school, secondary or high school, or other public school level authorized under rules of the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exceptional student” means any student who has been determined eligible for a special program in accordance with rules of the State Board of Education. The term includes students who are gifted and students with disabilities who have an intellectual disability; autism spectrum disorder; a speech impairment; a language impairment; an orthopedic impairment; an other health impairment; traumatic brain injury; a visual impairment; an emotional or behavioral disability; or a specific learning disability, including, but not limited to, dyslexia, dyscalculia, or developmental aphasia; students who are deaf or hard of hearing or dual sensory impaired; students who are hospitalized or homebound; children with developmental delays ages birth through 5 years, or children, ages birth through 2 years, with established conditions that are identified in State Board of Education rules pursuant to s. 1003.21(1)(e).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Special education services” means specially designed instruction and such related services as are necessary for an exceptional student to benefit from education. Such services may include: transportation; diagnostic and evaluation services; social services; physical and occupational therapy; speech and language pathology services; job placement; orientation and mobility training; braillists, typists, and readers for the blind; interpreters and auditory amplification; services provided by a certified listening and spoken language specialist; rehabilitation counseling; transition services; mental health services; guidance and career counseling; specified materials, assistive technology devices, and other specialized equipment; and other such services as approved by rules of the state board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Career education” means education that provides instruction for the following purposes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the elementary, middle, and high school levels, exploratory courses designed to give students initial exposure to a broad range of occupations to assist them in preparing their academic and occupational plans, and practical arts courses that provide generic skills that may apply to many occupations but are not designed to prepare students for entry into a specific occupation. Career education provided before high school completion must be designed to strengthen both occupational awareness and academic skills integrated throughout all academic instruction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the secondary school level, job-preparatory instruction in the competencies that prepare students for effective entry into an occupation, including diversified cooperative education, work experience, and job-entry programs that coordinate directed study and on-the-job training.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the postsecondary education level, courses of study that provide competencies needed for entry into specific occupations or for advancement within an occupation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Suspension,” also referred to as out-of-school suspension, means the temporary removal of a student from all classes of instruction on public school grounds and all other school-sponsored activities, except as authorized by the principal or the principal’s designee, for a period not to exceed 10 school days and remanding of the student to the custody of the student’s parent with specific homework assignments for the student to complete.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“In-school suspension” means the temporary removal of a student from the student’s regular school program and placement in an alternative program, such as that provided in s. 1003.53, under the supervision of district school board personnel, for a period not to exceed 10 school days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Expulsion” means the removal of the right and obligation of a student to attend a public school under conditions set by the district school board, and for a period of time not to exceed the remainder of the term or school year and 1 additional year of attendance. Expulsions may be imposed with or without continuing educational services and shall be reported accordingly.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporal punishment” means the moderate use of physical force or physical contact by a teacher or principal as may be necessary to maintain discipline or to enforce school rule. However, the term “corporal punishment” does not include the use of such reasonable force by a teacher or principal as may be necessary for self-protection or to protect other students from disruptive students.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Habitual truant” means a student who has 15 unexcused absences within 90 calendar days with or without the knowledge or consent of the student’s parent, is subject to compulsory school attendance under s. 1003.21(1) and (2)(a), and is not exempt under s. 1003.21(3) or s. 1003.24, or by meeting the criteria for any other exemption specified by law or rules of the State Board of Education. Such a student must have been the subject of the activities specified in ss. 1003.26 and 1003.27(3), without resultant successful remediation of the truancy problem before being dealt with as a child in need of services according to the provisions of chapter 984.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dropout” means a student who meets any one or more of the following criteria:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student has voluntarily removed himself or herself from the school system before graduation for reasons that include, but are not limited to, marriage, or the student has withdrawn from school because he or she has failed the statewide student assessment test and thereby does not receive any of the certificates of completion;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student has not met the relevant attendance requirements of the school district pursuant to State Board of Education rules, or the student was expected to attend a school but did not enter as expected for unknown reasons, or the student’s whereabouts are unknown;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student has withdrawn from school, but has not transferred to another public or private school or enrolled in any career, adult, home education, or alternative educational program;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student has withdrawn from school due to hardship, unless such withdrawal has been granted under the provisions of s. 322.091, court action, expulsion, medical reasons, or pregnancy; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The student is not eligible to attend school because of reaching the maximum age for an exceptional student program in accordance with the district’s policy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The State Board of Education may adopt rules to implement the provisions of this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alternative measures for students with special needs” or “special programs” means measures designed to meet the special needs of a student that cannot be met by regular school curricula.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Juvenile justice education programs or schools” means programs or schools operating for the purpose of providing educational services to youth in Department of Juvenile Justice programs, for a school year comprised of 250 days of instruction distributed over 12 months. At the request of the provider, a district school board may decrease the minimum number of days of instruction by up to 10 days for teacher planning for residential programs and up to 20 days for teacher planning for nonresidential programs, subject to the approval of the Department of Juvenile Justice and the Department of Education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Juvenile justice provider” means the Department of Juvenile Justice, the sheriff, or a private, public, or other governmental organization under contract with the Department of Juvenile Justice or the sheriff that provides treatment, care and custody, or educational programs for youth in juvenile justice intervention, detention, or commitment programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Children and youths who are experiencing homelessness,” for programs authorized under subtitle B, Education for Homeless Children and Youths, of Title VII of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act, 42 U.S.C. ss. 11431 et seq., means children and youths who lack a fixed, regular, and adequate nighttime residence, and includes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children and youths who are sharing the housing of other persons due to loss of housing, economic hardship, or a similar reason; are living in motels, hotels, travel trailer parks, or camping grounds due to the lack of alternative adequate accommodations; are living in emergency or transitional shelters; are abandoned in hospitals; or are awaiting foster care placement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children and youths who have a primary nighttime residence that is a public or private place not designed for or ordinarily used as a regular sleeping accommodation for human beings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children and youths who are living in cars, parks, public spaces, abandoned buildings, bus or train stations, or similar settings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Migratory children who are living in circumstances described in paragraphs (a)-(c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Regular school attendance” means the actual attendance of a student during the school day as defined by law and rules of the State Board of Education. Regular attendance within the intent of s. 1003.21 may be achieved by attendance in:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public school supported by public funds;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parochial, religious, or denominational school;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A private school supported in whole or in part by tuition charges or by endowments or gifts;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A home education program that meets the requirements of chapter 1002; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A private tutoring program that meets the requirements of chapter 1002.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Core-curricula courses” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courses in language arts/reading, mathematics, social studies, and science in prekindergarten through grade 3, excluding any extracurricular courses pursuant to subsection (15);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courses in grades 4 through 8 in subjects that are measured by state assessment at any grade level and courses required for middle school promotion, excluding any extracurricular courses pursuant to subsection (15);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Courses in grades 9 through 12 in subjects that are measured by state assessment at any grade level and courses that are specifically identified by name in statute as required for high school graduation and that are not measured by state assessment, excluding any extracurricular courses pursuant to subsection (15);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exceptional student education courses; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">English for Speakers of Other Languages courses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The term is limited in meaning and used for the sole purpose of designating classes that are subject to the maximum class size requirements established in s. 1, Art. IX of the State Constitution. This term does not include courses offered under ss. 1002.37, 1002.415, and 1002.45.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Extracurricular courses” means all courses that are not defined as “core-curricula courses,” which may include, but are not limited to, physical education, fine arts, performing fine arts, career education, and courses that may result in college credit. The term is limited in meaning and used for the sole purpose of designating classes that are not subject to the maximum class size requirements established in s. 1, Art. IX of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physical education” means the development or maintenance of skills related to strength, agility, flexibility, movement, and stamina, including dance; the development of knowledge and skills regarding teamwork and fair play; the development of knowledge and skills regarding nutrition and physical fitness as part of a healthy lifestyle; and the development of positive attitudes regarding sound nutrition and physical activity as a component of personal well-being.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 111, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2003-391; s. 81, ch. 2004-357; s. 15, ch. 2006-74; s. 2, ch. 2007-28; s. 5, ch. 2008-147; s. 3, ch. 2008-204; s. 6, ch. 2009-164; s. 14, ch. 2011-55; s. 15, ch. 2011-175; s. 10, ch. 2012-133.</History>
</Section>