<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1003.54" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Teenage parent programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall maintain a teenage parent program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Teenage parent programs” means educational programs designed to provide a specialized curriculum to meet the needs of students who are pregnant or students who are mothers or fathers and the children of the students.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall provide pregnant students or students who are parents and the children of these students with a comprehensive teenage parent program. The program shall provide pregnant students or students who are parents with the option of participating in regular classroom activities or enrolling in a special program designed to meet their needs pursuant to s. 1003.21. Students participating in teenage parent programs shall be exempt from minimum attendance requirements for absences related to pregnancy or parenting, but shall be required to make up work missed due to absence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The curriculum shall include instruction in such topics as prenatal and postnatal health care, parenting skills, benefits of sexual abstinence, and consequences of subsequent pregnancies. Parenting skills should include instruction in the stages of child growth and development, methods for aiding in the intellectual, language, physical, and social development of children, and guidance on constructive play activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision for necessary child care, health care, social services, parent education, and transportation shall be ancillary service components of teenage parent programs. Ancillary services may be provided through the coordination of existing programs and services and through joint agreements between district school boards and early learning coalitions or other appropriate public and private providers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board shall make adequate provisions for pregnant and parenting teenagers to complete the coursework necessary to earn a high school diploma.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children enrolled in child care provided by the district shall be funded at the special program cost factor pursuant to s. 1011.62 if the parent or parents are enrolled full time in a public school in the district.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Districts may modify courses listed in the State Course Code Directory for the purpose of providing teenage parent programs pursuant to the provisions of this section. Such modifications must be approved by the commissioner and may include lengthening or shortening of the school time allotted for in-class study, alternate methods of assessment of student performance, and the integration of curriculum frameworks or student performance standards to produce interdisciplinary units of instruction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt rules necessary to implement the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 148, ch. 2002-387; s. 14, ch. 2004-484.</History></Section>