<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1003.4935" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Middle school career and professional academy courses and career-themed courses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with the 2011-2012 school year, each district school board, in collaboration with regional workforce boards, economic development agencies, and state-approved postsecondary institutions, shall include plans to implement a career and professional academy or a career-themed course, as defined in s. 1003.493(1)(b), in at least one middle school in the district as part of the strategic 3-year plan pursuant to s. 1003.491(2). The strategic plan must provide students the opportunity to transfer from a middle school career and professional academy or a career-themed course to a high school career and professional academy or a career-themed course currently operating within the school district. Students who complete a middle school career and professional academy or a career-themed course must have the opportunity to earn an industry certificate and high school credit and participate in career planning, job shadowing, and business leadership development activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each middle school career and professional academy or career-themed course must be aligned with at least one high school career and professional academy or career-themed course offered in the district and maintain partnerships with local business and industry and economic development boards. Middle school career and professional academies and career-themed courses must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lead to careers in occupations designated as high-skill, high-wage, and high-demand in the Industry Certification Funding List approved under rules adopted by the State Board of Education;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Integrate content from core subject areas;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Integrate career and professional academy or career-themed course content with intensive reading and mathematics pursuant to s. 1003.428;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate with high schools to maximize opportunities for middle school students to earn high school credit;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide access to virtual instruction courses provided by virtual education providers legislatively authorized to provide part-time instruction to middle school students. The virtual instruction courses must be aligned to state curriculum standards for middle school career and professional academy courses or career-themed courses, with priority given to students who have required course deficits;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide instruction from highly skilled professionals who hold industry certificates in the career area in which they teach;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer externships; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide personalized student advisement that includes a parent-participation component.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with the 2012-2013 school year, if a school district implements a middle school career and professional academy or a career-themed course, the Department of Education shall collect and report student achievement data pursuant to performance factors identified under s. 1003.492(3) for students enrolled in an academy or a career-themed course.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt rules to identify industry certifications in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics offered in middle school to be included on the Industry Certified Funding List and which are eligible for additional full-time equivalent membership under s. 1011.62(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 2011-55; s. 22, ch. 2011-175; s. 16, ch. 2012-191.</History>
</Section>