<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1003.4205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disability history and awareness instruction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board may provide disability history and awareness instruction in all K-12 public schools in the district during the first 2 weeks in October each year. The district school board shall designate these 2 weeks as “Disability History and Awareness Weeks.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During this 2-week period, students may be provided intensive instruction to expand their knowledge, understanding, and awareness of individuals with disabilities, the history of disability, and the disability rights movement. Disability history may include the events and timelines of the development and evolution of services to, and the civil rights of, individuals with disabilities. Disability history may also include the contributions of specific individuals with disabilities, including the contributions of acknowledged national leaders.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The instruction may be integrated into the existing school curriculum in ways including, but not limited to, supplementing lesson plans, holding school assemblies, or providing other school-related activities. The instruction may be delivered by qualified school personnel or by knowledgeable guest speakers, with a particular focus on including individuals with disabilities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The goals of disability history and awareness instruction include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Better treatment for individuals with disabilities, especially for youth in school, and increased attention to preventing the bullying or harassment of students with disabilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encouragement to individuals with disabilities to develop increased self-esteem, resulting in more individuals with disabilities gaining pride in being an individual with a disability, obtaining postsecondary education, entering the workforce, and contributing to their communities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reaffirmation of the local, state, and federal commitment to the full inclusion in society of, and the equal opportunity for, all individuals with disabilities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2008-156.</History></Section>