<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1003.4295" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Acceleration options.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each high school shall advise each student of programs through which a high school student can earn college credit, including Advanced Placement, International Baccalaureate, Advanced International Certificate of Education, dual enrollment, and early admission courses, career academy courses, and courses that lead to national industry certification, as well as the availability of course offerings through virtual instruction. Students shall also be advised of the early and accelerated graduation options under ss. 1003.4281 and 1003.429.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with the 2011-2012 school year, each high school shall offer an International Baccalaureate Program, an Advanced International Certificate of Education Program, or a combination of at least four courses in dual enrollment or Advanced Placement, including one course each in English, mathematics, science, and social studies. To meet this requirement, school districts may provide courses through virtual instruction, if the virtual course significantly integrates postsecondary level content for which a student may earn college credit, as determined by the Department of Education, and for which a standardized end-of-course assessment, as approved by the department, is administered.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Credit Acceleration Program (CAP) is created for the purpose of allowing a student to earn high school credit in a course that requires a statewide, standardized end-of-course assessment if the student attains a specified score on the assessment. Notwithstanding s. 1003.436, a school district shall award course credit to a student who is not enrolled in the course, or who has not completed the course, if the student attains a passing score on the corresponding statewide, standardized end-of-course assessment. The school district shall permit a student who is not enrolled in the course, or who has not completed the course, to take the standardized end-of-course assessment during the regular administration of the assessment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2010-22; s. 10, ch. 2012-191.</History>
</Section>