<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1003.4281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Early high school graduation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to provide a student the option of early graduation if the student has completed a minimum of 24 credits and meets the graduation requirements set forth in s. 1003.428. For purposes of this section, the term “early graduation” means graduation from high school in less than 8 semesters or the equivalent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board shall adopt a policy that provides a high school student the option of early graduation. Each school district shall notify the parent of a student who is eligible to graduate early. A school district may not prohibit a student who meets the requirements of this section from graduating early.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student who graduates early may continue to participate in school activities and social events and attend and participate in graduation events with the student’s cohort, as if the student were still enrolled in high school. A student who graduates early will be included in class ranking, honors, and award determinations for the student’s cohort. A student who graduates early must comply with district school board rules and policies regarding access to the school facilities and grounds during normal operating hours.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If eligible for a Florida Bright Futures Scholarship Program award under ss. 1009.53-1009.538, a student who graduates from high school midyear may receive an initial award in the spring term following the student’s graduation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, a credit is equal to <Fraction>1/6</Fraction> FTE. A student may earn up to six paid high school credits equivalent to 1 FTE per school year in grades 9 through 12 for courses provided by the school district. High school credits earned in excess of six per school year in courses delivered by the school district are unpaid credits.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2012-191.</History>
</Section>