<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1003.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assistance to transitioning students from military families.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that school-aged dependents of military personnel, otherwise known as military students, are faced with numerous transitions during their formative years and that moves during the high school years provide special challenges to learning and future achievement. Recognizing the challenges faced by military students and the importance of military families to our community and economy, the Department of Education shall assist the transition of these students by improving the timely transfer of records, developing systems to ease student transition during the first 2 weeks of enrollment, promoting practices which foster access to extracurricular programs, establishing procedures to lessen the adverse impact of moves from the end of the junior year as well as before and during the senior year, encouraging or continuing partnerships between the military base and the school system, providing services for transitioning students when applying to and finding funding for postsecondary study, and providing other assistance as identified by department, school, and military personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall facilitate the development and implementation of memoranda of agreement between school districts and military installations which address strategies for assisting students who are the children of active duty military personnel in the transition to Florida schools.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dependent children of active duty military personnel who otherwise meet the eligibility criteria for special academic programs offered through public schools shall be given first preference for admission to such programs even if the program is being offered through a public school other than the school to which the student would generally be assigned. If such a program is offered through a public school other than the school to which the student would generally be assigned, the parent or guardian of the student must assume responsibility for transporting the student to that school. For purposes of this subsection, special academic programs include magnet schools, advanced studies programs, advanced placement, dual enrollment, Advanced International Certificate of Education, and International Baccalaureate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-44; s. 12, ch. 2004-230; s. 17, ch. 2006-74; s. 8, ch. 2006-190.</History></Section>