<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1003.51" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Other public educational services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The general control of other public educational services shall be vested in the State Board of Education except as provided herein. The State Board of Education shall, at the request of the Department of Children and Family Services and the Department of Juvenile Justice, advise as to standards and requirements relating to education to be met in all state schools or institutions under their control which provide educational programs. The Department of Education shall provide supervisory services for the educational programs of all such schools or institutions. The direct control of any of these services provided as part of the district program of education shall rest with the district school board. These services shall be supported out of state, district, federal, or other lawful funds, depending on the requirements of the services being supported.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt and maintain an administrative rule articulating expectations for effective education programs for youth in Department of Juvenile Justice programs, including, but not limited to, education programs in juvenile justice commitment and detention facilities. The rule shall articulate policies and standards for education programs for youth in Department of Juvenile Justice programs and shall include the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interagency collaborative process needed to ensure effective programs with measurable results.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The responsibilities of the Department of Education, the Department of Juvenile Justice, district school boards, and providers of education services to youth in Department of Juvenile Justice programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Academic expectations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service delivery options available to district school boards, including direct service and contracting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assessment procedures, which:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include appropriate academic and career assessments administered at program entry and exit that are selected by the Department of Education in partnership with representatives from the Department of Juvenile Justice, district school boards, and providers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require district school boards to be responsible for ensuring the completion of the assessment process.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require assessments for students in detention who will move on to commitment facilities, to be designed to create the foundation for developing the student’s education program in the assigned commitment facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require assessments of students sent directly to commitment facilities to be completed within the first 10 school days of the student’s commitment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The results of these assessments, together with a portfolio depicting the student’s academic and career accomplishments, shall be included in the discharge package assembled for each youth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommended instructional programs, including, but not limited to, career training and job preparation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funding requirements, which shall include the requirement that at least 90 percent of the FEFP funds generated by students in Department of Juvenile Justice programs or in an education program for juveniles under s. 985.19 be spent on instructional costs for those students. One hundred percent of the formula-based categorical funds generated by students in Department of Juvenile Justice programs must be spent on appropriate categoricals such as instructional materials and public school technology for those students.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualifications of instructional staff, procedures for the selection of instructional staff, and procedures to ensure consistent instruction and qualified staff year round.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transition services, including the roles and responsibilities of appropriate personnel in school districts, provider organizations, and the Department of Juvenile Justice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures and timeframe for transfer of education records when a youth enters and leaves a facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirement that each district school board maintain an academic transcript for each student enrolled in a juvenile justice facility that delineates each course completed by the student as provided by the State Course Code Directory.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirement that each district school board make available and transmit a copy of a student’s transcript in the discharge packet when the student exits a facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contract requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performance expectations for providers and district school boards, including the provision of a progress monitoring plan as required in s. 1008.25.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The role and responsibility of the district school board in securing workforce development funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A series of graduated sanctions for district school boards whose educational programs in Department of Juvenile Justice facilities are considered to be unsatisfactory and for instances in which district school boards fail to meet standards prescribed by law, rule, or State Board of Education policy. These sanctions shall include the option of requiring a district school board to contract with a provider or another district school board if the educational program at the Department of Juvenile Justice facility has failed a quality assurance review and, after 6 months, is still performing below minimum standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other aspects of program operations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education in partnership with the Department of Juvenile Justice, the district school boards, and providers shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain model contracts for the delivery of appropriate education services to youth in Department of Juvenile Justice programs to be used for the development of future contracts. The model contracts shall reflect the policy and standards included in subsection (2). The Department of Education shall ensure that appropriate district school board personnel are trained and held accountable for the management and monitoring of contracts for education programs for youth in juvenile justice residential and nonresidential facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain model procedures for transitioning youth into and out of Department of Juvenile Justice programs. These procedures shall reflect the policy and standards adopted pursuant to subsection (2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain standardized required content of education records to be included as part of a youth’s commitment record. These requirements shall reflect the policy and standards adopted pursuant to subsection (2) and shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the student’s individual educational plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assessment data, including grade level proficiency in reading, writing, and mathematics, and performance on tests taken according to s. 1008.22.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the student’s permanent cumulative record.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the student’s academic transcript.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A portfolio reflecting the youth’s academic accomplishments while in the Department of Juvenile Justice program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain model procedures for securing the education record and the roles and responsibilities of the juvenile probation officer and others involved in the withdrawal of the student from school and assignment to a commitment or detention facility. District school boards shall respond to requests for student education records received from another district school board or a juvenile justice facility within 5 working days after receiving the request.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall ensure that district school boards notify students in juvenile justice residential or nonresidential facilities who attain the age of 16 years of the provisions of law regarding compulsory school attendance and make available the option of enrolling in a program to attain a Florida high school diploma by taking the General Educational Development test prior to release from the facility. District school boards or Florida College System institutions, or both, shall waive GED testing fees for youth in Department of Juvenile Justice residential programs and shall, upon request, designate schools operating for the purpose of providing educational services to youth in Department of Juvenile Justice programs as GED testing centers, subject to GED testing center requirements. The administrative fees for the General Educational Development test required by the Department of Education are the responsibility of district school boards and may be required of providers by contractual agreement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall establish and operate, either directly or indirectly through a contract, a mechanism to provide quality assurance reviews of all juvenile justice education programs and shall provide technical assistance and related research to district school boards and providers on how to establish, develop, and operate educational programs that exceed the minimum quality assurance standards.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 145, ch. 2002-387; s. 3, ch. 2004-333; s. 85, ch. 2004-357; s. 28, ch. 2006-74; s. 172, ch. 2007-5; s. 7, ch. 2007-234; s. 37, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>