<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1003.575" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assistive technology devices; findings; interagency agreements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accessibility, utilization, and coordination of appropriate assistive technology devices and services are essential as a young person with disabilities moves from early intervention to preschool, from preschool to school, from one school to another, and from school to employment or independent living. If an individual education plan team makes a recommendation in accordance with State Board of Education rule for a student with a disability, as defined in s. 1003.01(3), to receive an assistive technology assessment, that assessment must be completed within 60 school days after the team’s recommendation. To ensure that an assistive technology device issued to a young person as part of his or her individualized family support plan, individual support plan, or an individual education plan remains with the individual through such transitions, the following agencies shall enter into interagency agreements, as appropriate, to ensure the transaction of assistive technology devices:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Infants and Toddlers Early Intervention Program in the Division of Children’s Medical Services of the Department of Health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Blind Services, the Bureau of Exceptional Education and Student Services, and the Division of Vocational Rehabilitation of the Department of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Voluntary Prekindergarten Education Program administered by the Department of Education and the Office of Early Learning.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Interagency agreements entered into pursuant to this section shall provide a framework for ensuring that young persons with disabilities and their families, educators, and employers are informed about the utilization and coordination of assistive technology devices and services that may assist in meeting transition needs, and shall establish a mechanism by which a young person or his or her parent may request that an assistive technology device remain with the young person as he or she moves through the continuum from home to school to postschool.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-188; s. 463, ch. 2011-142; s. 24, ch. 2011-175.</History>
</Section>