<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following may be distributed at retail without a prescription, but only by a registered pharmacist:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any compound, mixture, or preparation described in Schedule V.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any compound, mixture, or preparation containing any depressant or stimulant substance described in s. 893.03(2)(a) or (c) except any amphetamine drug or sympathomimetic amine drug or compound designated as a Schedule II controlled substance pursuant to this chapter; in s. 893.03(3)(a); or in Schedule IV, if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The compound, mixture, or preparation contains one or more active medicinal ingredients not having depressant or stimulant effect on the central nervous system, and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such ingredients are included therein in such combinations, quantity, proportion, or concentration as to vitiate the potential for abuse of the controlled substances which do have a depressant or stimulant effect on the central nervous system.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No compound, mixture, or preparation may be dispensed under subsection (1) unless such substance may, under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, be lawfully sold at retail without a prescription.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemptions authorized by this section shall be subject to the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The compounds, mixtures, and preparations referred to in subsection (1) may be dispensed to persons under age 18 only on prescription. A bound volume must be maintained as a record of sale at retail of excepted compounds, mixtures, and preparations, and the pharmacist must require suitable identification from every unknown purchaser.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such compounds, mixtures, and preparations shall be sold by the pharmacist in good faith as a medicine and not for the purpose of evading the provisions of this chapter. The pharmacist may, in his or her discretion, withhold sale to any person whom the pharmacist reasonably believes is attempting to purchase excepted compounds, mixtures, or preparations for the purpose of abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total quantity of controlled substance listed in Schedule V which may be sold to any one purchaser within a given 48-hour period shall not exceed 120 milligrams of codeine, 60 milligrams dihydrocodeine, 30 milligrams of ethyl morphine, or 240 milligrams of opium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the kind and quantity of any controlled substance that may be prescribed, administered, or dispensed to any person, or for the use of any person or animal, when it is prescribed, administered, or dispensed in compliance with the general provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dextrorotatory isomer of 3-methoxy-n-methylmorphinan and its salts (dextromethorphan) shall not be deemed to be included in any schedule by reason of enactment of this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 73-331; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 6, ch. 80-354; s. 4, ch. 89-281; s. 2, ch. 93-92; s. 1440, ch. 97-102; s. 105, ch. 97-264; s. 12, ch. 99-186.</History></Section>