<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pharmacist and practitioner.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pharmacist, in good faith and in the course of professional practice only, may dispense controlled substances upon a written or oral prescription of a practitioner, under the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Oral prescriptions must be promptly reduced to writing by the pharmacist or recorded electronically if permitted by federal law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written prescription must be dated and signed by the prescribing practitioner on the day when issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall appear on the face of the prescription or written record thereof for the controlled substance the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name and address of the person for whom, or the owner of the animal for which, the controlled substance is dispensed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name and address of the prescribing practitioner and the practitioner’s federal controlled substance registry number shall be printed thereon.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the prescription is for an animal, the species of animal for which the controlled substance is prescribed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the controlled substance prescribed and the strength, quantity, and directions for use thereof.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of the prescription, as recorded in the prescription files of the pharmacy in which it is filled.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initials of the pharmacist filling the prescription and the date filled.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prescription shall be retained on file by the proprietor of the pharmacy in which it is filled for a period of 2 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affixed to the original container in which a controlled substance is delivered upon a prescription or authorized refill thereof, as hereinafter provided, there shall be a label bearing the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the pharmacy from which such controlled substance was dispensed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date on which the prescription for such controlled substance was filled.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of such prescription, as recorded in the prescription files of the pharmacy in which it is filled.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the prescribing practitioner.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the patient for whom, or of the owner and species of the animal for which, the controlled substance is prescribed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The directions for the use of the controlled substance prescribed in the prescription.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear, concise warning that it is a crime to transfer the controlled substance to any person other than the patient for whom prescribed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prescription for a controlled substance listed in Schedule II may be dispensed only upon a written prescription of a practitioner, except that in an emergency situation, as defined by regulation of the Department of Health, such controlled substance may be dispensed upon oral prescription but is limited to a 72-hour supply. A prescription for a controlled substance listed in Schedule II may not be refilled.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prescription for a controlled substance listed in Schedule III, Schedule IV, or Schedule V may not be filled or refilled more than five times within a period of 6 months after the date on which the prescription was written unless the prescription is renewed by a practitioner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pharmacist may not dispense a controlled substance listed in Schedule II, Schedule III, or Schedule IV to any patient or patient’s agent without first determining, in the exercise of her or his professional judgment, that the order is valid. The pharmacist may dispense the controlled substance, in the exercise of her or his professional judgment, when the pharmacist or pharmacist’s agent has obtained satisfactory patient information from the patient or the patient’s agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any pharmacist who dispenses by mail a controlled substance listed in Schedule II, Schedule III, or Schedule IV is exempt from the requirement to obtain suitable identification for the prescription dispensed by mail if the pharmacist has obtained the patient’s identification through the patient’s prescription benefit plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any controlled substance listed in Schedule III or Schedule IV may be dispensed by a pharmacist upon an oral prescription if, before filling the prescription, the pharmacist reduces it to writing or records the prescription electronically if permitted by federal law. Such prescriptions must contain the date of the oral authorization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each written prescription prescribed by a practitioner in this state for a controlled substance listed in Schedule II, Schedule III, or Schedule IV must include both a written and a numerical notation of the quantity of the controlled substance prescribed on the face of the prescription and a notation of the date, with the abbreviated month written out on the face of the prescription. A pharmacist may, upon verification by the prescriber, document any information required by this paragraph. If the prescriber is not available to verify a prescription, the pharmacist may dispense the controlled substance but may insist that the person to whom the controlled substance is dispensed provide valid photographic identification. If a prescription includes a numerical notation of the quantity of the controlled substance or date, but does not include the quantity or date written out in textual format, the pharmacist may dispense the controlled substance without verification by the prescriber of the quantity or date if the pharmacy previously dispensed another prescription for the person to whom the prescription was written.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pharmacist may not dispense more than a 30-day supply of a controlled substance listed in Schedule III upon an oral prescription issued in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pharmacist may not knowingly fill a prescription that has been forged for a controlled substance listed in Schedule II, Schedule III, or Schedule IV.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), a pharmacist may dispense a one-time emergency refill of up to a 72-hour supply of the prescribed medication for any medicinal drug other than a medicinal drug listed in Schedule II, in compliance with the provisions of s. 465.0275.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The legal owner of any stock of controlled substances in a pharmacy, upon discontinuance of dealing in controlled substances, may sell said stock to a manufacturer, wholesaler, or pharmacy. Such controlled substances may be sold only upon an order form, when such an order form is required for sale by the drug abuse laws of the United States or this state, or regulations pursuant thereto.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 73-331; s. 2, ch. 75-18; s. 12, ch. 79-12; s. 2, ch. 90-2; s. 1436, ch. 97-102; s. 301, ch. 99-8; s. 2, ch. 2007-156; s. 5, ch. 2009-202.</History></Section>