<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0893.1495" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retail sale of ephedrine and related compounds.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “ephedrine or related compounds” means ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, phenylpropanolamine, or any of their salts, optical isomers, or salts of optical isomers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly obtain or deliver to an individual in any retail over-the-counter sale any nonprescription compound, mixture, or preparation containing ephedrine or related compounds in excess of the following amounts:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any single day, any number of packages that contain a total of 3.6 grams of ephedrine or related compounds;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any single retail, over-the-counter sale, three packages, regardless of weight, containing ephedrine or related compounds; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any 30-day period, in any number of retail, over-the-counter sales, a total of 9 grams or more of ephedrine or related compounds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly display and offer for retail sale any nonprescription compound, mixture, or preparation containing ephedrine or related compounds other than behind a checkout counter where the public is not permitted or other such location that is not otherwise accessible to the general public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is the owner or primary operator of a retail outlet where any nonprescription compound, mixture, or preparation containing ephedrine or related compounds is available for sale may not knowingly allow an employee to engage in the retail sale of such compound, mixture, or preparation unless the employee has completed an employee training program that shall include, at a minimum, basic instruction on state and federal regulations relating to the sale and distribution of such compounds, mixtures, or preparations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person purchasing, receiving, or otherwise acquiring any nonprescription compound, mixture, or preparation containing any detectable quantity of ephedrine or related compounds must:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 18 years of age.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Produce a government-issued photo identification showing his or her name, date of birth, address, and photo identification number or an alternative form of identification acceptable under federal regulation 8 C.F.R. s. 274a.2(b)(1)(v)(A) and (B).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sign his or her name on a record of the purchase, either on paper or on an electronic signature capture device.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement shall approve an electronic recordkeeping system for the purpose of recording and monitoring the real-time purchase of products containing ephedrine or related compounds and for the purpose of monitoring this information in order to prevent or investigate illegal purchases of these products. The approved electronic recordkeeping system shall be provided to a pharmacy or retailer without any additional cost or expense. A pharmacy or retailer may request an exemption from electronic reporting from the Department of Law Enforcement if the pharmacy or retailer lacks the technology to access the electronic recordkeeping system and such pharmacy or retailer maintains a sales volume of less than 72 grams of ephedrine or related compounds in a 30-day period. The electronic recordkeeping system shall record the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and time of the transaction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, date of birth, address, and photo identification number of the purchaser, as well as the type of identification and the government of issuance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of packages purchased, the total grams per package, and the name of the compound, mixture, or preparation containing ephedrine or related compounds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The signature of the purchaser, or a unique number relating the transaction to a paper signature maintained at the retail premises.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The electronic recordkeeping system shall provide for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Real-time tracking of nonprescription over-the-counter sales under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The blocking of nonprescription over-the-counter sales in excess of those allowed by the laws of this state or federal law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonprescription compound, mixture, or preparation containing any quantity of ephedrine or related compounds may not be sold over the counter unless reported to an electronic recordkeeping system approved by the Department of Law Enforcement. This subsection does not apply if the pharmacy or retailer has received an exemption from the Department of Law Enforcement under paragraph (5)(b).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to completing a transaction, a pharmacy or retailer distributing products containing ephedrine or related compounds to consumers in this state shall submit all required data into an electronic recordkeeping system approved by the Department of Law Enforcement at the point of sale or through an interface with the electronic recordkeeping system, unless granted an exemption by the Department of Law Enforcement pursuant to paragraph (5)(b).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The data submitted to the electronic recordkeeping system must be retained within the system for no less than 2 years following the date of entry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of this section relating to the marketing, sale, or distribution of products containing ephedrine or related compounds supersede any local ordinance or regulation passed by a county, municipality, or other local governmental authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed manufacturers manufacturing and lawfully distributing products in the channels of commerce.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wholesalers lawfully distributing products in the channels of commerce.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care facilities licensed under chapter 395.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed long-term care facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Government-operated health departments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physicians’ offices.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publicly operated prisons, jails, or juvenile correctional facilities or private adult or juvenile correctional facilities under contract with the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public or private educational institutions maintaining health care programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Government-operated or industry-operated medical facilities serving employees of the government or industry operating them.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who violates subsection (2), subsection (3), or subsection (4) commits:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a first offense, a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second offense, a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a third or subsequent offense, a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information contained within the electronic recordkeeping system shall be disclosed in a manner authorized by state or federal law. Any retailer or entity that collects information on behalf of a retailer as required by the Combat Methamphetamine Epidemic Act of 2005 and this section may not access or use that information, except for law enforcement purposes pursuant to state or federal law or to facilitate a product recall for public health and safety.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who sells any product containing ephedrine or related compounds who in good faith releases information under this section to federal, state, or local law enforcement officers, or any person acting on behalf of such an officer, is immune from civil liability for the release unless the release constitutes gross negligence or intentional, wanton, or willful misconduct.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement shall contract or enter into a memorandum of understanding, as applicable, with a private third-party administrator to implement the electronic recordkeeping system required by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement shall adopt rules necessary to implement this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2005-128; s. 1, ch. 2010-191.</History>
</Section>