<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.0356" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Control of new substances; findings of fact; “controlled substance analog” defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">New substances are being created which are not controlled under the provisions of this chapter but which have a potential for abuse similar to or greater than that for substances controlled under this chapter. These new substances are called “controlled substance analogs,” and can be designed to produce a desired pharmacological effect and to evade the controlling statutory provisions. Controlled substance analogs are being manufactured, distributed, possessed, and used as substitutes for controlled substances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The hazards attributable to the traffic in and use of controlled substance analogs are increased because their unregulated manufacture produces variations in purity and concentration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Many such new substances are untested, and it cannot be immediately determined whether they have useful medical or chemical purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The uncontrolled importation, manufacture, distribution, possession, or use of controlled substance analogs has a substantial and detrimental impact on the health and safety of the people of Florida.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Controlled substance analogs can be created more rapidly than they can be identified and controlled by action of the Legislature. There is a need for a speedy determination of their proper classification under this chapter. It is therefore necessary to identify and classify new substances that have a potential for abuse, so that they can be controlled in the same manner as other substances currently controlled under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “controlled substance analog” means a substance which, due to its chemical structure and potential for abuse, meets the following criteria:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is substantially similar to that of a controlled substance listed in Schedule I or Schedule II of s. 893.03; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system or is represented or intended to have a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system substantially similar to or greater than that of a controlled substance listed in Schedule I or Schedule II of s. 893.03.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Controlled substance analog” does not include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A controlled substance;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any substance for which there is an approved new drug application;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any controlled substance which is not for administration to a human being or animal, and which is packaged in such form or concentration, or with adulterants or denaturants, so that as packaged it does not present any significant potential for abuse; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any substance to which an investigational exemption applies under s. 505 of the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, 21 U.S.C. 355, but only to the extent that conduct with respect to the substance is pursuant to such exemption.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “potential for abuse” in this section means that a substance has properties as a central nervous system stimulant or depressant or a hallucinogen that create a substantial likelihood of its being:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Used in amounts that create a hazard to the user’s health or the safety of the community;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diverted from legal channels and distributed through illegal channels; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taken on the user’s own initiative rather than on the basis of professional medical advice.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Proof of potential for abuse can be based upon a showing that these activities are already taking place, or upon a showing that the nature and properties of the substance make it reasonable to assume that there is a substantial likelihood that such activities will take place, in other than isolated or occasional instances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following factors shall be relevant to a finding that a substance is a controlled substance analog within the purview of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its actual or relative potential for abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Scientific evidence of its pharmacological effect, if known.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state of current scientific knowledge regarding the substance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its history and current pattern of abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The scope, duration, and significance of abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What, if any, risk there is to the public health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its psychic or physiological dependence liability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its diversion from legitimate channels, and clandestine importation, manufacture, or distribution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the substance is an immediate precursor of a substance already controlled under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A controlled substance analog shall, for purposes of drug abuse prevention and control, be treated as a controlled substance in Schedule I of s. 893.03.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In construing this section, due consideration and great weight should be given to interpretations of the United States Attorney General and the federal courts relating to s. 201 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970, 21 U.S.C. s. 811, as amended and in effect on April 1, 1985. New substances controlled under this section shall not be treated in a manner inconsistent with the rules of the United States Attorney General and the decisions of the federal courts interpreting the provisions of s. 201 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970, 21 U.S.C. s. 811, as amended and in effect on April 1, 1985.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The treatment of a new substance as a controlled substance pursuant to this section shall not affect prosecution or punishment for any crime previously committed with respect to that substance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 87-243; s. 11, ch. 99-186; s. 20, ch. 2000-320.</History></Section>