<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0893.0551" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public records exemption for the prescription drug monitoring program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Active investigation” has the same meaning as provided in s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dispenser” has the same meaning as provided in s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care practitioner” or “practitioner” has the same meaning as provided in s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care regulatory board” has the same meaning as provided in s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law enforcement agency” has the same meaning as provided in s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pharmacist” means any person licensed under chapter 465 to practice the profession of pharmacy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pharmacy” has the same meaning as provided in s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prescriber” has the same meaning as provided in s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following information of a patient or patient’s agent, a health care practitioner, a dispenser, an employee of the practitioner who is acting on behalf of and at the direction of the practitioner, a pharmacist, or a pharmacy that is contained in records held by the department under s. 893.055 is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Telephone number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance plan number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Government-issued identification number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provider number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drug Enforcement Administration number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other unique identifying information or number.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall disclose such confidential and exempt information to the following entities after using a verification process to ensure the legitimacy of that person’s or entity’s request for the information:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General and his or her designee when working on Medicaid fraud cases involving prescription drugs or when the Attorney General has initiated a review of specific identifiers of Medicaid fraud regarding prescription drugs. The Attorney General or his or her designee may disclose the confidential and exempt information received from the department to a criminal justice agency as defined in s. 119.011 as part of an active investigation that is specific to a violation of prescription drug abuse or prescription drug diversion law as it relates to controlled substances. The Attorney General’s Medicaid fraud investigators may not have direct access to the department’s database.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department’s relevant health care regulatory boards responsible for the licensure, regulation, or discipline of a practitioner, pharmacist, or other person who is authorized to prescribe, administer, or dispense controlled substances and who is involved in a specific controlled substances investigation for prescription drugs involving a designated person. The health care regulatory boards may request information from the department but may not have direct access to its database. The health care regulatory boards may provide such information to a law enforcement agency pursuant to ss. 456.066 and 456.073.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A law enforcement agency that has initiated an active investigation involving a specific violation of law regarding prescription drug abuse or diversion of prescribed controlled substances. The law enforcement agency may disclose the confidential and exempt information received from the department to a criminal justice agency as defined in s. 119.011 as part of an active investigation that is specific to a violation of prescription drug abuse or prescription drug diversion law as it relates to controlled substances. A law enforcement agency may request information from the department but may not have direct access to its database.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care practitioner who certifies that the information is necessary to provide medical treatment to a current patient in accordance with ss. 893.05 and 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pharmacist who certifies that the requested information will be used to dispense controlled substances to a current patient in accordance with ss. 893.04 and 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A patient or the legal guardian or designated health care surrogate for an incapacitated patient, if applicable, making a request as provided in s. 893.055(7)(c)4.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The patient’s pharmacy, prescriber, or dispenser who certifies that the information is necessary to provide medical treatment to his or her current patient in accordance with s. 893.055.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall disclose such confidential and exempt information to the applicable law enforcement agency in accordance with s. 893.055(7)(f). The law enforcement agency may disclose the confidential and exempt information received from the department to a criminal justice agency as defined in s. 119.011 as part of an active investigation that is specific to a violation of s. 893.13(7)(a)8., s. 893.13(8)(a), or s. 893.13(8)(b).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agency or person who obtains such confidential and exempt information pursuant to this section must maintain the confidential and exempt status of that information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who willfully and knowingly violates this section commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15 and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2014, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2009-197; s. 13, ch. 2010-211; s. 51, ch. 2011-4.</History>
</Section>