<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contraband; seizure, forfeiture, sale.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All substances controlled by this chapter and all listed chemicals, which substances or chemicals are handled, delivered, possessed, or distributed contrary to any provisions of this chapter, and all such controlled substances or listed chemicals the lawful possession of which is not established or the title to which cannot be ascertained, are declared to be contraband, are subject to seizure and confiscation by any person whose duty it is to enforce the provisions of the chapter, and shall be disposed of as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as in this section otherwise provided, the court having jurisdiction shall order such controlled substances or listed chemicals forfeited and destroyed. A record of the place where said controlled substances or listed chemicals were seized, of the kinds and quantities of controlled substances or listed chemicals destroyed, and of the time, place, and manner of destruction shall be kept, and a return under oath reporting said destruction shall be made to the court by the officer who destroys them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon written application by the Department of Health, the court by whom the forfeiture of such controlled substances or listed chemicals has been decreed may order the delivery of any of them to said department for distribution or destruction as hereinafter provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application by any hospital or laboratory within the state not operated for private gain, the department may, in its discretion, deliver any controlled substances or listed chemicals that have come into its custody by authority of this section to the applicant for medical use. The department may from time to time deliver excess stocks of such controlled substances or listed chemicals to the United States Drug Enforcement Administration or destroy same.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall keep a full and complete record of all controlled substances or listed chemicals received and of all controlled substances or listed chemicals disposed of, showing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exact kinds, quantities, and forms of such controlled substances or listed chemicals;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The persons from whom received and to whom delivered;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By whose authority received, delivered, and destroyed; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dates of the receipt, disposal, or destruction,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">which record shall be open to inspection by all persons charged with the enforcement of federal and state drug abuse laws.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vessel, vehicle, aircraft, or drug paraphernalia as defined in s. 893.145 which has been or is being used in violation of any provision of this chapter or in, upon, or by means of which any violation of this chapter has taken or is taking place may be seized and forfeited as provided by the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All real property, including any right, title, leasehold interest, and other interest in the whole of any lot or tract of land and any appurtenances or improvements, which real property is used, or intended to be used, in any manner or part, to commit or to facilitate the commission of, or which real property is acquired with proceeds obtained as a result of, a violation of any provision of this chapter related to a controlled substance described in s. 893.03(1) or (2) may be seized and forfeited as provided by the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act except that no property shall be forfeited under this paragraph to the extent of an interest of an owner or lienholder by reason of any act or omission established by that owner or lienholder to have been committed or omitted without the knowledge or consent of that owner or lienholder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys, negotiable instruments, securities, and other things of value furnished or intended to be furnished by any person in exchange for a controlled substance described in s. 893.03(1) or (2) or a listed chemical in violation of any provision of this chapter, all proceeds traceable to such an exchange, and all moneys, negotiable instruments, and securities used or intended to be used to facilitate any violation of any provision of this chapter or which are acquired with proceeds obtained in violation of any provision of this chapter may be seized and forfeited as provided by the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act, except that no property shall be forfeited under this paragraph to the extent of an interest of an owner or lienholder by reason of any act or omission established by that owner or lienholder to have been committed or omitted without the knowledge or consent of that owner or lienholder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All books, records, and research, including formulas, microfilm, tapes, and data which are used, or intended for use, or which are acquired with proceeds obtained, in violation of any provision of this chapter related to a controlled substance described in s. 893.03(1) or (2) or a listed chemical may be seized and forfeited as provided by the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the property described in this subsection:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cannot be located;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been transferred to, sold to, or deposited with, a third party;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been placed beyond the jurisdiction of the court;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been substantially diminished in value by any act or omission of the defendant; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been commingled with any property which cannot be divided without difficulty,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the court shall order the forfeiture of any other property of the defendant up to the value of any property subject to forfeiture under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement agency is empowered to authorize or designate officers, agents, or other persons to carry out the seizure provisions of this section. It shall be the duty of any officer, agent, or other person so authorized or designated, or authorized by law, whenever she or he shall discover any vessel, vehicle, aircraft, real property or interest in real property, money, negotiable instrument, security, book, record, or research which has been or is being used or intended to be used, or which is acquired with proceeds obtained, in violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, or in, upon, or by means of which any violation of this chapter has taken or is taking place, to seize such vessel, vehicle, aircraft, real property or interest in real property, money, negotiable instrument, security, book, record, or research and place it in the custody of such person as may be authorized or designated for that purpose by the respective law enforcement agency pursuant to these provisions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights of any bona fide holder of a duly recorded mortgage or duly recorded vendor’s privilege on the property seized under this chapter shall not be affected by the seizure.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 73-331; ss. 10, 11, ch. 74-385; s. 471, ch. 77-147; s. 185, ch. 79-164; s. 4, ch. 80-30; s. 9, ch. 80-68; s. 5, ch. 89-148; s. 4, ch. 91-279; s. 1444, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 98-395; s. 303, ch. 99-8; s. 13, ch. 99-186; s. 21, ch. 2000-320; s. 17, ch. 2004-11.</History></Section>