<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Practitioners and persons administering controlled substances in their absence.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A practitioner, in good faith and in the course of his or her professional practice only, may prescribe, administer, dispense, mix, or otherwise prepare a controlled substance, or the practitioner may cause the same to be administered by a licensed nurse or an intern practitioner under his or her direction and supervision only. A veterinarian may so prescribe, administer, dispense, mix, or prepare a controlled substance for use on animals only, and may cause it to be administered by an assistant or orderly under the veterinarian’s direction and supervision only.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any controlled substance is dispensed by a practitioner, there shall be affixed to the original container in which the controlled substance is delivered a label on which appears:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of delivery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The directions for use of such controlled substance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of such practitioner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the patient and, if such controlled substance is prescribed for an animal, a statement describing the species of the animal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clear, concise warning that it is a crime to transfer the controlled substance to any person other than the patient for whom prescribed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who obtains from a practitioner or the practitioner’s agent, or pursuant to prescription, any controlled substance for administration to a patient during the absence of such practitioner shall return to such practitioner any unused portion of such controlled substance when it is no longer required by the patient.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 73-331; s. 1437, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>