<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0893.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension, revocation, and reinstatement of business and professional licenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of s. 120.60(6), any conviction in any court reported to the Comprehensive Case Information System of the Florida Association of Court Clerks and Comptrollers, Inc., for the sale of, or trafficking in, a controlled substance or for conspiracy to sell, or traffic in, a controlled substance constitutes an immediate serious danger to the public health, safety, or welfare, and is grounds for disciplinary action by the licensing state agency. A state agency shall initiate an immediate emergency suspension of an individual professional license issued by the agency, in compliance with the procedures for summary suspensions in s. 120.60(6), upon the agency’s findings of the licensee’s conviction in any court reported to the Comprehensive Case Information System of the Florida Association of Court Clerks and Comptrollers, Inc., for the sale of, or trafficking in, a controlled substance, or for conspiracy to sell, or traffic in, a controlled substance. Before renewing any professional license, a state agency that issues a professional license must use the Comprehensive Case Information System of the Florida Association of Court Clerks and Comptrollers, Inc., to obtain information relating to any conviction for the sale of, or trafficking in, a controlled substance or for conspiracy to sell, or traffic in, a controlled substance. The clerk of court shall provide electronic access to each state agency at no cost and also provide certified copies of the judgment upon request to the agency. Upon a showing by any such convicted defendant whose professional license has been suspended or revoked pursuant to this section that his or her civil rights have been restored or upon a showing that the convicted defendant meets the following criteria, the agency head may reinstate or reactivate such license when:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has complied with the conditions of paragraphs (a) and (b) which shall be monitored by the Department of Corrections while the person is under any supervisory sanction. If the person fails to comply with provisions of these paragraphs by either failing to maintain treatment or by testing positive for drug use, the department shall notify the licensing agency, which shall revoke the license. The person under supervision may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek evaluation and enrollment in, and once enrolled maintain enrollment in until completion, a drug treatment and rehabilitation program which is approved or regulated by the Department of Children and Family Services. The treatment and rehabilitation program shall be specified by:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, in the case of court-ordered supervisory sanctions;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Parole Commission, in the case of parole, control release, or conditional release; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections, in the case of imprisonment or any other supervision required by law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to periodic urine drug testing pursuant to procedures prescribed by the Department of Corrections. If the person is indigent, the costs shall be paid by the Department of Corrections; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has successfully completed an appropriate program under the Correctional Education Program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “professional license” includes any license, permit, or certificate that authorizes a person to practice his or her profession. However, the term does not include any of the taxes, fees, or permits regulated, controlled, or administered by the Department of Revenue in accordance with s. 213.05.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 73-331; s. 1, ch. 77-117; s. 19, ch. 78-95; s. 3, ch. 90-266; s. 126, ch. 91-112; s. 14, ch. 95-325; s. 1443, ch. 97-102; s. 302, ch. 99-8; s. 18, ch. 2012-100.</History>
</Section>