<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0893.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following words and phrases as used in this chapter shall have the following meanings, unless the context otherwise requires:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administer” means the direct application of a controlled substance, whether by injection, inhalation, ingestion, or any other means, to the body of a person or animal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Analog” or “chemical analog” means a structural derivative of a parent compound that is a controlled substance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cannabis” means all parts of any plant of the genus <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Cannabis</Font>, whether growing or not; the seeds thereof; the resin extracted from any part of the plant; and every compound, manufacture, salt, derivative, mixture, or preparation of the plant or its seeds or resin.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Controlled substance” means any substance named or described in Schedules I-V of s. 893.03. Laws controlling the manufacture, distribution, preparation, dispensing, or administration of such substances are drug abuse laws.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cultivating” means the preparation of any soil or hydroponic medium for the planting of a controlled substance or the tending and care or harvesting of a controlled substance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deliver” or “delivery” means the actual, constructive, or attempted transfer from one person to another of a controlled substance, whether or not there is an agency relationship.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dispense” means the transfer of possession of one or more doses of a medicinal drug by a pharmacist or other licensed practitioner to the ultimate consumer thereof or to one who represents that it is his or her intention not to consume or use the same but to transfer the same to the ultimate consumer or user for consumption by the ultimate consumer or user.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Distribute” means to deliver, other than by administering or dispensing, a controlled substance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Distributor” means a person who distributes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Homologue” means a chemical compound in a series in which each compound differs by one or more alkyl functional groups on an alkyl side chain.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hospital” means an institution for the care and treatment of the sick and injured, licensed pursuant to the provisions of chapter 395 or owned or operated by the state or Federal Government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Laboratory” means a laboratory approved by the Drug Enforcement Administration as proper to be entrusted with the custody of controlled substances for scientific, medical, or instructional purposes or to aid law enforcement officers and prosecuting attorneys in the enforcement of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Listed chemical” means any precursor chemical or essential chemical named or described in s. 893.033.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacture” means the production, preparation, propagation, compounding, cultivating, growing, conversion, or processing of a controlled substance, either directly or indirectly, by extraction from substances of natural origin, or independently by means of chemical synthesis, or by a combination of extraction and chemical synthesis, and includes any packaging of the substance or labeling or relabeling of its container, except that this term does not include the preparation, compounding, packaging, or labeling of a controlled substance by:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A practitioner or pharmacist as an incident to his or her administering or delivering of a controlled substance in the course of his or her professional practice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A practitioner, or by his or her authorized agent under the practitioner’s supervision, for the purpose of, or as an incident to, research, teaching, or chemical analysis, and not for sale.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer” means and includes every person who prepares, derives, produces, compounds, or repackages any drug as defined by the Florida Drug and Cosmetic Act. However, this definition does not apply to manufacturers of patent or proprietary preparations as defined in the Florida Pharmacy Act. Pharmacies, and pharmacists employed thereby, are specifically excluded from this definition.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mixture” means any physical combination of two or more substances.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Patient” means an individual to whom a controlled substance is lawfully dispensed or administered pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pharmacist” means a person who is licensed pursuant to chapter 465 to practice the profession of pharmacy in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Possession” includes temporary possession for the purpose of verification or testing, irrespective of dominion or control.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Potential for abuse” means that a substance has properties of a central nervous system stimulant or depressant or an hallucinogen that create a substantial likelihood of its being:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Used in amounts that create a hazard to the user’s health or the safety of the community;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diverted from legal channels and distributed through illegal channels; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taken on the user’s own initiative rather than on the basis of professional medical advice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Proof of potential for abuse can be based upon a showing that these activities are already taking place, or upon a showing that the nature and properties of the substance make it reasonable to assume that there is a substantial likelihood that such activities will take place, in other than isolated or occasional instances.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practitioner” means a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458, a dentist licensed pursuant to chapter 466, a veterinarian licensed pursuant to chapter 474, an osteopathic physician licensed pursuant to chapter 459, a naturopath licensed pursuant to chapter 462, or a podiatric physician licensed pursuant to chapter 461, provided such practitioner holds a valid federal controlled substance registry number.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prescription” means and includes an order for drugs or medicinal supplies written, signed, or transmitted by word of mouth, telephone, telegram, or other means of communication by a duly licensed practitioner licensed by the laws of the state to prescribe such drugs or medicinal supplies, issued in good faith and in the course of professional practice, intended to be filled, compounded, or dispensed by another person licensed by the laws of the state to do so, and meeting the requirements of s. 893.04. The term also includes an order for drugs or medicinal supplies so transmitted or written by a physician, dentist, veterinarian, or other practitioner licensed to practice in a state other than Florida, but only if the pharmacist called upon to fill such an order determines, in the exercise of his or her professional judgment, that the order was issued pursuant to a valid patient-physician relationship, that it is authentic, and that the drugs or medicinal supplies so ordered are considered necessary for the continuation of treatment of a chronic or recurrent illness. However, if the physician writing the prescription is not known to the pharmacist, the pharmacist shall obtain proof to a reasonable certainty of the validity of said prescription. A prescription order for a controlled substance shall not be issued on the same prescription blank with another prescription order for a controlled substance which is named or described in a different schedule, nor shall any prescription order for a controlled substance be issued on the same prescription blank as a prescription order for a medicinal drug, as defined in s. 465.003(8), which does not fall within the definition of a controlled substance as defined in this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wholesaler” means any person who acts as a jobber, wholesale merchant, or broker, or an agent thereof, who sells or distributes for resale any drug as defined by the Florida Drug and Cosmetic Act. However, this definition does not apply to persons who sell only patent or proprietary preparations as defined in the Florida Pharmacy Act. Pharmacies, and pharmacists employed thereby, are specifically excluded from this definition.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 73-331; s. 1, ch. 75-18; s. 470, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 184, ch. 79-164; s. 1, ch. 79-325; s. 37, ch. 82-225; s. 169, ch. 83-216; s. 1, ch. 85-242; s. 1, ch. 91-279; s. 1, ch. 92-19; s. 1434, ch. 97-102; s. 104, ch. 97-264; s. 234, ch. 98-166; s. 300, ch. 99-8; s. 10, ch. 99-186; s. 1, ch. 2000-320; s. 3, ch. 2001-55; s. 10, ch. 2002-78; s. 13, ch. 2005-128; s. 1, ch. 2008-184; s. 18, ch. 2010-117; s. 1, ch. 2011-73.</History>
</Section>