<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.146" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of paraphernalia.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining whether an object is drug paraphernalia, a court or other authority or jury shall consider, in addition to all other logically relevant factors, the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Statements by an owner or by anyone in control of the object concerning its use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proximity of the object, in time and space, to a direct violation of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proximity of the object to controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existence of any residue of controlled substances on the object.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct or circumstantial evidence of the intent of an owner, or of anyone in control of the object, to deliver it to persons who he or she knows, or should reasonably know, intend to use the object to facilitate a violation of this act. The innocence of an owner, or of anyone in control of the object, as to a direct violation of this act shall not prevent a finding that the object is intended for use, or designed for use, as drug paraphernalia.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instructions, oral or written, provided with the object concerning its use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Descriptive materials accompanying the object which explain or depict its use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any advertising concerning its use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which the object is displayed for sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the owner, or anyone in control of the object, is a legitimate supplier of like or related items to the community, such as a licensed distributor of or dealer in tobacco products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct or circumstantial evidence of the ratio of sales of the object or objects to the total sales of the business enterprise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existence and scope of legitimate uses for the object in the community.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expert testimony concerning its use.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 80-30; s. 1445, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>