<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.145" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">“Drug paraphernalia” defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “drug paraphernalia” means all equipment, products, and materials of any kind which are used, intended for use, or designed for use in planting, propagating, cultivating, growing, harvesting, manufacturing, compounding, converting, producing, processing, preparing, testing, analyzing, packaging, repackaging, storing, containing, concealing, transporting, injecting, ingesting, inhaling, or otherwise introducing into the human body a controlled substance in violation of this chapter or s. 877.111. Drug paraphernalia is deemed to be contraband which shall be subject to civil forfeiture. The term includes, but is not limited to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Kits used, intended for use, or designed for use in the planting, propagating, cultivating, growing, or harvesting of any species of plant which is a controlled substance or from which a controlled substance can be derived.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Kits used, intended for use, or designed for use in manufacturing, compounding, converting, producing, processing, or preparing controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Isomerization devices used, intended for use, or designed for use in increasing the potency of any species of plant which is a controlled substance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Testing equipment used, intended for use, or designed for use in identifying, or in analyzing the strength, effectiveness, or purity of, controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Scales and balances used, intended for use, or designed for use in weighing or measuring controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diluents and adulterants, such as quinine hydrochloride, mannitol, mannite, dextrose, and lactose, used, intended for use, or designed for use in cutting controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Separation gins and sifters used, intended for use, or designed for use in removing twigs and seeds from, or in otherwise cleaning or refining, cannabis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Blenders, bowls, containers, spoons, and mixing devices used, intended for use, or designed for use in compounding controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Capsules, balloons, envelopes, and other containers used, intended for use, or designed for use in packaging small quantities of controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Containers and other objects used, intended for use, or designed for use in storing, concealing, or transporting controlled substances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hypodermic syringes, needles, and other objects used, intended for use, or designed for use in parenterally injecting controlled substances into the human body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Objects used, intended for use, or designed for use in ingesting, inhaling, or otherwise introducing cannabis, cocaine, hashish, hashish oil, or nitrous oxide into the human body, such as:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Metal, wooden, acrylic, glass, stone, plastic, or ceramic pipes, with or without screens, permanent screens, hashish heads, or punctured metal bowls.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water pipes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carburetion tubes and devices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Smoking and carburetion masks.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Roach clips: meaning objects used to hold burning material, such as a cannabis cigarette, that has become too small or too short to be held in the hand.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Miniature cocaine spoons, and cocaine vials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chamber pipes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carburetor pipes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electric pipes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Air-driven pipes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chillums.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bongs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ice pipes or chillers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cartridge or canister, which means a small metal device used to contain nitrous oxide.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charger, sometimes referred to as a “cracker,” which means a small metal or plastic device that contains an interior pin that may be used to expel nitrous oxide from a cartridge or container.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charging bottle, which means a device that may be used to expel nitrous oxide from a cartridge or canister.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A whip-it, which means a device that may be used to expel nitrous oxide.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tank.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A balloon.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hose or tube.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 2-liter-type soda bottle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duct tape.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-30; s. 6, ch. 2000-320; s. 15, ch. 2000-360.</History></Section>