<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0893.147" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use, possession, manufacture, delivery, transportation, or advertisement of drug paraphernalia.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OR POSSESSION OF DRUG PARAPHERNALIA.<EmDash />It is unlawful for any person to use, or to possess with intent to use, drug paraphernalia:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To plant, propagate, cultivate, grow, harvest, manufacture, compound, convert, produce, process, prepare, test, analyze, pack, repack, store, contain, or conceal a controlled substance in violation of this chapter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To inject, ingest, inhale, or otherwise introduce into the human body a controlled substance in violation of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MANUFACTURE OR DELIVERY OF DRUG PARAPHERNALIA.<EmDash />It is unlawful for any person to deliver, possess with intent to deliver, or manufacture with intent to deliver drug paraphernalia, knowing, or under circumstances where one reasonably should know, that it will be used:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To plant, propagate, cultivate, grow, harvest, manufacture, compound, convert, produce, process, prepare, test, analyze, pack, repack, store, contain, or conceal a controlled substance in violation of this act; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To inject, ingest, inhale, or otherwise introduce into the human body a controlled substance in violation of this act.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DELIVERY OF DRUG PARAPHERNALIA TO A MINOR.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person 18 years of age or over who violates subsection (2) by delivering drug paraphernalia to a person under 18 years of age is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to sell or otherwise deliver hypodermic syringes, needles, or other objects which may be used, are intended for use, or are designed for use in parenterally injecting substances into the human body to any person under 18 years of age, except that hypodermic syringes, needles, or other such objects may be lawfully dispensed to a person under 18 years of age by a licensed practitioner, parent, or legal guardian or by a pharmacist pursuant to a valid prescription for same. Any person who violates the provisions of this paragraph is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TRANSPORTATION OF DRUG PARAPHERNALIA.<EmDash />It is unlawful to use, possess with the intent to use, or manufacture with the intent to use drug paraphernalia, knowing or under circumstances in which one reasonably should know that it will be used to transport:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A controlled substance in violation of this chapter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contraband as defined in s. 932.701(2)(a)1.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any person who violates this subsection commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADVERTISEMENT OF DRUG PARAPHERNALIA.<EmDash />It is unlawful for any person to place in any newspaper, magazine, handbill, or other publication any advertisement, knowing, or under circumstances where one reasonably should know, that the purpose of the advertisement, in whole or in part, is to promote the sale of objects designed or intended for use as drug paraphernalia. Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 80-30; s. 1, ch. 81-149; s. 54, ch. 83-215; s. 1, ch. 85-8; s. 223, ch. 91-224; s. 16, ch. 2000-360.</History></Section>