<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0933.19" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Searches and seizures of vehicles carrying contraband or illegal intoxicating liquors or merchandise.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of the opinion rendered by the Supreme Court of the United States on March 2, 1925, in that certain cause wherein George Carroll and John Kiro were plaintiffs in error and the United States was defendant in error, reported in 267 United States Reports, beginning at page 132, relative to searches and seizures of vehicles carrying contraband or illegal intoxicating liquors or merchandise, and construing the Fourth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, are adopted as the statute law of the state applicable to searches and seizures under s. 12, Art. I of the State Constitution, when searches and seizures shall be made by any duly authorized and constituted bonded officer of this state exercising police authority in the enforcement of any law of the state relative to the unlawful transportation or hauling of intoxicating liquors or other contraband or illegal drugs or merchandise prohibited or made unlawful or contraband by the laws of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The same rules as to admissibility of evidence and liability of officers for illegal or unreasonable searches and seizures as were laid down in said case by the Supreme Court of the United States shall apply to and govern the rights, duties and liabilities of officers and citizens in the state under the like provisions of the Florida Constitution relating to searches and seizures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All points of law decided in the aforesaid case relating to the construction or interpretation of the provisions of the Constitution of the United States relative to searches and seizures of vehicles carrying contraband or illegal intoxicating liquors or merchandise shall be taken to be the law of the state enacted by the Legislature to govern and control such subject.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 12257, 1927; CGL 7644; s. 2, ch. 69-216.</History></Section>