<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0100.321" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Test suit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any taxpayer of the county, district, or municipality wherein bonds are declared to have been authorized, shall have the right to test the legality of the referendum and of the declaration of the result thereof, by an action in the circuit court of the county in which the referendum was held. The action shall be brought against the county commissioners in the case of a county or district referendum, or against the governing authority of the municipality in the case of a municipal referendum. In case any such referendum or the declaration of results thereof shall be adjudged to be illegal and void in any such suit, the judgment shall have the effect of nullifying the referendum. No suit shall be brought to test the validity of any bond referendum unless the suit shall be instituted within 60 days after the declaration of the results of the referendum. In the event proceedings shall be filed in any court to validate the bonds, which have been voted for, then any such taxpayer shall be bound to intervene in such validation suit and contest the validity of the holding of the referendum or the declaration of the results thereof, in which event the exclusive jurisdiction to determine the legality of such referendum or the declaration of the results thereof shall be vested in the court hearing and determining said validation proceedings. If said bonds in the validation proceedings shall be held valid on final hearing or an intervention by the taxpayer shall be interposed and held not to have been sustained, then the judgment in said validation proceedings shall be final and conclusive as to the legality and validity of the referendum and of the declaration of the results thereof, and no separate suit to test the same shall be thereafter permissible.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 14715, 1931; CGL 1936 Supp. 457(16); s. 4, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 12, ch. 77-175.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 103.18.</Text></Note></Section>