<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0100.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of special election to fill any vacancy in office.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a special election is required to fill any vacancy in office, the Governor, after consultation with the Secretary of State, shall issue an order declaring on what day the election shall be held and deliver the order to the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State shall prepare a notice stating what offices are to be filled in the special election, the dates set for the special primary election and the special election, the dates fixed for qualifying for office, the dates fixed for qualifying by the petition process pursuant to s. 99.095, and the dates fixed for filing campaign expense statements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deliver a copy of such notice to the supervisor of elections of each county in which the special election is to be held. The supervisor shall have the notice published two times in a newspaper of general circulation in the county at least 10 days prior to the first day set for qualifying for office. If such a newspaper is not published within the period set forth, the supervisor shall post at least five copies of the notice in conspicuous places in the county not less than 10 days prior to the first date set for qualifying.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 3879, 1889; RS 160; s. 7, ch. 4328, 1895; GS 177; RGS 221; CGL 256; s. 3, ch. 25383, 1949; s. 1, ch. 26329, 1949; s. 4, ch. 26870, 1951; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 12, ch. 77-175; s. 14, ch. 90-315; s. 13, ch. 99-318; s. 21, ch. 2005-277; s. 14, ch. 2005-286.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 98.10.</Text></Note></Section>