<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0100.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Officers chosen at general election.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State senators shall be elected for terms of 4 years, those from odd-numbered districts in each year the number of which is a multiple of 4 and those from even-numbered districts in each even-numbered year the number of which is not a multiple of 4. Members of the House of Representatives shall be elected for terms of 2 years in each even-numbered year. In each county, a clerk of the circuit court, sheriff, superintendent of schools, property appraiser, and tax collector shall be chosen by the qualified electors at the general election in each year the number of which is a multiple of 4. The Governor and the administrative officers of the executive branch of the state shall be elected for terms of 4 years in each even-numbered year the number of which is not a multiple of 4. The terms of state offices other than the terms of members of the Legislature shall begin on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January after said election. The term of office of each member of the Legislature shall begin upon election.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county commissioner from an odd-numbered district shall be elected at the general election in each year the number of which is a multiple of 4, for a 4-year term commencing on the second Tuesday following such election, and each county commissioner from an even-numbered district shall be elected at the general election in each even-numbered year the number of which is not a multiple of 4, for a 4-year term commencing on the second Tuesday following such election. A county commissioner is “elected” for purposes of this paragraph on the date that the county canvassing board certifies the results of the election pursuant to s. 102.151.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), the governing board of a charter county may provide by ordinance, to be approved by referendum, that the terms of its members shall commence on a date later than the second Tuesday following general elections, but in any case the date of commencement shall be uniform for all members and shall be no later than the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January following each member’s election.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School board members shall be elected at a general election for terms of 4 years. The term of office of a school board member and of a superintendent of schools shall begin on the second Tuesday following the general election in which such member or superintendent is elected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In each school district which has five school board members, the terms shall be arranged so that three members are elected at one general election and two members elected at the next ensuing general election.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of office of each county and each district officer not otherwise provided by law shall commence on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January following his or her election.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 3879, 1889; RS 156; s. 3, ch. 4328, 1895; s. 2, ch. 4537, 1897; GS 172; s. 10, ch. 7838, 1919; RGS 217; CGL 252; s. 4, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 15, ch. 28156, 1953; s. 1, ch. 59-140; s. 1, ch. 63-479; s. 1, ch. 67-98; s. 1, ch. 67-510; s. 11, ch. 69-216; s. 1, ch. 69-300; (4) formerly s. 14, Art. XVIII of the Constitution of 1885, as amended; converted to statutory law by s. 10, Art. XII of the Constitution as revised in 1968; s. 1, ch. 73-47; s. 18, ch. 73-334; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 12, ch. 77-175; s. 1, ch. 78-321; s. 21, ch. 79-164; s. 14, ch. 85-226; s. 1, ch. 88-85; s. 14, ch. 89-338; s. 545, ch. 95-147; s. 11, ch. 98-129; s. 20, ch. 2007-30.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 98.05.</Text></Note></Section>