<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0563.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Malt beverages; exclusive sales territories.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No distributor shall sell or deliver any brand or brands of malt beverages in this state to any retail vendor whose place of business is outside of the distributor’s restricted exclusive sales territory for such products. The restricted exclusive sales territory shall be mutually agreed upon by the manufacturer or importer and each distributor, and shall be embodied in a formal written agreement between the manufacturer or importer and each distributor, which agreement shall designate the specified brand or brands for which the territory is granted and set forth the exact geographical area of the territory. Where a manufacturer or importer sells several brands, the agreement may apply to all brands sold by the manufacturer or importer or may apply to one brand or several brands so long as each brand is covered by an exclusive territorial agreement. No manufacturer or importer shall provide by such written agreement for the distribution of a brand to more than one distributor for all or any part of the designated territory. All such agreements shall be filed with the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a prima facie showing of a violation of this section, the division, on its own motion or on complaint of a manufacturer or distributor, may pursue appropriate administrative remedies provided by law, including the revocation or suspension of licenses, the imposition of fines or any combination of the foregoing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision of any written agreement required by this section shall expressly, by implication, or in its own operation establish or maintain the resale price of any brand or brands of beer sold by the malt beverage distributor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 88-308.</History></Section>