<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.9126" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reports by liability insurers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer transacting commercial multiperil, products liability, commercial automobile liability, private passenger automobile liability, or other line of liability insurance shall maintain information as specified in this section. Such information shall be maintained for each line of insurance and for direct Florida business only. The office may conduct a sampling of claims or actions for damages for personal injury or property damage claimed to have been caused by error, omission, or negligence of insureds if the claim resulted in:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final judgment in any amount.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A settlement in any amount.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final disposition not resulting in payment on behalf of the insured.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request of the office, an insurer shall, within 60 days, submit to the office a report that contains:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final judgment in any amount.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A settlement in any amount.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final disposition not resulting in payment on behalf of the insured.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reports required by subsection (2) shall contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and class or line of coverage of the insured.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insured’s policy number.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of the occurrence which created the claim.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the claim was reported to the insurer or self-insurer.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of suit, if filed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The claimant’s name, age, and sex; however, the name of the claimant is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total number and names of all defendants involved in the claim.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims settled after a suit was filed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims paid based on a judgment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Judgments appealed by the insurer, together with the total results of such appeals.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and amount of final judgment or settlement, if any, including the itemization of the verdict, together with a copy of the settlement or final judgment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a settlement, such information as the office may require with regard to the injured person’s incurred and anticipated medical expense, wage loss, and other expenses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The loss adjustment expense paid to defense counsel and other allocated loss adjustment expense paid.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date and reason for final disposition, if no judgment or settlement.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary of the occurrence which created the claim, which shall include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the facility, business, or institution, if any, and the location within the facility, business, or institution at which the injury occurred.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the principal injury giving rise to the claim.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The safety management steps that have been taken by the insured to make similar occurrences or injuries less likely in the future.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information required by the office to analyze and evaluate the nature, causes, location, cost, and damages involved in liability cases.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no liability on the part of, and no cause of action of any nature shall arise against, any insurer reporting hereunder or its agents or employees or the office or its employees for any action taken by them pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 42, ch. 86-160; s. 2, ch. 87-50; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 10, ch. 93-289; s. 384, ch. 96-406; s. 91, ch. 98-199; s. 1228, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>