<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6571" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Guaranteed renewability of coverage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an insurer that issues a group health insurance policy must renew or continue in force such coverage at the option of the policyholder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may nonrenew or discontinue a group health insurance policy based only on one or more of the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policyholder has failed to pay premiums or contributions in accordance with the terms of the policy or the insurer has not received timely premium payments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policyholder has performed an act or practice that constitutes fraud or made an intentional misrepresentation of material fact under the terms of the policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policyholder has failed to comply with a material provision of the plan which relates to rules for employer contributions or group participation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer is ceasing to offer a particular type of coverage in a market in accordance with subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an insurer that offers health insurance coverage through a network plan, there is no longer any enrollee in connection with such plan who lives, resides, or works in the service area of the insurer or in the area in which the insurer is authorized to do business and, in the case of the small-group market, the insurer would deny enrollment with respect to such plan under s. 627.6699(5)(i).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of health insurance coverage that is made available only through one or more bona fide associations as defined in subsection (5) or through one or more small employer health alliances as described in s. 627.654(1)(b), the membership of an employer in the association or in the small employer health alliance, on the basis of which the coverage is provided, ceases, but only if such coverage is terminated under this paragraph uniformly without regard to any health-status-related factor that relates to any covered individuals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may discontinue offering a particular policy form of group health insurance coverage offered in the small-group market or large-group market only if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer provides notice to each policyholder provided coverage of this form in such market, and to participants and beneficiaries covered under such coverage, of such discontinuation at least 90 days prior to the date of the nonrenewal of such coverage;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer offers to each policyholder provided coverage of this form in such market the option to purchase all, or in the case of the large-group market, any other health insurance coverage currently being offered by the insurer in such market; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In exercising the option to discontinue coverage of this form and in offering the option of coverage under subparagraph 2., the insurer acts uniformly without regard to the claims experience of those policyholders or any health-status-related factor that relates to any participants or beneficiaries covered or new participants or beneficiaries who may become eligible for such coverage.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case in which an insurer elects to discontinue offering all health insurance coverage in the small-group market or the large-group market, or both, in this state, health insurance coverage may be discontinued by the insurer only if:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer provides notice to the office and to each policyholder, and participants and beneficiaries covered under such coverage, of such discontinuation at least 180 days prior to the date of the nonrenewal of such coverage; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health insurance issued or delivered for issuance in this state in such market is discontinued and coverage under such health insurance coverage in such market is not renewed.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a discontinuation under subparagraph 1. in a market, the insurer may not provide for the issuance of any health insurance coverage in the market in this state during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the discontinuation of the last insurance coverage not renewed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mailing to one household constitutes a mailing to all covered persons residing in that household. A separate mailing is required for each separate household.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of coverage renewal, an insurer may modify the health insurance coverage for a product offered:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the large-group market; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the small-group market if, for coverage that is available in such market other than only through one or more bona fide associations as defined in subsection (5) or through one or more small employer health alliances as described in s. 627.654(1)(b), such modification is consistent with s. 627.6699 and effective on a uniform basis among group health plans with that product.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “bona fide association” means an association that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been actively in existence for at least 5 years;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been formed and maintained in good faith for purposes other than obtaining insurance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not condition membership in the association on any health-status-related factor that relates to an individual, including an employee of an employer or a dependent of an employee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes health insurance coverage offered through the association available to all members regardless of any health-status-related factor that relates to such members or individuals eligible for coverage through a member; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not make health insurance coverage offered through the association available other than in connection with a member of the association.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In applying this section in the case of health insurance coverage that is made available by an insurer in the small-group market or large-group market to employers only through one or more associations or through one or more small employer health alliances as described in s. 627.654(1)(b), a reference to “policyholder” is deemed, with respect to coverage provided to an employer member of the association, to include a reference to such employer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 97-179; s. 7, ch. 98-159; s. 36, ch. 2000-256; s. 3, ch. 2000-296; s. 1166, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 34(2), ch. 97-179, provides that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Except as provided in section 627.6561(9), (10), and (11), and section 641.31071(10), (11), and (12), Florida Statutes, in the case of a group health plan or group health insurance contract maintained pursuant to one or more collective bargaining agreements between employee representatives and one or more employers which is ratified before this act becomes a law, sections 627.6561, 627.65615, 627.65625, 627.6571, 627.6699, 641.31071, 641.31072, 641.31073, and 641.31074, Florida Statutes, except for section 627.6561(8)(b), Florida Statutes, as amended or created by this act, apply to policies or contracts with plan years that begin on or after the later of:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) The date on which the last of any collective bargaining agreement that relates to the plan terminates, determined without regard to any extension thereof, which is agreed to after the date this act becomes a law; or</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) July 1, 1997.”</Text></Note></Section>