<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.331" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recording and reporting of loss, expense, and claims experience; rating information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may promulgate rules and statistical plans which shall thereafter be used by each insurer in the recording and reporting of its loss, expense, and claims experience, in order that the experience of all insurers may be made available at least annually in such form and detail as may be necessary to aid the office in determining whether the insurer’s activities comply with the applicable standards of this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In promulgating such rules and plans, the commission shall give due consideration to the rating systems in use in this state and, in order that such rules and plans may be as uniform as is practicable among the several states, to the rules and to the form of the plans used for such rating systems in other states. No insurer shall be required to record or report its loss experience on a classification basis that is inconsistent with the rating system used by it, except for motor vehicle insurance as otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may designate one or more rating organizations or other agencies to assist it in gathering such experience and making compilations thereof; and such compilations shall be made available, subject to reasonable rules adopted by the commission, to insurers and rating organizations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 443, ch. 59-205; s. 19, ch. 67-9; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-75; s. 1, ch. 70-321; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 1, ch. 73-153; s. 1, ch. 74-320; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 27, ch. 77-468; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 350, 357, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 49, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 10, ch. 83-288; s. 1, ch. 84-352; s. 12, ch. 86-160; s. 22, ch. 89-360; s. 1, ch. 89-528; ss. 11, 35, ch. 90-119; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1100, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>