<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.983" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No insurer shall participate in any consolidation unless it complies with the following requirements:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offer of new coverage shall be made on a timely basis as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a consolidation conducted in connection with a loan transfer, the offer of new coverage to the prospective insured must be made as soon as reasonably possible. If the offer of new coverage is not made within 30 days after the loan transfer, or at least 30 days prior to the proposed effective date of the new coverage, the insurer shall notify the debtor, in writing, that she or he has the right to an unconditional refund of all premiums paid for the new coverage if she or he exercises that right, in writing, within 30 days after the date of the notification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all other consolidations, the offer of new coverage shall be made to the prospective insured at least 30 days prior to the proposed effective date of the new coverage. If the offer is not made at least 30 days in advance, the insurer shall notify the debtor, in writing, that she or he has the right to an unconditional refund of all premiums paid for the new coverage provided she or he exercises that right, in writing, within 30 days from the date of the notification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A group certificate or individual policy shall be delivered to each debtor insured under the new plan. In addition to all other applicable requirements of the Florida Insurance Code, the group certificate or individual policy shall include the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name or names of the single or joint insureds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of the insured mortgage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of insurance under the new plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The premium for the new coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective date of the new coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary for the new coverage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No group certificate or individual policy evidencing the new coverage shall include a contestability clause or, in the case of life insurance, a provision excluding suicide.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All group life insurance certificates issued in connection with any consolidation shall include a conversion privilege permitting an insured to convert, without evidence of insurability, to an individual policy of decreasing term insurance within 30 days after the date the insured’s group coverage is terminated for any reason other than the nonpayment of premiums. The initial amount of coverage under the individual policy shall be an amount equal to the amount of coverage terminated under the group policy and shall decrease over a term that corresponds with the scheduled term of the insured’s mortgage loan. The premium for the individual policy shall be the same premium the insured was paying under the group policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 627.984, the new coverage shall be effectuated for the prospective insured only after the new insurer receives an application which has been signed by the prospective insured.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 627.984, the new insurer must calculate premiums for the new coverage on the basis of its own rates, the prospective insured’s then-attained age, if applicable, and the amount of insurance offered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for consolidations conducted in connection with a loan transfer, the new insurer shall send written notice to the old insurer of its intent to conduct a consolidation at least 30 days in advance of the effective date of the consolidation. Such notice may be made on behalf of the new insurer by the financial institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurers shall maintain a list of certificateholders insured under each group mortgage insurance plan, which list shall be provided upon request to the servicer who collects premiums for the plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 90-149; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 378, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>