<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.917" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Uniform risk classification reporting system for motor vehicle insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall establish and promulgate a uniform statewide reporting system to classify risks for the purpose of evaluating rates and premiums and for the purpose of evaluating competition and the availability of motor vehicle insurance in the voluntary market. The system shall divide risks into classifications based upon variations in hazards or expenses of claims. The classification system may include any difference among risks that can be demonstrated to have a probable effect upon losses or expenses, but in no event shall the system adopted by the commission discriminate among risks based upon race, creed, color, or national origin. The classification system shall divide the state into geographical areas based upon hazards or expenses of claims.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer shall annually file with the office a statement reflecting the total number of persons insured by the insurer within each classification by coverage, the premium volume in each classification by coverage, the paid and reserved losses incurred in each classification by coverage, the number of cancellations or nonrenewals by the insurer during the period, and the number of new insureds during the period. This statement shall be filed annually on a date determined by the commission and shall cover a 1-year period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules to require each insurer to report its loss and expense experience by classification, in such detail and as often as may be necessary to aid the office in determining the reasonableness of rates, the validity of loss projections, and the validity of the risk classification system.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 78-374; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 357, 623, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1232, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 627.343.</Text></Note></Section>