<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.9404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Long-term care insurance policy” means any insurance policy or rider advertised, marketed, offered, or designed to provide coverage on an expense-incurred, indemnity, prepaid, or other basis for one or more necessary or medically necessary diagnostic, preventive, therapeutic, curing, treating, mitigating, rehabilitative, maintenance, or personal care services provided in a setting other than an acute care unit of a hospital. Long-term care insurance shall not include any insurance policy which is offered primarily to provide basic Medicare supplement coverage, basic hospital expense coverage, basic medical-surgical expense coverage, hospital confinement indemnity coverage, major medical expense coverage, disability income protection coverage, accident only coverage, specified disease or specified accident coverage, or limited health insurance coverage not otherwise defined as long-term care insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicant” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an individual long-term care insurance policy, the person who seeks to contract for benefits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a group long-term care insurance policy, the proposed certificateholder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate” means any certificate issued under a group long-term care insurance policy, which policy has been delivered or issued for delivery in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Chronically ill” means certified by a licensed health care practitioner as:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to perform, without substantial assistance from another individual, at least two activities of daily living for a period of at least 90 days due to a loss of functional capacity; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring substantial supervision for protection from threats to health and safety due to severe cognitive impairment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cognitive impairment” means a deficiency in a person’s short-term or long-term memory, orientation as to person, place, and time, deductive or abstract reasoning, or judgment as it relates to safety awareness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed health care practitioner” means any physician, nurse licensed under part I of chapter 464, or psychotherapist licensed under chapter 490 or chapter 491, or any individual who meets any requirements prescribed by rule by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited benefit policy” means any long-term care insurance policy that limits coverage to care in a nursing home or to one or more lower levels of care required or authorized to be provided by this part or by commission rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Maintenance or personal care services” means any care the primary purpose of which is the provision of needed assistance with any of the disabilities as a result of which the individual is a chronically ill individual, including the protection from threats to health and safety due to severe cognitive impairment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Policy” means any policy, contract, subscriber agreement, rider, or endorsement delivered or issued for delivery in this state by any of the entities specified in s. 627.9403.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified limited benefit insurance policy” means an accident and health insurance contract as defined in s. 7702B of the Internal Revenue Code and all applicable sections of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified long-term care services” means necessary diagnostic, preventive, curing, treating, mitigating, and rehabilitative services, and maintenance or personal care services which are required by a chronically ill individual and are provided pursuant to a plan of care prescribed by a licensed health care practitioner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified long-term care insurance policy” means an accident and health insurance contract as defined in s. 7702B of the Internal Revenue Code and all applicable sections of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 88-57; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 2, ch. 96-275; s. 16, ch. 97-179; s. 17, ch. 98-159; s. 141, ch. 2000-318; s. 1237, ch. 2003-261; s. 8, ch. 2006-254.</History></Section>