<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.94073" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of cancellation; grace period.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A long-term care policy shall provide that the insured is entitled to a grace period of not less than 30 days, within which payment of any premium after the first may be made. The insurer may require payment of an interest charge not in excess of 8 percent per year for the number of days elapsing before the payment of the premium, during which period the policy shall continue in force. If the policy becomes a claim during the grace period before the overdue premium is paid, the amount of such premium or premiums with interest not in excess of 8 percent per year may be deducted in any settlement under the policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A long-term care policy may not be canceled for nonpayment of premium unless, after expiration of the grace period in subsection (1), and at least 30 days prior to the effective date of such cancellation, the insurer has mailed a notification of possible lapse in coverage to the policyholder and to a specified secondary addressee if such addressee has been designated in writing by name and address by the policyholder. For policies issued or renewed on or after October 1, 1996, the insurer shall notify the policyholder, at least once annually, of the right to designate a secondary addressee. The applicant has the right to designate at least one person who is to receive the notice of termination, in addition to the insured. Designation shall not constitute acceptance of any liability on the third party for services provided to the insured. The form used for the written designation must provide space clearly designated for listing at least one person. The form must also inform the policyholder to update any change made to the address of the secondary addressee. The designation shall include each person’s full name and home address. In the case of an applicant who elects not to designate an additional person, the waiver shall state: “Protection against unintended lapse.<EmDash />I understand that I have the right to designate at least one person other than myself to receive notice of lapse or termination of this long-term care or limited benefit insurance policy for nonpayment of premium. I understand that notice will not be given until 30 days after a premium is due and unpaid. I elect NOT to designate any person to receive such notice.” Notice of possible lapse in coverage due to nonpayment of premium shall be given by United States Postal Service proof of mailing or certified or registered mail to the policyholder and secondary designee at the address shown in the policy or the last known address provided to the insurer. Notice may not be given until 30 days after a premium is due and unpaid. Notice shall be deemed to have been given as of 5 days after the date of mailing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a policy is canceled due to nonpayment of premium, the policyholder is entitled to have the policy reinstated if, within a period of not less than 5 months after the date of cancellation, the policyholder or any secondary addressee designated pursuant to subsection (2) demonstrates that the failure to pay the premium when due was unintentional and due to the policyholder’s cognitive impairment, loss of functional capacity, or continuous confinement in a hospital, skilled nursing facility, or assisted living facility for a period in excess of 60 days. Policy reinstatement shall be subject to payment of overdue premiums. The standard of proof of cognitive impairment or loss of functional capacity shall not be more stringent than the benefit eligibility criteria for cognitive impairment or the loss of functional capacity, if any, contained in the policy and certificate. The insurer may require payment of an interest charge not in excess of 8 percent per year for the number of days elapsing before the payment of the premium, during which period the policy shall continue in force if the demonstration of cognitive impairment is made. If the policy becomes a claim during the 180-day period before the overdue premium is paid, the amount of the premium or premiums with interest not in excess of 8 percent per year may be deducted in any settlement under the policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the policyholder or certificateholder pays premium for a long-term care insurance policy or certificate policy through a payroll or pension deduction plan, the requirements in subsection (2) need not be met until 60 days after the policyholder or certificateholder is no longer on such a payment plan. The application or enrollment form for such policies or certificates shall clearly indicate the payment plan selected by the applicant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 96-275; s. 20, ch. 97-179; s. 19, ch. 98-159; s. 20, ch. 2008-220.</History></Section>