<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.574" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Liability of succeeding insurer on replacement of group policy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who is eligible for coverage in accordance with the succeeding insurer’s plan of benefits shall be covered by that insurer’s plan of benefits unless such coverage would result in duplication of benefits payable under the prior insurer’s plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person not covered under the succeeding insurer’s plan of benefits in accordance with subsection (1) must be covered by the succeeding insurer in accordance with the following provisions if such individual was validly covered, including benefit extensions, under the prior plan on the date of discontinuance of the prior plan and if such individual is a member of the class or classes of individuals eligible for coverage under the succeeding insurer’s plan.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum level of benefits to be provided by the succeeding insurer shall be the applicable level of benefits of the prior insurer’s plan reduced by any benefits payable by the prior plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage must be provided by the succeeding insurer until at least the earliest of the following dates:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the individual becomes eligible under the succeeding insurer’s plan as described in subsection (1).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the individual’s coverage would terminate in accordance with the succeeding insurer’s plan provisions applicable to individual termination of coverage, for example, at termination of employment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an individual was totally disabled immediately prior to the date the succeeding insurer’s coverage became effective and the policy of the prior insurer did not conform to s. 627.575, the date of the end of any period of extension or accrued liability which would have been required of the prior insurer by s. 627.575, had s. 627.575 been applicable.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 79-179; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 446, 448, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 100, ch. 83-216; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>