<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.94071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimum standards for home health care benefits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A long-term care insurance policy, certificate, or rider that contains a home health care benefit must meet or exceed the minimum standards specified in this section. The policy, certificate, or rider may not exclude benefits by any of the following means:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing that home health care cannot be covered unless the insured or claimant would, without the home health care, require skilled care in a skilled nursing facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring that the insured or claimant first or simultaneously receive nursing or therapeutic services in a home setting or community setting before home health care services are covered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limiting eligible services to services provided by registered nurses or licensed practical nurses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring that a nurse or therapist provide services covered by the policy that can be provided by a home health aide or by another licensed or certified home care worker acting within the scope of his or her license or certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring that a licensed home health agency provide services covered by the policy that can be provided by a nurse registry licensed under chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Excluding coverage for personal care services provided by a home health aide.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring that the provision of home health care services be at a level of certification of licensure greater than that required by the eligible service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring that the insured/claimant have an acute condition before home health care services are covered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limiting benefits to services provided by Medicare-certified agencies or providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Excluding coverage for adult day care services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 147, ch. 92-33; s. 3, ch. 96-275; s. 18, ch. 97-179.</History></Section>