<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.7275" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Motor vehicle liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor vehicle insurance policy providing personal injury protection as set forth in s. 627.736 may not be delivered or issued for delivery in this state with respect to any specifically insured or identified motor vehicle registered or principally garaged in this state unless the policy also provides coverage for property damage liability as required by s. 324.022.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurers writing motor vehicle insurance in this state shall make available, subject to the insurers’ usual underwriting restrictions:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage under policies as described in subsection (1) to any applicant for private passenger motor vehicle insurance coverage who is seeking the coverage in order to reinstate the applicant’s driving privileges in this state when the driving privileges were revoked or suspended pursuant to s. 316.646 or s. 324.0221 due to the failure of the applicant to maintain required security.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage under policies as described in subsection (1), which also provides liability coverage for bodily injury, death, and property damage arising out of the ownership, maintenance, or use of the motor vehicle in an amount not less than the limits described in s. 324.021(7) and conforms to the requirements of s. 324.151, to any applicant for private passenger motor vehicle insurance coverage who is seeking the coverage in order to reinstate the applicant’s driving privileges in this state after such privileges were revoked or suspended under s. 316.193 or s. 322.26(2) for driving under the influence.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policies described in paragraph (a) shall be issued for a period of at least 6 months and as to the minimum coverages required under this section shall not be cancelable by the insured for any reason or by the insurer after a period not to exceed 30 days during which the insurer must complete underwriting of the policy. After the insurer has completed underwriting the policy within the 30-day period, the insurer shall notify the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles that the policy is in full force and effect and the policy shall not be cancelable for the remainder of the policy period. A premium shall be collected and coverage shall be in effect for the 30-day period during which the insurer is completing the underwriting of the policy whether or not the person’s driver license, motor vehicle tag, and motor vehicle registration are in effect. Once the noncancelable provisions of the policy become effective, the coverage or risk shall not be changed during the policy period and the premium shall be nonrefundable. If, during the pendency of the 2-year proof of insurance period required under s. 324.0221 or during the 3-year proof of financial responsibility required under s. 324.131, whichever is applicable, the insured obtains additional coverage or coverage for an additional risk or changes territories, the insured must obtain a new 6-month noncancelable policy in accordance with the provisions of this section. However, if the insured must obtain a new 6-month policy and obtains the policy from the same insurer, the policyholder shall receive credit on the new policy for any premium paid on the previously issued policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection controls to the extent of any conflict with any other section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer issuing a policy subject to this section may cancel the policy if, during the policy term, the named insured or any other operator, who resides in the same household or customarily operates an automobile insured under the policy, has his or her driver’s license suspended or revoked.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this subsection requires an insurer to offer a policy of insurance to an applicant if such offer would be inconsistent with the insurer’s underwriting guidelines and procedures.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 88-370; s. 3, ch. 89-238; s. 1, ch. 89-296; s. 2, ch. 91-106; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 29, ch. 95-211; s. 359, ch. 97-102; s. 90, ch. 98-199; s. 1191, ch. 2003-261; s. 3, ch. 2005-72; s. 6, ch. 2007-324.</History></Section>