<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.677" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Credit life insurance” means insurance on the life of a debtor pursuant to or in connection with a specific loan or other credit transaction. There are three recognized forms:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Group credit life insurance” means insurance which is subject to the provisions of s. 627.553.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Franchise credit life insurance” means insurance by which a master policy is issued to and in favor of a creditor and under which debtors are insured at the option of the creditor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Individual credit life insurance” means individual insurance upon the life of an individual debtor in favor of a creditor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Credit disability insurance” means insurance under which a borrower of money or a purchaser or a lessee of goods is insured in connection with a specific loan or credit transaction against loss of time resulting from accident or sickness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Creditor agent” means any lending or financing institution or other creditor, or a representative of such an institution or creditor, which writes credit life or disability insurance on the life or health of a debtor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consolidation” means any transaction in which a financial institution or servicer makes its premium collection services available to its debtors in connection with a particular insurer’s (“new insurer”) offer of credit insurance, which offer is made to debtors who, immediately prior to the offer, had credit insurance with another insurer (“old insurer”) and were paying premiums for that insurance on a monthly or other regular basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Financial institution” or “servicer” means any entity or organization that services loans or credit obligations by collecting and accounting for payments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Loan transfer” means a transaction in which the servicing of a block of loans or credit obligations is transferred from one servicer to another.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“New coverage” or “new plan” means the credit insurance coverage or credit insurance plan for which the financial institution collects premiums beginning on the effective date of consolidation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Old coverage” or “old plan” means the credit insurance coverage or credit insurance plan the insured debtor had or participated in immediately prior to the consolidation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 596, ch. 59-205; s. 19, ch. 61-530; s. 1, ch. 73-363; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 6, 7, ch. 80-387; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 528, 537, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; ss. 72, 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>