<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.406" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power to contract; purchase of insurance by or for minor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person of competent legal capacity may contract for insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any minor of the age of 15 years or more, as determined by the nearest birthday, may, notwithstanding his or her minority, contract for annuities or for insurance on his or her own life, body, health, property, liabilities, or other interests or on the person of another in whom the minor has an insurable interest. Such a minor shall, notwithstanding such minority, be deemed competent to exercise all rights and powers with respect to or under any contract for annuity or for insurance upon his or her own life, body, or health or any contract such minor effected on his or her own property, liabilities, or other interests or on the person of another, as might be exercised by a person of full legal age. Such minor may at any time surrender his or her interest in any such contracts and give a valid discharge for any benefits accruing or money payable thereunder. Such a minor shall not, by reason of his or her minority, be entitled to rescind, avoid, or repudiate the contract, nor to rescind, avoid, or repudiate any exercise of a right or privilege thereunder, except that such a minor, not otherwise emancipated, shall not be bound by any unperformed agreement to pay, by promissory note or otherwise, any premium on any such annuity or insurance contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any minor mentioned in subsection (2) is possessed of an estate that is being administered by a guardian or curator, no such contract shall be binding upon such estate as to payment of premiums, except as and when consented to by the guardian or curator and approved by the probate court of the county in which the administration of the estate is pending; and such consent and approval shall be required as to each premium payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any annuity contract or policy of life or health insurance procured by or for a minor under subsection (2) shall be made payable either to the minor or his or her estate or to a person having an insurable interest in the life of such minor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 455, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 360, 377, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 323, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>