<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.828" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in ss. 627.901 and 627.902, no person shall engage in the business of a premium finance company unless licensed by the office. Every premium finance company licensed under the provisions of this part shall maintain at all times a net worth of $35,000. However, in lieu of having a net worth of $35,000, a premium finance company that has a net worth of $10,000 may file a surety bond with the office or other acceptable collateral with the department as approved by the office or department in the amount of $35,000, which bond or collateral must be maintained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application for a license shall be in writing and in the form prescribed by the commission. Every applicant shall provide evidence of a net worth of $35,000 attested by two officers of the company, or a $35,000 surety bond and evidence of a net worth of $10,000 attested by two officers of the company. Assets to be used in computing the required net worth shall be determined by rules adopted by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each premium finance company authorized under the provisions of this part shall maintain at all times an errors and omissions insurance policy of no less than $500,000 covering the acts of its officers, employees, and agents. The policy may contain reasonable deductibles not to exceed 2 percent of the policy limits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A premium finance company with an unencumbered net worth of at least $15 million may self-insure the errors and omissions coverage if it meets the requirements of this paragraph.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To qualify as a self-insurer the premium finance company must:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have and maintain an unencumbered net worth of $15 million, which shall be determined based on assets permissible for insurers pursuant to ss. 625.012 and 625.031;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually demonstrate as part of its annual report, to the satisfaction of the department, that the net-worth requirement is being met; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtain, as a part of its annual application for licensure as a premium finance company, a certificate of self-insurance from the office to be renewed annually.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the office finds that the premium finance company:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not maintaining at all times an unencumbered net worth of at least $15 million; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not, in good faith, covering the errors and omissions of its officers, employees and agents,</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the office shall, in addition to other penalties under this code, revoke or suspend the certificate of self-insurance, and the premium finance company shall be subject to the requirements of paragraph (a).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may adopt rules necessary to administer this subsection, including rules prescribing the necessary forms.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A single license shall entitle the holder to operate more than one office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of filing an application for a license, the applicant shall pay to the office the license fee and, upon original application or upon application subsequent to denial of application, or revocation, suspension or surrender of a license, an investigation fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such license shall state the name and address of the licensee, and a copy shall be kept conspicuously posted in each office of the licensee and shall not be transferable or assignable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to moving an existing office to another location, a licensee shall notify the office in writing of its intention to do so.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-16; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 69-197; s. 1, ch. 72-249; s. 1, ch. 73-134; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 595, 612, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1, ch. 97-204; s. 1215, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 627.0992; consolidation of s. 627.828 and former ss. 627.830 and 627.831.</Text></Note></Section>