<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6743" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards for marketing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every insurer, health care service plan, or other entity marketing Medicare supplement insurance coverage in this state, directly or through its producers, shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish marketing procedures to assure that any comparison of policies by its agents or other producers will be fair and accurate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish marketing procedures to assure excessive insurance is not sold or issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display prominently by type, stamp, or other appropriate means, on the first page of the outline of coverage and policy, the following:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“Notice to buyer: This policy may not cover all of the costs associated with medical care incurred by the buyer during the period of coverage. The buyer is advised to review carefully all policy limitations.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inquire and otherwise make every reasonable effort to identify whether a prospective applicant or enrollee for Medicare supplement insurance already has accident and sickness insurance and the types and amounts of any such insurance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every insurer or entity marketing Medicare supplement insurance shall establish auditable procedures for verifying compliance with this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the practices prohibited in s. 626.9541, the following acts and practices are prohibited:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly making any misleading representation or incomplete or fraudulent comparison of any insurance policies or insurers for the purpose of inducing, or tending to induce, any person to lapse, forfeit, surrender, terminate, retain, pledge, assign, borrow on, or convert any insurance policy or to take out a policy of insurance with another insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employing any method of marketing having the effect of or tending to induce the purchase of insurance through force, fright, threat whether explicit or implied, or undue pressure to purchase or recommend the purchase of insurance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making use directly or indirectly of any method of marketing which fails to disclose in a conspicuous manner that a purpose of the method of marketing is solicitation of insurance and that contact will be made by an insurance agent or insurance company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 90-257; s. 18, ch. 91-20; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>