<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6482" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 627.648-627.6498, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agent” means a person who is licensed to sell health insurance in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Association” means the Florida Comprehensive Health Association created in s. 627.6488.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Case management” means the specific supervision and management of the medical care provided or prescribed for a specific individual, which may include the use of health care providers designated by the plan case manager.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plan case manager” means the person or persons employed by the association to supervise and manage or coordinate with the administrator the supervision and management of the medical care provided or prescribed for a specific individual.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the board of directors of the association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health insurance” means any hospital and medical expense incurred policy, minimum premium plan, stop-loss coverage, health maintenance organization contract, prepaid health clinic contract, multiple-employer welfare arrangement contract, or fraternal benefit society health benefits contract, whether sold as an individual or group policy or contract. The term does not include any policy covering medical payment coverage or personal injury protection coverage in a motor vehicle policy, coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance, or workers’ compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Insurer” means any insurance company authorized to transact health insurance in this state, any insurance company authorized to transact health insurance or casualty insurance in this state that is offering a minimum premium plan or stop-loss coverage for any person or entity providing health care benefits, health maintenance organization authorized to transact business in this state pursuant to part I of chapter 641, prepaid health clinic authorized to transact business in this state pursuant to part II of chapter 641, multiple-employer welfare arrangement authorized to transact business in this state pursuant to ss. 624.436-624.45, or fraternal benefit society providing health benefits to its members as authorized pursuant to chapter 632.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medicare” means coverage under both parts A and B of Title XVIII of the Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. ss. 1395 et seq., as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Minimum premium plan” means an arrangement whereby the expected amount of health care claims is self-funded, but the insurance company assumes the risk that claims will exceed that amount.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician” means a physician licensed under chapter 458; an osteopathic physician licensed under chapter 459; a chiropractic physician licensed under chapter 460; a podiatric physician licensed under chapter 461; or, for purposes of oral surgery only, a dental surgeon licensed under chapter 466.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plan” means the comprehensive health insurance plan adopted by the association or by rule of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Premium” means the entire cost of an insurance plan, including the administrative fee, the risk assumption charge, and, in the instance of a minimum premium plan or stop-loss coverage, the incurred claims whether or not such claims are paid directly by the insurer. “Premium” shall not include a health maintenance organization’s annual earned premium revenue for Medicare and Medicaid contracts for any assessment due for calendar years 1990 and 1991. For assessments due for calendar year 1992 and subsequent years, a health maintenance organization’s annual earned premium revenue for Medicare and Medicaid contracts is subject to assessments unless the office determines that the health maintenance organization has made a reasonable effort to amend its Medicare or Medicaid government contract for 1992 and subsequent years to provide reimbursement for any assessment on Medicare or Medicaid premiums paid by the health maintenance organization and the contract does not provide for such reimbursement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident” means a person who is legally domiciled in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Stop-loss coverage” means an arrangement whereby an insurer insures against the risk that any one claim will exceed a specific dollar amount or that an entire self-insurance plan’s loss will exceed a specific amount.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 496(2nd), 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 1, ch. 83-28; s. 103, ch. 83-216; s. 20, ch. 89-167; ss. 2, 13, 14, ch. 90-334; s. 1, ch. 91-304; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 24, ch. 95-211; s. 59, ch. 97-264; ss. 224, 292, ch. 98-166; s. 1156, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 12, ch. 90-334, provides that “[i]f an [assessment] against any insurer or insurers under the Florida Comprehensive Health Association Act is determined by a court of competent jurisdiction to be unlawful or prohibited, it is the intent of the Legislature that all provisions in ss. 627.648-627.6498 relating to assessments for funding the deficit of the association that were in effect on January 1, 1990 be reenacted and reinstated.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. As amended by s. 1, ch. 91-304. Section 10(2) and (3), ch. 91-304, provides that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) In the event that the application of the assessment to minimum premium plans, stop-loss plans or any other specific type of insurer or health insurance is determined by a court of competent jurisdiction to be unlawful, then the assessment method specified in this act shall continue to apply to all other insurers.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The provisions of section 12 of chapter 90-335 [The reference is apparently in error. Section 12, ch. 90-335, concerns public printing; ch. 90-334 is relevant], Laws of Florida, shall continue in full force and effect, but the provisions of this section shall control to the extent of any conflict.”</Text></Note></Section>