<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6492" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Participation of insurers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition of doing business in this state an insurer shall pay an assessment to the board, in the amount prescribed by this section. For operating losses incurred on July 1, 1991, and thereafter, each insurer shall annually be assessed by the board in the following calendar year a portion of such incurred operating losses of the plan; such portion shall be determined by multiplying such operating losses by a fraction, the numerator of which equals the insurer’s earned premium pertaining to direct writings of health insurance in the state during the calendar year preceding that for which the assessment is levied, and the denominator of which equals the total of all such premiums earned by participating insurers in the state during such calendar year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For operating losses incurred from July 1, 1991, through December 31, 1991, the total of all assessments upon a participating insurer shall not exceed .375 percent of such insurer’s health insurance premiums earned in this state during 1990. For operating losses incurred in 1992 and thereafter, the total of all assessments upon a participating insurer shall not exceed 1 percent of such insurer’s health insurance premium earned in this state during the calendar year preceding the year for which the assessments were levied.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For operating losses incurred from October 1, 1990, through June 30, 1991, the board shall assess each insurer in the amount and manner prescribed by chapter 90-334, Laws of Florida. The maximum assessment against an insurer, as provided in such act, shall apply separately to the claims incurred in 1990 (October 1 through December 31) and the claims incurred in 1991 (January 1 through June 30). For operating losses incurred on January 1, 1991, through June 30, 1991, the maximum assessment against an insurer shall be one-half of the amount of the maximum assessment specified for such insurer in former s. 627.6492(1)(b), 1990 Supplement, as amended by chapter 90-334, Laws of Florida.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rights, title, and interest in the assessment funds collected shall vest in this state. However, all of such funds and interest earned shall be used by the association to pay claims and administrative expenses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If assessments and other receipts by the association, board, or administrator exceed the actual losses and administrative expenses of the plan, the excess shall be held at interest and used by the board to offset future losses. As used in this subsection, the term “future losses” includes reserves for claims incurred but not reported.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer’s assessment shall be determined annually by the association based on annual statements and other reports deemed necessary by the association and filed with it by the insurer. Any deficit incurred under the plan shall be recouped by assessments against participating insurers by the board in the manner provided in subsection (1); and the insurers may recover the assessment in the normal course of their respective businesses without time limitation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 496(2nd), 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 6, ch. 83-28; s. 107, ch. 83-216; s. 2, ch. 89-131; ss. 9, 20, ch. 89-167; ss. 7, 13, 14, ch. 90-334; s. 5, ch. 91-304; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 22, ch. 2004-297.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 12, ch. 90-334, provides that “[i]f an [assessment] against any insurer or insurers under the Florida Comprehensive Health Association Act is determined by a court of competent jurisdiction to be unlawful or prohibited, it is the intent of the Legislature that all provisions in ss. 627.648-627.6498 relating to assessments for funding the deficit of the association that were in effect on January 1, 1990 be reenacted and reinstated.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. As amended by s. 5, ch. 91-304. Section 10(2) and (3), ch. 91-304, provides that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) In the event that the application of the assessment to minimum premium plans, stop-loss plans or any other specific type of insurer or health insurance is determined by a court of competent jurisdiction to be unlawful, then the assessment method specified in this act shall continue to apply to all other insurers.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The provisions of section 12 of chapter 90-335 [The reference is apparently in error. Section 12, ch. 90-335, concerns public printing; ch. 90-334 is relevant], Laws of Florida, shall continue in full force and effect, but the provisions of this section shall control to the extent of any conflict.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 22, ch. 2004-297, provides that “[u]pon implementation, as defined in s. 627.64872(2), Florida Statutes, and as provided in s. 627.64872(20), Florida Statutes, of the Florida Health Insurance Plan created under s. 627.64872, Florida Statutes, sections 627.6488, 627.6489, 627.649, 627.6492, 627.6494, 627.6496, and 627.6498, Florida Statutes, are repealed.”</Text></Note></Section>