<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6494" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assessments; deferment, limitation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 624.509, premiums for coverage issued or reinsured through the association shall, as to the association and participating insurers, be exempt from premium taxation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association, upon approval of the office, may abate or defer, in whole or in part, the assessment of a participating insurer if, in the opinion of the board, payment of the assessment would endanger the ability of the participating insurer to fulfill its contractual obligations. In the event that an assessment against a participating insurer is abated or deferred, in whole or in part, the amount by which such assessment is abated or deferred may be assessed against the other participating insurers in a manner consistent with the basis for assessments set forth in s. 627.6492; and the insurer receiving such abatement or deferment shall remain liable to the association for the deficiency for 4 years.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 496(2nd), 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 20, ch. 89-167; ss. 8, 13, 14, ch. 90-334; s. 6, ch. 91-304; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1161, ch. 2003-261; s. 22, ch. 2004-297.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 12, ch. 90-334, provides that “[i]f an [assessment] against any insurer or insurers under the Florida Comprehensive Health Association Act is determined by a court of competent jurisdiction to be unlawful or prohibited, it is the intent of the Legislature that all provisions in ss. 627.648-627.6498 relating to assessments for funding the deficit of the association that were in effect on January 1, 1990 be reenacted and reinstated.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. As amended by s. 6, ch. 91-304. Section 10(2) and (3), ch. 91-304, provides that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) In the event that the application of the assessment to minimum premium plans, stop-loss plans or any other specific type of insurer or health insurance is determined by a court of competent jurisdiction to be unlawful, then the assessment method specified in this act shall continue to apply to all other insurers.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The provisions of section 12 of chapter 90-335 [The reference is apparently in error. Section 12, ch. 90-335, concerns public printing; ch. 90-334 is relevant], Laws of Florida, shall continue in full force and effect, but the provisions of this section shall control to the extent of any conflict.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 22, ch. 2004-297, provides that “[u]pon implementation, as defined in s. 627.64872(2), Florida Statutes, and as provided in s. 627.64872(20), Florida Statutes, of the Florida Health Insurance Plan created under s. 627.64872, Florida Statutes, sections 627.6488, 627.6489, 627.649, 627.6492, 627.6494, 627.6496, and 627.6498, Florida Statutes, are repealed.”</Text></Note></Section>