<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.985" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclosure requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conjunction with any offer of new coverage made in any consolidation, the new insurer shall disclose in writing to each prospective insured all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the insured debtor may have the right to continue or convert her or his old coverage by paying premiums directly to the old insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the offer of new coverage is not conditioned upon either the termination or replacement of the old coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the old insurer and the new insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective date of the new coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beneficiary of the new coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether premium rates under the new plan are guaranteed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amount of coverage for both the new and old plans. If the amount of coverage for the old plan is not known, a statement that the amount may be scheduled and it may be less than or greater than the amount of the loan and the insured should check the policy schedule for an exact amount of coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material differences, if any, between the new plan and the old plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to whether the old plan was an individual or group plan and a statement as to whether the new plan is an individual or group plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A consumer information phone number to call with questions regarding the consolidation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosures required under this part may be made on behalf of the new insurer by the financial institution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 90-149; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 379, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>