<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preexisting condition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health insurance policy must comply with the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A preexisting condition provision may not exclude coverage for a period beyond 24 months following the individual’s effective date of coverage and may relate only to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conditions that, during the 24-month period immediately preceding the effective date of coverage, had manifested themselves in such a manner as would cause an ordinarily prudent person to seek medical advice, diagnosis, care, or treatment or for which medical advice, diagnosis, care, or treatment was recommended or received; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pregnancy existing on the effective date of coverage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining whether a preexisting condition provision applies to an eligible insured or dependent, credit must be given for the time the person was covered under previous coverage if the previous coverage was similar to or exceeded the coverage provided under the new policy and if the previous coverage was continuous to a date not more than 62 days before the effective date of the new coverage, exclusive of any applicable waiting period under the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to short-term, nonrenewable health insurance policies of no more than a 6-month policy term, provided that it is clearly disclosed to the applicant in the advertising and application, in 10-point contrasting type, that “This policy does not meet the definition of qualifying previous coverage or qualifying existing coverage as defined in <Reference Number="1" />s. 627.6699. As a result, if purchased in lieu of a conversion policy or other group coverage, you may have to meet a preexisting condition requirement when renewing or purchasing other coverage.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to disability income insurance or income replacement insurance coverage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 96-223.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 627.6699(3)(r), which defined the terms “qualifying previous coverage” and “qualifying existing coverage,” was deleted by s. 15, ch. 97-179.</Text></Note></Section>