<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.8405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts; financing companies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No premium finance company shall, in a premium finance agreement or other agreement, finance the cost of or otherwise provide for the collection or remittance of dues, assessments, fees, or other periodic payments of money for the cost of:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A membership in an automobile club. The term “automobile club” means a legal entity which, in consideration of dues, assessments, or periodic payments of money, promises its members or subscribers to assist them in matters relating to the ownership, operation, use, or maintenance of a motor vehicle; however, this definition of “automobile club” does not include persons, associations, or corporations which are organized and operated solely for the purpose of conducting, sponsoring, or sanctioning motor vehicle races, exhibitions, or contests upon racetracks, or upon racecourses established and marked as such for the duration of such particular events. The words “motor vehicle” used herein have the same meaning as defined in chapter 320.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accidental death and dismemberment policy sold in combination with a personal injury protection and property damage only policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any product not regulated under the provisions of this insurance code.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This section also applies to premium financing by any insurance agent or insurance company under part XVI. The commission shall adopt rules to assure disclosure, at the time of sale, of coverages financed with personal injury protection and shall prescribe the form of such disclosure.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 604, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 117, ch. 83-216; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 21, ch. 93-410; s. 3, ch. 95-424; s. 2, ch. 97-204; s. 16, ch. 2000-370; s. 1223, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>