<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0627.4133" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of cancellation, nonrenewal, or renewal premium.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer issuing a policy providing coverage for workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurance, property, casualty, except mortgage guaranty, surety, or marine insurance, other than motor vehicle insurance subject to s. 627.728, shall give the first-named insured at least 45 days’ advance written notice of nonrenewal or of the renewal premium. If the policy is not to be renewed, the written notice shall state the reason or reasons as to why the policy is not to be renewed. This requirement applies only if the insured has furnished all of the necessary information so as to enable the insurer to develop the renewal premium prior to the expiration date of the policy to be renewed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer issuing a policy providing coverage for property, casualty, except mortgage guaranty, surety, or marine insurance, other than motor vehicle insurance subject to s. 627.728 or s. 627.7281, shall give the first-named insured written notice of cancellation or termination other than nonrenewal at least 45 days prior to the effective date of the cancellation or termination, including in the written notice the reason or reasons for the cancellation or termination, except that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When cancellation is for nonpayment of premium, at least 10 days’ written notice of cancellation accompanied by the reason therefor shall be given. As used in this subparagraph and s. 440.42(3), the term “nonpayment of premium” means failure of the named insured to discharge when due any of her or his obligations in connection with the payment of premiums on a policy or any installment of such premium, whether the premium is payable directly to the insurer or its agent or indirectly under any premium finance plan or extension of credit, or failure to maintain membership in an organization if such membership is a condition precedent to insurance coverage. “Nonpayment of premium” also means the failure of a financial institution to honor an insurance applicant’s check after delivery to a licensed agent for payment of a premium, even if the agent has previously delivered or transferred the premium to the insurer. If a dishonored check represents the initial premium payment, the contract and all contractual obligations shall be void ab initio unless the nonpayment is cured within the earlier of 5 days after actual notice by certified mail is received by the applicant or 15 days after notice is sent to the applicant by certified mail or registered mail, and if the contract is void, any premium received by the insurer from a third party shall be refunded to that party in full; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When such cancellation or termination occurs during the first 90 days during which the insurance is in force and the insurance is canceled or terminated for reasons other than nonpayment of premium, at least 20 days’ written notice of cancellation or termination accompanied by the reason therefor shall be given except where there has been a material misstatement or misrepresentation or failure to comply with the underwriting requirements established by the insurer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">After the policy has been in effect for 90 days, no such policy shall be canceled by the insurer except when there has been a material misstatement, a nonpayment of premium, a failure to comply with underwriting requirements established by the insurer within 90 days of the date of effectuation of coverage, or a substantial change in the risk covered by the policy or when the cancellation is for all insureds under such policies for a given class of insureds. This subsection does not apply to individually rated risks having a policy term of less than 90 days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an insurer fails to provide the 45-day or 20-day written notice required under this section, the coverage provided to the named insured shall remain in effect until 45 days after the notice is given or until the effective date of replacement coverage obtained by the named insured, whichever occurs first. The premium for the coverage shall remain the same during any such extension period except that, in the event of failure to provide notice of nonrenewal, if the rate filing then in effect would have resulted in a premium reduction, the premium during such extension of coverage shall be calculated based upon the later rate filing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any personal lines or commercial residential property insurance policy, including, but not limited to, any homeowner’s, mobile home owner’s, farmowner’s, condominium association, condominium unit owner’s, apartment building, or other policy covering a residential structure or its contents:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer shall give the first-named insured at least 45 days’ advance written notice of the renewal premium.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer shall give the first-named insured written notice of nonrenewal, cancellation, or termination at least 100 days before the effective date of the nonrenewal, cancellation, or termination. However, the insurer shall give at least 100 days’ written notice, or written notice by June 1, whichever is earlier, for any nonrenewal, cancellation, or termination that would be effective between June 1 and November 30. The notice must include the reason or reasons for the nonrenewal, cancellation, or termination, except that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer shall give the first-named insured written notice of nonrenewal, cancellation, or termination at least 120 days prior to the effective date of the nonrenewal, cancellation, or termination for a first-named insured whose residential structure has been insured by that insurer or an affiliated insurer for at least a 5-year period immediately prior to the date of the written notice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If cancellation is for nonpayment of premium, at least 10 days’ written notice of cancellation accompanied by the reason therefor must be given. As used in this subparagraph, the term “nonpayment of premium” means failure of the named insured to discharge when due her or his obligations in connection with the payment of premiums on a policy or any installment of such premium, whether the premium is payable directly to the insurer or its agent or indirectly under any premium finance plan or extension of credit, or failure to maintain membership in an organization if such membership is a condition precedent to insurance coverage. The term also means the failure of a financial institution to honor an insurance applicant’s check after delivery to a licensed agent for payment of a premium, even if the agent has previously delivered or transferred the premium to the insurer. If a dishonored check represents the initial premium payment, the contract and all contractual obligations are void ab initio unless the nonpayment is cured within the earlier of 5 days after actual notice by certified mail is received by the applicant or 15 days after notice is sent to the applicant by certified mail or registered mail, and if the contract is void, any premium received by the insurer from a third party must be refunded to that party in full.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such cancellation or termination occurs during the first 90 days the insurance is in force and the insurance is canceled or terminated for reasons other than nonpayment of premium, at least 20 days’ written notice of cancellation or termination accompanied by the reason therefor must be given unless there has been a material misstatement or misrepresentation or failure to comply with the underwriting requirements established by the insurer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirement for providing written notice by June 1 of any nonrenewal that would be effective between June 1 and November 30 does not apply to the following situations, but the insurer remains subject to the requirement to provide such notice at least 100 days before the effective date of nonrenewal:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A policy that is nonrenewed due to a revision in the coverage for sinkhole losses and catastrophic ground cover collapse pursuant to s. 627.706.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A policy that is nonrenewed by Citizens Property Insurance Corporation, pursuant to s. 627.351(6), for a policy that has been assumed by an authorized insurer offering replacement coverage to the policyholder is exempt from the notice requirements of paragraph (a) and this paragraph. In such cases, the corporation must give the named insured written notice of nonrenewal at least 45 days before the effective date of the nonrenewal.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">After the policy has been in effect for 90 days, the policy may not be canceled by the insurer unless there has been a material misstatement, a nonpayment of premium, a failure to comply with underwriting requirements established by the insurer within 90 days after the date of effectuation of coverage, or a substantial change in the risk covered by the policy or if the cancellation is for all insureds under such policies for a given class of insureds. This paragraph does not apply to individually rated risks having a policy term of less than 90 days.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an insurer may cancel or nonrenew a property insurance policy after at least 45 days’ notice if the office finds that the early cancellation of some or all of the insurer’s policies is necessary to protect the best interests of the public or policyholders and the office approves the insurer’s plan for early cancellation or nonrenewal of some or all of its policies. The office may base such finding upon the financial condition of the insurer, lack of adequate reinsurance coverage for hurricane risk, or other relevant factors. The office may condition its finding on the consent of the insurer to be placed under administrative supervision pursuant to s. 624.81 or to the appointment of a receiver under chapter 631.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A policy covering both a home and motor vehicle may be nonrenewed for any reason applicable to either the property or motor vehicle insurance after providing 90 days’ notice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insurer fails to provide the notice required by this subsection, other than the 10-day notice, the coverage provided to the named insured shall remain in effect until the effective date of replacement coverage or until the expiration of a period of days after the notice is given equal to the required notice period, whichever occurs first. The premium for the coverage shall remain the same during any such extension period except that, in the event of failure to provide notice of nonrenewal, if the rate filing then in effect would have resulted in a premium reduction, the premium during such extension shall be calculated based on the later rate filing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a declaration of an emergency pursuant to s. 252.36 and the filing of an order by the Commissioner of Insurance Regulation, an insurer may not cancel or nonrenew a personal residential or commercial residential property insurance policy covering a dwelling or residential property located in this state which has been damaged as a result of a hurricane or wind loss that is the subject of the declaration of emergency for a period of 90 days after the dwelling or residential property has been repaired. A structure is deemed to be repaired when substantially completed and restored to the extent that it is insurable by another authorized insurer that is writing policies in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, an insurer or agent may cancel or nonrenew such a policy prior to the repair of the dwelling or residential property:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon 10 days’ notice for nonpayment of premium; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon 45 days’ notice:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a material misstatement or fraud related to the claim;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insurer determines that the insured has unreasonably caused a delay in the repair of the dwelling; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insurer has paid policy limits.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insurer elects to nonrenew a policy covering a property that has been damaged, the insurer shall provide at least 90 days’ notice to the insured that the insurer intends to nonrenew the policy 90 days after the dwelling or residential property has been repaired. Nothing in this paragraph shall prevent the insurer from canceling or nonrenewing the policy 90 days after the repairs are complete for the same reasons the insurer would otherwise have canceled or nonrenewed the policy but for the limitations of subparagraph 1. The Financial Services Commission may adopt rules, and the Commissioner of Insurance Regulation may issue orders, necessary to implement this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph shall also apply to personal residential and commercial residential policies covering property that was damaged as the result of Tropical Storm Bonnie, Hurricane Charley, Hurricane Frances, Hurricane Ivan, or Hurricane Jeanne.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any cancellation or nonrenewal of a policy subject to this subsection is to take effect during the duration of a hurricane as defined in s. 627.4025(2)(c), the effective date of such cancellation or nonrenewal is extended until the end of the duration of such hurricane. The insurer may collect premium at the prior rates or the rates then in effect for the period of time for which coverage is extended. This paragraph does not apply to any property with respect to which replacement coverage has been obtained and which is in effect for a claim occurring during the duration of the hurricane.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims on property insurance policies that are the result of an act of God may not be used as a cause for cancellation or nonrenewal, unless the insurer can demonstrate, by claims frequency or otherwise, that the insured has failed to take action reasonably necessary as requested by the insurer to prevent recurrence of damage to the insured property.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 440.42(3), if cancellation of a policy providing coverage for workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurance is requested in writing by the insured, such cancellation shall be effective on the date requested by the insured or, if no date is specified by the insured, cancellation shall be effective on the date of the written request. The carrier is not required to send notice of cancellation to the insured if the cancellation is requested in writing by the insured. Any retroactive assumption of coverage and liabilities under a policy providing workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurance may not exceed 21 days.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer that cancels a property insurance policy on property secured by a mortgage due to the failure of the lender to timely pay the premium when due shall reinstate the policy as required by s. 501.137.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A single claim on a property insurance policy which is the result of water damage may not be used as the sole cause for cancellation or nonrenewal unless the insurer can demonstrate that the insured has failed to take action reasonably requested by the insurer to prevent a future similar occurrence of damage to the insured property.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective August 1, 2007, with respect to any residential property insurance policy, every notice of renewal premium must specify:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dollar amounts recouped for assessments by the Florida Hurricane Catastrophe Fund, the Citizens Property Insurance Corporation, and the Florida Insurance Guaranty Association. The actual names of the entities must appear next to the dollar amounts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dollar amount of any premium increase that is due to an approved rate increase and the total dollar amount that is due to coverage changes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Financial Services Commission may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon expiration of the policy term, an insurer may transfer a commercial lines policy to another authorized insurer that is a member of the same group or owned by the same holding company as the transferring insurer. The transfer constitutes a renewal of the policy and may not be treated as a cancellation or a nonrenewal of the policy. The insurer must provide notice of its intent to transfer the policy at least 45 days before the effective date of the transfer along with the financial rating of the authorized insurer to which the policy is being transferred. Such notice may be provided in the notice of renewal premium. This subsection does not apply to a policy providing residential property insurance coverage, except for farmowners insurance and commercial general liability policies providing farm coverage or commercial property policies providing farm coverage.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 86-160; s. 2, ch. 87-50; s. 8, ch. 87-124; s. 12, ch. 90-119; ss. 35, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 15, ch. 93-410; s. 99, ch. 93-415; s. 13, ch. 2004-370; s. 43, ch. 2004-374; ss. 109, 158, ch. 2004-390; s. 10, ch. 2005-111; s. 47, ch. 2006-12; s. 12, ch. 2006-305; s. 25, ch. 2007-1; s. 16, ch. 2007-90; s. 150, ch. 2008-4; s. 14, ch. 2008-66; s. 17, ch. 2011-39; s. 9, ch. 2011-174; s. 8, ch. 2012-213.</History>
</Section>