<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.660" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conditions and provisions of blanket health insurance policies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual application shall not be required from a person covered under a blanket health insurance policy or contract, nor shall it be necessary for the insurer to furnish such person a certificate, except as provided in subsection (6).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any benefit under a blanket health policy shall be payable as provided in s. 627.614.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No such policy shall contain any provision relative to notice or proof of loss, to the time for paying benefits, or to the time within which suit may be brought on the policy, which provision is less favorable to the individuals insured than would be permitted by the comparable provision required for individual health insurance policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of part VI of this chapter do not apply to blanket health insurance policies, but no such policy shall contain any provision relative to notice or proof of loss, to the time for paying benefits, or to the time within which suit may be brought on the policy, which provision is less favorable to the individuals insured than would be permitted by the comparable provision required for individual health insurance policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in s. 627.659 or in this section shall be deemed to affect the legal liability of policyholders for the death or injury to any person insured under a blanket disability policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer shall issue, or cause to be issued, to each insured person covered under a policy issued pursuant to s. 627.659(3) a written certificate setting forth the essential features of the insurance coverage. The certificate shall be subject to filing and approval in accordance with ss. 627.410 and 627.640.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 592, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 65-10; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 510, 523, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>