<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.7845" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of insurability required; preservation of evidence of title search and examination.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A title insurer may not issue a title insurance commitment, endorsement, or title insurance policy until the title insurer has caused to be made a determination of insurability based upon the evaluation of a reasonable title search or a search of the records of a Uniform Commercial Code filing office, as applicable, has examined such other information as may be necessary, and has caused to be made a determination of insurability of title or the existence, attachments, perfection, and priority of a Uniform Commercial Code security interest, including endorsement coverages, in accordance with sound underwriting practices.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The title insurer shall cause the evidence of the determination of insurability and the reasonable title search or search of the records of a Uniform Commercial Code filing office to be preserved and retained in its files or in the files of its title insurance agent or agency for a period of not less than 7 years after the title insurance commitment, title insurance policy, or guarantee of title was issued. The title insurer or agent or agency must produce the evidence required to be maintained by this subsection at its offices upon the demand of the office. Instead of retaining the original evidence, the title insurer or the title insurance agent or agency may, in the regular course of business, establish a system under which all or part of the evidence is recorded, copied, or reproduced by any photographic, photostatic, microfilm, microcard, miniature photographic, or other process which accurately reproduces or forms a durable medium for reproducing the original.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The title insurer or its agent or agency must maintain a record of the actual premium charged for issuance of the policy and any endorsements in its files for a period of not less than 7 years. The title insurer, agent, or agency must produce the record at its office upon demand of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to an insurer assuming no primary liability in a contract of reinsurance or to an insurer acting as a coinsurer if any other coinsuring insurer has complied with this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 582, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 4, ch. 85-185; ss. 102, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 18, ch. 99-286; s. 1207, ch. 2003-261; s. 3, ch. 2005-153; s. 7, ch. 2007-44.</History></Section>