<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.40951" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standard personal lines residential insurance policy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that many consumers who filed property loss claims as a result of the hurricanes that struck this state in 2004 were inadequately insured due to the difficulty consumers encounter in trying to understand the complex nature of property insurance policies. The purpose and intent of this section is to have property and casualty insurers offer standard personal lines residential property insurance policies and standard checklists of policy contents, in accordance with s. 627.4143, to consumers and to ensure that these policies and checklists are written in a simple format with easily readable language that will enable most consumers to understand the principal benefits and coverage provided in the policy; the principal exclusions and limitations or reductions contained in the policy, including, but not limited to, deductibles, coinsurance, and any other limitations or reductions; and any additional coverage provided through any rider or endorsement that accompanies the policy and renewal or cancellation provisions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall appoint an advisory committee composed of two representatives of insurers currently selling personal lines residential property insurance coverage, two representatives of property and casualty agents, two representatives of consumers, two representatives of the Commissioner of Insurance Regulation, and the Insurance Consumer Advocate or her or his designee. The Chief Financial Officer or her or his designee shall serve as chair of the committee. The committee shall develop policy language for coverage that represents general industry standards in the market for comprehensive coverage under personal lines residential insurance policies and shall develop a checklist to be used with each type of personal lines residential property insurance policy. The committee shall review policies and related forms written by Insurance Services Office, Inc. The committee shall file a report containing its recommendations to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 15, 2006. No insurer shall be required to offer the standard policy unless required by further act of the Legislature.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2005-111.</History></Section>