<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.783" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rate deviation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A title insurer may petition the office for an order authorizing a specific deviation from the adopted premium. The petition shall be in writing and sworn to and shall set forth allegations of fact upon which the petitioner will rely, including the petitioner’s reasons for requesting the deviation. Any authorized title insurer, agent, or agency may join in the petition for like authority to deviate or may file a separate petition praying for like authority or opposing the deviation. The office shall rule on all such petitions simultaneously.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, in the judgment of the office, the requested deviation is not justified, the office may enter an order denying the petition. An order granting a petition constitutes an amendment to the adopted premium as to the petitioners named in the order, and is subject to s. 627.782.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 65-359; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 580, 584, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 9, ch. 89-305; ss. 96, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 13, ch. 99-286; s. 1205, ch. 2003-261; s. 6, ch. 2007-44.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 23, ch. 2008-220, provides that “[t]he Legislature finds that the Uniform Commercial Code insurance product authorized by section 1 of Chapter 2005-153, Laws of Florida, will open new markets in this state and will result in generation of new revenue for the state. Accordingly, title insurers may petition for a rate deviation as provided by s. 627.783, Florida Statutes, for the uniform commercial code insurance product. In determining whether to approve such petition for a rate deviation for the uniform commercial code insurance product, the office shall be guided by standards for national rates for the product currently being offered in other states.”</Text></Note></Section>