<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0627.06281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public hurricane loss projection model; reporting of data by insurers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after a written request for loss data and associated exposure data by the office or the Florida International University center established to study mitigation, residential property insurers and licensed rating and advisory organizations that compile residential property insurance loss data shall provide loss data and associated exposure data for residential property insurance policies to the office or the Florida International University center established to study mitigation, as directed by the office, for the purposes of developing, maintaining, and updating a public model for hurricane loss projections. The loss data and associated exposure data provided shall be in writing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public model must be submitted to the Florida Commission on Hurricane Loss Projection Methodology for review under s. 627.0628 by March 1, 2007. The office may continue to use the model for its review of rate filings pursuant to ss. 627.062 and 627.351 until such time as the Florida Commission on Hurricane Loss Projection Methodology determines that the public model is not accurate or reliable pursuant to the same process and standards as the commission uses for the review of other hurricane loss projection models.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A residential property insurer may have access to and use the public hurricane loss projection model, including all assumptions and factors and all detailed loss results, for the purpose of calculating rate indications in a rate filing and for analytical purposes, including any analysis or evaluation of the model required under actuarial standards of practice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees charged for private sector access and use of the model shall be the reasonable costs associated with the operation and maintenance of the model by the office. Such fees do not apply to access and use of the model by the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2005-111; s. 13, ch. 2006-12; s. 59, ch. 2007-217; s. 18, ch. 2008-66; s. 13, ch. 2011-39.</History>
</Section>