<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6744" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recommended purchase and excessive insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicare supplement insurance may not be issued or sold, whether directly, through the mail, or otherwise, to an individual unless the issuer or seller obtains from the individual, as a part of the application, a written statement signed by the individual stating what Medicare supplement policies the individual has, from what source, and whether the individual has applied for and been determined to be entitled to Medicaid. The written statement must be accompanied by a written acknowledgment, signed by the seller, of the request for and receipt of the statement. The written acknowledgment does not constitute a verification or affirmation by the seller of the truth of any information supplied by the individual in the written statement. The written statement shall be on forms prescribed by the commission in accordance with the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (Pub. L. No. 101-508).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicare supplement insurance may not be issued or sold to an individual if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual’s written statement indicates that the individual is entitled to Medicaid, unless this state’s Medicaid plan under Title XIX pays the premiums for the policy, or pays less than an individual’s full liability for Medicare cost sharing as defined under the federal Medicare law; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of Medicare supplement coverage will provide an individual more than one Medicare supplement policy or certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit the sale of a Medicare supplement policy to an individual who has another Medicare supplement policy if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual indicates in writing that the policy replaces the other policy and indicates an intent to terminate the policy being replaced when the new policy becomes effective; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer providing the replacement policy forwards the statement to the insurer whose policy is being replaced.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a request of the policyholder, an insurer shall suspend the benefits and premiums of the Medicare supplement policy for the period in which the policyholder indicates that he or she has applied for and been determined to be entitled to Medicaid. The period of suspension shall not exceed 24 months. If the policyholder loses entitlement to Medicaid and the policyholder provides notice within 90 days after the loss of entitlement, the policy shall be automatically reinstated as of the termination of Medicaid entitlement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 90-257; s. 18, ch. 91-201; s. 16, ch. 91-296; ss. 144, 149, ch. 92-33; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1176, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>