<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appeal from rating organization; workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurance filings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member or subscriber to a rating organization may appeal to the office from the action or decision of such rating organization in approving or rejecting any proposed change in or addition to the workers’ compensation or employer’s liability insurance filings of such rating organization, and the office shall issue an order approving the decision of such rating organization or directing it to give further consideration to such proposal. If such appeal is from the action or decision of the rating organization in rejecting a proposed addition to its filings, the office may, in the event it finds that such action or decision was unreasonable, issue an order directing the rating organization to make an addition to its filings, on behalf of its members and subscribers, in a manner consistent with its findings, within a reasonable time after the issuance of such order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If such appeal is based upon the failure of the rating organization to make a filing on behalf of such member or subscriber which is based on a system of expense provisions which differs, in accordance with the right granted in s. 627.072(2), from the system of expense provisions included in a filing made by the rating organization, the office shall, if it grants the appeal, order the rating organization to make the requested filing for use by the appellant. In deciding such appeal, the office shall apply the applicable standards set forth in ss. 627.062 and 627.072.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 438, ch. 59-205; s. 13, ch. 67-9; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; s. 105, ch. 79-40; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 357, 806, ch. 82-243; s. 49, ch. 82-386; ss. 9, 10, ch. 87-124; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1093, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>