<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.663" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Franchise health insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Franchise health insurance,” also known as “franchise group insurance,” is that form of health insurance issued to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two or more employees of any corporation, professional association, copartnership, or individual employer or of any governmental corporation, agency, or department; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten or more individuals who are members of any trade association or labor union or any other association having had an active existence for at least 2 years if such association or union has a constitution or bylaws and is formed in good faith for purposes other than that of obtaining insurance; when such persons, with or without their dependents, are issued the same form of an individual policy varying only as to amounts and kinds of coverage applied for by such persons under an arrangement whereby the premiums on such policies may be paid to the insurer periodically by the employer, with or without payroll deductions, or by the association, or by some designated person acting on behalf of such employer or association. Notwithstanding the provisions of any state antidiscriminatory law, such provisions shall not prohibit different rates charged or benefits payable or a different underwriting procedure for individuals insured under a franchise plan provided the rates charged, benefits payable, or underwriting procedure used does not discriminate between franchise plans.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of part VI of this chapter also apply to franchise insurance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 594, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 1, ch. 79-67; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 514, 523, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 63, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>