<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.4239" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coverage for use of drugs in treatment of cancer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical literature” means scientific studies published in a United States peer-reviewed national professional journal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Standard reference compendium” means authoritative compendia identified by the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services and recognized by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COVERAGE FOR TREATMENT OF CANCER.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may not exclude coverage in any individual or group insurance policy issued, amended, delivered, or renewed in this state which covers the treatment of cancer for any drug prescribed for the treatment of cancer on the ground that the drug is not approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration for a particular indication, if that drug is recognized for treatment of that indication in a standard reference compendium or recommended in the medical literature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage for a drug required by this section also includes the medically necessary services associated with the administration of the drug.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICABILITY AND SCOPE.<EmDash />This section may not be construed to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alter any other law with regard to provisions limiting coverage for drugs that are not approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require coverage for any drug if the United States Food and Drug Administration has determined that the use of the drug is contraindicated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require coverage for a drug that is not otherwise approved for any indication by the United States Food and Drug Administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affect the determination as to whether particular levels, dosages, or usage of a medication associated with bone marrow transplant procedures are covered under an individual or group health insurance policy or health maintenance organization contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply to specified disease or supplemental policies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section is intended, expressly or by implication, to create, impair, alter, limit, modify, enlarge, abrogate, prohibit, or withdraw any authority to provide reimbursement for drugs used in the treatment of any other disease or condition.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 95-268; s. 1, ch. 2009-202; s. 72, ch. 2009-223.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 72, ch. 2009-223. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Paragraph (1)(b) was also amended by s. 1, ch. 2009-202, and that version reads:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) “Standard reference compendium” means an authoritative compendium identified by the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services and recognized by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</Text></Note></Section>