<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.65626" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance rebates for healthy lifestyles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any rate, rating schedule, or rating manual for a health insurance policy that provides creditable coverage as defined in s. 627.6561(5) filed with the office shall provide for an appropriate rebate of premiums paid in the last policy year, contract year, or calendar year when the majority of members of a health plan have enrolled and maintained participation in any health wellness, maintenance, or improvement program offered by the group policyholder and health plan. The rebate may be based upon premiums paid in the last calendar year or policy year. The group must provide evidence of demonstrative maintenance or improvement of the enrollees’ health status as determined by assessments of agreed-upon health status indicators between the policyholder and the health insurer, including, but not limited to, reduction in weight, body mass index, and smoking cessation. The group or health insurer may contract with a third-party administrator to assemble and report the health status required in this subsection between the policyholder and the health insurer. Any rebate provided by the health insurer is presumed to be appropriate unless credible data demonstrates otherwise, or unless the rebate program requires the insured to incur costs to qualify for the rebate which equal or exceed the value of the rebate, but the rebate may not exceed 10 percent of paid premiums.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The premium rebate authorized by this section shall be effective for an insured on an annual basis unless the number of participating members on the policy renewal anniversary becomes less than the majority of the members eligible for participation in the wellness program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 2004-297; s. 6, ch. 2005-231.</History></Section>