<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.4143" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Outline of coverage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No private passenger automobile or basic homeowner’s policy shall be delivered or issued for delivery in this state unless an appropriate outline of coverage has been delivered prior to issuance of the policy or accompanies the policy when issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The outline of coverage for a private passenger motor vehicle insurance policy shall contain all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brief description of the principal benefits and coverage provided in the policy, broken down by each class or type of coverage provided under the policy for which a premium is charged, and itemization of the applicable premium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary statement of the principal exclusions and limitations or reductions contained in the policy by class or type, including, but not limited to, deductibles, coinsurance, and any other limitations or reductions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary statement of any renewal or cancellation provisions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the credit or surcharge plan that is being applied. The description may display numerical or alphabetical codes on the declarations page or premium notice to enable the insured to determine the reason or reasons why her or his policy is being surcharged or is receiving a credit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of any additional coverage provided through any rider or endorsement which accompanies the policy. The list shall contain a descriptive reference to each additional coverage, rather than solely a reference to a form or code number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent of coverage provided to the insured in the event of collision damage to a rental vehicle rented by the insured. The proof-of-insurance card required by s. 316.646 must also specify whether rental car coverage is provided, and may refer to the outline of coverage as to the details or extent of coverage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A basic homeowner’s, mobile home owner’s, dwelling, or condominium unit owner’s policy may not be delivered or issued for delivery in this state unless a comprehensive checklist of coverage on a form adopted by the commission and an appropriate outline of coverage have been delivered prior to issuance of the policy or accompanies the policy when issued. The commission shall, by rule, adopt a form for the checklist for each type of policy to which this subsection applies. Each form shall indicate that it was adopted by the commission.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The checklist must contain a list of the standard provisions and elements that may typically be included in these policies, whether or not they are included in the particular policy being issued, in a format that allows the insurer to place a check mark next to the provisions elements that are included so that the consumer can see both what is included and what is not included in the policy. As an alternative to checking the boxes on the checklist, an insurer may delete the check boxes from the form and replace them with text indicating whether the provision’s elements are included or not. Limits of liability shall be listed for each item. The checklist must include, but is not limited to, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property coverage for the principal premises shown in the declarations.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property coverage for other structures on the residence premises.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the principal premises and other structures are insured against the following perils:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fire.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lightning.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Explosion.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hurricane loss.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonhurricane wind loss.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collapse.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mold.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sinkhole loss.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vandalism.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal property coverage.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether personal property is insured against the following perils:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fire.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lightning.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hurricane loss.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonhurricane wind loss.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collapse.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mold.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sinkhole loss.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Theft.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following additional coverages:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Debris removal.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loss assessment.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additional living expenses.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal liability coverage.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical payments coverage.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discounts applied to the premium.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deductibles for loss due to hurricane and loss to other perils.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building ordinance or law coverage.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Replacement cost coverage.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actual cash value coverage.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The forms shall allow insurers to place other coverages on the checklists which may or may not be included in the insurer’s policies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The outline of coverage must contain:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brief description of the principal benefits and coverage provided in the policy, broken down by each class or type of coverage provided under the policy for which a premium is charged, and itemization of the applicable premium.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary statement of the principal exclusions and limitations or reductions contained in the policy by class or type, including, but not limited to, deductibles, coinsurance, and any other limitations or reductions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary statement of any renewal or cancellation provisions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the credit or surcharge plan that is being applied. The description may display numerical or alphabetical codes on the declarations page or premium notice to enable the insured to determine the reason or reasons why her or his policy is being surcharged or is receiving a credit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary of any additional coverage provided through any rider or endorsement that accompanies the policy.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The outline of coverage for a private passenger motor vehicle policy is required only on the initial policy issued by an insurer. The outline of coverage and the checklist for a basic homeowner’s, mobile home owner’s, dwelling, or condominium unit owner’s policy is required on the initial policy and each renewal thereof issued by an insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer must insert the following language on the outline of coverage:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">“The following outline of coverage or checklist is for informational purposes only. Florida law prohibits this outline or checklist from changing any of the provisions of the insurance contract which is the subject of this outline. Any endorsement regarding changes in types of coverage, exclusions, limitations, reductions, deductibles, coinsurance, renewal provisions, cancellation provisions, surcharges, or credits will be sent separately.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither this section nor the outline of coverage or checklist mandated by this section alters or modifies the terms of the insurance contract, creates a cause of action, or is admissible in any civil action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 89-360; s. 1, ch. 90-192; ss. 39, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 328, ch. 97-102; s. 11, ch. 2005-111.</History></Section>