<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.0625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Commercial property and casualty risk management plans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial property insurance” means insurance as defined in s. 624.604, but limited to coverage of commercial risks, excluding windstorm coverage, flood insurance, federal crop insurance, crop hail insurance, the Pollution Liability Insurance Association, and other federal governmental pools and associations. If separate rates and supporting experience data are not filed and justified for windstorm coverage, the insurer shall, using generally accepted actuarial and economic principles and techniques, identify and justify the premiums, losses, reserves, and associated data for the windstorm coverage excluded from commercial property insurance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial casualty insurance” means insurance as defined in s. 624.605, other than workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurance, but limited to coverage of commercial risks.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial umbrella liability insurance” means insurance as defined in s. 624.605 but limited to any policy or endorsement which provides coverage in the amount of $300,000 or more in excess of an underlying policy providing $300,000 liability or equivalent limits of insurance, on a specific insured vehicle, location, business operation, or other specific commercial risk.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall apply only to commercial property insurance and to commercial casualty insurance as those terms are defined in subsection (1), or any combination thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer or insurer group offering commercial casualty insurance or commercial property insurance covering risks located in this state shall develop and make available to insureds guidelines for risk management plans. The risk management program shall include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Safety measures, including, as applicable, the following areas:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pollution and environmental hazards;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disease hazards;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accidental occurrences;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fire hazards and fire prevention and detection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Liability for acts from the course of business;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Slip and fall hazards;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Product injury; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hazards unique to a particular class or category of insureds.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Training to insureds in safety management techniques.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Safety management counseling services.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">There shall be no civil cause of action against any insurer or its agents or employees for acts or omissions in any way connected with the requirements of this subsection. This shall not limit the authority for the office to enforce the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 86-160; s. 2, ch. 87-50; s. 2, ch. 88-390; s. 18, ch. 89-167; s. 1, ch. 89-225; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1065, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>