<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.5515" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Out-of-state groups.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any group life insurance policy issued or delivered outside this state under which a resident of this state is provided coverage shall comply with the provisions of this part in the same manner as group life policies issued in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not apply to a group life insurance policy issued or delivered outside this state under which a resident of this state is provided coverage if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy is issued to an employee group the composition of which is substantially as described in s. 627.552; a labor union group the composition of which is substantially as described in s. 627.554; a trustee group the composition of which is substantially as described in s. 627.555; a credit union group the composition of which is substantially as described in s. 627.556; an additional group complying with s. 627.5565; an association group the composition of which is substantially as described in s. 627.5567; an association group to cover persons associated in any other common group, which common group is formed primarily for purposes other than providing insurance; a group which is established primarily for the purpose of providing group insurance, provided the benefits are reasonable in relation to the premiums charged thereunder and issuance of the group policy has resulted, or will result, in economies of administration; or a group of insurance agents of an insurer, which insurer is the policyholder;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certificates evidencing coverage under the policy are issued to residents of this state and contain in contrasting color and not less than 10-point type the following statement: “The benefits of the policy providing your coverage are governed primarily by the law of a state other than Florida.”; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy provides the benefits specified in s. 627.566.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 624.428 is not applicable when residents of this state are enrolled for coverage under a policy or certificate issued in accordance with subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to solicitation in this state, a copy of the master policy and a copy of the form of the certificate evidencing coverage that will be issued to residents of this state shall be filed with the office for informational purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to solicitation in this state, an officer of the insurer shall truthfully certify to the office that the policy and certificates evidencing coverage have been reviewed and approved by the state in which the group policy is issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurer who provides coverage under certificates of insurance issued to residents of this state shall designate one Florida-licensed resident agent as agent of record for the service of such certificates, unless the policy is issued to a group substantially as described in s. 627.552, s. 627.554, s. 627.555, s. 627.556, s. 627.5565, or s. 627.5567.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 422, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 98, ch. 83-216; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 30, ch. 99-3; s. 1138, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>