<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.832" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for refusal, suspension, or revocation of license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may deny, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew any license, if it finds:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the licensee has failed to pay the annual license fee or any sum of money lawfully demanded under authority of any other section of this part or has failed to comply with any order of the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the licensee has violated any provision of this part or any rule of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That any fact or condition exists which, if it had existed at the time of the original application, clearly would have warranted a refusal to issue the license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material misstatement, misrepresentation, or fraud in obtaining the license or permit, or in attempting to obtain the license or permit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the license or permit is being willfully used, or is to be used, to circumvent any of the requirements or prohibitions of this code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful misrepresentation of any premium finance contract or willful deception with regard to any such contract, accomplished either in person or by any form of dissemination of information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A demonstrated lack of fitness or trustworthiness.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent or dishonest practices in the conduct of business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misappropriation, conversion, or unlawful withholding of moneys belonging to insurers, insureds, or beneficiaries or to others and received in the conduct of business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the licensee has been found guilty of, or has pleaded guilty to, a felony in this state or any other state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee may surrender a license by delivering to the office written notice that she or he thereby surrenders such license, but such surrender shall not affect such licensee’s civil or criminal liability for acts committed prior to such surrender.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No revocation, suspension, or surrender of a license shall impair or affect the obligation of any insured under any lawful premium finance agreement previously acquired or held by the licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every license issued hereunder shall remain in force and effect until it has been surrendered, revoked, or suspended or expires in accordance with the provisions of this part; but the office may reinstate a suspended license or issue a new license to a licensee whose license has been revoked, if no fact or condition then exists which clearly would have warranted office refusal originally to issue such license under this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 63-16; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 597, 612, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 115, ch. 83-216; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 364, ch. 97-102; s. 1217, ch. 2003-261; s. 125, ch. 2004-5.</History></Section>