<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rate filings; workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurances, every insurer shall file with the office every manual of classifications, rules, and rates, every rating plan, and every modification of any of the foregoing which it proposes to use. Every insurer is authorized to include deductible provisions in its manual of classifications, rules, and rates. Such deductibles shall in all cases be in a form and manner which is consistent with the underlying purpose of chapter 440.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every such filing shall state the proposed effective date thereof, and shall indicate the character and extent of the coverage contemplated. When a filing is not accompanied by the information upon which the insurer supports the filing and the office does not have sufficient information to determine whether the filing meets the applicable requirements of this part, it shall within 15 days after the date of filing require the insurer to furnish the information upon which it supports the filing. The information furnished in support of a filing may include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The experience or judgment of the insurer or rating organization making the filing;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its interpretation of any statistical data it relies upon;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The experience of other insurers or rating organizations; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other factors which the insurer or rating organization deems relevant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A filing and any supporting information shall be open to public inspection as provided in s. 119.07(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may satisfy its obligation to make such filings by becoming a member of, or a subscriber to, a licensed rating organization which makes such filings and by authorizing the office to accept such filings in its behalf; but nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as requiring any insurer to become a member or a subscriber to any rating organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the provisions of s. 624.3161, the office may examine the underlying statistical data used in such filings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the committee of a recognized rating organization with responsibility for workers’ compensation and employer’s liability insurance rates in this state meets to discuss the necessity for, or a request for, Florida rate increases or decreases, the determination of Florida rates, the rates to be requested, and any other matters pertaining specifically and directly to such Florida rates, such meetings shall be held in this state and shall be subject to s. 286.011. The committee of such a rating organization shall provide at least 3 weeks’ prior notice of such meetings to the office and shall provide at least 14 days’ prior notice of such meetings to the public by publication in the Florida Administrative Weekly.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 419, ch. 59-205; s. 5, ch. 67-9; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 20, ch. 78-300; s. 95, ch. 79-40; ss. 20, 22, ch. 80-236; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 357, 806, ch. 82-243; s. 49, ch. 82-386; ss. 4, 9, 10, ch. 87-124; s. 63, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 93-289; s. 1076, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>