<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6578" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coverage for natural-born, adopted, and foster children; children in insured’s custodial care.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A group, blanket, or franchise health insurance policy that provides coverage for a family member of the certificateholder or subscriber shall, as to such family member’s coverage, provide that benefits applicable to children of the certificateholder or subscriber also apply to an adopted child or a foster child of the certificateholder or subscriber placed in compliance with chapter 63, from the moment of placement in the residence of the certificateholder or subscriber. Except in the case of a foster child, the policy may not exclude coverage for any preexisting condition of the child. In the case of a newborn child, coverage begins at the moment of birth if a written agreement to adopt such child has been entered into by the certificateholder or subscriber prior to the birth of the child, whether or not the agreement is enforceable. This section does not require coverage for an adopted child who is not ultimately placed in the residence of the certificateholder or subscriber in compliance with chapter 63.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A policy or contract may require the insured to notify the insurer of the birth or placement of an adopted child within a specified time period of not less than 30 days after the birth or placement in the residence of a child adopted by the insured. If timely notice is given, the insurer may not charge an additional premium for coverage of the child for the duration of the notice period. If timely notice is not given, the insurer may charge an additional premium from the date of birth or placement. If notice is given within 60 days of the birth or placement of the child, the insurer may not deny coverage for the child due to the failure of the insured to timely notify the insurer of the birth or placement of the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the policy does not require the insured to notify the insurer of the birth or placement of an adopted child within a specified time period, the insurer may not deny coverage for such child or retroactively charge the insured an additional premium for such child. However, the insurer may prospectively charge the insured an additional premium for the child if the insurer provides at least 45 days’ notice of the additional premium required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to increase access to postnatal, infant, and pediatric health care for all children placed in court-ordered custody, including foster children, all group, blanket, and franchise health insurance policies that provide coverage for a family member of the certificateholder or subscriber shall, as to such family member’s coverage, provide that benefits applicable for children shall be payable with respect to a foster child or other child in court-ordered temporary or other custody of the certificateholder or subscriber.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 5, ch. 85-189; s. 2, ch. 88-269; s. 2, ch. 91-185; ss. 134, 149, ch. 92-33; s. 6, ch. 92-278; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 10, ch. 98-159.</History></Section>