<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0627.4137" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclosure of certain information required.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer which does or may provide liability insurance coverage to pay all or a portion of any claim which might be made shall provide, within 30 days of the written request of the claimant, a statement, under oath, of a corporate officer or the insurer’s claims manager or superintendent setting forth the following information with regard to each known policy of insurance, including excess or umbrella insurance:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the insurer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each insured.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limits of the liability coverage.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of any policy or coverage defense which such insurer reasonably believes is available to such insurer at the time of filing such statement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the policy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In addition, the insured, or her or his insurance agent, upon written request of the claimant or the claimant’s attorney, shall disclose the name and coverage of each known insurer to the claimant and shall forward such request for information as required by this subsection to all affected insurers. The insurer shall then supply the information required in this subsection to the claimant within 30 days of receipt of such request.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statement required by subsection (1) shall be amended immediately upon discovery of facts calling for an amendment to such statement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any request made to a self-insured corporation pursuant to this section shall be sent by certified mail to the registered agent of the disclosing entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 543, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 22, ch. 83-288; ss. 38, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 327, ch. 97-102; s. 10, ch. 2011-174.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 627.7264.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>