<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.914" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reports of information by workers’ compensation insurers required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt rules and statistical plans that must thereafter be used by each insurer and self-insurance fund as defined in s. 624.461 in the recording and reporting of loss, expense, and claims experience, in order that the experience of all insurers and self-insurance funds may be made available at least annually in such form and detail as may be necessary to aid the office in determining whether Florida experience for workers’ compensation insurance is sufficient for establishing rates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer and self-insurance fund authorized to write a policy of workers’ compensation insurance shall transmit the following information annually on both Florida experience and nationwide experience separately:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payrolls by classification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manual premiums by classification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standard premiums by classification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Losses by classification and injury type.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A report of this information shall be filed no later than July 1 of each year. All reports shall be filed in accordance with standard reporting procedures for insurers, which procedures have received approval by the office, and shall contain data for the most recent policy period available. A statistical or rating organization may be used by insurers and self-insurance funds to report the data required by this section. The statistical or rating organization shall report each data element in the aggregate only for insurers and self-insurance funds required to report under this section who elect to have the organization report on their behalf. Such insurers and self-insurance funds shall be named in the report.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual self-insurers as defined in s. 440.02 shall report only Florida data as prescribed in paragraphs (2)(a)-(e) to the office.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall publish the dates and forms necessary to enable individual self-insurers to comply with this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statistical or rating organization may be used by individual self-insurers for the purposes of reporting the data required by this section and calculating experience ratings.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall provide a summary of information provided pursuant to subsection (2) in its annual report.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 78-300; s. 81, ch. 79-40; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 621, 625, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 120, ch. 83-216; s. 25, ch. 83-288; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 67, ch. 99-5; s. 36, ch. 2001-91; s. 68, ch. 2002-194; s. 1230, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 624.435.</Text></Note></Section>