<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.4091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Specific reasons for denial, cancellation, or nonrenewal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The denial of an application for an insurance policy must be accompanied by the specific reasons for denial, including the specific underwriting reasons, if applicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each notice of nonrenewal or cancellation must be accompanied by the specific reasons for nonrenewal or cancellation, including the specific underwriting reasons, if applicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No cause of action in the nature of defamation, invasion of privacy, or negligence shall arise against any person for disclosing personal or privileged information in accordance with this section, nor shall such a cause of action arise against any person for furnishing personal or privileged information to an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization; however, this section shall provide no immunity for disclosing or furnishing false information through gross negligence or with malice or willful intent to injure any person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of any other statute respecting disclosure of personal information control to the extent of any conflict with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an insurer refuses to provide private passenger automobile insurance or personal lines residential property insurance, including, but not limited to, homeowner’s, mobile home owner’s, condominium unit owner’s, or other insurance covering a personal residential structure, to an applicant due to adverse underwriting information, the insurer shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to the applicant specific information regarding the reasons for the refusal to insure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the reason for the refusal to insure is based on a loss underwriting history or report from a consumer reporting agency, to the extent applicable identify the loss underwriting history and notify the applicant of his or her right under the federal Fair and Accurate Credit Transactions Act to obtain a copy of the report from the consumer reporting agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 92-318; s. 12, ch. 2004-370; s. 157, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>