<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.758" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Surety on auto club traffic arrest bond; conditions, limit; bail bond.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any authorized surety insurer may, in any year, become surety in an amount not to exceed $1,000 with respect to any guaranteed traffic arrest bond certificate issued in such year by an automobile club or association by filing with the office an undertaking to become surety.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The undertaking shall be in the form prescribed by the commission and shall state the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the automobile club or association with respect to the guaranteed traffic arrest bond certificates for which the surety insurer undertakes to be surety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unqualified obligation of the surety insurer to pay the fine or forfeiture in an amount not to exceed $1,000 for any person who, after posting a guaranteed traffic arrest bond certificate with respect to which the insurer has undertaken to be surety, fails to make the appearance for which the certificate was posted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “guaranteed traffic arrest bond certificate” means any printed card or other certificate issued by the automobile club or association to any of its members, which card or certificate is signed by such member and contains a printed statement that such automobile club or association and a named surety company guarantee the appearance of the person whose signature appears on the card or certificate and that they will, in the event of failure of the person to appear in court at the time of trial, pay any traffic fine or forfeiture imposed on the person in an amount not to exceed $1,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 626.311 or chapter 648, any surety insurer identified in a guaranteed traffic arrest bond certificate or any licensed general lines agent of the surety insurer may execute a bail bond for the automobile club or association member identified in the guaranteed traffic arrest bond certificate in an amount not in excess of $5,000 for any violation of chapter 316 or any similar traffic law or ordinance except for driving under the influence of alcoholic beverages, chemical substances, or controlled substances, as prohibited by s. 316.193.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 618, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 571, 573, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 70, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 1, ch. 85-48; s. 23, ch. 86-296; s. 1, ch. 88-309; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1199, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>