<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.476" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Life Insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section shall be known as the “Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Life Insurance.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NONFORFEITURE PROVISIONS.<EmDash />In the case of policies issued on or after the operative date of this section as defined in subsection (14), no policy of life insurance, except as set forth in subsection (13), shall be delivered or issued for delivery in this state unless it contains in substance the following provisions, or corresponding provisions which in the opinion of the office are at least as favorable to the defaulting or surrendering policyholder as are the minimum requirements hereinafter specified and are essentially in compliance with subsection (12):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That in the event of default in any premium payment, after premiums have been paid for at least 1 full year in the case of ordinary insurance or 3 full years in the case of industrial insurance, the insurer will grant, upon proper request not later than 60 days after the due date of the premium in default, a paid-up nonforfeiture benefit on a plan stipulated in the policy, effective as of such due date, of such amount as may be hereinafter specified. In lieu of such stipulated paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, the company may substitute, upon proper request not later than 60 days after the due date of the premium in default, an actuarially equivalent alternative paid-up nonforfeiture benefit which provides a greater amount or longer period of death benefits or, if applicable, a greater amount or earlier payment of endowment benefits. With respect to all policy forms filed on or after October 1, 1990, the policy forms shall include, but not be limited to, a reduced paid-up nonforfeiture benefit. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “reduced paid-up nonforfeiture benefit” means a benefit whereby the policy may be continued at the option of the insured as reduced paid-up life insurance, the amount of which shall be as much as the surrender value of the policy will provide on the date of default, calculated using the surrender value of the policy as a net single premium on the due date of the first unpaid premium at the then-current age of the insured.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That upon surrender of the policy within 60 days after the due date of any premium payment in default after premiums have been paid for at least 3 full years in the case of ordinary insurance or 5 full years in the case of industrial insurance, the insurer will pay, in lieu of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, a cash surrender value of such amount as may be hereinafter specified.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a specified paid-up nonforfeiture benefit shall become effective as specified in the policy unless the person entitled to make such election elects another available option not later than 60 days after the due date of the premium in default.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That if the policy becomes paid up by completion of all premium payments, or if it is continued under any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit which became effective on or after the third policy anniversary in the case of ordinary insurance or the fifth policy anniversary in the case of industrial insurance, the insurer will pay, upon surrender of the policy within 30 days after any policy anniversary, a cash surrender value of such amount as may be hereinafter specified.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a policy which causes on a basis guaranteed in the policy unscheduled changes in benefits or premiums, or which provides an option for changes in benefits or premiums other than a change to a new policy, a statement of the mortality table, interest rate, and method used in calculating cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits available under the policy. In the case of any other policy, a statement of the mortality table and interest rate used in calculating the cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits available under the policy, together with a table showing the cash surrender value, if any, and paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, if any, available under the policy on each policy anniversary, either during the first 20 policy years or during the term of the policy, whichever is shorter, such values and benefits to be calculated upon the assumption that there are no dividends or paid-up additions credited to the policy and that there is no indebtedness to the insurer on the policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits available under the policy are not less than the minimum values and benefits required by or pursuant to the insurance law of this state; an explanation of the manner in which the cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits are altered by the existence of any paid-up additions credited to the policy or any indebtedness to the insurer on the policy; if a detailed statement of the method of computation of the values and benefits shown in the policy is not stated therein, a statement that such method of computation has been filed with the insurance supervisory official of the state in which the policy is delivered; and a statement of the method to be used in calculating the cash surrender value and paid-up nonforfeiture benefit available under the policy on any policy anniversary beyond the last anniversary for which such values and benefits are consecutively shown in the policy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OMITTED PROVISIONS.<EmDash />Any of the provisions or portions thereof set forth in paragraphs (2)(a)-(f) which are not applicable by reason of the plan of insurance may, to the extent inapplicable, be omitted from the policy. The insurer shall reserve the right to defer the payment of any cash surrender value for a period of 6 months after demand therefor with surrender of the policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CASH SURRENDER VALUE.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any cash surrender value available under the policy in the event of default in the premium payment due on any policy anniversary, whether or not required by subsection (2), shall be an amount not less than the excess, if any, of the present value on such anniversary of the future guaranteed benefits which would have been provided for by the policy, including any existing paid-up additions, if there had been no default, over the sum of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The then-present value of the adjusted premiums as defined in subsections (6) and (9), corresponding to premiums which would have fallen due on and after such anniversary, and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of any indebtedness to the insurer on account of or secured by the policy.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any policy issued on or after the operative date of subsection (9), as defined therein, which provides supplemental life insurance or annuity benefits at the option of the insured and for an identifiable additional premium by rider or supplemental policy provision, the cash surrender value referred to in paragraph (a) shall be an amount not less than the sum of the cash surrender value as defined in such paragraph for an otherwise similar policy issued at the same age without such rider or supplemental policy provision and the cash surrender value as defined in such paragraph for a policy which provides only the benefits otherwise provided by such rider or supplemental policy provision. For any family policy issued on or after the operative date of subsection (9), as defined therein, which defines a primary insured and provides term insurance on the life of the spouse of the primary insured expiring before the spouse reaches age 71, the cash surrender value referred to in paragraph (a) shall be an amount not less than the sum of the cash surrender value as defined in such paragraph for an otherwise similar policy issued at the same age without such term insurance on the life of the spouse and the cash surrender value as defined in such paragraph for a policy which provides only the benefits otherwise provided by such term insurance on the life of the spouse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any cash surrender value available within 30 days after any policy anniversary under any policy paid up by completion of all premium payments, or any policy continued under any paid-up nonforfeiture benefits, whether or not required by subsection (2), shall be an amount not less than the present value, on such anniversary, of the future guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy, including any existing paid-up additions, decreased by any indebtedness to the insurer on account of or secured by the policy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PAID-UP NONFORFEITURE BENEFITS.<EmDash />Any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit available under the policy in the event of default in the premium payment due on any policy anniversary shall be such that its present value as of such anniversary shall be at least equal to the cash surrender value then provided for by the policy, or, if none is provided for, that cash surrender value which would have been required by this section in the absence of the condition that premiums shall have been paid for at least a specified period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THE ADJUSTED PREMIUM.<EmDash />This subsection shall not apply to policies issued on or after the operative date of subsection (9), as defined therein. The adjusted premiums for any policy shall be calculated on an annual basis and shall be such uniform percentage of the respective premiums specified in the policy for each policy year, excluding extra premiums on a substandard policy, that the present value, at the date of issue of the policy, of all such adjusted premiums shall be equal to the sum of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The then-present value of the future guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two percent of the amount of the insurance if the insurance is uniform in amount, or of the equivalent uniform amount, as hereinafter defined, if the amount of insurance varies with the duration of the policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forty percent of the adjusted premium for the first policy year; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent of either the adjusted premium for the first policy year or the adjusted premium for a whole life policy of the same uniform or equivalent uniform amount with uniform premiums for the whole of life issued at the same age for the same amount of insurance, whichever is less.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, in applying the percentages specified in paragraphs (c) and (d), no adjusted premium shall be deemed to exceed 4 percent of the amount of insurance or uniform amount equivalent thereto. The date of issue of a policy for the purpose of this subsection shall be the date as of which the rated age of the insured is determined.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EQUIVALENT UNIFORM AMOUNT.<EmDash />This subsection shall not apply to policies issued on or after the operative date of subsection (9), as defined therein. In the case of a policy providing an amount of insurance varying with the duration of the policy, the equivalent uniform amount thereof for the purpose of subsection (6) shall be deemed to be the uniform amount of insurance provided by an otherwise similar policy, containing the same endowment benefit or benefits, if any, issued at the same age and for the same term, the amount of which does not vary with duration and the benefits under which have the same present value at the date of issue as the benefits under the policy, except that, in the case of a policy for a varying amount of insurance issued on the life of a child under age 10, the equivalent uniform amount may be computed as though the amount of insurance provided by the policy prior to the attainment of age 10 were the amount provided by such policy at age 10.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MORTALITY TABLES; INTEREST.<EmDash />This subsection shall not apply to policies issued on or after the operative date of subsection (9), as defined therein. All adjusted premiums and present values referred to in this section shall for all policies of ordinary insurance be calculated on the basis of the Commissioners’ 1958 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table, except that, for any category of such policies issued on female risks, adjusted premiums and present values may be calculated according to an age not more than 6 years younger than the actual age of the insured. Such calculations for all policies of industrial insurance shall be made on the basis of the following tables:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on and after the operative date of this section but before January 1, 1968, the 1941 Standard Industrial Mortality Table, unless the Commissioners’ 1961 Standard Industrial Mortality Table is applicable according to subsection (14);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on and after January 1, 1968, the Commissioners’ 1961 Standard Industrial Mortality Table.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">All calculations shall be made on the basis of the rate of interest specified in the policy for calculating cash surrender values and paid-up nonforfeiture benefits; however, such rate of interest shall not exceed 3.5 percent per year, except that a rate of interest not exceeding 4 percent per year may be used for policies issued on or after July 1, 1973, and prior to October 1, 1979, and a rate of interest not exceeding 4.5 percent per year may be used for policies issued on or after October 1, 1979, and a rate of interest not exceeding 5.5 percent per year may be used for policies issued on or after October 1, 1980. In calculating the present value of any paid-up term insurance with accompanying pure endowment, if any, offered as a nonforfeiture benefit, the rates of mortality assumed may be not more than those shown in the Commissioners’ 1958 Extended Term Insurance Table, for ordinary policies. In the case of industrial policies:</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on and after the operative date of this section but before January 1, 1968, not more than 130 percent of the rates of mortality according to the 1941 Standard Industrial Mortality Table, unless the Commissioners’ 1961 Industrial Extended Term Insurance Table is applicable according to subsection (14), in which case not more than those of the latter table;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For policies issued on and after January 1, 1968, not more than those of the Commissioners’ 1961 Industrial Extended Term Insurance Table.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For insurance issued on a substandard basis, the calculation of any such adjusted premiums and present values may be based on such other table of mortality as may be specified by the insurer and approved by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CALCULATION OF ADJUSTED PREMIUMS AND PRESENT VALUES FOR POLICIES ISSUED AFTER OPERATIVE DATE OF THIS SUBSECTION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall apply to all policies issued on or after the operative date of this subsection, as defined herein. Except as provided in paragraph (g), the adjusted premiums for any policy shall be calculated on an annual basis and shall be such uniform percentage of the respective premiums specified in the policy for each policy year, excluding amounts payable as extra premiums to cover impairments or special hazards and also excluding any uniform annual contract charge or policy fee specified in the policy in a statement of the method to be used in calculating the cash surrender values and paid-up nonforfeiture benefits, that the present value, at the date of issue of the policy, of all adjusted premiums shall be equal to the sum of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The then-present value of the future guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One percent of either the amount of insurance, if the insurance is uniform in amount, or the average amount of insurance at the beginning of each of the first 10 policy years; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred and twenty-five percent of the nonforfeiture net-level premium as hereinafter defined.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, in applying the percentage specified in subparagraph 3., no nonforfeiture net-level premium shall be deemed to exceed 4 percent of either the amount of insurance, if the insurance is uniform in amount, or the average amount of insurance at the beginning of each of the first 10 policy years. The date of issue of a policy for the purpose of this subsection shall be the date as of which the rated age of the insured is determined.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonforfeiture net-level premium shall be equal to the present value, at the date of issue of the policy, of the guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy divided by the present value, at the date of issue of the policy, of an annuity of one per annum payable on the date of issue of the policy and on each anniversary of such policy on which a premium falls due.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a policy which causes on a basis guaranteed in the policy unscheduled changes in benefits or premiums, or which provides an option for changes in benefits or premiums other than a change to a new policy, the adjusted premiums and present values shall initially be calculated on the assumption that future benefits and premiums do not change from those stipulated at the date of issue of the policy. At the time of any such change in the benefits or premiums, the future adjusted premiums, nonforfeiture net-level premiums, and present values shall be recalculated on the assumption that future benefits and premiums do not change from those stipulated by the policy immediately after the change.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (g), the recalculated future adjusted premiums for any such policy shall be such uniform percentage of the respective future premiums specified in the policy for each policy year, excluding amounts payable as extra premiums to cover impairments and special hazards, and also excluding any uniform annual contract charge or policy fee specified in the policy in a statement of the method to be used in calculating the cash surrender values and paid-up nonforfeiture benefits, that the present value, at the time of change to the newly defined benefits or premiums, of all such future adjusted premiums shall be equal to the excess of the sum of the then-present value of the then future guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy and the additional expense allowance, if any, over the then cash surrender value, if any, or present value of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit under the policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The additional expense allowance, at the time of the change to the newly defined benefits or premiums, shall be the sum of 1 percent of the excess, if positive, of the average amount of insurance at the beginning of each of the first 10 policy years subsequent to the change over the average amount of insurance prior to the change at the beginning of each of the first 10 policy years subsequent to the time of the most recent previous change, or, if there has been no previous change, the date of issue of the policy; and 125 percent of the increase, if positive, in the nonforfeiture net-level premium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recalculated nonforfeiture net-level premium shall be equal to the result obtained by dividing (A) and (B) where:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">(A) equals the sum of:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonforfeiture net-level premium applicable prior to the change times the present value of an annuity of one per annum payable on each anniversary of the policy on or subsequent to the date of the change on which a premium would have fallen due had the change not occurred, and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The present value of the increase in future guaranteed benefits provided for by the policy; and</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">(B) equals the present value of an annuity of one per annum payable on each anniversary of the policy on or subsequent to the date of change on which a premium falls due.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subsection to the contrary, in the case of a policy issued on a substandard basis which provides reduced graded amounts of insurance so that, in each policy year, such policy has the same tabular mortality cost as an otherwise similar policy issued on the standard basis which provides higher uniform amounts of insurance, adjusted premiums and present values for such substandard policy may be calculated as if it were issued to provide such higher uniform amounts of insurance on the standard basis.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All adjusted premiums and present values referred to in this section shall for all policies of ordinary insurance be calculated on the basis of the Commissioners’ 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table or, at the election of the insurer for any one or more specified plans of life insurance, the Commissioners’ 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table with Ten-Year Select Mortality Factors; shall for all policies of industrial insurance be calculated on the basis of the Commissioners’ 1961 Standard Industrial Mortality Table; and shall for all policies issued in a particular calendar year be calculated on the basis of a rate of interest not exceeding the nonforfeiture interest rate as defined in this subsection for policies issued in that calendar year. However:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the option of the insurer, calculations for all policies issued in a particular calendar year may be made on the basis of a rate of interest not exceeding the nonforfeiture interest rate, as defined in this subsection, for policies issued in the immediately preceding calendar year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, including any paid-up dividend additions, any cash surrender value available, whether or not required by subsection (2), shall be calculated on the basis of the mortality table and rate of interest used in determining the amount of such paid-up nonforfeiture benefit and paid-up dividend additions, if any.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may calculate the amount of any guaranteed paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, including any paid-up additions under the policy, on the basis of an interest rate no lower than that specified in the policy for calculating cash surrender values.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In calculating the present value of any paid-up term insurance with accompanying pure endowment, if any, offered as a nonforfeiture benefit, the rates of mortality assumed may be not more than those shown in the Commissioners’ 1980 Extended Term Insurance Table for policies of ordinary insurance and not more than the Commissioners’ 1961 Industrial Extended Term Insurance Table for policies of industrial insurance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of the mortality tables specified in this section, at the option of the insurance company and subject to rules adopted by the commission, the insurance company may substitute:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 1958 CSO or CET Smoker and Nonsmoker Mortality Tables, whichever is applicable, for policies issued on or after the operative date of this subsection and before January 1, 1989;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 1980 CSO or CET Smoker and Nonsmoker Mortality Tables, whichever is applicable, for policies issued on or after the operative date of this subsection;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mortality table that is a blend of the sex-distinct 1980 CSO or CET mortality table standard, whichever is applicable, or a mortality table that is a blend of the sex-distinct 1980 CSO or CET smoker and nonsmoker mortality table standards, whichever is applicable, for policies that are subject to the United States Supreme Court decision in <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Arizona Governing Committee v. Norris</Font> to prevent unfair discrimination in employment situations.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ordinary mortality tables, adopted after 1980 by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, adopted by rule by the commission for use in determining the minimum nonforfeiture standard may be substituted for the Commissioners’ 1980 Standard Ordinary Mortality Table with or without Ten-Year Select Mortality Factors or for the Commissioners’ 1980 Extended Term Insurance Table.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For insurance issued on a substandard basis, the calculation of any such adjusted premiums and present values may be based on appropriate modifications of the aforementioned tables.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonforfeiture interest rate per year for any policy issued in a particular calendar year shall be equal to 125 percent of the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for such policy as defined in the Standard Valuation Law, rounded to the nearest one-fourth of 1 percent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision in this code to the contrary, any refiling of nonforfeiture values or their methods of computation for any previously approved policy form which involves only a change in the interest rate or mortality table used to compute nonforfeiture values shall not require refiling of any other provisions of that policy form.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After October 1, 1981, any insurer may file with the office a written notice of its election to comply with the provisions of this subsection after a specified date before January 1, 1989, which shall be the operative date of this subsection for that insurer. If an insurer makes no such election, the operative date of this subsection for the insurer shall be January 1, 1989.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INDETERMINATE PREMIUMS OR MINIMUM VALUES.<EmDash />In the case of any plan of life insurance which provides for future premium determination, the amounts of which are to be determined by the insurer based on then estimates of future experience, or in the case of any plan of life insurance which is of such a nature that minimum values cannot be determined by the methods described in subsections (2)-(9):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office must be satisfied that the benefits provided under the plan are substantially as favorable to policyholders and insureds as the minimum benefits otherwise required by subsections (2)-(9);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office must be satisfied that the benefits and the pattern of premiums of that plan are not such as to mislead prospective policyholders or insureds; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cash surrender values and paid-up nonforfeiture benefits provided by such plan must not be less than the minimum values and benefits required for the plan computed by a method consistent with the principles of this Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Life Insurance, as determined by rules promulgated by the commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CALCULATION OF VALUES.<EmDash />Any cash surrender value and any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit available under the policy in the event of default in a premium payment due at any time other than on the policy anniversary shall be calculated with allowance for the lapse of time and the payment of fractional premiums beyond the last preceding policy anniversary. All values referred to in subsections (4)-(9) may be calculated upon the assumption that any death benefit is payable at the end of the policy year of death. The net value of any paid-up additions, other than paid-up term additions, shall be not less than the amounts used to provide such additions. If term insurance benefits are provided by a rider or by a supplemental policy provision to which, if issued as a separate policy, this section would apply, additional cash surrender values and additional paid-up nonforfeiture benefits, if any, at least equal to those required if issued as a separate policy, may be provided by the insurer and shall be deemed to be in compliance with this section. Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (4), additional benefits payable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of death or dismemberment by accident or accidental means,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of total and permanent disability,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As reversionary annuity or deferred reversionary annuity benefits,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As term insurance benefits provided by a rider or supplemental policy provision to which, if issued as a separate policy, this section would not apply,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As term insurance on the life of a child or on the lives of children provided in a policy on the life of a parent of the child, if such term insurance expires before the child’s age is 26, is uniform in amount after the child’s age is 1, and has not become paid up by reason of the death of a parent of the child, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As other policy benefits additional to life insurance by endowment benefits,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and premiums for all such additional benefits, shall be disregarded in ascertaining cash surrender values and nonforfeiture benefits required by this section; and no such additional benefits shall be required to be included in any paid-up nonforfeiture benefits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CALCULATION OF VALUES FOR POLICIES ISSUED AFTER 1984.<EmDash />This subsection, in addition to all other applicable subsections of this section, shall apply to all policies issued on or after January 1, 1985. Any cash surrender value available under the policy in the event of default in a premium payment due on any policy anniversary shall be in an amount which does not differ by more than 0.2 percent of either the amount of insurance, if the insurance is uniform in amount, or the average amount of insurance at the beginning of each of the first 10 policy years, from the sum of the greater of zero and the basic cash value hereinafter specified and the present value of any existing paid-up additions less the amount of any indebtedness to the insurer under the policy. The basic cash value shall be equal to the present value, on such anniversary, of the future guaranteed benefits which would have been provided for by the policy, excluding any existing paid-up additions and before deduction of any indebtedness to the insurer, if there had been no default, less the then-present value of the nonforfeiture factors, as hereinafter defined, corresponding to premiums which would have fallen due on and after such anniversary. However, the effects on the basic cash value of supplemental life insurance or annuity benefits or of family coverage, as described in subsection (4), shall be the same as are the effects specified in subsection (4) on the cash surrender values defined in that subsection. The nonforfeiture factor for each policy year shall be an amount equal to a percentage of the adjusted premium for the policy year, as defined in subsection (6) or subsection (9), whichever is applicable. Except as is required by the next succeeding sentence of this paragraph, such percentage:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be the same percentage for each policy year between the second policy anniversary and the later of the fifth policy anniversary and the first policy anniversary at which there is available under the policy a cash surrender value in an amount, before including any paid-up additions and before deducting any indebtedness, of at least 0.2 percent of either the amount of insurance, if the insurance is uniform in amount, or the average amount of insurance at the beginning of each of the first 10 policy years; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be such that no percentage after the later of the two policy anniversaries specified in paragraph (a) may apply to fewer than 5 consecutive policy years.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, no basic cash value may be less than the value which would be obtained if the adjusted premiums for the policy, as defined in subsection (6) or subsection (9), whichever is applicable, were substituted for the nonforfeiture factors in the calculation of the basic cash value. All adjusted premiums and present values referred to in this subsection shall be calculated for a particular policy on the same mortality and interest bases as are used in demonstrating the compliance of the policy with the other subsections of this law. The cash surrender values referred to in this subsection shall include any endowment benefits provided for by the policy. Any cash surrender value available other than in the event of default in a premium payment due on a policy anniversary, and the amount of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit available under the policy in the event of default in a premium payment, shall be determined in manners consistent with the manners specified for determining the analogous minimum amounts in subsections (2), (3), (4), (5), (9), and (11). The amounts of any cash surrender values and of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefits granted in connection with additional benefits such as those listed in paragraphs (11)(a)-(f) shall conform with the principles of this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXCEPTIONS.<EmDash />This section does not apply to any:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reinsurance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Group insurance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pure endowment contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annuity or reversionary annuity contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Term policy of uniform amount which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits, or renewal thereof, of, 20 years or less expiring before age 71, for which uniform premiums are payable during the entire term of the policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Term policy of decreasing amount which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits, on which each adjusted premium calculated as specified in subsections (6)-(9) is less than the adjusted premium so calculated on a policy of uniform amount which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits, or renewal thereof, issued at the same age and for the same initial amount of insurance for a term of 20 years or less expiring before age 71, for which uniform premiums are payable during the entire term of the policy; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policy which provides no guaranteed nonforfeiture or endowment benefits for which no cash surrender value, if any, or present value of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, at the beginning of any policy year, calculated as specified in subsections (4)-(9) exceeds 2.5 percent of the amount of insurance at the beginning of the same policy year.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of determining the applicability of this section, the age at expiry for a joint term life insurance policy shall be the age at expiry of the oldest life.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OPERATIVE DATE.<EmDash />After the effective date of this code, any insurer may file with the office a written notice or notices of its election to comply with the provisions of this section on and after a specified date or dates before January 1, 1966, as to either or both of its policies of ordinary and industrial insurance, in which case such specified date or dates shall be the operative date of this section with respect to such policies. The operative date of this section for policies of both ordinary and industrial insurance shall be the earlier of January 1, 1966, and any prior operative date or dates resulting from such previously filed written notices. With respect to policies of industrial insurance issued on and after the operative date of this section for such policies but before January 1, 1968, any insurer may file with the office written notice of its election to have the Commissioners’ 1961 Standard Industrial Mortality Table and the Commissioners’ 1961 Industrial Extended Term Insurance Table applicable with respect to subsection (8) for policies issued on and after the date specified in such election.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 503, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 61-106; ss. 2, 3, ch. 65-11; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 73-324; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 2, ch. 77-324; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 79-356; ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-137; ss. 5, 6, ch. 81-289; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 398, 404, 809(2nd), 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 54, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 13, ch. 90-119; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 10, ch. 97-292; s. 1130, ch. 2003-261; s. 14, ch. 2004-370; s. 159, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>