<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.426" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Claims administration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without limitation of any right or defense of an insurer otherwise, none of the following acts by or on behalf of an insurer shall be deemed to constitute a waiver of any provision of a policy or of any defense of the insurer thereunder:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acknowledgment of the receipt of notice of loss or claim under the policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnishing forms for reporting a loss or claim, for giving information relative thereto, or for making proof of loss, or receiving or acknowledging receipt of any such forms or proofs completed or uncompleted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigating any loss or claim under any policy or engaging in negotiations looking toward a possible settlement of any such loss or claim.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A liability insurer shall not be permitted to deny coverage based on a particular coverage defense unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after the liability insurer knew or should have known of the coverage defense, written notice of reservation of rights to assert a coverage defense is given to the named insured by registered or certified mail sent to the last known address of the insured or by hand delivery; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 60 days of compliance with paragraph (a) or receipt of a summons and complaint naming the insured as a defendant, whichever is later, but in no case later than 30 days before trial, the insurer:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gives written notice to the named insured by registered or certified mail of its refusal to defend the insured;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtains from the insured a nonwaiver agreement following full disclosure of the specific facts and policy provisions upon which the coverage defense is asserted and the duties, obligations, and liabilities of the insurer during and following the pendency of the subject litigation; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retains independent counsel which is mutually agreeable to the parties. Reasonable fees for the counsel may be agreed upon between the parties or, if no agreement is reached, shall be set by the court.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 475, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 375(1st), 377, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 53, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 97, ch. 83-216; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>