<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.4136" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonjoinder of insurers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be a condition precedent to the accrual or maintenance of a cause of action against a liability insurer by a person not an insured under the terms of the liability insurance contract that such person shall first obtain a settlement or verdict against a person who is an insured under the terms of such policy for a cause of action which is covered by such policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), any insurer who pays any taxable costs or attorney’s fees which would be recoverable by the insured but for the fact that such costs or fees were paid by the insurer shall be considered a party for the purpose of recovering such fees or costs. No person who is not an insured under the terms of a liability insurance policy shall have any interest in such policy, either as a third-party beneficiary or otherwise, prior to first obtaining a settlement or verdict against a person who is an insured under the terms of such policy for a cause of action which is covered by such policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurers are affirmatively granted the substantive right to insert in liability insurance policies contractual provisions that preclude persons who are not designated as insureds in such policies from joining a liability insurer as a party defendant with its insured prior to the rendition of a verdict. The contractual provisions authorized in this subsection shall be fully enforceable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time a judgment is entered or a settlement is reached during the pendency of litigation, a liability insurer may be joined as a party defendant for the purposes of entering final judgment or enforcing the settlement by the motion of any party, unless the insurer denied coverage under the provisions of s. 627.426(2) or defended under a reservation of rights pursuant to s. 627.426(2). A copy of the motion to join the insurer shall be served on the insurer by certified mail. If a judgment is reversed or remanded on appeal, the insurer’s presence shall not be disclosed to the jury in a subsequent trial.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 76-266; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 542, 563, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 38, ch. 90-119; ss. 37, 114, ch. 92-318.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 627.7262.</Text></Note></Section>