<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.915" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurer experience reporting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer transacting private passenger automobile insurance in this state shall report certain information annually to the office. The information will be due on or before July 1 of each year. The information shall be divided into the following categories: bodily injury liability; property damage liability; uninsured motorist; personal injury protection benefits; medical payments; comprehensive and collision. The information given shall be on direct insurance writings in the state alone and shall represent total limits data. The information set forth in paragraphs (a)-(f) is applicable to voluntary private passenger and Joint Underwriting Association private passenger writings and shall be reported for each of the latest 3 calendar-accident years, with an evaluation date of March 31 of the current year. The information set forth in paragraphs (g)-(j) is applicable to voluntary private passenger writings and shall be reported on a calendar-accident year basis ultimately seven times at seven different stages of development.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums earned for the latest 3 calendar-accident years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loss development factors and the historic development of those factors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholder dividends incurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses for other acquisition and general expense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses for agents’ commissions and taxes, licenses, and fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Profit and contingency factors as utilized in the insurer’s automobile rate filings for the applicable years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Losses paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Losses unpaid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loss adjustment expenses paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loss adjustment expenses unpaid.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer transacting fire, homeowner’s multiple peril, commercial multiple peril, medical malpractice, products liability, workers’ compensation, private passenger automobile liability, commercial automobile liability, private passenger automobile physical damage, commercial automobile physical damage, officers’ and directors’ liability insurance, or other liability insurance shall report, for each such line of insurance, the information specified in this subsection to the office. The information shall be reported for direct Florida business only and shall be reported on a calendar-year basis annually by April 1 for the preceding calendar year:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct premiums written.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct premiums earned.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loss reserves for all known claims:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At beginning of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At end of the year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves for losses incurred but not reported:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At beginning of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At end of the year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allocated loss adjustment expense:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserve at beginning of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserve at end of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paid during the year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unallocated loss adjustment expense:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserve at beginning of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserve at end of the year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paid during the year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct losses paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Underwriting income or loss.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commissions and brokerage fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taxes, licenses, and fees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other acquisition costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General expenses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholder dividends.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net investment gain or loss and other income gain or loss allocated pro rata by earned premium to Florida business utilizing the investment allocation formula contained in the National Association of Insurance Commissioner’s Profitability Report by line by state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no liability on the part of, and no cause of action of any nature shall arise against, any insurer reporting hereunder or its agents or employees or the office or its employees for any action taken by them pursuant to this section unless such action otherwise constitutes a violation of this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall provide a summary of information provided pursuant to subsections (1) and (2) in its annual report.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurer or insurer group which does not write at least 0.5 percent of the Florida market based on premiums written shall not have to file any report required by subsection (2) other than a report indicating its percentage of the market share. That percentage shall be calculated by dividing the current premiums written by the preceding year’s total premiums written in the state for that line of insurance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 622, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 71, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 121, ch. 83-216; s. 18, ch. 85-245; s. 2, ch. 86-140; s. 10, ch. 87-245; s. 18, ch. 90-119; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1231, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>