<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.982" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consolidation” means any transaction in which a financial institution or servicer makes its premium collection services available to its mortgage debtors in connection with a particular insurer’s (“new insurer”) offer of mortgage insurance, which offer is made to debtors who, immediately prior to the offer, had mortgage insurance with another insurer (“old insurer”) and were paying premiums for that insurance with their monthly mortgage payments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Financial institution” or “servicer” means any entity or organization that services mortgage loans by collecting and accounting for monthly mortgage payments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Loan transfer” means a transaction in which the servicing of a block of mortgage loans is transferred from one servicer to another.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgage” or “mortgage loan” means an indebtedness of more than 10 years’ duration which is secured by a first real estate mortgage and which is not subject to part IX.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgage insurance” means life, accidental death, or disability insurance, or any combination thereof, designed to pay off all or a part of a mortgage loan in the event of the insured’s death or disability.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“New coverage” or “new plan” means the mortgage insurance coverage or mortgage insurance plan for which the financial institution collects premiums beginning on the effective date of consolidation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Old coverage” or “old plan” means the mortgage insurance coverage or mortgage insurance plan the insured debtor had or participated in immediately prior to the consolidation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 90-149; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>