<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.641" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coverage for newborn children.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health insurance policy that provides coverage on an expense-incurred basis for a member of the family of the insured or subscriber shall, as to the family member’s coverage, also provide that the health insurance benefits applicable for children will be payable with respect to a newborn child of the insured or subscriber, or covered family member of the insured or subscriber, from the moment of birth. However, with respect to a newborn child of a covered family member other than the spouse of the insured or subscriber, the coverage for the newborn child terminates 18 months after the birth of the newborn child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coverage for newborn children required by this section consists of coverage for injury or sickness, including the necessary care or treatment of medically diagnosed congenital defects, birth abnormalities, or prematurity, and transportation costs of the newborn to and from the nearest available facility appropriately staffed and equipped to treat the newborn’s condition, when such transportation is certified by the attending physician as necessary to protect the health and safety of the newborn child. The coverage of such transportation costs may not exceed the usual and customary charges, up to $1,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to disability income or hospital indemnity policies or to normal maternity policy provisions applicable to the mother.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A policy may require the insured, subscriber, or covered family member to notify the insurer of the birth of a child within a time period, as specified in the policy, of not less than 30 days after the birth. If timely notice is given, the insurer may not charge an additional premium for coverage of the newborn child for the duration of the notice period. If timely notice is not given, the insurer may charge an additional premium from the date of birth. The insurer may not deny coverage for a child due to the failure of the insured to timely notify the insurer of the birth of the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the policy does not require the insured to notify the insurer of the birth of a child within a specified time period, the insurer may not deny coverage for such child or retroactively charge the insured an additional premium for such child. However, the insurer may prospectively charge the insured an additional premium for the child if the insurer provides at least 45 days’ notice of the additional premium required.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 72-82; s. 1, ch. 74-8; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 1, ch. 80-177; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 490, 497, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 1, ch. 84-202; ss. 123, 149, ch. 92-33; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>