<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.65625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibiting discrimination against individual participants and beneficiaries based on health status.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsection (2), an insurer that offers a group health insurance policy may not establish rules for eligibility, including continued eligibility, of an individual to enroll under the terms of the policy based on any of the following health-status-related factors in relation to the individual or a dependent of the individual:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical condition, including physical and mental illnesses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims experience.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receipt of health care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical history.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Genetic information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of insurability, including conditions arising out of acts of domestic violence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disability.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) does not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require an insurer to provide particular benefits other than those provided under the terms of such plan or coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevent such a plan or coverage from establishing limitations or restrictions on the amount, level, extent, or nature of the benefits or coverage for similarly situated individuals enrolled in the plan or coverage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of subsection (1), rules for eligibility to enroll under a policy include rules for defining any applicable waiting periods of enrollment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer that offers health insurance coverage may not require any individual, as a condition of enrollment or continued enrollment under the policy, to pay a premium or contribution that is greater than such premium or contribution for a similarly situated individual enrolled under the policy on the basis of any health-status-related factor in relation to the individual or to an individual enrolled under the policy as a dependent of the individual.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restrict the amount that an employer may be charged for coverage under a group health insurance policy; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevent an insurer that offers group health insurance coverage from establishing premium discounts or rebates or modifying otherwise applicable copayments or deductibles in return for adherence to programs of health promotion and disease prevention.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 97-179.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 34(2), ch. 97-179, provides that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Except as provided in section 627.6561(9), (10), and (11), and section 641.31071(10), (11), and (12), Florida Statutes, in the case of a group health plan or group health insurance contract maintained pursuant to one or more collective bargaining agreements between employee representatives and one or more employers which is ratified before this act becomes a law, sections 627.6561, 627.65615, 627.65625, 627.6571, 627.6699, 641.31071, 641.31072, 641.31073, and 641.31074, Florida Statutes, except for section 627.6561(8)(b), Florida Statutes, as amended or created by this act, apply to policies or contracts with plan years that begin on or after the later of:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(a) The date on which the last of any collective bargaining agreement that relates to the plan terminates, determined without regard to any extension thereof, which is agreed to after the date this act becomes a law; or</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(b) July 1, 1997.”</Text></Note></Section>