<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.4301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Genetic information for insurance purposes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Genetic information” means information derived from genetic testing to determine the presence or absence of variations or mutations, including carrier status, in an individual’s genetic material or genes that are scientifically or medically believed to cause a disease, disorder, or syndrome, or are associated with a statistically increased risk of developing a disease, disorder, or syndrome, which is asymptomatic at the time of testing. Such testing does not include routine physical examinations or chemical, blood, or urine analysis, unless conducted purposefully to obtain genetic information, or questions regarding family history.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health insurer” means an authorized insurer offering health insurance as defined in s. 624.603, a self-insured plan as defined in s. 624.031, a multiple-employer welfare arrangement as defined in s. 624.437, a prepaid limited health service organization as defined in s. 636.003, a health maintenance organization as defined in s. 641.19, a prepaid health clinic as defined in s. 641.402, a fraternal benefit society as defined in s. 632.601, or any health care arrangement whereby risk is assumed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OF GENETIC INFORMATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of a diagnosis of a condition related to genetic information, no health insurer authorized to transact insurance in this state may cancel, limit, or deny coverage, or establish differentials in premium rates, based on such information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health insurers may not require or solicit genetic information, use genetic test results, or consider a person’s decisions or actions relating to genetic testing in any manner for any insurance purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to the underwriting or issuance of a life insurance policy, disability income policy, long-term care policy, accident-only policy, hospital indemnity or fixed indemnity policy, dental policy, or vision policy or any other actions of an insurer directly related to a life insurance policy, disability income policy, long-term care policy, accident-only policy, hospital indemnity or fixed indemnity policy, dental policy, or vision policy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-182; s. 43, ch. 2000-256; s. 10, ch. 2000-296.</History></Section>