<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delivery of policy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the insurer’s requirement as to payment of premium, every policy shall be mailed or delivered to the insured or to the person entitled thereto not later than 60 days after the effectuation of coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the original policy is delivered or is so required to be delivered to or for deposit with any vendor, mortgagee, or pledgee of any motor vehicle, and in which policy any interest of the vendee, mortgagor, or pledgor in or with reference to such vehicle is insured, a duplicate of such policy setting forth the name and address of the insurer, insurance classification of vehicle, type of coverage, limits of liability, premiums for the respective coverages, and duration of the policy, or memorandum thereof containing the same such information, shall be delivered by the vendor, mortgagee, or pledgee to each such vendee, mortgagor, or pledgor named in the policy or coming within the group of persons designated in the policy to be so included. If the policy does not provide coverage of legal liability for injury to persons or damage to the property of third parties, a statement of such fact shall be printed, written, or stamped conspicuously on the face of such duplicate policy or memorandum. This subsection does not apply to inland marine floater policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any automobile liability or physical damage policy shall contain on the front page a summary of major coverages, conditions, exclusions, and limitations contained in that policy. Any such summary shall state that the issued policy should be referred to for the actual contractual governing provisions. The company may, in lieu of the summary, provide a readable policy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 470, ch. 59-205; s. 1, ch. 75-218; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 377, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 18, ch. 86-160; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>