<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.623" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance with other insurers; other benefits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract may include the following provision:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">“Insurance With Other Insurers: If there is other valid coverage, not with this insurer, providing benefits for the same loss on other than an expense-incurred basis and of which this insurer has not been given written notice prior to the occurrence or commencement of loss, the only liability for such benefits under this policy shall be for such proportion of the indemnities otherwise provided hereunder for such loss as the like indemnities of which the insurer had notice (including the indemnities under this policy) bear to the total amount of all like indemnities for such loss, and for the return of such portion of the premium paid as shall exceed the pro rata portion for the indemnities thus determined.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the foregoing policy provision is included in a policy which also contains the policy provision set out in s. 627.622, there shall be added to the caption of the foregoing provision the phrase: “<EmDash />Other Benefits.” The insurer may, at its option, include in this provision a definition of “other valid coverage,” approved as to form by the office, which definition shall be limited to coverage provided by organizations subject to regulation by the insurance law of any jurisdiction. In the absence of such definition, such term does not include group insurance, or benefits provided by union welfare plans or by employer or employee benefit organizations. Any benefit provided for an insured pursuant to any compulsory benefit statute shall in all cases be deemed to be “other valid coverage” of which the insurer has had notice. In applying the foregoing policy provision, no third-party liability coverage shall be included as “other valid coverage.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 566, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 111, ch. 79-40; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 473, 497, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1147, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>