<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0627.6745" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Loss ratio standards; public rate hearings.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicare supplement policies shall return the following to policyholders in the form of aggregate benefits under the policy, with respect to the lifetime of the policy, on the basis of earned premiums and on the basis of incurred claims experience or, if coverage is provided by a health maintenance organization based on service rather than reimbursement, incurred health care expenses, and in accordance with accepted actuarial principles and practices:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 75 percent of the aggregate amount of premiums earned in the case of group policies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For individual policies issued or renewed prior to July 1, 1989, at least 60 percent of the aggregate amount of premiums earned and for individual policies issued on or after July 1, 1989, at least 65 percent of the aggregate amount of premiums earned. For the purposes of this section, policies issued as a result of solicitations of individuals through the mail or by mass media advertising shall be deemed to be individual policies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each entity providing Medicare supplement policies or certificates in this state shall file annually its rates, rating schedules, and supporting documentation demonstrating that it is in compliance with the applicable loss ratio standards of this code. The filing of rates and rating schedules shall demonstrate that the actual and expected losses in relation to premiums comply with the requirements of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, a policy form complies with the loss ratio standards if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the most recent year, the ratio of the incurred losses to earned premiums for policies or certificates which have been in force for 3 years or more is greater than or equal to the applicable percentages contained in this section; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expected losses in relation to premiums over the lifetime of the policy comply with the requirements of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">An expected third-year loss ratio that is greater than or equal to the applicable percentage must be demonstrated for policies or certificates in force less than 3 years. Loss ratios shall be calculated in accordance with a uniform methodology, including uniform reporting standards specified by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners pursuant to the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (Pub. L. No. 101-508).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer providing Medicare supplement insurance to residents of this state shall annually submit to the office information on actual loss ratios on forms prescribed by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners pursuant to the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 (Pub. L. No. 101-508).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer providing Medicare supplement insurance to residents of this state shall provide a proportional refund, or a credit against future premiums of a proportional amount, based on premiums paid or based on the amount of premiums received necessary to assure that the loss ratio (net of any refunds or credits) complies with the loss ratio requirements. Such refunds or credits shall be applied to each type of policy by policy form number, and shall not apply for the first 2 years of a policy. The refund or credit shall be made to each policyholder insured under the policy as of the last day of the year involved. The refund or credit shall include interest from the end of the policy year involved until the date of the refund or credit at a rate that is not less than the average rate of interest for 13-week Treasury notes. Refunds or credits against premiums due shall be made no later than the third quarter of the succeeding policy year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer providing Medicare supplement insurance to residents of this state shall maintain and make available to interested persons a copy of each Medicare supplement policy, its most recent premium, and its loss ratios for the most recent 3-year period.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt a written policy statement regarding the holding of public hearings prior to approval of any premium increases for Medicare supplement insurance policies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an insurer that enters into a network agreement pursuant to s. 627.6741(6), the waiver of the Medicare Part A deductible and premium credit shall be factored into the insurer’s loss-ratio calculation and policy premium.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 88-338; s. 5, ch. 89-296; s. 95, ch. 89-360; s. 17, ch. 91-296; ss. 145, 149, ch. 92-33; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1177, ch. 2003-261; s. 8, ch. 2010-175.</History>
</Section>