<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.7283" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cancellation; return of premium.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insured cancels a policy of motor vehicle insurance, the insurer must mail the unearned portion of any premium paid within 30 days after the effective date of the policy cancellation or receipt of notice or request for cancellation, whichever is later. This requirement applies to a cancellation initiated by an insured for any reason.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an insurer cancels a policy of motor vehicle insurance, the insurer must mail the unearned premium portion of any premium within 15 days after the effective date of the policy cancellation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the unearned premium is not mailed within the applicable period, the insurer must pay to the insured 8 percent interest on the amount due. If the unearned premium is not mailed within 45 days after the applicable period, the insured may bring an action against the insurer pursuant to s. 624.155.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insured cancels, the insurer may retain up to 10 percent of the unearned premium and must refund at least 90 percent of the unearned premium. If the insurer cancels, the insurer must refund 100 percent of the unearned premium. Cancellation is without prejudice to any claim originating prior to the effective date of the cancellation. For purposes of this section, unearned premiums must be computed on a pro rata basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer must refund 100 percent of the unearned premium if the insured is a servicemember, as defined in s. 250.01, who cancels because he or she is called to active duty or transferred by the United States Armed Forces to a location where the insurance is not required. The insurer may require a servicemember to submit either a copy of the official military orders or a written verification signed by the servicemember’s commanding officer to support the refund authorized under this subsection. If the insurer cancels, the insurer must refund 100 percent of the unearned premium. Cancellation is without prejudice to any claim originating prior to the effective date of the cancellation. For purposes of this section, unearned premiums must be computed on a pro rata basis.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 86-262; s. 2, ch. 87-50; ss. 82, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 7, ch. 2002-282; s. 18, ch. 2003-72.</History></Section>