<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.681" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Term and evidence of insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of credit life insurance coverages shall not extend more than 15 days beyond the term of the indebtedness, except when extended without additional cost to the insured borrower or purchaser; and in no event shall the term of the insurance policy exceed 10 years from the date of issue thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of credit disability insurance on any debtor insured under this section shall not exceed the term of indebtedness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 627.6785(3), the term of credit life or credit disability insurance may be for less than the term of the indebtedness. However, except for the age limitations referred to in s. 627.6785(3), the term shall extend for at least 5 years or for the term of the indebtedness, whichever is less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All credit insurance sold shall be evidenced by a policy, certificate, or statement of insurance, which shall be delivered to the insured borrower or purchaser. Upon acceptance of the insurance by the insurer and within 60 days of the date upon which the indebtedness is incurred, the insurer shall cause the individual policy or group certificates of insurance to be delivered to the debtor. The policy, certificate, or statement of insurance shall set forth a description of the coverage, including any exceptions, limitations, or restrictions, and the amount of the premium in the case of individual or franchise insurance, or the amount of any identifiable charge in the case of group insurance, except that, in the case of group insurance, in lieu of setting forth the amount of identifiable charge in the certificate or statement of insurance, such identifiable charge may be set forth in an instrument in writing, which shall be delivered to the insured borrower or purchaser. The policy group certificate or statement of insurance shall state that the benefits shall be paid to the creditor to reduce or extinguish the unpaid indebtedness and, whenever the amount exceeds the unpaid indebtedness, any such excess shall be payable to a beneficiary, other than the creditor, named by the debtor, or to his or her estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the named insurer does not accept the risk and coverage is accepted by another insurer, the debtor shall receive a policy or certificate of insurance setting forth the name and home office address of the substituted insurer and the amount of the premium to be charged; and, if the amount of premium is less than that set forth in the notice of proposed insurance, an appropriate refund shall be made.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 600, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 71-150; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 5, 7, ch. 80-387; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 533, 537, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 354, ch. 97-102; s. 83, ch. 98-199; s. 6, ch. 2008-75.</History></Section>