<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.410" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filing, approval of forms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No basic insurance policy or annuity contract form, or application form where written application is required and is to be made a part of the policy or contract, or group certificates issued under a master contract delivered in this state, or printed rider or endorsement form or form of renewal certificate, shall be delivered or issued for delivery in this state, unless the form has been filed with the office by or in behalf of the insurer which proposes to use such form and has been approved by the office. This provision does not apply to surety bonds or to policies, riders, endorsements, or forms of unique character which are designed for and used with relation to insurance upon a particular subject (other than as to health insurance), or which relate to the manner of distribution of benefits or to the reservation of rights and benefits under life or health insurance policies and are used at the request of the individual policyholder, contract holder, or certificateholder. As to group insurance policies effectuated and delivered outside this state but covering persons resident in this state, the group certificates to be delivered or issued for delivery in this state shall be filed with the office for information purposes only.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every such filing must be made not less than 30 days in advance of any such use or delivery. At the expiration of such 30 days, the form so filed will be deemed approved unless prior thereto it has been affirmatively approved or disapproved by order of the office. The approval of any such form by the office constitutes a waiver of any unexpired portion of such waiting period. The office may extend by not more than an additional 15 days the period within which it may so affirmatively approve or disapprove any such form, by giving notice of such extension before expiration of the initial 30-day period. At the expiration of any such period as so extended, and in the absence of such prior affirmative approval or disapproval, any such form shall be deemed approved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, for cause, withdraw a previous approval. No insurer shall issue or use any form disapproved by the office, or as to which the office has withdrawn approval, after the effective date of the order of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, by order, exempt from the requirements of this section for so long as it deems proper any insurance document or form or type thereof as specified in such order, to which, in its opinion, this section may not practicably be applied, or the filing and approval of which are, in its opinion, not desirable or necessary for the protection of the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section also applies to any such form used by domestic insurers for delivery in a jurisdiction outside this state if the insurance supervisory official of such jurisdiction informs the office that such form is not subject to approval or disapproval by such official, and upon the order of the office requiring the form to be submitted to it for the purpose. The applicable same standards apply to such forms as apply to forms for domestic use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer shall not deliver or issue for delivery or renew in this state any health insurance policy form until it has filed with the office a copy of every applicable rating manual, rating schedule, change in rating manual, and change in rating schedule; if rating manuals and rating schedules are not applicable, the insurer must file with the office applicable premium rates and any change in applicable premium rates. This paragraph does not apply to group health insurance policies, effectuated and delivered in this state, insuring groups of 51 or more persons, except for Medicare supplement insurance, long-term care insurance, and any coverage under which the increase in claim costs over the lifetime of the contract due to advancing age or duration is prefunded in the premium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may establish by rule, for each type of health insurance form, procedures to be used in ascertaining the reasonableness of benefits in relation to premium rates and may, by rule, exempt from any requirement of paragraph (a) any health insurance policy form or type thereof (as specified in such rule) to which form or type such requirements may not be practically applied or to which form or type the application of such requirements is not desirable or necessary for the protection of the public. With respect to any health insurance policy form or type thereof which is exempted by rule from any requirement of paragraph (a), premium rates filed pursuant to ss. 627.640 and 627.662 shall be for informational purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every filing made pursuant to this subsection shall be made within the same time period provided in, and shall be deemed to be approved under the same conditions as those provided in, subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every filing made pursuant to this subsection, except disability income policies and accidental death policies, shall be prohibited from applying the following rating practices:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Select and ultimate premium schedules.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premium class definitions which classify insured based on year of issue or duration since issue.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attained age premium structures on policy forms under which more than 50 percent of the policies are issued to persons age 65 or over.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 1., an insurer shall continue to make available for purchase any individual policy form issued on or after October 1, 1993. A policy form shall not be considered to be available for purchase unless the insurer has actively offered it for sale in the previous 12 months.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may discontinue the availability of a policy form if the insurer provides to the office in writing its decision at least 30 days prior to discontinuing the availability of the form of the policy or certificate. After receipt of the notice by the office, the insurer shall no longer offer for sale the policy form or certificate form in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer that discontinues the availability of a policy form pursuant to subparagraph 1. shall not file for approval a new policy form providing similar benefits as the discontinued form for a period of 5 years after the insurer provides notice to the office of the discontinuance. The period of discontinuance may be reduced if the office determines that a shorter period is appropriate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The experience of all policy forms providing similar benefits shall be combined for all rating purposes.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer subject to the requirements of subsection (6) shall make an annual filing with the office no later than 12 months after its previous filing, demonstrating the reasonableness of benefits in relation to premium rates. The office, after receiving a request to be exempted from the provisions of this section, may, for good cause due to insignificant numbers of policies in force or insignificant premium volume, exempt a company, by line of coverage, from filing rates or rate certification as required by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing required by this subsection shall be satisfied by one of the following methods:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rate filing prepared by an actuary which contains documentation demonstrating the reasonableness of benefits in relation to premiums charged in accordance with the applicable rating laws and rules promulgated by the commission.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no rate change is proposed, a filing which consists of a certification by an actuary that benefits are reasonable in relation to premiums currently charged in accordance with applicable laws and rules promulgated by the commission.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “actuary” means an individual who is a member of the Society of Actuaries or the American Academy of Actuaries. If an insurer does not employ or otherwise retain the services of an actuary, the insurer’s certification shall be prepared by insurer personnel or consultants with a minimum of 5 years’ experience in insurance ratemaking. The chief executive officer of the insurer shall review and sign the certification indicating his or her agreement with its conclusions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If at the time a filing is required under this section an insurer is in the process of completing a rate review, the insurer may apply to the office for an extension of up to an additional 30 days in which to make the filing. The request for extension must be received by the office no later than the date the filing is due.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an insurer fails to meet the filing requirements of this subsection and does not submit the filing within 60 days following the date the filing is due, the office may, in addition to any other penalty authorized by law, order the insurer to discontinue the issuance of policies for which the required filing was not made, until such time as the office determines that the required filing is properly submitted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of subsections (6) and (7), benefits of an individual accident and health insurance policy form, including Medicare supplement policies as defined in s. 627.672, when authorized by rules adopted by the commission, and excluding long-term care insurance policies as defined in s. 627.9404, and other policy forms under which more than 50 percent of the policies are issued to individuals age 65 and over, are deemed to be reasonable in relation to premium rates if the rates are filed pursuant to a loss ratio guarantee and both the initial rates and the durational and lifetime loss ratios have been approved by the office, and such benefits shall continue to be deemed reasonable for renewal rates while the insurer complies with such guarantee, provided the currently expected lifetime loss ratio is not more than 5 percent less than the filed lifetime loss ratio as certified to by an actuary. The office shall have the right to bring an administrative action should it deem that the lifetime loss ratio will not be met. For Medicare supplement filings, the office may withdraw a previously approved filing which was made pursuant to a loss ratio guarantee if it determines that the filing is not in compliance with ss. 627.671-627.675 or the currently expected lifetime loss ratio is less than the filed lifetime loss ratio as certified by an actuary in the initial guaranteed loss ratio filing. If this section conflicts with ss. 627.671-627.675, ss. 627.671-627.675 shall control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The renewal premium rates shall be deemed to be approved upon filing with the office if the filing is accompanied by the most current approved loss ratio guarantee. The loss ratio guarantee shall be in writing, shall be signed by an officer of the insurer, and shall contain at least:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recitation of the anticipated lifetime and durational target loss ratios contained in the actuarial memorandum filed with the policy form when it was originally approved. The durational target loss ratios shall be calculated for 1-year experience periods. If statutory changes have rendered any portion of such actuarial memorandum obsolete, the loss ratio guarantee shall also include an amendment to the actuarial memorandum reflecting current law and containing new lifetime and durational loss ratio targets.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guarantee that the applicable loss ratios for the experience period in which the new rates will take effect, and for each experience period thereafter until new rates are filed, will meet the loss ratios referred to in subparagraph 1.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guarantee that the applicable loss ratio results for the experience period will be independently audited at the insurer’s expense. The audit shall be performed in the second calendar quarter of the year following the end of the experience period, and the audited results shall be reported to the office no later than the end of such quarter. The commission shall establish by rule the minimum information reasonably necessary to be included in the report. The audit shall be done in accordance with accepted accounting and actuarial principles.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guarantee that affected policyholders in this state shall be issued a proportional refund, based on the premium earned, of the amount necessary to bring the applicable experience period loss ratio up to the durational target loss ratio referred to in subparagraph 1. The refund shall be made to all policyholders in this state who are insured under the applicable policy form as of the last day of the experience period, except that no refund need be made to a policyholder in an amount less than $10. Refunds less than $10 shall be aggregated and paid pro rata to the policyholders receiving refunds. The refund shall include interest at the then-current variable loan interest rate for life insurance policies established by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, from the end of the experience period until the date of payment. Payments shall be made during the third calendar quarter of the year following the experience period for which a refund is determined to be due. However, no refunds shall be made until 60 days after the filing of the audit report in order that the office has adequate time to review the report.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guarantee that if the applicable loss ratio exceeds the durational target loss ratio for that experience period by more than 20 percent, provided there are at least 2,000 policyholders on the form nationwide or, if not, then accumulated each calendar year until 2,000 policyholder years is reached, the insurer, if directed by the office, shall withdraw the policy form for the purposes of issuing new policies.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Loss ratio” means the ratio of incurred claims to earned premium.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicable loss ratio” means the loss ratio attributable solely to this state if there are 2,000 or more policyholders in the state. If there are 500 or more policyholders in this state but less than 2,000, it is the linear interpolation of the nationwide loss ratio and the loss ratio for this state. If there are less than 500 policyholders in this state, it is the nationwide loss ratio.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Experience period” means the period, ordinarily a calendar year, for which a loss ratio guarantee is calculated.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 459, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 71-17; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 364, 377, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 2, ch. 84-235; s. 3, ch. 89-360; s. 20, ch. 90-249; s. 12, ch. 90-366; s. 1, ch. 91-73; ss. 32, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 62, ch. 93-129; s. 22, ch. 93-260; s. 325, ch. 97-102; s. 3, ch. 98-159; s. 4, ch. 98-173; s. 5, ch. 2002-282; s. 1112, ch. 2003-261; s. 20, ch. 2004-297.</History></Section>