<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.4585" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Maximum rate of interest on policy loans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the “published monthly average” means the value of the interest rate index, as defined in s. 625.121(6)(e).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policies issued on or after October 1, 1981, shall provide for policy loan interest rates through:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision permitting a maximum interest rate of not more than 10 percent a year; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision permitting an adjustable maximum interest rate established from time to time by the life insurer as permitted by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate of interest charged on a policy loan made under paragraph (2)(b) shall not exceed the higher of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The published monthly average for the calendar month ending 2 months before the date on which the rate is determined; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate used to compute the cash surrender values under the policy during the applicable period plus 1 percent a year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the maximum rate of interest is determined pursuant to paragraph (2)(b), the policy shall contain a provision setting forth the frequency at which the rate is to be determined for that policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum rate for each policy must be determined at regular intervals at least once every 12 months, but not more frequently than once in any 3-month period. At the intervals specified in the policy:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate being charged may be increased whenever such increase as determined under subsection (3) would increase that rate by 50 basis points or more a year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate being charged must be reduced whenever such reduction as determined under subsection (3) would decrease that rate by 50 basis points or more a year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The life insurer shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the policyholder at the time a cash loan is made of the initial rate of interest on the loan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the policyholder with respect to premium loans of the initial rate of interest on the loan as soon as it is reasonably practicable to do so after making the initial loan. Notice need not be given to the policyholder when a further premium loan is added, except as provided in paragraph (c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Send to policyholders with loans reasonable advance notice of any increase or decrease in the rate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include in the notices required in this section the substance of the pertinent provisions of subsections (2) and (4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No policy shall terminate in a policy year as the sole result of a change in the interest rate during that policy year, and the life insurer shall maintain coverage during that policy year until the time at which it would otherwise have terminated if there had been no change during that policy year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The substance of the pertinent provisions of subsections (2) and (4) shall be set forth in the policies to which they apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate of interest on policy loans permitted under this section includes the interest rate charged on reinstatement of policy loans for the period during and after any lapse of a policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “policy loan” includes any premium loan made under a policy to pay one or more premiums that were not paid to the life insurer as they fell due.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “policyholder” includes the owner of the policy or the person designated to pay premiums as shown on the records of the life insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “policy” includes certificates issued by a fraternal benefit society and annuity contracts which provide for policy loans.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No other provision of law shall apply to policy loan interest rates unless made specifically applicable to such rates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 6, ch. 81-289; ss. 386, 809(2nd), 810, ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 65, ch. 91-108; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>