<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.7842" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Policy exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a survey meeting the minimum technical standards for surveying required by the Department of Business and Professional Regulation and certified to the title insurer by a registered Florida surveyor has been completed on the property within 90 days before the date of closing, the title policy may only except from coverage the encroachments, overlays, boundary line disputes, and other matters which are actually shown on the survey.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If at closing the seller signs an affidavit swearing that there is no person in possession of the property or with a claim of possession to the property except the seller, the title policy may not exclude from coverage rights or claims of parties in possession not shown by the public records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If at closing the seller signs an affidavit swearing that no improvements have been made to the property within the past 90 days for which payment has not been made in full, the title policy may not except from coverage any lien or right to a lien for services, labor, or material furnished which is imposed by law and not shown by the public record.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The title insurer, agent, or agency issuing the title policy may except from coverage the items specified in subsection (1) if the title insurer, agent, or agency has knowledge of facts requiring the exceptions, notwithstanding the survey or affidavits, if the insurer, agent, or agency discloses such facts to the proposed insured.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 85-20; s. 1, ch. 86-286; ss. 100, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 225, ch. 94-218; s. 17, ch. 99-286.</History></Section>