<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.70161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Family day care insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE AND INTENT.<EmDash />The Legislature recognizes that family day care homes fulfill a vital role in providing child care in Florida. It is the intent of the Legislature that residential property insurance coverage should not be canceled, denied, or nonrenewed solely on the basis of the family day care services at the residence. The Legislature also recognizes that the potential liability of residential property insurers is substantially increased by the rendition of child care services on the premises. The Legislature therefore finds that there is a public need to specify that contractual liabilities that arise in connection with the operation of the family day care home are excluded from residential property insurance policies unless they are specifically included in such coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child care” means the care, protection, and supervision of a child, for a period of less than 24 hours a day on a regular basis, which supplements parental care, enrichment, and health supervision for the child, in accordance with his or her individual needs, and for which a payment, fee, or grant is made for care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Family day care home” means an occupied residence in which child care is regularly provided for children from at least two unrelated families and which receives a payment, fee, or grant for any of the children receiving care, whether or not operated for a profit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAMILY DAY CARE; COVERAGE.<EmDash />A residential property insurance policy shall not provide coverage for liability for claims arising out of, or in connection with, the operation of a family day care home, and the insurer shall be under no obligation to defend against lawsuits covering such claims, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifically covered in a policy; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Covered by a rider or endorsement for business coverage attached to a policy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DENIAL, CANCELLATION, REFUSAL TO RENEW PROHIBITED.<EmDash />An insurer may not deny, cancel, or refuse to renew a policy for residential property insurance solely on the basis that the policyholder or applicant operates a family day care home. In addition to other lawful reasons for refusing to insure, an insurer may deny, cancel, or refuse to renew a policy of a family day care home provider if one or more of the following conditions occur:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policyholder or applicant provides care for more children than authorized for family day care homes by s. 402.302;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policyholder or applicant fails to maintain a separate commercial liability policy or an endorsement providing liability coverage for the family day care home operations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policyholder or applicant fails to comply with the family day care home licensure and registration requirements specified in s. 402.313; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discovery of willful or grossly negligent acts or omissions or any violations of state laws or regulations establishing safety standards for family day care homes by the named insured or his or her representative which materially increase any of the risks insured.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-6; s. 43, ch. 99-7.</History></Section>