<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0627.777" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Approval of forms.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A title insurer may not issue or agree to issue any form of title insurance commitment, title insurance policy, other contract of title insurance, or related form until it is filed with and approved by the office. The office may not disapprove a title guarantee or policy form on the ground that it has on it a blank form for an attorney’s opinion on the title.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall approve or disapprove a form filed for approval within 180 days after receipt.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the office approves any form, it shall determine if the current rate in effect applies or if the coverages require the adoption of a rule pursuant to s. 627.782.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may revoke approval of any form after providing 180 days’ notice to the title insurer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may not achieve a competitive advantage over any other insurer, agency, or agent as to rates or forms. If a form or rate is approved for an insurer, the office shall expeditiously approve the forms of other insurers who apply for approval if those forms contain identical coverages, rates, and deviations which have been approved under s. 627.783.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 65-359; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 584, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; ss. 90, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 7, ch. 99-286; s. 1201, ch. 2003-261; s. 4, ch. 2012-206.</History>
</Section>