<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.951" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties; cease and desist orders; injunctions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A risk retention group which violates any applicable provision of the Florida Insurance Code shall be subject to fines and penalties applicable to licensed insurers generally, including revocation of its license or the right to do business in this state. In addition, any such risk retention group shall be subject to the issuance of a cease and desist order of the office or an injunction issued by a court of competent jurisdiction prohibiting such violation or prohibiting the soliciting, selling, or transacting of insurance or otherwise operating or conducting business in this state in violation of the laws of this state. The office may obtain an order from a court of competent jurisdiction to enjoin a risk retention group from further operation or from transacting insurance in this state if the risk retention group is in hazardous financial condition or financially impaired or to enjoin a risk retention group from the soliciting, selling, or transacting of insurance with respect to any person who is not eligible for membership in the group under state or federal law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A purchasing group which violates any applicable provision of the Florida Insurance Code shall be subject to fines and penalties applicable to licensed insurers and agents generally. In addition, any such purchasing group shall be subject to the issuance of a cease and desist order of the office or an injunction issued by any court of competent jurisdiction prohibiting the soliciting, selling, transacting, or purchasing of insurance or otherwise operating or conducting business in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 5, ch. 87-282; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1249, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>