<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6418" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coverage for mammograms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accident or health insurance policy issued, amended, delivered, or renewed in this state must provide coverage for at least the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A baseline mammogram for any woman who is 35 years of age or older, but younger than 40 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mammogram every 2 years for any woman who is 40 years of age or older, but younger than 50 years of age, or more frequently based on the patient’s physician’s recommendation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mammogram every year for any woman who is 50 years of age or older.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more mammograms a year, based upon a physician’s recommendation, for any woman who is at risk for breast cancer because of a personal or family history of breast cancer, because of having a history of biopsy-proven benign breast disease, because of having a mother, sister, or daughter who has or has had breast cancer, or because a woman has not given birth before the age of 30.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (1)(b), for mammograms done more frequently than every 2 years for women 40 years of age or older but younger than 50 years of age, the coverage required by subsection (1) applies, with or without a physician prescription, if the insured obtains a mammogram in an office, facility, or health testing service that uses radiological equipment registered with the Department of Health for breast cancer screening. The coverage is subject to the deductible and coinsurance provisions applicable to outpatient visits, and is also subject to all other terms and conditions applicable to other benefits. This section does not affect any requirements or prohibitions relating to who may perform, analyze, or interpret a mammogram or the persons to whom the results of a mammogram may be furnished or released.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to disability income, specified disease, or hospital indemnity policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every insurer subject to the requirements of this section shall make available to the policyholder as part of the application, for an appropriate additional premium, the coverage required in this section without such coverage being subject to the deductible or coinsurance provisions of the policy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 88-269; s. 125, ch. 92-33; s. 6, ch. 95-188; s. 260, ch. 99-8; s. 89, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>