<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.7711" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Closing services” means services performed by a licensed title insurer, title insurance agent or agency, or attorney agent in the agent’s or agency’s capacity as such, including, but not limited to, preparing documents necessary to close the transaction, conducting the closing, or handling the disbursing of funds related to the closing in a real estate closing transaction in which a title insurance commitment or policy is to be issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Primary title services” means determining insurability in accordance with sound underwriting practices based upon evaluation of a reasonable title search or a search of the records of a Uniform Commercial Code filing office and such other information as may be necessary, determination and clearance of underwriting objections and requirements to eliminate risk, preparation and issuance of a title insurance commitment setting forth the requirements to insure, and preparation and issuance of the policy. Such services do not include closing services or title searches, for which a separate charge or separate charges may be made.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Premium” means the charge, as specified by rule of the commission, that is made by a title insurer for a title insurance policy, including the charge for performance of primary title services by a title insurer or title insurance agent or agency, and incurring the risks incident to such policy, under the several classifications of title insurance contracts and forms, and upon which charge a premium tax is paid under s. 624.509. As used in this part or in any other law, with respect to title insurance, the word “premium” does not include a commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Title insurer” means any domestic company organized and authorized to do business under the provisions of chapter 624, for the purpose of issuing title insurance, or any insurer organized under the laws of another state, the District of Columbia, or a foreign country and holding a certificate of authority to transact business in this state, for the purpose of issuing title insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Title search” means the compiling of title information from official or public records.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 575, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; ss. 88, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 6, ch. 99-286; s. 1200, ch. 2003-261; s. 2, ch. 2005-153; s. 3, ch. 2007-44.</History></Section>