<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.669" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Optional coverage required for substance abuse impaired persons; exception.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurers, health maintenance organizations, and nonprofit health care services plans transacting group health insurance or providing prepaid health care in this state shall make available to the policyholder as part of the application for any such policy of insurance issued or delivered in this state or contract executed or operative in this state the level of benefits specified in subsection (2) for the necessary care and treatment of substance abuse impaired persons, subject to the right of the applicant for a group policy or contract to select any alternative benefits or level of benefits as may be offered by the insurer, health maintenance organization, or plan. For the purposes of this section, the term “substance abuse impaired” has the same meaning ascribed in s. 397.311.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inpatient benefits or outpatient benefits shall consist of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Basic benefit.</Font><EmDash />Intensive treatment program for the treatment of substance abuse impaired persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Limitations.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Benefits shall be available only to covered individuals in a group health plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a minimum lifetime benefit of $2,000.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be allowable a maximum of 44 outpatient visits.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum benefit payable for an outpatient visit shall not exceed $35.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Detoxification shall not be considered as a benefit under the outpatient program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The benefits provided under this section shall be applicable only if treatment is provided by, or under the supervision of, or is prescribed by, a licensed physician or licensed psychologist and if services are provided in a program accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals or approved by the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 79-392; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 522, 523, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 83-216; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 35, ch. 93-39.</History></Section>