<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rating organizations; licensing; fee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person, whether located within or outside this state, may make application to the office for a license as a rating organization. As to property or inland marine insurance, the application shall be for such kinds of insurance or subdivisions thereof or classes of risk or a part or combination thereof as are specified in the application. As to casualty and surety insurances, the application shall be for such kinds of insurance or subdivisions thereof as are specified in the application. The applicant shall file with its application:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of its constitution, its articles of agreement or association or its certificate of incorporation, and of its bylaws, rules, and regulations governing the conduct of its business;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of its members and subscribers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of a resident of this state upon whom notices or orders of the office or process affecting such rating organization may be served; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of its qualifications as a rating organization.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the office finds that the applicant is competent, trustworthy, and otherwise qualified to act as a rating organization and that its constitution, articles of agreement or association or certificate of incorporation, and its bylaws, rules, and regulations governing the conduct of its business conform to the requirements of law, it shall issue a license specifying (in the case of a casualty or surety rating organization) the kinds of insurance or subdivisions thereof, or (in the case of a property insurance rating organization) the kinds of insurance or subdivisions thereof or classes of risk or a part or combination thereof, for which the applicant is authorized to act as a rating organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licenses issued pursuant to this section shall expire on the September 30 next following date of issuance and shall be subject to annual renewal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for the license shall be in the amount specified therefor in s. 624.501. This fee, when collected, shall be deposited to the credit of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 432, ch. 59-205; s. 17, ch. 65-269; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 346, 357, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 49, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1090, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>