<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.609" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reinstatement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract shall include the following provision:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">“Reinstatement: If the renewal premium is not paid before the grace period ends, the policy will lapse. Later acceptance of the premium by the insurer, or by an agent authorized to accept payment without requiring an application for reinstatement, will reinstate this policy. If the insurer or its agent requires an application, the insured will be given a conditional receipt for the premium. If the application is approved, the policy will be reinstated as of the approval date. Lacking such approval, the policy will be reinstated on the 45th day after the date of the conditional receipt unless the insurer has previously written the insured of its disapproval. The reinstated policy will cover only loss that results from an injury sustained after the date of reinstatement or sickness that starts more than 10 days after such date. In all other respects, the rights of the insured and the insurer will remain the same, subject to any provisions noted on or attached to the reinstated policy. Any premiums the insurer accepts for a reinstatement will be applied to a period for which premiums have not been paid. No premiums will be applied to any period more than 60 days before the reinstatement date.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The last two sentences of the above provision may be omitted from any policy which the insured has the right to continue in force subject to its terms by the timely payment of premiums until at least age 50 or, in the case of a policy issued after age 44, for at least 5 years from its date of issue.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 552, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 458, 497, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318.</History></Section>