<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.672" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of ss. 627.671-627.675:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “Medicare supplement policy” is a health insurance policy or other health benefit plan offered by a private entity to individuals who are entitled to have payments for health care costs made under Medicare, Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (“Medicare”), as presently constituted and as may later be amended, which provides reimbursement for expenses incurred for services and items for which payment may be made under Medicare but which expenses are not reimbursable by reason of the applicability of deductibles, coinsurance amounts, or other limitations imposed by Medicare. The term does not include any such policy or plan of one or more labor organizations, or of the trustees of a fund established by one or more labor organizations, or a combination thereof, for employees or former employees, or a combination thereof, or for members or former members, or a combination thereof, of the labor organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “policy” includes a certificate issued or delivered in this state under a group Medicare supplement policy which has been effectuated within or outside this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicant” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an individual Medicare supplement policy or subscriber contract, the person who seeks to contract for insurance benefits; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a group Medicare supplement policy or subscriber contract, the proposed certificateholder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 80-156; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 524, 527, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 5, ch. 86-271; s. 1, ch. 88-338; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1, ch. 2000-202.</History></Section>