<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.551" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Group contracts and plans of self-insurance must meet group requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A life insurance policy insuring the lives of more than one individual may be delivered or issued for delivery in this state only if the policy is issued to one of the groups specified in ss. 627.552-627.5575, and only if the policy complies with the other applicable provisions of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plan of self-insurance providing benefits in the event of death to residents of this state may be established or maintained only if the plan complies with the applicable provisions of this part relating to the rights of individuals to specified benefits and coverages.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) does not apply to life insurance policies or plans of self-insurance:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insuring or providing benefits only to individuals related by blood, marriage, or legal adoption.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insuring or providing benefits only to individuals who have a common interest through ownership of a business enterprise, or a substantial legal interest or equity therein, and who are actively engaged in the management of the business enterprise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insuring or providing benefits only to individuals otherwise having an insurable interest in each other’s lives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insuring or providing benefits pursuant to s. 627.404(2)(b)8. or 9.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Policy,” “insurance policy,” and “group life insurance policy” include plans of self-insurance providing death benefits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Amount of insurance” and “insurance” include the death benefits provided under a plan of self-insurance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Insurer” includes any person or governmental unit providing a plan of self-insurance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nongovernmental self-insurance plan providing life insurance may not be contributory by participants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to any plan which is established or maintained by an individual employer in accordance with the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974. This subsection does not allow an authorized insurer to issue a group life insurance policy or certificate which does not comply with this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 524, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 3, 10, ch. 80-341; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 421, 448, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 55, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 5, ch. 83-203; s. 16, ch. 83-288; ss. 46, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 10, ch. 2008-237.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 12, ch. 2008-237, provides in part that “[e]ffective [June 30, 2008,] the Department of Financial Services may adopt rules to implement this act.”</Text></Note></Section>