<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.231" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Subscribers to rating organizations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to rules and regulations which have been approved by the office as reasonable, each rating organization shall permit any insurer, not a member, to subscribe to its rating services. As to property and marine rating organizations, an insurer shall be so permitted to subscribe to rating services for any kind of insurance, subdivision thereof, or class of risk or a part or combination thereof for which the rating organization is authorized so to act. As to casualty and surety rating organizations, an insurer shall be so permitted to subscribe to rating services for any kind of insurance or subdivision thereof for which the rating organization is authorized so to act. The rating organization shall give notice to subscribers of proposed changes in such rules and regulations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonableness of any rule or regulation in its application to subscribers, or the refusal of any rating organization to admit an insurer as a subscriber, shall, at the request of any subscriber or any such insurer, be reviewed by the office. If the office finds that such rule or regulation is unreasonable in its application to subscribers, it shall order that such rule or regulation shall not be applicable to subscribers. If the rating organization fails to grant or reject an insurer’s application for subscribership within 30 days after it was made, the insurer may request a review by the office as if the application had been rejected. If the office finds that the insurer has been refused admittance to the rating organization as a subscriber without justification, it shall order the rating organization to admit the insurer as a subscriber. If it finds that the action of the rating organization was justified, it shall make an order affirming its action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each rating organization shall furnish its rating services without discrimination to its members and subscribers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 433, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 357, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 49, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 1091, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>