<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purposes of this part; interpretation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes of this part are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote the public welfare by regulating insurance rates as herein provided to the end that they shall not be excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To encourage independent action by, and reasonable price competition among, insurers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To authorize the existence and operation of qualified rating organizations and advisory organizations and to require that specified rating services of such rating organizations be generally available to all authorized insurers; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To authorize cooperation between insurers in ratemaking and other related matters.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the purpose of this part to protect policyholders and the public against the adverse effects of excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory insurance rates, and to authorize the office to regulate such rates. If at any time the office has reason to believe any such rate is excessive, inadequate, or unfairly discriminatory under the law, it is directed to take the necessary action to cause such rate to comply with the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part shall be construed to repeal or modify the provisions of part IX of chapter 626, relating to unfair trade practices.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 411, ch. 59-205; s. 1, ch. 67-9; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 71-3(B); s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 338, 357, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; ss. 49, 79, ch. 82-386; s. 28, ch. 87-228; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 54, ch. 2001-63; s. 1061, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>