<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.0621" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transparency in rate regulation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rate filing” means any original or amended rate residential property insurance filing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recommendation” means any proposed, preliminary, or final recommendation from an office actuary reviewing a rate filing with respect to the issue of approval or disapproval of the rate filing or with respect to rate indications that the office would consider acceptable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WEBSITE FOR PUBLIC ACCESS TO RATE FILING INFORMATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any residential property rate filing, the office shall provide the following information on a publicly accessible Internet website:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The overall rate change requested by the insurer.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate change approved by the office along with all of the actuary’s assumptions and recommendations forming the basis of the office’s decision.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification by the office’s actuary that, based on the actuary’s knowledge, his or her recommendations are consistent with accepted actuarial principles.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any rate filing, whether or not the filing is subject to a public hearing, the office shall provide on its website a means for any policyholder who may be affected by a proposed rate change to send an e-mail regarding the proposed rate change. Such e-mail must be accessible to the actuary assigned to review the rate filing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2008-66; s. 82, ch. 2009-21; s. 8, ch. 2009-87.</History></Section>