<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6499" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reporting by insurers and third-party administrators.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may require any insurer, third-party administrator, or service company to report any information reasonably required to assist the board in assessing insurers as required by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health insurance issuer shall make available on its Internet website a link to the performance outcome and financial data that is published by the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to s. 408.05(3)(k) and shall include in every policy delivered or issued for delivery to any person in the state or any materials provided as required by s. 627.64725 notice that such information is available electronically and the address of its Internet website.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 91-304; s. 1163, ch. 2003-261; s. 40, ch. 2004-297; s. 15, ch. 2006-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 10(2) and (3), ch. 91-304, provides that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) In the event that the application of the assessment to minimum premium plans, stop-loss plans or any other specific type of insurer or health insurance is determined by a court of competent jurisdiction to be unlawful, then the assessment method specified in this act shall continue to apply to all other insurers.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The provisions of section 12 of chapter 90-335 [The reference is apparently in error. Section 12, ch. 90-335, concerns public printing; ch. 90-334 is relevant], Laws of Florida, shall continue in full force and effect, but the provisions of this section shall control to the extent of any conflict.”</Text></Note></Section>