<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6645" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notification of cancellation, expiration, nonrenewal, or change in rates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every insurer delivering or issuing for delivery a group health insurance policy under the provisions of this part shall give the policyholder at least 45 days’ advance notice of cancellation, expiration, nonrenewal, or a change in rates. Such notice shall be mailed to the policyholder’s last address as shown by the records of the insurer. However, if cancellation is for nonpayment of premium, only the requirements of subsection (5) apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the policyholder shall forward, as soon as practicable, the notice of expiration, cancellation, or nonrenewal to each certificateholder covered under the policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an insurer bills any certificateholder directly at his or her home address for collection of any premiums due, the notice required by subsection (1) shall be provided by the insurer directly to each such certificateholder covered under the policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insurer fails to provide the 45 days’ notice required by this section, the coverage shall remain in effect at the existing rates until 45 days after the notice is given or until the effective date of replacement coverage obtained by the insured, whichever occurs first.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of cancellation, the insurer must return promptly the unearned portion of any premium paid. If the insured cancels, the earned premium shall be computed by the use of the short-rate table last filed with the state official having supervision of insurance in the state where the insured resided when the policy was issued. If the insurer cancels, the earned premium shall be computed pro rata. Cancellation shall be without prejudice to any claim originating prior to the effective date of cancellation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If cancellation is due to nonpayment of premium, the insurer may not retroactively cancel the policy to a date prior to the date that notice of cancellation was provided to the policyholder unless the insurer mails notice of cancellation to the policyholder prior to 45 days after the date the premium was due. Such notice must be mailed to the policyholder’s last address as shown by the records of the insurer and may provide for a retroactive date of cancellation no earlier than midnight of the date that the premium was due.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 83-157; s. 2, ch. 89-222; s. 4, ch. 90-249; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 351, ch. 97-102; s. 12, ch. 99-204; s. 6, ch. 99-275; s. 11, ch. 99-393.</History></Section>