<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.6425" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Renewability of individual coverage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this section, an insurer that provides individual health insurance coverage to an individual shall renew or continue in force such coverage at the option of the individual. For the purpose of this section, the term “individual health insurance” means health insurance coverage, as described in s. 627.6561(5)(a)2., offered to an individual in this state, including certificates of coverage offered to individuals in this state as part of a group policy issued to an association outside this state, but the term does not include short-term limited duration insurance or excepted benefits specified in subsection (6) or subsection (7).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may nonrenew or discontinue health insurance coverage of an individual in the individual market based only on one or more of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual has failed to pay premiums, contributions, or a required copayment payable to the insurer in accordance with the terms of the health insurance coverage or the insurer has not received timely premium payments. When the copayment is payable to the insurer and exceeds $300, the insurer shall allow the insured up to 90 days after the date of the procedure to pay the required copayment. The insurer shall print in 10-point type on the Declaration of Benefits page notification that the insured could be terminated for failure to make any required copayment to the insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual has performed an act or practice that constitutes fraud or made an intentional misrepresentation of material fact under the terms of the coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer is ceasing to offer coverage in the individual market in accordance with subsection (3) and applicable state law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a health insurer that offers health insurance coverage in the market through a network plan, the individual no longer resides, lives, or works in the service area, or in an area for which the insurer is authorized to do business, but only if such coverage is terminated under this paragraph uniformly without regard to any health-status-related factor of covered individuals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of health insurance coverage that is made available in the individual market only through one or more bona fide associations, as defined in s. 627.6571(5), the membership of the individual in the association, on the basis of which the coverage is provided, ceases, but only if such coverage is terminated under this paragraph uniformly without regard to any health-status-related factor of covered individuals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case in which an insurer decides to discontinue offering a particular policy form for health insurance coverage offered in the individual market, coverage under such form may be discontinued by the insurer only if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer provides notice to each covered individual provided coverage under this policy form in the individual market of such discontinuation at least 90 days prior to the date of the nonrenewal of such coverage;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer offers to each individual in the individual market provided coverage under this policy form the option to purchase any other individual health insurance coverage currently being offered by the insurer for individuals in such market in the state; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In exercising the option to discontinue coverage of this policy form and in offering the option of coverage under subparagraph 2., the insurer acts uniformly without regard to any health-status-related factor of enrolled individuals or individuals who may become eligible for such coverage.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subparagraph (a)3., in any case in which an insurer elects to discontinue offering all health insurance coverage in the individual market in this state, health insurance coverage may be discontinued by the insurer only if:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer provides notice to the office and to each individual of such discontinuation at least 180 days prior to the date of the nonrenewal of such coverage; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All health insurance issued or delivered for issuance in the state in the individual market is discontinued and coverage under such health insurance coverage in such market is not renewed.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a discontinuation under subparagraph 1. in the individual market, the insurer may not provide for the issuance of any individual health insurance coverage in this state during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the discontinuation of the last health insurance coverage not so renewed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of coverage renewal, an insurer may modify the health insurance coverage for a policy form offered to individuals in the individual market so long as such modification is consistent with the laws of this state and effective on a uniform basis among all individuals with that policy form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In applying this section in the case of health insurance coverage that is made available by an insurer in the individual market to individuals only through one or more associations, a reference to an “individual” includes a reference to such an association of which the individual is a member.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of this section do not apply to any health insurance coverage in relation to its provision of excepted benefits described in s. 627.6561(5)(b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of this section do not apply to any health insurance coverage in relation to its provision of excepted benefits described in s. 627.6561(5)(c), (d), or (e), if the benefits are provided under a separate policy, certificate, or contract of insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to health insurance coverage offered, sold, issued, or renewed in the individual market on or after July 1, 1997.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 96-223; s. 2, ch. 97-179; s. 4, ch. 98-159; s. 33, ch. 2002-400; s. 1151, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>