<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.744" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Required preinsurance inspection of private passenger motor vehicles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A private passenger motor vehicle insurance policy providing physical damage coverage, including collision or comprehensive coverage, may not be issued in this state unless the insurer has inspected the motor vehicle in accordance with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a policy for a policyholder who has been insured for 2 years or longer, without interruption, under a private passenger motor vehicle policy which provides physical damage coverage, if the agent of the insurer verifies the previous coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a new, unused motor vehicle purchased from a licensed motor vehicle dealer or leasing company, if the insurer is provided with:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bill of sale or buyer’s order which contains a full description of the motor vehicle, including all options and accessories; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the title which establishes transfer of ownership from the dealer or leasing company to the customer and a copy of the window sticker or the dealer invoice showing the itemized options and equipment and the total retail price of the vehicle.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For the purposes of this paragraph, the physical damage coverage on the motor vehicle may not be suspended during the term of the policy due to the applicant’s failure to provide the required documents. However, payment of a claim is conditioned upon the receipt by the insurer of the required documents, and no physical damage loss occurring after the effective date of the coverage is payable until the documents are provided to the insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a temporary substitute motor vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a motor vehicle which is leased for less than 6 months, if the insurer receives the lease or rental agreement containing a description of the leased motor vehicle, including its condition. Payment of a physical damage claim is conditioned upon receipt of the lease or rental agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a vehicle that is 10 years old or older, as determined by reference to the model year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any renewal policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a motor vehicle policy issued in a county with a 1988 estimated population of less than 500,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any other vehicle or policy exempted by rule of the commission. The commission may base a rule under this paragraph only on a determination that the likelihood of a fraudulent physical damage claim is remote or that the inspection would cause a serious hardship to the insurer or the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the insurer’s authorized inspection service has no inspection facility either in the municipality in which the automobile is principally garaged or within 10 miles of such municipality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the insured vehicle is insured under a commercially rated policy that insures five or more vehicles.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an insurance producer is transferring a book of business from one insurer to another.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an individual insured’s coverage is being transferred and initiated by a producer to a new insurer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not prohibit an insurer from requiring a preinsurance inspection of any motor vehicle as a condition of issuance of physical damage coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inspection required by this section shall be provided by the insurer or by a person or organization authorized by the insurer. The applicant may be required to pay the cost of the inspection, not to exceed $5. The inspection shall be recorded on a form prescribed by the commission, and the form or a copy shall be retained by the insurer with its policy records for the insured. The insurer shall provide a copy of the form to the insured upon request. Any inspection fee paid directly by the applicant may not be considered part of the premium. However, an insurer that provides the inspection at no cost to the applicant may include the expense of the inspection within a rate filing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inspection shall include at least the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taking a physical imprint of the vehicle identification number of the vehicle or otherwise recording the vehicle identification number in a manner prescribed by the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recording the presence of accessories required by the commission to be recorded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recording the locations of and a description of existing damage to the vehicle.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer may defer an inspection for 30 calendar days following the effective date of coverage for a new policy, but not for a renewal policy, and for additional or replacement vehicles to an existing policy, if an inspection at the time of the request for coverage would create a serious inconvenience for the applicant and such hardship is documented in the insured’s policy record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may, by rule, establish such procedures and notice requirements that it finds necessary to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 41, 52, ch. 90-119; ss. 85, 114, ch. 92-318; s. 28, ch. 95-146; s. 1198, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>