<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0627.642" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Outline of coverage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No individual or family accident and health insurance policy shall be delivered, or issued for delivery, in this state unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is accompanied by an appropriate outline of coverage; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appropriate outline of coverage is completed and delivered to the applicant at the time application is made, and an acknowledgment of receipt or certificate of delivery of such outline is provided to the insurer with the application.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In the case of a direct response, such as a written application to the insurance company from an applicant, the outline of coverage shall accompany the policy when issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The outline of coverage shall contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement identifying the applicable category of coverage afforded by the policy, based on the minimum basic standards set forth in the rules issued to effect compliance with s. 627.643.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brief description of the principal benefits and coverage provided in the policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary statement of the principal exclusions and limitations or reductions contained in the policy, including, but not limited to, preexisting conditions, probationary periods, elimination periods, deductibles, coinsurance, and any age limitations or reductions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary statement of the renewal and cancellation provisions, including any reservation of the insurer of a right to change premiums.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the outline contains a summary only of the details of the policy as issued or of the policy as applied for and that the issued policy should be referred to for the actual contractual governing provisions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When home health care coverage is provided, a statement that such benefits are provided in the policy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the outline of coverage, a policy as specified in s. 627.6699(3)(k) must be accompanied by an identification card that contains, at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the organization issuing the policy or the name of the organization administering the policy, whichever applies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the contract holder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of plan only if the plan is filed in the state, an indication that the plan is self-funded, or the name of the network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The member identification number, contract number, and policy or group number, if applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contact phone number or electronic address for authorizations and admission certifications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A phone number or electronic address whereby the covered person or hospital, physician, or other person rendering services covered by the policy may obtain benefits verification and information in order to estimate patient financial responsibility, in compliance with privacy rules under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The national plan identifier, in accordance with the compliance date set forth by the federal Department of Health and Human Services.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The identification card must present the information in a readily identifiable manner or, alternatively, the information may be embedded on the card and available through magnetic stripe or smart card. The information may also be provided through other electronic technology.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-69; s. 1, ch. 74-281; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 491, 497, 809(2nd), ch. 82-243; s. 79, ch. 82-386; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 2, ch. 2008-119.</History></Section>