<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.3203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirement for a written manufacturer/dealer agreement; area of sales responsibility.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manufacturer or distributor may not sell a recreational vehicle in this state to or through a dealer without having first entered into a manufacturer/dealer agreement with a dealer which has been signed by both parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer shall designate the area of sales responsibility exclusively assigned to a dealer in the manufacturer/dealer agreement and may not change such area or contract with another dealer for sale of the same line-make in the designated area during the duration of the agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The area of sales responsibility may not be reviewed or changed until 1 year after the execution of the manufacturer/dealer agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor vehicle dealer may not sell a new recreational vehicle in this state without having first entered into a manufacturer/dealer agreement with a manufacturer or distributor and may not sell outside of the area of sales responsibility designated in the agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (4), a dealer may sell outside of its designated area of sales responsibility if the dealer obtains an offsite/supplemental license pursuant to s. 320.771(7) and meets any one of the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For sales of the same line-make within another dealer’s designated area of sales responsibility, the dealer must obtain in advance of the off-premise sale a written agreement signed by the dealer, the manufacturer of the recreational vehicles to be sold at the off-premise sale, and the dealer in whose designated area of sales responsibility the off-premise sale will occur which:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designates the line-make of the recreational vehicles to be sold;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sets forth the time period for the off-premise sale; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affirmatively authorizes the sale of the same line-make of the recreational vehicles.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The off-premise sale is not located within any dealer’s designated area of sales responsibility and is in conjunction with a public vehicle show.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The off-premise sale is in conjunction with a public vehicle show in which more than 35 dealers are participating and the show is predominantly funded by manufacturers. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “public vehicle show” means an event sponsored by an organization approved under s. 501(c)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code which has the purpose of promoting the welfare of the recreational vehicle industry and is located at a site that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Will be used to display and sell recreational vehicles;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not used for off-premise sales for more than 10 days in a calendar year; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not the location set forth on any dealer’s license as its place of business.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2007-258.</History></Section>