<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.0607" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Replacement license plates, validation decal, or mobile home sticker.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer or department license and registration inspector may at any time inspect a license plate or validation decal for proper display and legibility as prescribed by chapter 316. A damaged or defaced plate or decal may be required to be replaced.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a license plate, mobile home sticker, or validation decal has been lost, stolen, or destroyed, the owner of the motor vehicle or mobile home for which the plate, sticker, or decal was issued shall make application to the department for a replacement. The application shall contain the plate, sticker, or decal number being replaced and a statement that the item was lost, stolen, or destroyed. If the application includes a copy of the police report prepared in response to a report of a stolen plate, sticker, or decal, such plate, sticker, or decal must be replaced at no charge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2), upon filing of an application accompanied by a fee of $28 plus applicable service charges, the department shall issue a replacement plate, sticker, or decal, as applicable, if it is satisfied that the information reported in the application is true. The replacement fee shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any license plate, sticker, or decal lost in the mail may be replaced at no charge. Neither the service charge nor the replacement fee shall be applied to this replacement. However, the application for a replacement shall contain a statement of such fact, the audit number of the lost item, and the date issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the issuance of an original license plate, the applicant shall pay a fee of $28 to be deposited in the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds derived from the sale of temporary tags under the provisions of s. 320.131 shall be deposited in the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 83-318; s. 3, ch. 86-88; s. 51, ch. 90-132; s. 64, ch. 93-120; s. 49, ch. 94-306; s. 14, ch. 2009-71.</History></Section>