<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dealer and manufacturer license plates and alternative method of registration.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensed motor vehicle dealer and any licensed mobile home dealer may, upon payment of the license tax imposed by s. 320.08(12), secure one or more dealer license plates, which are valid for use on motor vehicles or mobile homes owned by the dealer to whom such plates are issued while the motor vehicles are in inventory and for sale, or while being operated in connection with such dealer’s business, but are not valid for use for hire. Dealer license plates may not be used on any tow truck or wrecker unless the tow truck or wrecker is being demonstrated for sale, and the dealer license plates may not be used on a vehicle used to transport another motor vehicle for the motor vehicle dealer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Marine boat trailer dealers and manufacturers may, upon payment of the license taxes imposed by s. 320.08(12), secure one or more dealer plates, which are valid for use on boat trailers owned by the dealer to whom such plates are issued while being used in connection with such dealer’s business, but are not valid for use for hire.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the method currently used to license marine boat trailer dealers to do business in the state, that is, by an occupational license issued by the city or county, not be changed. The department shall not interpret this act to mean that it is empowered to license such dealers to do business. An occupational license tax certificate shall be sufficient proof upon which the department may issue dealer license plates.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dealer of heavy trucks as defined in s. 320.01(10), upon payment of the license tax imposed by s. 320.08(12), may secure one or more dealer license plates that are valid for use on vehicles owned by the dealer to whom such plates are issued while the heavy trucks are in inventory and for sale and are being used only in the state for demonstration purposes. The license plates may be used for demonstration purposes for a period not to exceed 24 hours. The license plates must be validated on a form prescribed by the department and must be retained in the vehicle being operated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed manufacturer, importer, or distributor of motor vehicles may, upon payment of the license tax imposed by s. 320.08(12), secure one or more manufacturer license plates, which are valid for use on motor vehicles owned by the manufacturer, importer, or distributor to whom such plates are issued while the motor vehicles are in inventory and for sale, being operated for demonstration purposes, or in connection with the manufacturer’s business, but are not valid for use for hire.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a licensed dealer or a marine boat trailer dealer chooses to register any motor vehicle or boat trailer he or she owns and has for sale and secure a regular motor vehicle license plate therefor, the dealer may, upon sale thereof, submit to the department a transfer fee of $4.50 and an application for transfer of the license plate to a comparable motor vehicle or boat trailer owned by the dealer of the same weight series as set forth under s. 320.08.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 9159, 1923; CGL 1313, 1315; s. 1, ch. 24186, 1947; s. 1, ch. 63-173; s. 6, ch. 65-190; s. 1, ch. 65-461; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 72-79; ss. 1, 3, ch. 76-135; s. 1, ch. 76-137; s. 3, ch. 77-125; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 20, ch. 77-357; s. 128, ch. 79-400; s. 37, ch. 83-318; s. 5, ch. 84-155; s. 29, ch. 95-143; s. 358, ch. 95-148; s. 40, ch. 96-413; s. 32, ch. 99-248; s. 25, ch. 2009-71; s. 40, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>