<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalty for violating s. 320.28.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No action or right of action to recover any such motor vehicle, or any part of the selling price thereof, shall be maintained in the courts of this state by any such dealer or vendor or his or her successors or assigns in any case wherein such vendor or dealer shall have failed to comply with the terms and provisions of s. 320.28, and in addition thereto, such vendor or dealer, upon conviction for the violation of any of the provisions of said sections, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083 and by confiscation of the vehicle or vehicles offered for sale. Any municipal or county law enforcement agency that enforces, or assists the department in enforcing, the provisions of this section which enforcement results in a forfeiture of property as provided in this section is entitled to receive all or a share of any such property based upon its participation in such enforcement. Any property seized by any municipal or county law enforcement agency may be retained or sold by the law enforcement agency in accordance with the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act. Any funds received by a municipal or county law enforcement agency pursuant to this section constitute supplemental funds and may not be used as replacement funds by the municipality or county. However, this section shall not apply to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder of a note or notes representing a portion of the purchase price of such motor vehicle when the owner thereof was and is a bona fide purchaser of said note or notes, before maturity, for value and without knowledge that the vendor of such vehicle had not complied with said sections; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bona fide purchaser of such motor vehicle for value and without knowledge that the vendor or dealer of such vehicle had not complied with said sections.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 17113, 1935; s. 3, ch. 18032, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 1317(3), (8), 8132(1), (2); s. 201, ch. 71-136; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 25, ch. 77-357; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 15, 17, ch. 80-217; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 20, 21, ch. 88-395; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 361, ch. 95-148; s. 36, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>