<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.0705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Semiannual registration or renewal for certain vehicles.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of a motor vehicle taxed under s. 320.08(4) or (6)(b) may register his or her vehicle semiannually, if the amount of license tax due annually is more than $100 and the vehicle registration fee is not required to be apportioned, upon payment of a fee of $2.50 for each semiannual registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the first 3 months of the semiannual registration period beginning either June 1 or December 1, the semiannual tax shall be one-half of the respective annual amount set forth in s. 320.08. The fee for registration during the fourth month of the semiannual period or thereafter shall be at the rate of one-twelfth of the annual amount for the month of registration and one-twelfth of the annual amount for each month of the semiannual registration period succeeding the month of registration. However, any vehicle not registered in this state during the prior semiannual period and not subject to registration during such prior registration period may be registered in any month of the semiannual registration period beginning June 1 or December 1 at the rate of one-twelfth of the annual amount for the month of registration and one-twelfth of the annual amount for each month of the semiannual period succeeding the month of registration. The provisions of s. 320.14 do not apply to such vehicles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of a motor vehicle taxed under s. 320.08(6)(a) may register such vehicle for any 6-month period upon payment of one-half the annual license tax plus an additional fee of $2.50 for each period; provided, notwithstanding any other provision of law, such person is not entitled to a refund of any tax imposed under s. 320.08(6) upon such vehicle.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 83-318; s. 48, ch. 85-180; s. 3, ch. 89-364; s. 351, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>