<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.1316" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Failure to surrender vehicle or vessel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt from a lienor who claims a lien on a vehicle pursuant to s. 319.27 by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles of written notice to surrender a vehicle or vessel that has been disposed of, concealed, removed, or destroyed by the lienee, the department shall place the name of the registered owner of that vehicle on the list of those persons who may not be issued a license plate, revalidation sticker, or replacement license plate for any motor vehicle under s. 320.03(8) owned by the lienee at the time the notice was given by the lienor. If the vehicle is owned jointly by more than one person, the name of each registered owner shall be placed on the list.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice to surrender the vehicle shall be submitted on forms developed by the department, which must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number of the lienor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the registered owner of the vehicle and the address to which the lienor provided notice to surrender the vehicle to the registered owner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general description of the vehicle, including its color, make, model, body style, and year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vehicle identification number, registration license plate number, if known, or other identification number, as applicable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registered owner of the vehicle may dispute a notice to surrender the vehicle by notifying the department of the dispute in writing on forms provided by the department and presenting proof that the vehicle was sold to a motor vehicle dealer licensed under s. 320.27, a mobile home dealer licensed under s. 320.77, or a recreational vehicle dealer licensed under s. 320.771.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2009-206.</History></Section>