<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.0605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certificate of registration; possession required; exception.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registration certificate or an official copy thereof, a true copy of rental or lease documentation issued for a motor vehicle or issued for a replacement vehicle in the same registration period, a temporary receipt printed upon self-initiated electronic renewal of a registration via the Internet, or a cab card issued for a vehicle registered under the International Registration Plan shall, at all times while the vehicle is being used or operated on the roads of this state, be in the possession of the operator thereof or be carried in the vehicle for which issued and shall be exhibited upon demand of any authorized law enforcement officer or any agent of the department, except for a vehicle registered under s. 320.0657. The provisions of this section do not apply during the first 30 days after purchase of a replacement vehicle. A violation of this section is a noncriminal traffic infraction, punishable as a nonmoving violation as provided in chapter 318.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rental or lease documentation that is sufficient to satisfy the requirement in subsection (1) includes the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Date of rental and time of exit from rental facility;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rental station identification;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rental agreement number;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rental vehicle identification number;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rental vehicle license plate number and state of registration;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vehicle’s make, model, and color;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vehicle’s mileage; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorized renter’s name.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 83-318; s. 5, ch. 86-185; s. 14, ch. 86-243; s. 48, ch. 94-306; s. 913, ch. 95-148; s. 50, ch. 96-350; s. 265, ch. 99-248; s. 28, ch. 2000-313; s. 62, ch. 2005-164; s. 31, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>