<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.8325" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mobile homes, manufactured homes, and park trailers; uniform installation standards; injunctions; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules setting forth uniform standards for the installation of mobile homes, manufactured homes, and park trailers and for the manufacture of components, products, or systems used in the installation of mobile homes, manufactured homes, and park trailers. The rules shall ensure that the home or park trailer is installed on a permanent foundation that resists wind, flood, flotation, overturning, sliding, and lateral movement of the home or park trailer. No entity, other than the department, has authority to amend these uniform standards. The owner of the mobile home, manufactured home, or park trailer shall be responsible for the installation in accordance with department rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons licensed in this state to engage in the business of insuring mobile homes, manufactured homes, or park trailers that are subject to the provisions of this section against damage from windstorm shall issue such insurance only if the mobile home, manufactured home, or park trailer has been installed in accordance with the requirements of this chapter and department rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a mobile home, manufactured home, or park trailer is insured against damage caused by windstorm and subsequently sustains windstorm damage of a nature that indicates that the mobile home, manufactured home, or park trailer was not installed in the manner required by this chapter and department rules, the person issuing the policy shall not be relieved from meeting the obligations specified in the insurance policy with respect to such damage on the basis that the mobile home or park trailer was not properly installed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a person or entity that engages in the business of manufactured housing installation or in the business of manufacturing components, products, or systems in this state and does so in a manner that is not in accordance with the uniform standards set forth by the department, a person or entity aggrieved thereby may bring an action in the appropriate court for actual damages. In addition, the court may provide appropriate equitable relief, including the enjoining of a violator from engaging in the business or from engaging in further violations. Whenever it is established to the satisfaction of the court that a willful violation has occurred, the court shall award punitive damages to the aggrieved party. The losing party may be liable for court costs and reasonable attorney’s fees incurred by the prevailing party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to other penalties provided in this section, the department or the state attorneys and their assistants are authorized to apply to the circuit courts within their respective jurisdictions, and such courts shall have jurisdiction, upon hearing and for cause shown, to grant temporary or permanent injunctions restraining any person or entity engaging in the business of manufactured housing installation or the manufacturing of components, products, or systems from installing homes or manufacturing or selling such components, products, or systems in a manner not in accordance with the uniform standards set forth by the department or restraining any persons in the business of installing such components, products, or systems from using devices that do not meet the uniform standards set forth by the department or from installing such components, products, or systems in a manner not in accordance with the uniform standards set forth by the department, whether or not there exists an adequate remedy at law, and such injunctions shall issue without bond.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies only to a mobile home, manufactured home, or park trailer that is being used as a dwelling place and that is located on a particular location for a period of time exceeding 14 days, for a mobile or manufactured home, or 45 days, for a park trailer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the definitions set forth in s. 320.822 apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 73-182; s. 2, ch. 74-9; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 4, ch. 84-182; s. 12, ch. 85-343; ss. 19, 20, ch. 88-147; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 38, ch. 99-248; s. 7, ch. 2004-283.</History></Section>