<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reciprocal agreements for nonresident exemption.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may negotiate and consummate with the proper authorities of the several states of the United States or any foreign country reciprocal agreements whereby residents of such other states or foreign country operating motor vehicles properly licensed and registered in their respective states or foreign country may have such privileges and exemption in the operation of their motor vehicles in this state as residents of this state whose vehicles are properly registered in this state may have and enjoy in the operation of their motor vehicles in such other states or foreign country. However, nothing herein may be construed to relieve any motor vehicle owner or operator from complying with and abiding by all other applicable laws and rules relating to safety of operation of motor vehicles and the preservation of the highways of this state. In the making of such reciprocal agreements, such departments shall have due regard for the benefits to be achieved for and the convenience of motor vehicle owners and the citizens of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles is authorized to continue membership in the International Registration Plan, a reciprocal agreement among the states and the provinces of Canada which provides for proportional payment of license fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No such reciprocal agreement consummated by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may become effective until approved by the Governor; and all such reciprocal agreements shall be made subject to cancellation at any time by the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall give proper publicity to the terms of every such reciprocal agreement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-3, ch. 19479, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 1326(2)-(4); s. 1, ch. 24095, 1947; s. 1, ch. 63-279; s. 2, ch. 63-496; s. 1, ch. 65-52; s. 6, ch. 65-190; ss. 23, 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 73-326; s. 26, ch. 77-357; s. 4, ch. 82-129; s. 52, ch. 83-318; s. 12, ch. 84-260; s. 54, ch. 85-180.</History></Section>