<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition of license tax moneys.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The revenue derived from the registration of motor vehicles, including any delinquent fees and excluding those revenues collected and distributed under the provisions of s. 320.081, must be distributed monthly, as collected, as follows:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first proceeds, to the extent necessary to comply with the provisions of s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885, as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution, and the additional provisions of s. 9(d) and s. 1010.57, must be deposited in the district Capital Outlay and Debt Service School Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five million dollars per year of such revenues must be deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund, with priority use assigned to completion of the interstate highway system. However, any excess funds may be utilized for general transportation purposes, consistent with the Department of Transportation’s legislatively approved objectives.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law except subsections (1) and (2), $15 million shall be deposited annually into the State Transportation Trust Fund solely for the purposes of funding the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program as provided in chapter 311. Such revenues shall be distributed on a 50-50 matching basis to any port listed in s. 311.09(1) to be used for funding projects as described in s. 311.07(3)(b). Such revenues may be assigned, pledged, or set aside as a trust for the payment of principal or interest on bonds, tax anticipation certificates, or any other form of indebtedness issued by an individual port or appropriate local government having jurisdiction thereof, or collectively by interlocal agreement among any of the ports, or used to purchase credit support to permit such borrowings. However, such debt is not a general obligation of the state. The state covenants with holders of such revenue bonds or other instruments of indebtedness issued that it will not repeal or impair or amend in any manner that will materially and adversely affect the rights of such holders so long as bonds authorized by this section are outstanding. Any revenues that are not pledged to the repayment of bonds authorized by this section may be used for purposes authorized under the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program. This revenue source is in addition to any amounts provided and appropriated in accordance with s. 311.07. The Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council shall approve the distribution of funds to ports for projects that have been approved pursuant to s. 311.09(5)-(8). The council and the Department of Transportation may perform acts required to facilitate and implement this subsection. To better enable the ports to cooperate to their mutual advantage, the governing body of each port may exercise powers provided to municipalities or counties in s. 163.01(7)(d) subject to chapter 311 and special acts, if any, pertaining to a port. The use of funds provided pursuant to this subsection are limited to eligible projects listed in this subsection. Income derived from a project completed with the use of program funds, beyond operating costs and debt service, is restricted solely to further port capital improvements consistent with maritime purposes. Use of such income for nonmaritime purposes is prohibited. The revenues available under this subsection may not be pledged to the payment of any bonds other than the Florida Ports Financing Commission Series 1996 and Series 1999 Bonds currently outstanding; however, such revenues may be pledged to secure payment of refunding bonds to refinance the Florida Ports Financing Commission Series 1996 and Series 1999 Bonds. Refunding bonds secured by revenues available under this subsection may not be issued with a final maturity later than the final maturity of the Florida Ports Financing Commission Series 1996 and Series 1999 Bonds or which provide for higher debt service in any year than is currently payable on such bonds. Any revenue bonds or other indebtedness issued after July 1, 2000, other than refunding bonds shall be issued by the Division of Bond Finance at the request of the Department of Transportation pursuant to the State Bond Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law except subsections (1), (2), and (3), $10 million shall be deposited annually into the State Transportation Trust Fund solely for the purposes of funding the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program as provided in chapter 311 and for funding seaport intermodal access projects of statewide significance as provided in s. 341.053. Such revenues shall be distributed to any port listed in s. 311.09(1), to be used for funding projects as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any seaport intermodal access projects that are identified in the 1997-1998 Tentative Work Program of the Department of Transportation, up to the amounts needed to offset the funding requirements of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For seaport intermodal access projects as described in s. 341.053(5) which are identified in the 5-year Florida Seaport Mission Plan as provided in s. 311.09(3). Funding for such projects shall be on a matching basis as mutually determined by the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council and the Department of Transportation if a minimum of 25 percent of total project funds come from any port funds, local funds, private funds, or specifically earmarked federal funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On a 50-50 matching basis for projects as described in s. 311.07(3)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For seaport intermodal access projects that involve the dredging or deepening of channels, turning basins, or harbors; or the rehabilitation of wharves, docks, or similar structures. Funding for such projects requires a 25 percent match of the funds received pursuant to this subsection. Matching funds must come from any port funds, federal funds, local funds, or private funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such revenues may be assigned, pledged, or set aside as a trust for the payment of principal or interest on bonds, tax anticipation certificates, or other form of indebtedness issued by an individual port or appropriate local government having jurisdiction thereof, or collectively by interlocal agreement among any of the ports, or used to purchase credit support to permit such borrowings. However, such debt is not a general obligation of the state. This state covenants with holders of such revenue bonds or other instruments of indebtedness issued hereunder that it will not repeal or impair or amend this subsection in any manner that will materially and adversely affect the rights of holders so long as bonds authorized by this subsection are outstanding. Any revenues that are not pledged to the repayment of bonds as authorized by this section may be used for purposes authorized under the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program. This revenue source is in addition to any amounts provided for and appropriated in accordance with s. 311.07 and subsection (3). The Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council shall approve distribution of funds to ports for projects that have been approved pursuant to s. 311.09(5)-(8), or for seaport intermodal access projects identified in the 5-year Florida Seaport Mission Plan as provided in s. 311.09(3) and mutually agreed upon by the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council and the Department of Transportation. All contracts for actual construction of projects authorized by this subsection must include a provision encouraging employment of participants in the welfare transition program. The goal for such employment is 25 percent of all new employees employed specifically for the project, unless the Department of Transportation and the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council demonstrate that such a requirement would severely hamper the successful completion of the project. In such an instance, Workforce Florida, Inc., shall establish an appropriate percentage of employees who are participants in the welfare transition program. The council and the Department of Transportation may perform such acts as are required to facilitate and implement the provisions of this subsection. To better enable the ports to cooperate to their mutual advantage, the governing body of each port may exercise powers provided to municipalities or counties in s. 163.01(7)(d) subject to the provisions of chapter 311 and special acts, if any, pertaining to a port. The use of funds provided pursuant to this subsection is limited to eligible projects listed in this subsection. The revenues available under this subsection may not be pledged to the payment of any bonds other than the Florida Ports Financing Commission Series 1996 and Series 1999 Bonds currently outstanding; however, such revenues may be pledged to secure payment of refunding bonds to refinance the Florida Ports Financing Commission Series 1996 and Series 1999 Bonds. Refunding bonds secured by revenues available under this subsection may not be issued with a final maturity later than the final maturity of the Florida Ports Financing Commission Series 1996 and Series 1999 Bonds or which provide for higher debt service in any year than is currently payable on such bonds. Any revenue bonds or other indebtedness issued after July 1, 2000, other than refunding bonds shall be issued by the Division of Bond Finance at the request of the Department of Transportation pursuant to the State Bond Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (c), the remainder of such revenues must be deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer each month shall deposit in the State Transportation Trust Fund an amount, drawn from other funds in the State Treasury which are not immediately needed or are otherwise in excess of the amount necessary to meet the requirements of the State Treasury, which when added to such remaining revenues each month will equal one-twelfth of the amount of the anticipated annual revenues to be deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund under paragraph (a) as determined by the Chief Financial Officer after consultation with the Revenue Estimating Conference held pursuant to s. 216.136(3). The transfers required hereunder may be suspended by action of the Legislative Budget Commission in the event of a significant shortfall of state revenues.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any month in which the remaining revenues derived from the registration of motor vehicles exceed one-twelfth of those anticipated annual remaining revenues as determined by the Chief Financial Officer after consultation with the Revenue Estimating Conference, the excess shall be credited to those state funds in the State Treasury from which the amount was originally drawn, up to the amount which was deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund under paragraph (b). A final adjustment must be made in the last months of a fiscal year so that the total revenue deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund each year equals the amount derived from the registration of motor vehicles, less the amount distributed under subsection (1). For the purposes of this paragraph and paragraph (b), the term “remaining revenues” means all revenues deposited into the State Transportation Trust Fund under paragraph (a) and subsections (2) and (3). In order that interest earnings continue to accrue to the General Revenue Fund, the Department of Transportation may not invest an amount equal to the cumulative amount of funds deposited in the State Transportation Trust Fund under paragraph (b) less funds credited under this paragraph as computed on a monthly basis. The amounts to be credited under this and the preceding paragraph must be calculated and certified to the Chief Financial Officer by the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 7275, 1917; RGS 1031; s. 12, ch. 8410, 1921; CGL 1304; s. 4, ch. 15625, 1931; s. 44, ch. 26869, 1951; s. 1, ch. 65-514; s. 31, ch. 69-216; s. 1, ch. 69-300; s. 1, ch. 77-416; s. 1, ch. 81-222; s. 53, ch. 83-3; s. 14, ch. 83-138; s. 44, ch. 83-318; s. 7, ch. 85-81; s. 68, ch. 85-180; s. 20, ch. 89-301; ss. 61, 62, ch. 90-136; s. 30, ch. 95-143; s. 136, ch. 96-320; s. 50, ch. 97-278; s. 10, ch. 97-280; s. 104, ch. 99-13; s. 274, ch. 99-248; s. 14, ch. 99-385; s. 84, ch. 2000-165; s. 5, ch. 2000-266; s. 54, ch. 2000-371; s. 68, ch. 2001-61; s. 965, ch. 2002-387; s. 360, ch. 2003-261; s. 45, ch. 2005-152; s. 13, ch. 2012-128; s. 87, ch. 2012-174.</History>
</Section>