<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.0815" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mobile homes and recreational vehicle-type units required to have appropriate license plates or stickers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recreational vehicle-type units taxed under s. 320.08(9) and (10) shall be issued appropriate license plates, except as provided in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home or recreational vehicle-type unit which is permanently affixed to the land shall be issued a mobile home sticker at the fee prescribed in s. 320.08(11) unless the mobile home or recreational vehicle-type unit is qualified and taxed as real property, in which case the mobile home or recreational vehicle-type unit shall be issued an “RP” series sticker. Series “RP” stickers shall be provided by the department to the tax collectors, and such a sticker will be issued by the tax collector to the registered owner of such a mobile home or recreational vehicle-type unit upon the production of a certificate of the respective property appraiser that such mobile home or recreational vehicle-type unit is included in an assessment of the property of such registered owner for ad valorem taxation. An “RP” series sticker shall be issued by the tax collector for an aggregate fee of $3 each, to be distributed as follows: $2.50 shall be retained by the tax collector as a service charge; 25 cents shall be remitted to the property appraiser; and 25 cents shall be remitted to the department to defray the cost of manufacture and handling. Mobile home stickers and “RP” series stickers shall be of a size to be determined by the department. A mobile home sticker or “RP” series sticker shall be affixed to the lower left corner of the window closest to the street or road providing access to such residence.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 70-391; s. 5, ch. 72-339; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 94, ch. 77-104; s. 13, ch. 77-357; s. 6, ch. 78-207; s. 26, ch. 83-318; s. 4, ch. 85-324; s. 39, ch. 96-413.</History></Section>