<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.0807" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special license plates for Governor and federal and state legislators.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application by any member of the House of Representatives of Congress and payment of the fees prescribed by s. 320.0805, the department may issue to such member of Congress a license plate stamped “Official Congress” followed by the number of the appropriate congressional district and the letters “MC,” or any other configuration chosen by the member which is not already in use. Upon application by a United States Senator and payment of the fees prescribed by s. 320.0805, the department may issue a license plate stamped “USS,” followed by the numeral II in the case of the junior senator.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application by any member of the state House of Representatives and payment of the fees prescribed by s. 320.0805, the department may issue the state representative license plates stamped “Official House,” followed by the number of the appropriate House of Representatives district and the letters “HR,” or any other configuration chosen by the member which is not already in use. Upon application by a state senator and payment of the fees prescribed by s. 320.0805, the department may issue license plates stamped “Official Senate,” followed by the number of the appropriate Senate district and the letters “SN,” or any other configuration chosen by the member which is not already in use.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application by the Governor and payment of the appropriate fees, the department may issue to the Governor two license plates stamped “Florida 1” and “Florida 2.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">License plates purchased under subsection (1), subsection (2), or subsection (3) shall be replaced by the department at no cost, other than the fees required by ss. 320.04 and 320.06(3)(b), when the person to whom the plates have been issued leaves the elective office with respect to which the license plates were issued. Within 30 days after leaving office, the person to whom the license plates have been issued shall make application to the department for a replacement license plate. The person may return the prestige license plates to the department or may retain the plates as souvenirs. Upon receipt of the replacement license plate, the person may not continue to display on any vehicle the prestige license plate or plates issued with respect to his or her former office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application by any current or former President of the Senate and payment of the fees prescribed by s. 320.0805, the department may issue a license plate stamped “Senate President” followed by the number assigned by the department or chosen by the applicant if it is not already in use. Upon application by any current or former Speaker of the House of Representatives and payment of the fees prescribed by s. 320.0805, the department may issue a license plate stamped “House Speaker” followed by the number assigned by the department or chosen by the applicant if it is not already in use.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application by any former member of Congress or former member of the state Legislature, payment of the fees prescribed by s. 320.0805, and payment of a one-time fee of $500, the department may issue a former member of Congress, state senator, or state representative a license plate stamped “Retired Congress,” “Retired Senate,” or “Retired House,” as appropriate, for a vehicle owned by the former member.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To qualify for a Retired Congress, Retired Senate, or Retired House prestige license plate, a former member must have served at least 4 years as a member of Congress, state senator, or state representative, respectively.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four hundred fifty dollars of the one-time fee collected under paragraph (a) shall be distributed to the account of the citizen support organization established pursuant to s. 272.129 and used for the benefit of the Legislative Research Center and Museum at the Historic Capitol, and the remaining $50 shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may create a unique plate design for plates to be used by members or former members of the Legislature or Congress as provided in subsections (2), (5), and (6).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who does not make application for a replacement license plate as required by subsection (4), or who, after receipt of the replacement license plate, continues to display on any vehicle the prestige license plate or plates issued with respect to his or her former office, is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 83-318; s. 1, ch. 84-108; s. 7, ch. 87-225; s. 353, ch. 95-148; s. 12, ch. 97-96; s. 3, ch. 2006-297; s. 27, ch. 2010-223; s. 37, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>