<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.08062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Audits and attestations required; annual use fees of specialty license plates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All organizations that receive annual use fee proceeds from the department are responsible for ensuring that proceeds are used in accordance with ss. 320.08056 and 320.08058.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any organization not subject to audit pursuant to s. 215.97 shall annually attest, under penalties of perjury, that such proceeds were used in compliance with ss. 320.08056 and 320.08058. The attestation shall be made annually in a form and format determined by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any organization subject to audit pursuant to s. 215.97 shall submit an audit report in accordance with rules promulgated by the Auditor General. The annual attestation shall be submitted to the department for review within 9 months after the end of the organization’s fiscal year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days after receiving an organization’s audit or attestation, the department shall determine which recipients of revenues from specialty license plate annual use fees have not complied with subsection (1). If the department determines that an organization has not complied or has failed to use the revenues in accordance with ss. 320.08056 and 320.08058, the department must discontinue the distribution of the revenues to the organization until the department determines that the organization has complied. If an organization fails to comply within 12 months after the annual use fee proceeds are withheld by the department, the proceeds shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund to offset department costs related to the issuance of specialty license plates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has the authority to examine all records pertaining to the use of funds from the sale of specialty license plates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-194; s. 7, ch. 95-282; s. 3, ch. 98-414; s. 270, ch. 99-248; s. 8, ch. 2001-196; s. 102, ch. 2001-266.</History></Section>