<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advance registration renewal; procedures.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of any motor vehicle or mobile home currently registered in this state may file an application for renewal of registration with the department, or its authorized agent in the county wherein the owner resides, any time during the 3 months preceding the date of expiration of the registration period. The registration period may not exceed 27 months.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of any apportioned motor vehicle currently registered in this state may file an application for renewal of registration with the department any time during the 3 months preceding the date of expiration of the registration period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of the application and payment of the appropriate license tax under s. 320.08, service charges required by s. 320.04, and any additional fees required by law, the department or its agent shall issue to the owner of the motor vehicle or mobile home a validation sticker or mobile home sticker, as appropriate, which, when affixed to the license plate or mobile home, shall renew the registration for the appropriate registration period.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who uses a mobile home sticker or validation sticker without lawful authority or who willfully violates any rule of the department relating to this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 70-6; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 194, ch. 71-136; s. 10, ch. 77-357; s. 20, ch. 83-318; s. 18, ch. 86-243; s. 5, ch. 2007-242; s. 19, ch. 2010-223.</History>
</Section>