<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.835" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mobile home and recreational vehicle warranties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manufacturer, dealer, installer, and supplier of mobile homes or recreational vehicles shall warrant each new mobile home or recreational vehicle sold in this state and the setup of each such mobile home, in accordance with the warranty requirements prescribed by this section, for a period of at least 12 months, measured from the date of delivery of the mobile home to the buyer or the date of sale of the recreational vehicle in the case of a manufacturer or dealer, or from the date of receipt of a certificate of occupancy in the case of an installer. The warranty requirements of each manufacturer, dealer, installer, and supplier of mobile homes or recreational vehicles are as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer warrants:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a mobile home or recreational vehicle, that all structural elements; plumbing systems; heating, cooling, and fuel-burning systems; electrical systems; fire prevention systems; and any other components or conditions included by the manufacturer are free from substantial defect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That 100-ampere electrical service exists in the mobile home.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dealer warrants:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That any modifications or alterations made to the mobile home or recreational vehicle by the dealer or authorized by the dealer shall be free from substantial defect. Alterations or modifications made by a dealer shall relieve the manufacturer of warranty responsibility only as to the item altered or modified.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That setup operations performed on the mobile home are performed in compliance with s. 320.8325.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That substantial defects do not occur to the mobile home during setup or by transporting it to the occupancy site.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">When the setup of a mobile home is performed by a person who is not an employee or agent of the mobile home manufacturer or dealer and is not compensated or authorized by, or connected with, such manufacturer or dealer, then the warranty responsibility of the manufacturer or dealer as to setup shall be limited to transporting the mobile home to the occupancy site free from substantial defect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The installer warrants that the setup operations performed on the mobile home are performed in compliance with s. 320.8325 and department rules governing the installation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supplier warrants that any warranties generally offered in the ordinary sale of his or her product to consumers shall be extended to buyers of mobile homes and recreational vehicles. When no warranty is extended by suppliers, the manufacturer shall assume warranty responsibility for that component.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules under chapter 120 to resolve disputes that may arise among the mobile home manufacturer, dealer, installer, or supplier. Those rules must comply with the dispute resolution process as set forth in the federal Manufactured Housing Improvement Act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 74-68; s. 9, ch. 74-169; s. 42, ch. 77-357; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 19, 20, ch. 88-147; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 379, ch. 95-148; s. 9, ch. 2004-283.</History></Section>