<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.0601" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lease and rental car companies; identification of vehicles as for-hire.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rental car company may not rent in this state any for-hire vehicle, other than vehicles designed to transport cargo, that has affixed to its exterior any bumper stickers, insignias, or advertising that identifies the vehicle as a rental vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bumper stickers, insignias, or advertising” does not include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any emblem of no more than two colors which is less than 2 inches by 4 inches, which is placed on the rental car for inventory purposes only, and which does not display the name or logo of the rental car company; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any license required by the law of the state in which the vehicle is registered.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rent in this state” means to sign a rental contract in this state or to deliver a car to a renter in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A rental car company that leases a motor vehicle that is found to be in violation of this section shall be punished by a fine of $500 per occurrence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any registration or renewal as required under s. 320.02 for an original or transfer of a long-term leased motor vehicle must be in the name and address of the lessee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-398; s. 264, ch. 99-248; s. 61, ch. 2005-164.</History></Section>