<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.0715" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">International Registration Plan; motor carrier services; permits; retention of records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All commercial motor vehicles domiciled in this state and engaged in interstate commerce shall be registered in accordance with the provisions of the International Registration Plan and shall display apportioned license plates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An International Registration Plan motor vehicle trip permit registration may be issued for any vehicle which could be lawfully operated in the International Registration Plan jurisdiction if full registration or proportional registration were obtained. A Florida trip permit shall expire 10 days after issuance. The cost of a trip permit shall be $30, payment of which shall exempt the vehicle from payment of Florida apportioned license plate fees during the term for which the permit is valid. Any vehicle for which a trip permit has been issued may be operated in interstate or intrastate commerce in the jurisdiction for the period allowed under such permit. No motor carrier to whom a trip permit is issued shall knowingly allow the permit to be used by any other person, organization, or vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor carrier may, upon payment of the $30 fee, secure from the department or a designated authorized agent of the department a Florida International Registration Plan motor vehicle trip permit which shall be valid for 10 days. Such trip permit shall show the name and address of the motor carrier to whom it is issued, the date the vehicle is placed in and removed from service, a complete identification of the vehicle on which the permit is to be used, and the name and address of the owner or lessee of the vehicle. The permit shall then be carried on the vehicle which it identifies and shall be exhibited on demand to any authorized personnel. The motor carrier to whom a permit is issued shall be solely responsible for the proper use of the permit by its employees and lessees. Any erasure, alteration, or unauthorized use of such permit shall render it invalid and of no effect. Florida International Registration Plan motor vehicle trip permits may be transmitted to the motor carrier by electronic means and shall be complete as outlined by department personnel prior to transmittal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special temporary permits shall be provided to owner-operators not operating as a lessor, for a fee of $5. Such permit shall be valid for 10 days and shall only be utilized for owner-operator vehicles with a registered gross weight not in excess of the empty or unladen weight of the vehicle. Special temporary permits may be issued by the department or by any of its designated authorized agents. A special temporary permit may be transmitted to the owner-operator by electronic means and must be completed as outlined by department personnel prior to transmittal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department is unable to immediately issue the apportioned license plate to an applicant currently registered in this state under the International Registration Plan or to a vehicle currently titled in this state, the department or its designated agent is authorized to issue a 60-day temporary operational permit. The department or agent of the department shall charge a $3 fee and the service charge authorized by s. 320.04 for each temporary operational permit it issues.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall in no event issue a temporary operational permit for any commercial motor vehicle to any applicant until the applicant has shown that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All sales or use taxes due on the registration of the vehicle are paid; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance requirements have been met in accordance with ss. 320.02(5) and 627.7415.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a temporary operational permit provides commercial motor vehicle registration privileges in each International Registration Plan member jurisdiction designated on said permit and therefore requires payment of all applicable registration fees and taxes due for that period of registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for permanent registration must be made to the department within 10 days from issuance of a temporary operational permit. Failure to file an application within this 10-day period may result in cancellation of the temporary operational permit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each motor carrier registered under the International Registration Plan shall maintain and keep, for a period of 4 years, pertinent records and papers as may be required by the department for the reasonable administration of this chapter.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall withhold registrations and license plates for commercial motor vehicles unless the identifying number issued by the federal agency responsible for motor carrier safety is provided for the motor carrier and the entity responsible for motor carrier safety for each motor vehicle as part of the application process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a commercial motor vehicle registration or license plate to, and may not transfer the commercial motor vehicle registration or license plate for, a motor carrier or vehicle owner who has been prohibited from operating by a federal or state agency responsible for motor carrier safety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, with notice, shall suspend any commercial motor vehicle registration and license plate issued to a motor carrier or vehicle owner who has been prohibited from operating by a federal or state agency responsible for motor carrier safety.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section do not apply to any commercial motor vehicle domiciled in a foreign state that enters this state solely for the purpose of bringing a commercial vehicle in for repairs, or picking up a newly purchased commercial vehicle, so long as the commercial motor vehicle is operated by its owner and is not hauling a load.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 50, ch. 85-180; s. 19, ch. 86-243; s. 27, ch. 87-198; s. 8, ch. 88-306; s. 8, ch. 90-329; s. 27, ch. 95-143; s. 40, ch. 99-385; s. 20, ch. 2008-176.</History></Section>