<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.08058" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Specialty license plates.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MANATEE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a manatee license plate to commemorate the official state marine mammal. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Save the Manatee” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manatee license plate annual use fee must be deposited into the Save the Manatee Trust Fund, created within the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, and shall be used only for the purposes specified in s. 379.2431(4).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (b), up to 10 percent of the annual use fee deposited in the Save the Manatee Trust Fund from the sale of the manatee license plate may be used to promote and market the license plate issued by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles after June 30, 2007.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHALLENGER/COLUMBIA LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Challenger/Columbia license plate to commemorate the seven astronauts who died when the space shuttle Challenger exploded on liftoff in 1986 and the seven astronauts who died when the Columbia exploded on reentry in 2003. The word “Florida” shall appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Challenger/Columbia” must appear at the bottom of the plate, in small letters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent of the Challenger/Columbia license plate annual use fee must be distributed to the Astronauts Memorial Foundation, Inc., to support the operations of the Center for Space Education and the Education Technology Institute. Funds received by the Astronauts Memorial Foundation, Inc., may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operation of the center and the institute. These funds must be used for the maintenance and support of the operations of the Center for Space Education and the Education Technology Institute operated by the Astronauts Memorial Foundation, Inc. These operations must include preservice and inservice training in the use of technology for the state’s instructional personnel in a manner consistent with state training programs and approved by the Department of Education. Up to 20 percent of funds received by the Center for Space Education and the Education Technology Institute may be expended for administrative costs directly associated with the operation of the center and the institute.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent must be distributed to the Technological Research and Development Authority created by s. 2, chapter 87-455, Laws of Florida, for the purpose of funding space-related research grants, the Teacher/Quest Scholarship Program under s. 1009.61 as approved by the Florida Department of Education, and space-related economic development programs. The Technological Research and Development Authority shall coordinate and distribute available resources among state universities and independent colleges and universities based on the research strengths of such institutions in space science technology, community colleges, public school districts, and not-for-profit educational organizations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 percent of the funds distributed under paragraphs (b) and (c) may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General has the authority to examine any and all records pertaining to the Astronauts Memorial Foundation, Inc., and the Technological Research and Development Authority to determine compliance with the law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COLLEGIATE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a collegiate license plate as provided in this section for state and independent universities domiciled in this state. However, any collegiate license plate created or established after October 1, 2002, must comply with the requirements of s. 320.08053 and be specifically authorized by an act of the Legislature. Collegiate license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department as appropriate for each state and independent university. The word “Florida” must be stamped across the bottom of the plate in small letters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A collegiate plate annual use fee is to be distributed to the state or independent university foundation designated by the purchaser for deposit in an unrestricted account. The Board of Governors of the State University System shall require each state university to submit a plan for approval of the expenditure of all funds so designated. These funds may be used only for academic enhancement, including scholarships and private fundraising activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA SALUTES VETERANS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Salutes Veterans license plate. The words “Florida Salutes Veterans” and the flag of the United States of America must appear on the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Salutes Veterans license plate annual use fee shall be distributed as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent shall be distributed to a direct-support organization created under s. 292.055 for a period not to exceed 48 months after the date the direct-support organization is incorporated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any remaining fees must be deposited in the State Homes for Veterans Trust Fund, which is created in the State Treasury. All such moneys are to be administered by the Department of Veterans’ Affairs and must be used solely for the purpose of constructing, operating, and maintaining domiciliary and nursing homes for veterans and for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate, subject to the requirements of chapter 216. </Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA PANTHER LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida panther license plate as provided in this section. Florida panther license plates must bear the design of a Florida panther and the colors that department approves. In small letters, the word “Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida panther license plate annual use fee must be deposited in the Florida Panther Research and Management Trust Fund in the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission to be used for education and programs to protect the endangered Florida panther, and up to 10 percent of such deposit may be used to promote and market the license plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or corporation that purchases 10,000 or more panther license plates shall pay an annual use fee of $5 per plate and an annual processing fee of $2 per plate, in addition to the applicable license tax required under s. 320.08.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA UNITED STATES OLYMPIC COMMITTEE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the United States Olympic Committee has selected this state to participate in a combined fundraising program that provides for one-half of all money raised through volunteer giving to stay in this state and be administered by Enterprise Florida, Inc., to support amateur sports, and because the United States Olympic Committee and Enterprise Florida, Inc., are nonprofit organizations dedicated to providing athletes with support and training and preparing athletes of all ages and skill levels for sports competition, and because Enterprise Florida, Inc., assists in the bidding for sports competitions that provide significant impact to the economy of this state, and the Legislature supports the efforts of the United States Olympic Committee and Enterprise Florida, Inc., the Legislature establishes a Florida United States Olympic Committee license plate for the purpose of providing a continuous funding source to support this worthwhile effort. Florida United States Olympic Committee license plates must contain the official United States Olympic Committee logo and must bear a design and colors that are approved by the department. The word “Florida” must be centered at the top of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees are to be annually distributed as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first $5 million collected annually must be paid to the direct-support organization to be distributed as follows:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent must be distributed to the direct-support organization to be used for Florida’s Sunshine State Games.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent must be distributed to the United States Olympic Committee.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional fees must be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SPECIAL OLYMPICS FLORIDA LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special Olympics Florida license plates must contain the official Special Olympics Florida logo and must bear a design and colors that are approved by the department. The word “Florida” must be centered at the bottom of the plate, and the words “Everyone Wins” must be centered at the top of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees are to be annually distributed as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first $5 million collected annually must be forwarded to the private nonprofit corporation as described in s. 393.002 and must be used solely for Special Olympics purposes as approved by the private nonprofit corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional fees must be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA EDUCATIONAL LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop a Florida educational license plate as provided in this section. Florida educational license plates must bear a design and colors that the department approves. The word “Florida” must appear in small letters at the top of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license annual use fees are to be distributed annually as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 percent of the moneys raised from the sale of the plates may be used for continuing marketing and promotion of the plates.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In each school district that has a district prekindergarten through grade 12 public school foundation or a direct-support organization, the moneys raised in that school district through the sale of Florida educational license plates must be distributed to the foundation or organization for enhancing educational programs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In each school district that does not have a district prekindergarten through grade 12 public school foundation or a direct-support organization, the moneys raised in that school district through the sale of Florida educational license plates must be distributed to the district school board and must be used at the discretion of the board for enhancing educational programs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA PROFESSIONAL SPORTS TEAM LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop a Florida Professional Sports Team license plate as provided in this section for Major League Baseball, National Basketball Association, National Football League, Arena Football Teams, and National Hockey League teams domiciled in this state. However, any Florida Professional Sports Team license plate created or established after January 1, 1997, must comply with the requirements of s. 320.08053 and be specifically authorized by an act of the Legislature. Florida Professional Sports Team license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department and must include the official league or team logo, or both, as appropriate for each team. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees are to be annually distributed as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty-five percent of the proceeds from the Florida Professional Sports Team plate must be deposited into the Professional Sports Development Trust Fund within the Department of Economic Opportunity. These funds must be used solely to attract and support major sports events in this state. As used in this subparagraph, the term “major sports events” means, but is not limited to, championship or all-star contests of Major League Baseball, the National Basketball Association, the National Football League, the National Hockey League, the men’s and women’s National Collegiate Athletic Association Final Four basketball championship, or a horseracing or dogracing Breeders’ Cup. All funds must be used to support and promote major sporting events, and the uses must be approved by the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds of the Florida Professional Sports Team license plate must be allocated to Enterprise Florida, Inc. These funds must be deposited into the Professional Sports Development Trust Fund within the Department of Economic Opportunity. These funds must be used by Enterprise Florida, Inc., to promote the economic development of the sports industry; to distribute licensing and royalty fees to participating professional sports teams; to promote education programs in Florida schools that provide an awareness of the benefits of physical activity and nutrition standards; to partner with the Department of Education and the Department of Health to develop a program that recognizes schools whose students demonstrate excellent physical fitness or fitness improvement; to institute a grant program for communities bidding on minor sporting events that create an economic impact for the state; to distribute funds to Florida-based charities designated by Enterprise Florida, Inc., and the participating professional sports teams; and to fulfill the sports promotion responsibilities of the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall provide an annual financial audit in accordance with s. 215.981 of its financial accounts and records by an independent certified public accountant pursuant to the contract established by the Department of Economic Opportunity. The auditor shall submit the audit report to the Department of Economic Opportunity for review and approval. If the audit report is approved, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall certify the audit report to the Auditor General for review.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraphs 1. and 2., proceeds from the Professional Sports Development Trust Fund may also be used for operational expenses of Enterprise Florida, Inc., and financial support of the Sunshine State Games.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA INDIAN RIVER LAGOON LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the Indian River Lagoon system has been targeted by the state as a priority water body for restoration and preservation since the 1987 Surface Water Improvement and Management Act, and because the St. Johns River and South Florida Water Management Districts have jointly developed a management plan that includes water quality improvement, habitat restoration, and public awareness and education, and because the United States Environmental Protection Agency has declared the Indian River Lagoon to be an estuary of national significance, and because coastal lagoon activities relating to saltwater fishing account for a multibillion dollar economic base, and because the Legislature supports the restoration efforts of the water management districts, the Legislature establishes a Florida Indian River Lagoon license plate for the purpose of providing a continuous funding source to support this worthwhile effort and to heighten public awareness of this economically significant resource. Florida Indian River Lagoon license plates must contain the fish “snook,” which has been used as the Indian River Lagoon Surface Water Improvement and Management logo, suspended over seagrass, and must bear the colors and design approved by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees are to be distributed annually as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first $5 million collected annually must be transferred to the St. Johns River Water Management District. The district shall account for these funds separate from all other funds received. These funds must be distributed as follows:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on Florida Indian River Lagoon license plate sales data from each county tax collector for Volusia, Brevard, Indian River, St. Lucie, Martin, and Palm Beach Counties, each county’s total number of Florida Indian River Lagoon license plates sold between October 1 and September 30 must represent a percentage of the six-county total, calculated as follows: the total number sold for county A divided by the total number sold for counties A, B, C, D, E, and F is multiplied by 100. The percentage determined for St. Lucie, Martin, and Palm Beach Counties must be totaled, and that total percentage of the statewide Florida Indian River Lagoon license plate revenues must be transferred to the South Florida Water Management District special Indian River Lagoon License Plate Revenue Account and distributed proportionately among St. Lucie, Martin, and Palm Beach Counties. The remaining funds in the St. Johns River Water Management District Revenue Account must be divided proportionately between Volusia, Brevard, and Indian River Counties.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each water management district is responsible for administering projects in its respective counties funded with the appropriate percentage of license plate revenues.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 5 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fee may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional fees must be deposited into the General Revenue Fund. Fees are not to be deposited into the general revenue funds of the water management districts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of Florida Indian River Lagoon license plate annual use fees is to be administered by the St. Johns River and South Florida Water Management Districts for Indian River Lagoon projects and in accordance with their contracting and purchasing policies and procedures, with the following restrictions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual amount of the total license plate use fees must be earmarked for each of the six lagoon basin counties, as determined in sub-subparagraph (b)1.a., to be expended in those counties on habitat restoration, including water quality improvement, and environmental education projects. At least 80 percent of the use fees must be used for restoration projects, and not more than 20 percent may be used for environmental education in each county. These project funds may serve as matching funds for other local, state, or federal funds or grants. Unencumbered funds from one year may be carried over to the following year but must be dedicated to a project within 2 years in the form of a contract, an interlocal agreement, or an approved plan by the governing board of the respective district.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Indian River Lagoon license plate annual use fees may not be used for administrative salaries or overhead within the water management districts, nor for any general coordination fees or overhead outside of the districts which is not specifically related to a project, nor for any projects which are considered to be research, studies, inventories, or evaluations, nor for administrative salaries or overhead related to environmental education or ongoing regular maintenance. Annual use fees may be used for acquisition of rights-of-way specific to the implementation of restoration or improvement projects, if acquisition expenditures do not exceed 20 percent of a county’s appropriation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In Volusia County, project implementation may occur in all estuarine waters extending north to and including the Tomoka Basin.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In Palm Beach County, first priority must be given to projects within the Indian River Lagoon. Second priority must be given to projects within adjacent estuarine waters.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that revenues generated by the Florida Indian River Lagoon license plate annual use fees must not be used as replacement funds for Surface Water Improvement and Management Act funds, but must be used solely for the enhancement of the Indian River Lagoon area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVEST IN CHILDREN LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop an Invest in Children license plate. Invest in Children license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Invest in Children” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the Invest in Children license plate annual use fee must be deposited into the Juvenile Crime Prevention and Early Intervention Trust Fund within the Department of Juvenile Justice. Based on the recommendations of the juvenile justice councils, the department shall use the proceeds of the fee to fund programs and services that are designed to prevent juvenile delinquency. The department shall allocate moneys for programs and services within each county based on that county’s proportionate share of the license plate annual use fee collected by the county.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA ARTS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop a Florida arts license plate as provided in this section. In small letters, the word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the word “Art” or “Arts” or a combination of words including the word “Art” or “Arts” may appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees are to be distributed quarterly to the single arts council officially designated by the county in direct proportion to the amounts of fees collected in each county. If there is no county arts council, fees collected must be forwarded to such other agency in the county as the highest ranking county administrative official designates, to be applied by the arts council or agency to support arts organizations, arts programs, and arts activities within the county.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BETHUNE-COOKMAN UNIVERSITY LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Bethune-Cookman University license plate to commemorate Bethune-Cookman University.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees must be distributed to Bethune-Cookman University.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA AGRICULTURAL LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop a Florida Agricultural license plate. Florida Agricultural license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Agriculture” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Keeps Florida Green” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the Florida Agricultural license plate annual use fee must be forwarded to the direct-support organization created in s. 570.903. The funds must be used for the sole purpose of funding and promoting the Florida agriculture in the classroom program established within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services pursuant to s. 570.91.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 25 percent of the funds distributed under paragraphs (a) and (b) may be used for promotion, marketing, and administrative costs directly associated with the license plate and Florida agriculture in the classroom programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POLICE ATHLETIC LEAGUE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Police Athletic League license plate as provided in this section to commemorate the Police Athletic League in this state. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, the words “Police Athletic League” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and a shield with the Police Athletic League logo must appear to the left of the numerals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the State of Florida Association of Police Athletic/Activities Leagues, Inc.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The league may use a maximum of 15 percent of such fees for administrative costs and a maximum of 10 percent to market and promote the plate. The balance of such fees shall be used to provide educational materials, athletic equipment, transportation, food, medical checkups, counseling, scholarships, and other direct expenses incurred by the league in conducting its youth programs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOY SCOUTS OF AMERICA LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop a Boy Scouts of America license plate. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Scouting Teaches Values” must appear at the bottom of the plate. The license plate must contain the official Boy Scouts of America logo, the fleur-de-lis, in the center of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Central Florida Council is the lead Boy Scout council on behalf of the nine councils in this state. The proceeds from the annual use fee must be sent to the Central Florida Council together with statistics on sales of the license plates which are tabulated by county. The Central Florida Council must distribute to each of the nine councils the moneys received from sales in the counties within the respective council.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Boy Scouts of America license plate annual use fee may be used by the councils for basic administrative expenses, office and professional services, year-round camping facilities, the recruitment of adult leaders and their continuing training, the maintenance of current facilities, and the continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LARGEMOUTH BASS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Largemouth Bass license plate as provided in this section to commemorate the official freshwater fish of this state. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, the words “Go Fishing” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and a representation of a largemouth bass must appear to the left of the numerals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the State Game Trust Fund and used by the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission to fund current conservation programs that maintain current levels of protection and management of this state’s fish and wildlife resources, including providing hunting, fishing, and nonconsumptive wildlife opportunities. Up to 10 percent of the annual use fees deposited into the trust fund may be used to promote and market the license plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SEA TURTLE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Sea Turtle license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, the words “Helping Sea Turtles Survive” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and the image of a sea turtle must appear in the center of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first $500,000 of annual use fees shall be deposited in the Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund in the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission and shall be used by the Florida Marine Turtle Protection Program to conduct sea turtle protection, research, and recovery programs. The next $215,000 in annual use fees shall be distributed to the Caribbean Conservation Corporation to fund sea turtle research and education programs. The Caribbean Conservation Corporation shall annually distribute assigned funds through a Sea Turtle Grants Program that supports sea turtle research and education activities of Florida-based nonprofit groups, education and research institutions, and coastal counties in this state. The Caribbean Conservation Corporation shall write and publish procedures for submitting grant applications and criteria for allocating available funds, and shall appoint a technical advisory committee, composed of at least five members, including two representatives from the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, to establish funding priorities and select grant recipients from proposals submitted by eligible entities. Two of the members shall be selected from the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission; one member shall be selected on a rotating biennial basis from a county bordering on the Atlantic Coast with sea turtle nesting sites; one member shall be selected on a rotating biennial basis from a county bordering on the Gulf Coast with sea turtle nesting sites; one member shall be the executive director of the Caribbean Conservation Corporation; and two members shall be selected at large. Any additional annual revenue shall be distributed as follows: 70 percent shall be deposited in the Marine Resources Conservation Trust Fund and used by the Florida Marine Turtle Protection Program for sea turtle conservation activities and 30 percent shall be assigned to the Caribbean Conservation Corporation for distribution through the Sea Turtle Grants Program. From the funds distributed to the Caribbean Conservation Corporation, an amount not to exceed 10 percent of the total annual revenue from the sale of the plate may be used for marketing the Sea Turtle license plate and for administrative costs directly associated with the grants program. Funds received by the Caribbean Conservation Corporation from the Sea Turtle license plate or the Sea Turtle Grants Program and funds received by any grant recipient of the Sea Turtle Grants Program may not be used for litigation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROTECT WILD DOLPHINS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Protect Wild Dolphins license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Protect Wild Dolphins” may appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., to fund wild dolphins related research. The Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., shall distribute available resources for research of the wild Florida Bottlenose Dolphin. Up to 15 percent of the funds received by Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., may be expended for administrative costs directly associated with the operations of the institution. Up to 10 percent of the funds distributed may be used by Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate. The remainder of the funds must be used to collect, analyze, and archive scientific data regarding the wild dolphin population in Florida waters; provide care and assistance to stranded wild dolphins; distribute information to the scientific community, federal, state, and local government agencies, educational institutions, and the public for the purpose of protecting and preserving wild dolphins; individually identify wild dolphins through a photographic identification program; and advance the research technology associated with tracking and categorizing wild dolphins.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Auditor General may examine any records of the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., and any other organization that receives funds from the sale of this plate, to determine compliance with law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BARRY UNIVERSITY LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Barry University license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Barry University” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Barry University Alumni Endowed Scholarship Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EVERGLADES RIVER OF GRASS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop an Everglades River of Grass license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Everglades River of Grass” must appear at the bottom of the plate. A roseate spoonbill bird standing beside mangroves must appear on the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Everglades Trust Fund established by s. 17, Art. X of the State Constitution and administered by the South Florida Water Management District and used for the conservation and protection of the natural resources and abatement of water pollution in the Everglades. The funds must be used for Everglades conservation and restoration projects in accordance with state contracting and purchasing procedures with the following restrictions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent of the fees must be used for Everglades research.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees may not be used for administrative salaries or other overhead within the district or for any general coordination fees or overhead expenses out of the district.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenues generated by these fees may not be used as replacement funds for Surface Water Improvement and Management Act funds or Everglades Forever Act Funds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">KEEP KIDS DRUG-FREE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Keep Kids Drug-Free license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Keep Kids Drug-Free” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Keep Kids Drug-Free Foundation, Inc., which shall use the fees to fund activities to reduce substance abuse among residents of this state. The foundation shall develop a plan to distribute the funds for drug-abuse prevention programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 320.08062, up to 10 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fee may be used for marketing the Keep Kids Drug-Free license plate and for administrative costs directly related to the management and distribution of the proceeds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA SHERIFFS YOUTH RANCHES LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Sheriffs Youth Ranches license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Sponsored by the Florida Sheriffs Association” must appear at the bottom of the plate. The Florida Sheriffs Youth Ranches logo must appear on the left quarter of the plate, surrounded by the words “Florida Sheriffs Youth Ranches” and the words “Preventing delinquency since 1957” must appear below the numerals on the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Sheriffs Youth Ranches, Inc., for its operations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSERVE WILDLIFE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Conserve Wildlife license plate. Conserve Wildlife license plates shall bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” shall appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Conserve Wildlife” shall appear at the bottom of the plate. The plate design shall include the likeness of a Florida black bear.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the Conserve Wildlife license plate annual use fee shall be forwarded to the Wildlife Foundation of Florida, Inc., a citizen support organization created pursuant to s. 379.223.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 320.08062, up to 10 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fee may be used for marketing the Conserve Wildlife license plate and administrative costs directly related to the management and distribution of the proceeds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds from the annual use fee shall be used for programs and activities of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission that contribute to the health and well-being of Florida black bears and other wildlife diversity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA MEMORIAL UNIVERSITY LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Memorial University license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Florida Memorial University” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Florida Memorial University.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="26">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TAMPA BAY ESTUARY LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Tampa Bay Estuary license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, the words “Tampa Bay Estuary” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and the image of a tarpon must appear on the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Tampa Bay Estuary Program created by s. 163.01.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of 5 percent of such fees may be used for marketing the plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent of the proceeds from the annual use fee, not to exceed $50,000, shall be provided to the Tampa Bay Regional Planning Council for activities of the Agency on Bay Management implementing the Council/Agency Action Plan for the restoration of the Tampa Bay estuary, as approved by the Tampa Bay Estuary Program Policy Board.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds must be used to implement the Comprehensive Conservation and Management Plan for Tampa Bay, pursuant to priorities approved by the Tampa Bay Estuary Program Policy Board.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="27">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA WILDFLOWER LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Wildflower license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “State Wildflower” and “coreopsis” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Reference Number="1" />
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Wildflower Foundation, Inc., a nonprofit corporation under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. The proceeds must be used to establish native Florida wildflower research programs, wildflower educational programs, and wildflower grant programs to municipal, county, and community-based groups in this state.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Wildflower Foundation, Inc., shall develop procedures of operation, research contracts, education and marketing programs, and wildflower planting grants for Florida native wildflowers, plants, and grasses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of 15 percent of the proceeds from the sale of such plates may be used for administrative and marketing costs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Florida Wildflower Foundation, Inc., ceases to be an active nonprofit corporation under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, the proceeds from the annual use fee shall be deposited into the General Inspection Trust Fund created within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. Any funds held by the Florida Wildflower Foundation, Inc., must be promptly transferred to the General Inspection Trust Fund. The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services shall use and administer the proceeds from the use fee in the manner specified in this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="28">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a United States Marine Corps license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top center of the plate, and the words “Marine Corps” must appear at the bottom center of the plate. The United States Marine Corps logo, 3 inches in diameter, must appear on the left side centered top to bottom of the plate in proper colors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall distribute the United States Marine Corps license plate annual use fees as provided in this paragraph.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first $50,000 collected annually shall be distributed to the Marine Corps Scholarship Foundation, Inc.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any remaining fees collected annually shall be distributed as follows:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirty-five percent shall be deposited in the State Homes for Veterans Trust Fund and must be used solely for the purpose of constructing, operating, and maintaining domiciliary and nursing homes for veterans subject to the requirements of chapter 216.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sixty-five percent shall be distributed to the Marine Corps Scholarship Foundation, Inc., which shall use all fees distributed by the department to fund scholarships and assist Marine Corps Junior ROTC and Young Marine programs of this state. The foundation shall develop a plan to distribute the funds to recipients nominated by residents of the state to receive scholarships, and to the Marine Corps Junior ROTC and Young Marine programs in the state.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="29">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHOOSE LIFE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Choose Life license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and the words “Choose Life” must appear at the top of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed annually to Choose Life, Inc., along with a report that specifies the ratio that the annual use fees collected by each county bear to the total fees collected for the plates within the state. Choose Life, Inc., shall distribute each county’s share of the funds to nongovernmental, not-for-profit agencies within each Florida county which assist pregnant women who are making an adoption plan for their children. Funds may not be distributed to any agency that is involved or associated with abortion activities, including counseling for or referrals to abortion clinics, providing medical abortion-related procedures, or proabortion advertising, and funds may not be distributed to any agency that charges women for services received.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agencies that receive the funds must use the funds to provide for the material needs of pregnant women who are making an adoption plan for their children, including, but not limited to, clothing, housing, medical care, food, utilities, and transportation. Such funds may also be expended on birth mothers for 60 days after delivery and on infants awaiting placement with adoptive parents.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds may also be used for adoption-related counseling, training, or advertising but may not be used for administrative expenses, legal expenses, or capital expenditures. However, a maximum of 15 percent of the total funds received annually may be used by Choose Life, Inc., for the administration and promotion of the Choose Life license plate program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no qualified agency applies to receive funds in a county in any year, that county’s Choose Life funds shall be distributed pro rata to any qualified agencies that apply and maintain a place of business within a 100-mile radius of the county seat of such county. If no qualified agencies apply, the funds shall be held by Choose Life, Inc., until a qualified agency under this section applies for the funds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency that receives such funds must submit an annual attestation to Choose Life, Inc. Any unused funds that exceed 10 percent of the funds received by an agency each year must be returned to Choose Life, Inc., which shall distribute the funds to other qualified agencies within the State of Florida.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By October 1, 2011, the department and each county shall transfer all of its Choose Life license plate funds to Choose Life, Inc.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="30">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHARE THE ROAD LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Share the Road license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Share the Road” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Bike Florida, Inc., up to 25 percent of which shall be used for marketing and promotion of the “Share the Road” concept and license plate. The remaining funds shall be divided equally between Bike Florida, Inc., and the Florida Bicycle Association, Inc., to be used for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Education and awareness programs, for bicycle safety and motorist safety, with emphasis on sharing the roadway by all users.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Training, workshops, educational materials, and media events.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The promotion of safe bicycling.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="31">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AMERICAN RED CROSS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop an American Red Cross license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “American Red Cross” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall retain all revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and issuing the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, 50 percent of the annual use fees shall be distributed to the American Red Cross Chapter of Central Florida, with statistics on sales of license plates, which are tabulated by county. The American Red Cross Chapter of Central Florida must distribute to each of the chapters in this state the moneys received from sales in the counties covered by the respective chapters, which moneys must be used for education and disaster relief in Florida. Fifty percent of the annual use fees shall be distributed proportionately to the three statewide approved poison control centers for purposes of combating bioterrorism and other poison-related purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="32">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNITED WE STAND LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a United We Stand license plate as provided in this section. The American Flag must appear on the license plate in addition to the words “United We Stand.” The colors of the license plate must be red, white, and blue.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall retain all revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and issuing the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, 100 percent of the annual use fee shall be distributed to the Department of Transportation to fund security-related aviation projects pursuant to chapter 332.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="33">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BREAST CANCER RESEARCH LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop a Breast Cancer Research license plate as provided in this section. The plate shall be designed to include a figure on the left side of the plate with a pink ribbon on the chest, along with a pink banner displaying the Florida Breast Cancer Coalition (FBCC) website. The background shall be blue, and the words “End Breast Cancer” shall appear at the top of the plate. The word “Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall distribute the Breast Cancer Research license plate annual use fee to the Florida Breast Cancer Coalition Research Foundation to be used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fees collected shall be forwarded quarterly to the Florida Breast Cancer Coalition Research Foundation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foundation shall provide for a peer review grant solicitation and award process to distribute fees for breast cancer research and education in the State of Florida. Research funding shall be made available for:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Basic, clinical, and translational breast cancer research.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Epidemiological studies of breast cancer.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research on possible links between breast cancer and the environment.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Psychoimmunological research.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Innovative awards and idea grants.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the first year that the plate is issued, no more than 25 percent of the fees collected may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operation of the Florida Breast Cancer Coalition Research Foundation and marketing and promotion of the Florida breast cancer research concept and license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the second and subsequent years that the plate is sold, no more than 20 percent of the fees collected may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operation of the Florida Breast Cancer Coalition Research Foundation and marketing and promotion of the Florida breast cancer research concept and license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="34">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROTECT FLORIDA WHALES LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Protect Florida Whales license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” shall appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Protect Florida Whales” shall appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., to fund whale research, rehabilitation, and education programs. Up to 15 percent of the funds received by the institution may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution’s Marine Mammal Research and Conservation program and this specialty license plate funding. Up to 10 percent of the funds may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate. Ten percent of the funds shall be distributed to the Wyland Foundation, Inc., and used specifically to conduct educational programs in this state which promote conservation of Florida marine mammals. The remainder of the funds shall be used to collect, analyze, and archive scientific data regarding whale populations that inhabit, utilize, or migrate in state waters; provide care and assistance to stranded whales; construct and maintain a Harbor-Branch-based teaching marine mammal hospital; train veterinary students in the rescue, medical and rehabilitation treatment, and release and postrelease monitoring of stranded whales; distribute information for the purpose of protecting and preserving whales; identify whale populations; conduct scientific research through genetic, telemetry, bioacoustical, and photographic identification research programs; advance the research technology associated with tracking, monitoring, and categorizing whales; develop methods of monitoring whale movements; and provide for methods of early-warning detection systems and advance notification that will help prevent accidental boat strikes in state waters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="35">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA GOLF LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall develop a Florida Golf license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate. The Dade Amateur Golf Association, following consultation with the PGA TOUR, Enterprise Florida, Inc., the LPGA, and the PGA of America may submit a revised sample plate for consideration by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall distribute the Florida Golf license plate annual use fee to the Dade Amateur Golf Association, a nonprofit organization under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. The license plate annual use fees are to be annually allocated as follows: </Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 15 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fees may be used by the Dade Amateur Golf Association for the administration of the Florida Junior Golf Program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Dade Amateur Golf Association shall receive the first $80,000 in proceeds from the annual use fees for the operation of youth golf programs in Miami-Dade County. Thereafter, 15 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fees shall be provided to the Dade Amateur Golf Association for the operation of youth golf programs in Miami-Dade County.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds from the annual use fees shall be available for grants to nonprofit organizations to operate youth golf programs and for marketing the Florida Golf license plates. All grant recipients shall be required to provide to the Dade Amateur Golf Association an annual program and financial report regarding the use of grant funds. Such reports shall be made available to the public.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Dade Amateur Golf Association shall establish a Florida Junior Golf Council. The Florida Junior Golf Council shall assist organizations for the benefit of youth, introduce young people to golf, instruct young people in golf, teach the values of golf, and stress life skills, fair play, courtesy, and self-discipline.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Dade Amateur Golf Association shall establish a seven-member Florida Junior Golf Council to offer advice regarding the distribution of the annual use fees for grants to nonprofit organizations. The council shall consist of one member from a group serving youth, one member from a group serving disabled youth, and five members at large.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="36">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA FIREFIGHTERS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a Florida Firefighters license plate as provided in this section. Florida Firefighters license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Salutes Firefighters” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of s. 320.08053 must be met prior to the issuance of the plate. Thereafter, the proceeds of the annual use fee shall be distributed to Florida Firefighters Charities, a s. 501(c)(3) nonprofit corporation. Florida Firefighters Charities shall distribute the moneys according to its articles of incorporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="37">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POLICE BENEVOLENT ASSOCIATION LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a Police Benevolent Association license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, the words “Support Law Enforcement” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and a shield with the Police Benevolent Association logo must appear to the left of the numerals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of s. 320.08053 must be met prior to the issuance of the plate. Thereafter, the proceeds of the annual use fee shall be distributed to the Florida Police Benevolent Association Heart Fund, Incorporated, a s. 501(c)(3) nonprofit corporation. The Florida Police Benevolent Association Heart Fund, Incorporated, shall distribute moneys according to its articles of incorporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="38">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MILITARY SERVICES LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a series of military services license plates for the United States Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the word “Army,” “Navy,” “Air Force,” or “Coast Guard” must appear at the bottom of the plate. The appropriate logo for the particular branch of the military must appear on the left side of the plate, approximately 3 inches in diameter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall retain all revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and issuing the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, the annual use fee shall be deposited into the State Homes for Veterans Trust Fund and must be used solely to construct, operate, and maintain domiciliary and nursing homes for veterans, subject to the requirements of chapter 216.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="39">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROTECT OUR REEFS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Protect Our Reefs license plate as provided in this section. Protect Our Reefs license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Protect Our Reefs” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the annual use fee shall be distributed to Mote Marine Laboratory, Inc., to fund Florida reef research, conservation, and education programs. Up to 15 percent of the funds received by Mote Marine Laboratory, Inc., may be expended for annual administrative costs directly associated with the administration of the Protect Our Reefs program. Up to 10 percent of the funds received by Mote Marine Laboratory, Inc., may be used by Mote Marine Laboratory, Inc., for the continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate. After reimbursement for documented costs expended in the establishment of the plate, Mote Marine Laboratory, Inc., shall use and distribute the remaining funds to eligible Florida-based scientific, conservation, and education organizations for the collection, analysis, and distribution of scientific, educational, and conservation information to the research community; federal, state, and local government agencies; educational institutions; and the public. Eligible organizations shall be based in Florida and engaged in reef research, conservation, or education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state Auditor General may examine any records of Mote Marine Laboratory, Inc., and any other organization that receives funds from the sale of the Protect Our Reefs license plate, to determine compliance with law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="40">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“FISH FLORIDA” LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Fish Florida license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Fish Florida!” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Foundation for Responsible Angling, Inc., to fund aquatic education, marine resource stewardship, and ethical angling practices in this state. A maximum of 15 percent of the funds received by the foundation may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the foundation’s grant distribution program and license plate funding. A maximum of 10 percent of the funds may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate. The foundation shall provide for a peer review grant solicitation and award process to distribute the remainder of the funds to benefit aquatic education, marine resource stewardship, and ethical angling practices in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="41">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHILD ABUSE PREVENTION AND INTERVENTION LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Child Abuse Prevention and Intervention license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Stop Child Abuse” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Children’s Home Society of Florida and the Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers as follows: The first $90,000 in annual use fees shall be equally divided between the two organizations, to be used to pay startup costs, including costs incurred in developing and issuing the plates. Thereafter, 50 percent of the proceeds shall be distributed to the Children’s Home Society of Florida, which must distribute the funds proportionately to each of its divisions, to be used for child abuse prevention programs. The other 50 percent of the proceeds shall be distributed to the board of directors of the Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc., who shall develop funding criteria and an allocation methodology that ensures an equitable distribution of those funds among network participant centers that meet the standards set forth in s. 39.3035. The criteria and methodologies shall take into account factors that include, but need not be limited to, the center’s accreditation status with respect to the National Children’s Alliance, the number of clients served, and the population of the area being served by the children’s advocacy center.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the first 5 years in which the plate is issued, a maximum of 20 percent of the fees collected may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operation of the marketing and promotion of the plate. Ten percent of the fees shall be allocated to the Children’s Home Society of Florida and 10 percent shall be allocated to the Florida Network of Children’s Advocacy Centers, Inc. Five years after the date the first license plate is issued, revenues from plate sales may not be used for marketing or promoting the license plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="42">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HOSPICE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Hospice license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Hospice: Every Day Is A Gift” must appear at the bottom of the plate. A figure of a butterfly in the colors of orange, light purple, and black shall appear on the left side of the plate and the background of the plate shall be in shades of orange and white.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Florida Hospices and Palliative Care, Inc., to be used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund projects relating to hospice care for special groups, such as children, veterans, and ethnic, religious, gender, or minority groups, or to provide disease-specific research or outreach.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund education and outreach for hospice volunteers, patients, families, and health care professionals.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund informational and educational media programs regarding the availability of hospice services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund the expansion or enhancement of the Florida Hospices and Palliative Care, Inc., toll-free referral line operated to provide hospice information.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund the expansion or enhancement of the Florida Hospices and Palliative Care, Inc., Internet website.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sum of $90,000 in annual use fees shall be distributed to Florida Hospices and Palliative Care, Inc., to be used to recover all startup costs for developing and issuing the plates. Thereafter, the proceeds shall be distributed to Florida Hospices and Palliative Care, Inc., which shall distribute the fees through a standing committee that reviews funding solicitations and awards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="43">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STOP HEART DISEASE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Stop Heart Disease license plate as provided in this section. Stop Heart Disease license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The plate shall be designed to include a red, white, and blue background with a slanted heart shape in the middle of the plate. The word “Florida” shall appear at the top of the plate in yellow outlined in black, and the words “Stop Heart Disease” shall appear at the bottom of the plate in yellow.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall remit the proceeds of the annual use fee to the Florida Heart Research Foundation, Inc. The first $80,000 of the use fee given to the Florida Heart Research Foundation, Inc., shall be used to pay startup costs, including costs incurred developing and issuing the plates. Thereafter, the Florida Heart Research Foundation, Inc., shall provide for a peer review grant solicitation and award process to distribute fees for cardiovascular disease research, education, and prevention within the state and shall make the funds available for any one or more of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Quality research to pursue top quality cardiovascular research that will further understanding of heart disease and its cause, treatment, cure, and prevention. Accepted projects must conform to the highest standards of scientific research, be efficiently organized, and report updates continually to ensure research credibility and excellence.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Heart disease prevention programs to provide cardiovascular screenings to state residents.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational programs to offer educational programs, literature, seminars, or speakers for both clinicians and lay people so that the latest risk factors, technologies, treatments, methodologies, protocols, and preventive measures are well known and used in the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the first year in which the plate is issued, no more than 25 percent of the fees collected may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operation of the Florida Heart Research Foundation, Inc., and marketing and promotion of the Stop Heart Disease license plate. In the second and subsequent years in which the plate is sold, no more than 20 percent of the fees collected may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operation of the Florida Heart Research Foundation, Inc., and marketing and promotion of the Stop Heart Disease license plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="44">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SAVE OUR SEAS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Save Our Seas license plate as provided in this section. Save Our Seas license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Save Our Seas” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc. After reimbursement for documented costs expended for establishing the license plate, the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., shall use the remaining funds for marine science research and education programs as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent of the funds shall be distributed to the Guy Harvey Research Institute of the Nova Southeastern University Oceanographic Center to conduct fisheries and shark research in the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 15 percent of the funds may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution’s marine science and marine education programs and administrative costs associated with the Save Our Seas license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 percent of the funds may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining funds shall be used to conduct scientific research and education on marine plants and animals and coastal oceanography in state marine waters; to collect and analyze long-term data sets on the state’s critical marine habitats; to determine changes in populations and communities of marine organisms and their impacts on the use of the state’s marine resources; to maintain reference collections of scientific specimens and photographic archives of the state’s marine plants and animals; and to conduct scientific conferences of relevance to the state’s marine resources and their management, utilization, and conservation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="45">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AQUACULTURE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop an Aquaculture license plate as provided in this section. Aquaculture license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the word “Aquaculture” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc. After reimbursement for documented costs expended for establishing the license plate, the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution, Inc., shall use the remaining funds for aquaculture research and education programs as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent of the funds shall be distributed to the Guy Harvey Research Institute of the Nova Southeastern University Oceanographic Center to conduct outreach and education regarding aquaculture in the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 15 percent of the funds may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the Harbor Branch Oceanographic Institution’s aquaculture programs and administrative costs associated with the Aquaculture license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 percent of the funds may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining funds shall be used to conduct scientific research on environmentally responsible and sustainable methods of farming freshwater and saltwater organisms such as fish, shellfish, and crustaceans for food; biomedical species for pharmaceutical and nutriceutical compounds; and marine ornamentals for the aquarium trade. These funds shall also be used to expand the institution’s educational programs that include secondary school field experiences, college degree programs, and intensive courses in order to further the objective of increasing aquaculture’s contribution to the state’s economy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="46">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAMILY FIRST LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Family First license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Family First” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Family First to fund programs, projects, seminars, events, and family resources that promote principles for building marriages, guiding parents, and raising children. Family First shall retain all revenues from the sale of the plate until its startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered. Up to 5 percent of the funds received by Family First may be expended for administrative costs directly associated with the operations of Family First. Up to 20 percent of the funds received by Family First may be expended for promoting and marketing the license plate. Family First may expend all remaining funds for programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="47">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SPORTSMEN’S NATIONAL LAND TRUST LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Sportsmen’s National Land Trust license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Sportsmen’s National Land Trust” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual revenues from the sales of the license plate shall be distributed to the Sportsmen’s National Land Trust. Such annual revenues must be used by the trust in the following manner:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent may be retained until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent must be used to fund programs and projects within the state that preserve open space and wildlife habitat, promote conservation, improve wildlife habitat, and establish open space for the perpetual use of the public.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent may be used for promotion, marketing, and administrative costs directly associated with operation of the trust.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the provisions of subparagraph (b)1. are met, those annual revenues shall be used for the purposes of subparagraph (b)2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="48">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIVE THE DREAM LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Live the Dream license plate as provided in this section. Live the Dream license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Live the Dream” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the annual use fee shall be distributed to the Dream Foundation, Inc. The Dream Foundation, Inc., shall retain the first $60,000 in proceeds from the annual use fees as reimbursement for administrative costs, startup costs, and costs incurred in the approval process. Thereafter, up to 25 percent shall be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate and concept. The remaining funds shall be used in the following manner:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent shall be distributed equally among the sickle cell organizations that are Florida members of the Sickle Cell Disease Association of America, Inc., for programs that provide research, care, and treatment for sickle cell disease.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent shall be distributed to the Florida chapter of the March of Dimes for programs and services that improve the health of babies through the prevention of birth defects and infant mortality.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent shall be distributed to the Florida Association of Healthy Start Coalitions to decrease racial disparity in infant mortality and to increase healthy birth outcomes. Funding will be used by local Healthy Start Coalitions to provide services and increase screening rates for high-risk pregnant women, children under 4 years of age, and women of childbearing age.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent shall be distributed to the Community Partnership for Homeless, Inc., for programs that provide relief from poverty, hunger, and homelessness.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five percent of the proceeds shall be used by the foundation for administrative costs directly associated with operations as they relate to the management and distribution of the proceeds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="49">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA FOOD BANKS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Food Banks license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and the word “Imagine” must appear at the top of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Association of Food Banks, Inc., which may use up to 25 percent of the proceeds to market the association’s concept and the license plate. The balance of the proceeds shall be used by the association to fund programs to end hunger in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advisory board, composed of a representative of each member food bank of the Florida Association of Food Banks, Inc., shall review the distribution of funds by the association.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="50">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCOVER FLORIDA’S OCEANS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Discover Florida’s Oceans license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Discover Florida’s Oceans” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Hubbs Florida Ocean Fund, Inc., which shall administer the fees as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent of the funds shall be distributed to the Wildlife Foundation of Florida, Inc., to be used for ocean, estuarine, or coastal scientific research, conservation, and education projects.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 percent of the funds may be used for administrative costs directly associated with research, conservation, and education programs of the Hubbs-SeaWorld Research Institute and with the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 15 percent of the funds may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remainder of the funds shall be used to collect, analyze, archive, and publish scientific data regarding the state’s ocean, estuary, and coastal habitats and the species that inhabit, use, or migrate in state waters or along the state’s coastal areas; to provide response, care, assistance, and research as part of the Hubbs-SeaWorld Research Institute’s role in responding to and archiving data on stranded marine species; to construct and maintain a marine and coastal research center in association with the Archie Carr National Wildlife Refuge on lands donated to the Hubbs-SeaWorld Research Institute by the Richard King Mellon Foundation; to train teachers and students to enhance scientific literacy, research competency, and technology development; to conduct ocean-space aquatic research and scientific research focused on ocean observations from space; to conduct research on economic benefits of the state’s ocean, estuary, and coastal resources and public use of those resources; to create research and education programs that contribute to the development of the state’s knowledge and diversify the economy; and to implement programs that seek objective, common-sense, scientific solutions to the complex marine and coastal ecological problems facing the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="51">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAMILY VALUES LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Family Values license plate as provided in this section. Family Values license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The words “Family Values” must appear at the top of the plate, and the word “Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Sheridan House, Inc., to be used in the following manner:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sheridan House, Inc., shall retain all revenues from the sale of Family Values license plates until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plates have been recovered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 5 percent of the funds received by Sheridan House, Inc., shall be expended for administrative costs directly associated with the operations of Sheridan House, Inc., and up to 20 percent of the funds received shall be expended for promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All remaining funds shall be expended by Sheridan House, Inc., to fund residential care programs, family counseling, social services for single parents and their children, resource materials, and facility construction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="52">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PARENTS MAKE A DIFFERENCE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Parents Make A Difference license plate as provided in this section. The words “Parents Make A Difference” must appear at the top of the plate, and the word “Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to The Gathering/USA, Inc., to fund personal counseling for parents, marriage seminars, Dads and Moms That Make A Difference seminars, father-and-son retreats, mother-and-daughter retreats, and personal parenting behavioral assessments. The Gathering/USA, Inc., shall distribute the Parents Make A Difference license plate annual use fees in the following manner:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Gathering/USA, Inc., shall retain all revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 5 percent of the funds received by The Gathering/USA, Inc., shall be expended for administrative costs directly associated with the operations of The Gathering/USA, Inc., and up to 20 percent of the funds received shall be expended for promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All remaining funds shall be expended by The Gathering/USA, Inc., for programs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="53">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUPPORT SOCCER LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Support Soccer license plate as provided in this section. Support Soccer license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Support Soccer” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Lighthouse Soccer Foundation, Inc., which shall retain the initial revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered, not to exceed $85,000. Thereafter, the proceeds of the annual use fee shall be used in the following manner:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 25 percent of the proceeds may be used by the Lighthouse Soccer Foundation, Inc., for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate and concept.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent shall be distributed to the Florida Youth Soccer Association for programs and services that foster the physical, mental, and emotional growth and development of Florida’s youth through the sport of soccer at all levels of age and competition, including a portion to be determined by the Florida Youth Soccer Association for the TOPSoccer program to promote participation by the physically and mentally disadvantaged.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent shall be distributed as grants for programs that promote participation by the economically disadvantaged and to support soccer programs where none previously existed.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent shall be distributed to the Florida State Soccer Association to promote the sport of soccer and the long-term development of the sport.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent shall be distributed as grants for programs that promote and support the construction of fields and soccer-specific infrastructure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent shall be distributed as grants for programs that foster and promote health, physical fitness, and educational opportunities through soccer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five percent shall be expended by the Lighthouse Soccer Foundation, Inc., for administrative costs directly associated with the foundation’s operations as they relate to the management and distribution of the proceeds.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="54">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">KIDS DESERVE JUSTICE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Kids Deserve Justice license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Kids Deserve Justice” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Bar Foundation, Inc., which shall use the funds to operate a grant award process to fund legal services programs for children, including legal services programs, programs to obtain federal benefits for disabled children, programs to obtain testing and services required by law for learning-disabled children, and programs to obtain permanent placement for abused and neglected children. The foundation may retain all proceeds until all costs for developing the plate have been recovered.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="55">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANIMAL FRIEND LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop an Animal Friend license plate as provided in this section. Animal Friend license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Animal Friend” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall retain all annual use fee revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and issuing the plates are recovered, not to exceed $60,000.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the department has recovered all startup costs for developing and issuing the plates, the annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Animal Friend, Inc., for spay and neuter programs in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 10 percent of the fees collected may be used for administrative costs directly associated with marketing and promotion of the Animal Friend license plate and distribution of funds as described in paragraph (c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds received from the purchase of the Animal Friend license plate shall not be used for litigation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="56">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUTURE FARMERS OF AMERICA LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a Future Farmers of America license plate as provided in this section. Future Farmers of America license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Agricultural Education” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fee shall be distributed quarterly to the Florida Future Farmers of America Foundation, Inc., to fund activities and services of the Future Farmers of America.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Future Farmers of America Foundation, Inc., shall retain all revenue from the annual use fees until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, up to 10 percent of the annual use fee revenue may be used for administrative, handling, and disbursement expenses and up to 5 percent may be used for advertising and marketing costs. All remaining annual use fee revenue shall be used by the Florida Future Farmers of America Foundation, Inc., to fund its activities, programs, and projects, including, but not limited to, student and teacher leadership programs, the Foundation for Leadership Training Center, teacher recruitment and retention, and other special projects.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="57">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DONATE ORGANS-PASS IT ON LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Donate Organs-Pass It On license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Donate Organs-Pass It On” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Transplant Foundation, Inc., and shall use up to 10 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fee for marketing and administrative costs that are directly associated with the management and distribution of the proceeds. The remaining proceeds shall be used to provide statewide grants for patient services, including preoperative, rehabilitative, and housing assistance; organ donor education and awareness programs; and statewide medical research.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="58">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A STATE OF VISION LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop an A State of Vision license plate as provided in this section. A State of Vision license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “A State of Vision” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees shall be distributed quarterly to the Florida Association of Agencies Serving the Blind, Inc., to fund direct-support services to blind and visually impaired people.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Association of Agencies Serving the Blind, Inc., shall retain all revenue from the annual use fees until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, up to 5 percent of the annual use fee revenue shall be used for administrative costs and up to 20 percent shall be used for promotion and marketing of the specialty license plate. All remaining annual use fee revenue shall be used by the Florida Association of Agencies Serving the Blind, Inc., to fund its activities, programs, and projects within the state through its local nonprofit organizations’ direct-support services to blind and visually impaired people.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="59">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HOMEOWNERSHIP FOR ALL LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Homeownership For All license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Support Homeownership For All” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Homeownership For All, Inc., which may use a maximum of 10 percent of the proceeds to promote and market the plate. The remainder of the proceeds shall be used by Homeownership For All, Inc., to fund programs that provide, promote, or otherwise support affordable housing in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="60">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA NASCAR LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida NASCAR license plate as provided in this section. Florida NASCAR license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the term “NASCAR” must appear at the bottom of the plate. The National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing, following consultation with Enterprise Florida, Inc., may submit a sample plate for consideration by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees shall be distributed to Enterprise Florida, Inc. The license plate annual use fees shall be annually allocated as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 5 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fees may be used by Enterprise Florida, Inc., for the administration of the NASCAR license plate program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing shall receive up to $60,000 in proceeds from the annual use fees to be used to pay startup costs, including costs incurred in developing and issuing the plates. Thereafter, 10 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fees shall be provided to the association for the royalty rights for the use of its marks.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds from the annual use fees shall be distributed to Enterprise Florida, Inc. Enterprise Florida, Inc., will retain 15 percent to support its regional grant program, attracting sporting events to Florida; 20 percent to support the marketing of motorsports-related tourism in the state; and 50 percent to be paid to the NASCAR Foundation, a s. 501(c)(3) charitable organization, to support Florida-based charitable organizations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enterprise Florida, Inc., shall provide an annual financial audit in accordance with s. 215.981 of its financial accounts and records by an independent certified public accountant pursuant to the contract established by the Department of Economic Opportunity. The auditor shall submit the audit report to the Department of Economic Opportunity for review and approval. If the audit report is approved, the Department of Economic Opportunity shall certify the audit report to the Auditor General for review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="61">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CORRECTIONS FOUNDATION LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Corrections Foundation license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, the words “Corrections Foundation” must appear at the bottom of the plate, and the Corrections Foundation logo must appear to the left of the numerals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to Corrections Foundation, Inc., a direct-support organization created pursuant to s. 944.802, and shall be used to continue and expand the charitable work of the foundation, as provided in s. 944.802 and the articles of incorporation of the foundation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="62">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROTECT FLORIDA SPRINGS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Protect Florida Springs license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Protect Florida Springs” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Wildlife Foundation of Florida, Inc., a citizen support organization created pursuant to s. 379.223, which shall administer the fees as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wildlife Foundation of Florida, Inc., shall retain the first $60,000 of the annual use fees as direct reimbursement for administrative costs, startup costs, and costs incurred in the development and approval process.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thereafter, a maximum of 10 percent of the fees may be used for administrative costs directly associated with education programs, conservation, springs research, and grant administration of the foundation. A maximum of 15 percent of the fees may be used for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 55 percent of the fees shall be available for competitive grants for targeted community-based springs research not currently available for state funding. The remaining 20 percent shall be directed toward community outreach programs aimed at implementing such research findings. The competitive grants shall be administered and approved by the board of directors of the Wildlife Foundation of Florida. The granting advisory committee shall be composed of nine members, including one representative from the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, one representative from the Department of Environmental Protection, one representative from the Department of Health, one representative from the Department of Economic Opportunity, three citizen representatives, and two representatives from nonprofit stakeholder groups.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining funds shall be distributed with the approval of and accountability to the board of directors of the Wildlife Foundation of Florida, and shall be used to support activities contributing to education, outreach, and springs conservation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="63">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">TREES ARE COOL LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Trees Are Cool license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Trees Are Cool” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Chapter of the International Society of Arboriculture, Inc., which shall retain the initial revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered not to exceed $60,000. Thereafter, the proceeds of the annual use fee shall be used in the following manner:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent of the funds may be used by the Florida Chapter of the International Society of Arboriculture, Inc., for continuing promotion and marketing of the license plate and concept. Five percent of the funds received by the Florida Society of Arboriculture, Inc., may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operations of the Florida Chapter of the International Society of Arboriculture, Inc., with respect to the management of the Trees Are Cool license plate program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seventy-five percent of the funds must be used to fulfill the mission of the Florida Chapter of the International Society of Arboriculture, Inc., which is to provide education and training statewide with respect to tree care and tree safety.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="64">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUPPORT OUR TROOPS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Support Our Troops license plate as provided in this section. The plate must bear the colors and design approved by the department and must contain the “Support Our Troops” mark of Support Our Troops, Inc. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate and the words “Support Our Troops” must appear at the bottom of the plate. The field of the plate may be colored.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees from the plate shall be distributed to Support Our Troops, Inc., to be used for the benefit of Florida troops and their families in accordance with its articles of incorporation. Support Our Troops, Inc., shall receive the first $60,000 of the use fees to offset startup costs for developing and establishing the plate. Thereafter, the department shall distribute the annual use fees as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent shall be distributed to Support Our Troops, Inc., to offset marketing, administration, and promotion costs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the remaining 75 percent, 65 percent shall be distributed to Support Our Troops, Inc., and 35 percent shall be distributed to the State Homes for Veterans Trust Fund within the Department of Veterans’ Affairs State Homes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="65">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA TENNIS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Tennis license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate and the words “Play Tennis” must appear at the bottom of the plate. The United States Tennis Association Florida Section Foundation may submit a revised sample plate for consideration by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall distribute the annual use fees to Enterprise Florida, Inc. The license plate annual use fees shall be annually allocated as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 5 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fees may be used by Enterprise Florida, Inc., to administer the license plate program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States Tennis Association Florida Section Foundation shall receive the first $60,000 in proceeds from the annual use fees to reimburse it for startup costs, administrative costs, and other costs it incurs in the development and approval process.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 5 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fees may be used for promoting and marketing the license plates. The remaining proceeds shall be available for grants by the United States Tennis Association Florida Section Foundation to nonprofit organizations to operate youth tennis programs and adaptive tennis programs for special populations of all ages, and for building, renovating, and maintaining public tennis courts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All grant recipients shall provide to the United States Tennis Association Florida Section Foundation an annual program and financial report regarding the use of grant funds. Such reports shall be made available to the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="66">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIGHTHOUSE ASSOCIATION LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Lighthouse Association license plate as provided in this section. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Visit Our Lights” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Lighthouse Association, Inc., which may use a maximum of 10 percent of the proceeds to promote and market the plates. The remaining proceeds shall be used by the association to fund the preservation, restoration, and protection of the 29 historic lighthouses remaining in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="67">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IN GOD WE TRUST LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop an In God We Trust license plate as provided in this section. However, the requirements of s. 320.08053 must be met before the plates are issued. In God We Trust license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “In God We Trust” must appear in the body of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees shall be distributed to the In God We Trust Foundation, Inc., to fund educational scholarships for the children of Florida residents who are members of the United States Armed Forces, the National Guard, and the United States Armed Forces Reserve and for the children of public safety employees who have died in the line of duty who are not covered by existing state law. Funds shall also be distributed to other s. 501(c)(3) organizations that may apply for grants and scholarships and to provide educational grants to public and private schools to promote the historical and religious significance of American and Florida history. The In God We Trust Foundation, Inc., shall distribute the license plate annual use fees in the following manner:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The In God We Trust Foundation, Inc., shall retain all revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent of the funds received by the In God We Trust Foundation, Inc., shall be expended for administrative costs, promotion, and marketing of the license plate directly associated with the operations of the In God We Trust Foundation, Inc.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All remaining funds shall be expended by the In God We Trust Foundation, Inc., for programs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="68">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HORSE COUNTRY LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a Horse Country license plate as provided in this section. Horse Country license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Horse Country” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of s. 320.08053 must be met prior to the issuance of the plate. Thereafter, the license plate annual use fees shall be distributed to PCMI Properties, Inc., to fund programs involved in the rehabilitation of at-risk youth as directed by the Board of Trustees of PCMI Properties, Inc. Such funds may be used to provide educational materials, athletic equipment, transportation, food, medical services, counseling, scholarships, and other direct administrative and program expenses. The funds may also be used as grants for expansion of youth rehabilitation programs in the state. Special consideration shall be given to programs using horses and other livestock in the efforts to redirect at-risk youth. PCMI Properties, Inc., may retain all revenue from the annual use fees until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered. Thereafter, up to 10 percent of the annual use fee revenue may be used for promotion and marketing of the plate, and as necessary for annual audit or compliance affidavit costs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="69">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTISM LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop an Autism license plate as provided in this section. Autism license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Support Autism Programs” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds from the license plate annual use fee shall be distributed to Achievement and Rehabilitation Centers, Inc., to fund service programs for autism and related disabilities throughout the state and to operate and establish programs to support individuals with autism and related disabilities through direct services, evaluation, training, and awareness. Achievement and Rehabilitation Centers, Inc., shall establish an Autism Services Grant Council that shall provide grants from available Autism license plate proceeds to nonprofit organizations for direct services and programs for individuals with autism and related disabilities and their families. Consideration for participation in such services and programs shall be given to applicants who are children or adults with autism and related disabilities and their families and shall include those who are on the Agency for Persons with Disabilities waiting lists for services. Achievement and Rehabilitation Centers, Inc., shall also establish an Autism License Plate Fund. Moneys in the fund shall be used by the grant council as provided in this paragraph. All funds received under this subsection must be used in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Achievement and Rehabilitation Centers, Inc., may retain all proceeds from the annual use fee up to $85,000 until all documented startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered. Thereafter, the proceeds from the annual use fee shall be used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 percent of the proceeds may be used for the cost of administration, marketing, and promotion of the Autism License Plate Fund, the Autism Services Grant Council, and related matters, including annual audit and compliance affidavit costs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds may be used as necessary for annual audit or compliance affidavit costs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirty-five percent of the proceeds shall be used to establish and operate programs to support individuals with autism and related disabilities and their families through direct services, evaluation, training, and awareness in the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Center for Autism and Related Disabilities at the University of Miami shall receive 15 percent of the proceeds for distribution, as determined appropriate by the director of that center, to the seven regional autism centers created under s. 1004.55. The regional centers shall use the proceeds to support the services they provide.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds shall be available to the Autism Services Grant Council for grants to nonprofit organizations to operate direct services programs for individuals with autism and related disabilities and their families. All grant recipients, including Achievement and Rehabilitation Centers, Inc., and the Center for Autism and Related Disabilities, must provide to the Autism Services Grant Council an annual program and financial report regarding the use of grant funds. Such reports must be available to the public.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="70">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ST. JOHNS RIVER LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a St. Johns River license plate as provided in this section. The St. Johns River license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “St. Johns River” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of s. 320.08053 must be met prior to the issuance of the plate. Thereafter, the license plate annual use fees shall be distributed to the St. Johns River Alliance, Inc., a s. 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization, which shall administer the fees as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The St. Johns River Alliance, Inc., shall retain the first $60,000 of the annual use fees as direct reimbursement for administrative costs, startup costs, and costs incurred in the development and approval process. Thereafter, up to 10 percent of the annual use fee revenue may be used for administrative costs directly associated with education programs, conservation, research, and grant administration of the organization, and up to 10 percent may be used for promotion and marketing of the specialty license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 30 percent of the fees shall be available for competitive grants for targeted community-based or county-based research or projects for which state funding is limited or not currently available. The remaining 50 percent shall be directed toward community outreach and access programs. The competitive grants shall be administered and approved by the board of directors of the St. Johns River Alliance, Inc. A grant advisory committee shall be composed of six members chosen by the St. Johns River Alliance board members.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any remaining funds shall be distributed with the approval of and accountability to the board of directors of the St. Johns River Alliance, Inc., and shall be used to support activities contributing to education, outreach, and springs conservation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="71">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HISPANIC ACHIEVERS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the requirements of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a Hispanic Achievers license plate as provided in this section. The plate must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Hispanic Achievers” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds from the license plate annual use fee shall be distributed to National Hispanic Corporate Achievers, Inc., a nonprofit corporation under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, to fund grants to nonprofit organizations to operate programs and provide scholarships and for marketing the Hispanic Achievers license plate. National Hispanic Corporate Achievers, Inc., shall establish a Hispanic Achievers Grant Council that shall provide recommendations for statewide grants from available Hispanic Achievers license plate proceeds to nonprofit organizations for programs and scholarships for Hispanic and minority Floridians. National Hispanic Corporate Achievers, Inc., shall also establish a Hispanic Achievers License Plate Fund. Moneys in the fund shall be used by the grant council as provided in this paragraph. All funds received under this subsection must be used in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">National Hispanic Corporate Achievers, Inc., may retain all proceeds from the annual use fee until documented startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered. Thereafter, the proceeds from the annual use fee shall be used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 percent of the proceeds may be used for the cost of administration of the Hispanic Achievers License Plate Fund, the Hispanic Achievers Grant Council, and related matters.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds may be used as necessary for annual audit or compliance affidavit costs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent of the proceeds shall be used by the Hispanic Corporate Achievers, Inc., located in Seminole County, for grants.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds shall be available to the Hispanic Achievers Grant Council to award grants for services, programs, or scholarships for Hispanic and minority individuals and organizations throughout Florida. All grant recipients must provide to the Hispanic Achievers Grant Council an annual program and financial report regarding the use of grant funds. Such reports must be available to the public.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="72">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHILDREN FIRST LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon Children First Florida, Inc., meeting the requirements of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a Children First license plate as provided in this section. The plate must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Children First” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds from the license plate annual use fee shall be distributed to Children First Florida, Inc., which shall retain all proceeds until the startup costs to develop and establish the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, the proceeds shall be used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of 10 percent of the proceeds may be used to administer the license plate program, for direct administrative costs associated with the operations of Children First Florida, Inc., and to promote and market the license plates.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining fees shall be used by Children First Florida, Inc., to fund public schools in this state, including teacher salaries.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="73">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VETERANS OF FOREIGN WARS LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon Veterans of Foreign Wars, Department of Florida, meeting the requirements of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a Veterans of Foreign Wars license plate as provided in this section. The plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department and must incorporate the Great Seal of the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States as described in Art. VIII, s. 801 of the Congressional Charter and By-Laws of the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the United States. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Veterans of Foreign Wars” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Veterans of Foreign Wars, Department of Florida shall retain all revenues from the sale of such plates until all startup costs for developing and issuing the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, 60 percent of the annual revenues shall be distributed to the Veterans of Foreign Wars, Department of Florida to support the Voice of Democracy and Patriots’ Pen Scholarship programs, to support high school and college ROTC programs, and for administration and marketing the plate; 20 percent of the annual revenues shall be distributed to the direct-support organization created under s. 292.055 under the Florida Department of Veterans’ Affairs; and 20 percent of the annual revenues shall be distributed to the direct-support organization created under s. 250.115 under the Department of Military Affairs. From the funds distributed to the Veterans of Foreign Wars, Department of Florida, an amount not to exceed 10 percent of the annual revenues received from the sale of the plate may be used for administration and marketing the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="74">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ENDLESS SUMMER LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop an Endless Summer license plate as provided in this section. Endless Summer license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Endless Summer” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees shall be distributed to Surfing’s Evolution &amp; Preservation Corporation to fund its activities, programs, and projects aimed at preserving the sport of surfing. Surfing’s Evolution &amp; Preservation Corporation may retain all revenue from the annual use fees until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered. Thereafter, up to 10 percent of the annual use fee revenue may be used for promotion and marketing of the specialty license plate and administrative costs directly associated with the corporation’s programs and the specialty license plate. Surfing’s Evolution &amp; Preservation Corporation shall use the remaining funds as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To fund the proposed Surfing’s Evolution &amp; Preservation Experience project.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide funds for the provision of lifeguards or the building of artificial reefs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide funds to organizations that house the history and artifacts of surfing or promote the sport through exhibits, lectures, and events.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To support programs and events of other organizations that support beaches and oceans and promote education on beach safety, coastal pollution, and beach ecology.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="75">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FRATERNAL ORDER OF POLICE LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Fraternal Order of Police license plate as provided in this section. The plate must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Fraternal Order of Police” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue the plate only to an applicant who submits a notarized letter from the Florida State Lodge of the Fraternal Order of Police stating that the applicant is a member of the lodge in good standing or a member of a lodge member’s family, together with other fees and documents required for a specialty plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida State Lodge of the Fraternal Order of Police, which shall retain all proceeds until the startup costs to develop and establish the plate have been recovered. Thereafter, the proceeds shall be distributed to the Florida State Lodge Memorial Foundation of the Fraternal Order of Police and used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of 10 percent of the proceeds may be used to promote and market the plate, to administer the license plate program, and to pay administrative costs directly associated with the state Fraternal Order of Police Law Enforcement Memorial.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds shall be used by the foundation to fund projects, programs, or events related to the memorial or to fund improvements, maintenance, or other support for the memorial.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="76">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CATCH ME, RELEASE ME LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Catch Me, Release Me license plate as provided in this section. Catch Me, Release Me license plates must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Catch Me, Release Me” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate annual use fees shall be distributed to the Guy Harvey Ocean Foundation, Inc., to fund marine-related scientific research, including research of free-ranging pelagic marine species that inhabit, use, or migrate through Florida waters; conservation initiatives; and education and public outreach programs targeting school-aged children in the state. The Guy Harvey Ocean Foundation, Inc., may retain all revenue up to $60,000 from the annual use fees until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered. Thereafter, up to 10 percent of the annual use fee revenue may be used for administrative costs directly associated with the operations of the Guy Harvey Ocean Foundation, Inc., and promotion and marketing of the specialty license plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="77">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA HORSE PARK LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Horse Park license plate as provided in this section. The plate must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Discover Florida’s Horses” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park Authority created by s. 570.952, which shall retain all proceeds until all startup costs for developing and establishing the plate have been recovered. Thereafter, the proceeds shall be used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of 5 percent of the proceeds from the annual use fees may be used for the administration of the Florida Horse Park license plate program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of 5 percent of the proceeds may be used to promote and market the license plate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining proceeds shall be used by the authority to promote the Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park located in Marion County; to support continued development of the park, including the construction of additional educational facilities, barns, and other structures; to provide improvements to the existing infrastructure at the park; and to provide for operational expenses of the Florida Agriculture Center and Horse Park.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="78">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FLORIDA BIODIVERSITY FOUNDATION LICENSE PLATES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop a Florida Biodiversity Foundation license plate as provided in this section. The plate must bear the colors and design approved by the department. The word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate, and the words “Save Wild Florida” must appear at the bottom of the plate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Biodiversity Foundation, Inc., which shall retain 50 percent of the proceeds until the startup costs to develop and establish the plates have been recovered. Thereafter, the proceeds shall be used as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum of 10 percent of the proceeds may be used to fund the administrative, promotion, and marketing costs of the license plate program and the foundation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remaining fees shall be used by the foundation to fund research, education, and scientific study of the diversity of animals and plants and to aid in the preservation, study, conservation, and recovery of imperiled organisms.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 95-282; s. 2, ch. 96-160; s. 2, ch. 96-161; s. 2, ch. 96-162; s. 2, ch. 96-163; s. 2, ch. 96-164; s. 2, ch. 96-165; s. 135, ch. 96-320; s. 15, ch. 96-321; s. 50, ch. 97-100; s. 1, ch. 97-252; s. 2, ch. 97-272; s. 28, ch. 97-300; s. 2, ch. 98-67; s. 2, ch. 98-72; s. 2, ch. 98-74; s. 2, ch. 98-76; s. 2, ch. 98-77; s. 2, ch. 98-181; s. 7, ch. 98-414; ss. 100, 101, ch. 99-13; s. 2, ch. 99-191; ss. 16, 17, 88, ch. 99-245; ss. 26, 27, 269, ch. 99-248; s. 8, ch. 99-251; s. 2, ch. 99-268; s. 2, ch. 99-294; s. 2, ch. 99-295; s. 2, ch. 99-301; s. 2, ch. 99-302; s. 29, ch. 2000-313; s. 2, ch. 2000-358; s. 1, ch. 2000-362; s. 101, ch. 2001-266; s. 2, ch. 2001-355; s. 43, ch. 2002-1; s. 73, ch. 2002-20; s. 2, ch. 2002-181; s. 2, ch. 2002-203; s. 2, ch. 2002-237; s. 2, ch. 2002-249; s. 964, ch. 2002-387; s. 2, ch. 2003-26; s. 2, ch. 2003-66; ss. 3, 5, ch. 2003-73; s. 1, ch. 2003-111; s. 2, ch. 2003-121; s. 2, ch. 2003-183; s. 2, ch. 2003-256; s. 76, ch. 2003-399; s. 10, ch. 2003-401; s. 50, ch. 2004-269; s. 2, ch. 2004-337; s. 2, ch. 2004-338; s. 36, ch. 2005-71; s. 16, ch. 2005-164; s. 35, ch. 2006-26; s. 1, ch. 2006-169; s. 2, ch. 2006-240; s. 33, ch. 2006-290; s. 2, ch. 2006-293; ss. 2, 5, ch. 2006-297; s. 1, ch. 2007-38; ss. 22, 23, 28, ch. 2007-73; s. 1, ch. 2007-91; s. 2, ch. 2007-103; s. 1, ch. 2007-184; s. 43, ch. 2007-217; s. 3, ch. 2007-223; s. 2, ch. 2008-37; s. 2, ch. 2008-38; s. 3, ch. 2008-84; s. 1, ch. 2008-140; s. 193, ch. 2008-247; s. 8, ch. 2009-20; s. 30, ch. 2009-21; s. 23, ch. 2009-71; s. 2, ch. 2010-81; s. 2, ch. 2010-168; s. 2, ch. 2010-215; s. 2, ch. 2010-216; s. 25, ch. 2010-223; s. 17, ch. 2010-225; s. 233, ch. 2011-142; s. 1, ch. 2011-186; s. 1, ch. 2012-95; s. 54, ch. 2012-96; s. 35, ch. 2012-181.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 1, ch. 2007-184, and redesignated as paragraph (27)(b) to conform to the deletion of former subsection (15) by s. 2, ch. 2007-103. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Paragraph (27)(b) was also amended by s. 2, ch. 2007-103, and that version reads:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The annual use fees shall be distributed to the Florida Wildflower Foundation, Inc., a nonprofit corporation under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. The proceeds must be used to establish native Florida wildflower research programs, wildflower educational programs, and wildflower grant programs to municipal, county, and community-based groups in this state:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. The foundation shall develop operation procedures, research contracts, education and marketing programs, and wildflower planting grants for Florida native wildflowers, plants, and grasses.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. A maximum of 15 percent of the proceeds from the sale of such plates may be used by the foundation for administrative costs and marketing costs.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. If the foundation ceases to be an active nonprofit corporation under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, any unexpended use fees held by the foundation must be promptly transferred to the General Inspection Trust Fund within the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and all future fees collected shall be deposited to the same trust fund in the department. The department shall use and administer the proceeds from the annual use fee in the manner specified in this paragraph.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>