<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.831" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever violates any provision of the National Mobile Home Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974, 42 U.S.C. ss. 5401 et seq., or any rules, regulations, or final order issued thereunder shall be liable for a civil penalty not to exceed $1,000 for each such violation. Each violation of a provision of the act or any rule, regulation, or order issued thereunder shall constitute a separate violation with respect to each mobile home or with respect to each failure or refusal to allow or perform an act required thereby, except that the maximum civil penalty may not exceed $1 million for any related series of violations occurring within 1 year from the date of the first violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual, or a director, officer, or agent of a corporation, who knowingly and willfully violates the provisions of s. 610 of the National Mobile Home Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 in a manner which threatens the health or safety of any purchaser is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any manufacturer, dealer, or inspector who violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of ss. 320.822-320.862 or any of the rules adopted by the department is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, provided such violation is not also a violation of the National Mobile Home Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 or any rule, regulation, or final order issued thereunder.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 67-350; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 74-99; s. 41, ch. 77-357; s. 5, ch. 78-221; s. 12, ch. 80-217; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 19, 20, ch. 88-147; s. 41, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>