<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.833" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retention, destruction, and reproduction of records; electronic retention.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records and documents of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, created in compliance with, and in the implementation of, chapter 319 and this chapter, shall be retained by the department as specified in record retention schedules established under the general provisions of chapter 119. Further, the department is hereby authorized:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To destroy, or otherwise dispose of, those records and documents, in conformity with the approved retention schedules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To photograph, microphotograph, or reproduce on film, as authorized and directed by the approved retention schedules, whereby each page will be exposed in exact conformity with the original records and documents retained in compliance with the provisions of this section. Photographs or microphotographs in the form of film or print of any records, made in compliance with the provisions of this section, shall have the same force and effect as the originals thereof would have and shall be treated as originals for the purpose of their admissibility in evidence. Duly certified or authenticated reproductions of such photographs or microphotographs shall be admitted in evidence equally with the original photographs or microphotographs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning December 1, 2001, the department may maintain all records required or obtained in compliance with, and in the implementation of, chapter 319 and this chapter exclusively by electronic means.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 65-190; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 77-443; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 19, 20, ch. 88-147; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 33, ch. 2000-313.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 318.051.</Text></Note></Section>