<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.0863" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Custom vehicles and street rods; registration and license plates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Blue dot tail light” means a red lamp that contains a blue or purple insert that is not more than one inch in diameter and is installed in the rear of a motor vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Custom vehicle” means a motor vehicle that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 25 years old or older and of a model year after 1948 or was manufactured to resemble a vehicle that is 25 years old or older and of a model year after 1948; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been altered from the manufacturer’s original design or has a body constructed from nonoriginal materials.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Street rod” means a motor vehicle that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is of a model year of 1948 or older or was manufactured after 1948 to resemble a vehicle of a model year of 1948 or older; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been altered from the manufacturer’s original design or has a body constructed from nonoriginal materials.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The model year and year of manufacture which the body of a custom vehicle or street rod resembles is the model year and year of manufacture listed on the certificate of title, regardless of when the vehicle was actually manufactured.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To register a street rod or custom vehicle, the owner shall apply to the department by submitting a completed application form and providing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license tax prescribed by s. 320.08(2)(a) and a processing fee of $3;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written statement that the vehicle will not be used for general daily transportation but will be maintained for occasional transportation, exhibitions, club activities, parades, tours, or other functions of public interest and similar uses; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written statement that the vehicle meets state equipment and safety requirements for motor vehicles. However, the vehicle must meet only the requirements that were in effect in this state as a condition of sale in the year listed as the model year on the certificate of title.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The registration numbers and special license plates assigned to such vehicles shall run in a separate series, commencing with “Custom Vehicle 1” or “Street Rod 1,” respectively, and the plates shall be of a distinguishing color and design.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vehicle registered under this section is exempt from any law or local ordinance that requires periodic vehicle inspections or the use and inspection of emission controls.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such vehicle may also be equipped with blue dot tail lights for stop lamps, rear turning indicator lamps, rear hazard lamps, and rear reflectors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-19; s. 1, ch. 2007-165.</History></Section>