<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.771" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">License required of recreational vehicle dealers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” means any person engaged in the business of buying, selling, or dealing in recreational vehicles or offering or displaying recreational vehicles for sale. The term “dealer” includes a recreational vehicle broker. Any person who buys, sells, deals in, or offers or displays for sale, or who acts as the agent for the sale of, one or more recreational vehicles in any 12-month period shall be prima facie presumed to be a dealer. The terms “selling” and “sale” include lease-purchase transactions. The term “dealer” does not include banks, credit unions, and finance companies that acquire recreational vehicles as an incident to their regular business and does not include mobile home rental and leasing companies that sell recreational vehicles to dealers licensed under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed dealer may transact business in recreational vehicles with a motor vehicle auction as defined in s. 320.27(1)(c)4. Further, a licensed dealer may, at retail or wholesale, sell a motor vehicle, as described in s. 320.01(1)(a), acquired in exchange for the sale of a recreational vehicle, if the acquisition is incidental to the principal business of being a recreational vehicle dealer. However, a recreational vehicle dealer may not buy a motor vehicle for the purpose of resale unless licensed as a motor vehicle dealer pursuant to s. 320.27. A dealer may apply for a certificate of title to a recreational vehicle required to be registered under s. 320.08(9), using a manufacturer’s statement of origin as permitted by s. 319.23(1), only if the dealer is authorized by a manufacturer/dealer agreement, as defined in s. 320.3202, on file with the department, to buy, sell, or deal in that particular line-make of recreational vehicle, and the dealer is authorized by the manufacturer/dealer agreement to perform delivery and preparation obligations and warranty defect adjustments on that line-make.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recreational vehicle broker” means any person who is engaged in the business of offering to procure or procuring used recreational vehicles for the general public; who holds himself or herself out through solicitation, advertisement, or otherwise as one who offers to procure or procures used recreational vehicles for the general public; or who acts as the agent or intermediary on behalf of the owner or seller of a used recreational vehicle which is for sale or who assists or represents the seller in finding a buyer for the recreational vehicle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recreational vehicle” does not include any camping trailer, as defined in s. 320.01(1)(b)2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSE REQUIRED.<EmDash />No person shall engage in business as, or serve in the capacity of, a dealer in this state unless such person possesses a valid, current license as provided in this section. Motor vehicle dealers licensed under s. 320.27 shall not be required to obtain the license provided in this section to sell motor vehicles as defined in s. 320.01(1)(b)4., 5., and 6.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION.<EmDash />The application for such license shall be in the form prescribed by the department and subject to such rules as may be prescribed by it. The application shall be verified by oath or affirmation and shall contain:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A full statement of the name and the date of birth of the person or persons applying therefor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the firm or copartnership with the names and places of residence of all its members, if the applicant is a firm or copartnership.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and places of residence of the principal officers, if the applicant is a body corporate or other artificial body.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the state under whose laws the corporation is organized.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The former place or places of residence of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prior businesses in which the applicant has been engaged, the dates during which the applicant was engaged in such businesses, and the locations thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the exact location of the place of business, when it was acquired, and whether it is owned in fee simple by the applicant. If leased, a true copy of the lease shall be attached to the application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification by the applicant that the location is a permanent one, not a tent or a temporary stand or other temporary quarters; that the location affords sufficient unoccupied space to store all recreational vehicles offered and displayed for sale; and that the location is a suitable place in which the applicant can in good faith carry on business and keep and maintain books, records, and files necessary to conduct such business, which will be available at all reasonable hours to inspection by the department or any of its inspectors or other employees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification by the applicant that the business of a recreational vehicle dealer is the principal business which shall be conducted at that location; however, this provision shall not apply to recreational vehicle or mobile home park operators licensed as mobile home or recreational vehicle dealers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the applicant is insured under a garage liability insurance policy, which shall include, at a minimum, $25,000 combined single-limit liability coverage, including bodily injury and property damage protection, and $10,000 personal injury protection, if the applicant is to be licensed as a dealer in, or intends to sell, recreational vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the applicant for a recreational vehicle license, issued pursuant to this section, has not and will not enter into any agreements, written or oral, with any other person or business entity which would constitute an unfair or deceptive trade practice in violation of part II of chapter 501.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other relevant information as may be required by the department. Each applicant, general partner in the case of a partnership, or corporate officer and director in the case of a corporate applicant, must file a set of fingerprints with the department for the purpose of determining any prior criminal record or any outstanding warrants. The department shall submit the fingerprinting to the Department of Law Enforcement for state processing and forwarding to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for federal processing. The actual cost of such state and federal processing shall be borne by the applicant and is to be in addition to the fee for licensure. The department may issue a license to an applicant pending the results of the fingerprint investigation, which license is fully revocable if the department subsequently determines that any facts set forth in the application are not true or correctly represented.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department shall, if it deems necessary, cause an investigation to be made to ascertain if the facts set forth in the application are true and shall not issue a license to the applicant until it is satisfied that the facts set forth in the application are true.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FEES.<EmDash />Upon making initial application, the applicant shall pay to the department a fee of $300 in addition to any other fees now required by law. The fee for renewal application shall be $100. The fee for application for change of location shall be $25. Any applicant for renewal who has failed to submit his or her renewal application by October 1 shall pay a renewal application fee equal to the original application fee. No fee is refundable. All fees shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DENIAL OF LICENSE.<EmDash />The department may deny any applicant a license on the ground that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has made a material misstatement in the application for a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has failed to comply with any applicable provision of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has failed to provide warranty service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or one or more of the applicant’s principals or agents has violated any law, rule, or regulation relating to the sale of recreational vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has proof of unfitness of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or licensee has engaged in previous conduct in any state which would have been a ground for revocation or suspension of a license in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or licensee has violated any of the provisions of the National Mobile Home Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 or any rule or regulation of the Department of Housing and Urban Development promulgated thereunder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Upon denial of a license, the department shall notify the applicant within 10 days, stating in writing its grounds for denial. The applicant is entitled to a public hearing and may request that such hearing be held within 45 days of denial of the license. All proceedings shall be pursuant to chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSE CERTIFICATE.<EmDash />A license certificate shall be issued by the department in accordance with the application when the same is regular in form and in compliance with the provisions of this section. The license certificate may be in the form of a document or a computerized card as determined by the department. The cost of each original, additional, or replacement computerized card shall be borne by the licensee and is in addition to the fee for licensure. The fees charged applicants for both the required background investigation and the computerized card as provided in this section shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund. The license, when so issued, shall entitle the licensee to carry on and conduct the business of a recreational vehicle dealer at the location set forth in the license for a period of 1 year from October 1 preceding the date of issuance. Each initial application received by the department shall be accompanied by verification that, within the preceding 6 months, the applicant or one or more of his or her designated employees has attended a training and information seminar conducted by the department or by a public or private provider approved by the department. Such seminar shall include, but not be limited to, statutory dealer requirements, which requirements include required bookkeeping and recording procedures, requirements for the collection of sales and use taxes, and such other information that in the opinion of the department will promote good business practices.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUPPLEMENTAL LICENSE.<EmDash />Any person licensed pursuant to this section shall be entitled to operate one or more additional places of business under a supplemental license for each such business if the ownership of each business is identical to that of the principal business for which the original license is issued. Each supplemental license shall run concurrently with the original license and shall be issued upon application by the licensee on a form to be furnished by the department and payment of a fee of $50 for each such license. Only one licensed dealer shall operate at the same place of business. A supplemental license authorizing off-premises sales shall be issued, at no charge to the dealer, for a period not to exceed 10 consecutive calendar days.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSE ENDORSEMENT.<EmDash />Any mobile home dealer licensed pursuant to s. 320.77, may apply to the department for authority to sell recreational vehicles. The mobile home dealer shall file an application required by this section and shall be governed by the licensing provisions contained herein. No additional license fees or bond shall be required for issuance of this endorsement to the mobile home dealer’s license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDS TO BE KEPT BY LICENSEE.<EmDash />Each licensee shall keep records in such form as shall be prescribed by the department. Such records shall include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record of the purchase, sale, or exchange, or receipt for the purpose of sale, of any recreational vehicle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The description of each such recreational vehicle, including the identification or serial number and such other numbers or identification marks as may be thereon, and a statement that a number has been obliterated, defaced, or changed, if such fact is apparent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the seller, the purchaser, and the alleged owner or other person from whom the recreational vehicle was purchased or received and the person to whom it was sold or delivered, as the case may be.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EVIDENCE OF TITLE REQUIRED.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall also have in his or her possession for each new recreational vehicle a manufacturer’s invoice or statement of origin.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each used recreational vehicle in the possession of a licensee and offered for sale by him or her, the licensee either shall have in his or her possession or control a duly assigned certificate of title from the owner in accordance with the provisions of chapter 319, or a registration certificate if the used recreational vehicle was previously registered in a nontitle state, from the time when the vehicle is delivered to the licensee and offered for sale by him or her until it has been disposed of by the licensee, or shall have reasonable indicia of ownership or right of possession, or shall have made proper application for a certificate of title or duplicate certificate of title in accordance with the provisions of chapter 319. A dealer may not sell or offer for sale a vehicle in his or her possession unless the dealer satisfies the requirements of this subsection. Reasonable indicia of ownership shall include a duly assigned certificate of title; in the case of a new vehicle, a manufacturer’s certificate of origin issued to or reassigned to the dealer; a consignment contract between the owner and the dealer along with a secure power of attorney from the owner to the dealer authorizing the dealer to apply for a duplicate certificate of title and assign the title on behalf of the owner; a court order awarding title to the vehicle to the dealer; a salvage certificate of title; a photocopy of a duly assigned certificate of title being held by a financial institution as collateral for a business loan of money to the dealer (“floor plan”); a copy of a canceled check or other documentation evidencing that an outstanding lien on a vehicle taken in trade by a licensed dealer has been satisfied and that the certificate of title will be, but has not yet been, received by the dealer; a vehicle purchase order or installment contract for a specific vehicle identifying that vehicle as a trade-in on a replacement vehicle; or a duly executed odometer disclosure statement as required by Title IV of the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act of 1972 (Pub. L. No. 92-513, as amended by Pub. L. No. 94-364 and Pub. L. No. 100-561) and by 49 C.F.R. part 580 bearing the signatures of the titled owners of a traded-in vehicle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SETUP OPERATIONS.<EmDash />Each licensee may perform setup operations only as defined in s. 320.822, and the department shall provide by rule for the uniform application of all existing statutory provisions relating to licensing and setup operations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PENALTY.<EmDash />The violation of any provision of this section is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INJUNCTION.<EmDash />In addition to the remedies provided in this chapter, and notwithstanding the existence of any adequate remedy at law, the department is authorized to make application to any circuit court of the state, and the circuit court shall have jurisdiction, upon a hearing and for cause shown, to grant a temporary or permanent injunction restraining any person from acting as a recreational vehicle dealer under the terms of this section who is not properly licensed or who violates or fails or refuses to comply with any of the provisions of chapter 319 and this chapter or any rule or regulation adopted thereunder. Such injunction shall be issued without bond. A single act in violation of the provisions of chapter 319 or this chapter shall be sufficient to authorize the issuance of an injunction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUSPENSION OR REVOCATION.<EmDash />The department shall, as it deems necessary, either suspend or revoke any license issued hereunder upon a finding that the licensee violated any provision of this section or of any other law of this state having to do with dealing in recreational vehicles or perpetrated a fraud upon any person as a result of such dealing in recreational vehicles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADMINISTRATIVE FINES.<EmDash />In addition to the exercise of other powers provided in this section, the department is authorized to assess, impose, levy, and collect by legal process fines, in an amount not to exceed $1,000 for each violation, against any licensee if it finds that a licensee has violated any provision of this section or has violated any other law of this state having to do with dealing in motor vehicles. Any licensee shall be entitled to a hearing pursuant to chapter 120 should the licensee wish to contest the fine levied, or about to be levied, upon him or her.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOND.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before any license shall be issued or renewed, the applicant shall deliver to the department a good and sufficient surety bond, executed by the applicant as principal and by a surety company qualified to do business in the state as surety. The bond shall be in a form to be approved by the department and shall be conditioned upon the dealer’s complying with the conditions of any written contract made by that dealer in connection with the sale, exchange, or improvement of any recreational vehicle and his or her not violating any of the provisions of chapter 319 or this chapter in the conduct of the business for which he or she is licensed. The bond shall be to the department and in favor of any retail customer who shall suffer any loss as a result of any violation of the conditions hereinabove contained. The bond shall be for the license period, and a new bond or a proper continuation certificate shall be delivered to the department at the beginning of each license period. However, the aggregate liability of the surety in any one license year shall in no event exceed the sum of such bond. The amount of the bond required shall be as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A single dealer who buys, sells, or deals in recreational vehicles and has four or fewer supplemental licenses shall provide a surety bond in the amount of $10,000.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A single dealer who buys, sells, or deals in recreational vehicles and who has more than four supplemental licenses shall provide a surety bond in the amount of $20,000.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For the purposes of this paragraph, any person who buys, sells, or deals in both mobile homes and recreational vehicles shall provide the same surety bond required of dealers who buy, sell, or deal in mobile homes only.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, upon denial, suspension, or revocation of any license, notify the surety company of the licensee, in writing, that the license has been denied, suspended, or revoked and shall state the reason for such denial, suspension, or revocation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any surety company which pays any claim against the bond of any licensee shall notify the department, in writing, that it has paid such a claim and shall state the amount of the claim.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any surety company which cancels the bond of any licensee shall notify the department, in writing, of such cancellation, giving reason for the cancellation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROHIBITED COMMISSION SHARING.<EmDash />In accordance with the provisions of s. 626.753, a dealer or recreational vehicle broker, as defined in this section, who is not a licensed insurance agent may not share in the commission on the sale of insurance coverage on the types of recreational vehicles defined in s. 320.01(1)(b) by the creation of a foreign partnership, corporation, or other entity which is controlled by a person or entity not licensed as an insurance agent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 95-333; s. 44, ch. 96-413; s. 35, ch. 97-96; s. 1, ch. 2000-247; s. 6, ch. 2009-93; s. 1, ch. 2012-18; s. 43, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>