<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.3202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 320.3201-320.3211, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Area of sales responsibility” means the geographical area agreed to by the dealer and the manufacturer in the manufacturer/dealer agreement within which the dealer has the exclusive right to display or sell the manufacturer’s new recreational vehicles of a particular line-make.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” means any person, firm, corporation, or business entity licensed or required to be licensed under s. 320.771.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Distributor” means any person, firm, corporation, or business entity that purchases new recreational vehicles for resale to dealers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Factory campaign” means an effort on the part of a warrantor to contact recreational vehicle owners or dealers in order to address a part or equipment issue.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Family member” means a spouse, child, grandchild, parent, sibling, niece, or nephew, or the spouse thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Line-make” means a specific series of recreational vehicle products that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are identified by a common series trade name or trademark;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are targeted to a particular market segment, as determined by their decor, features, equipment, size, weight, and price range;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have lengths and interior floor plans that distinguish the recreational vehicles from other recreational vehicles with substantially the same decor, equipment, features, price, and weight;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Belong to a single, distinct classification of recreational vehicle product type having a substantial degree of commonality in the construction of the chassis, frame, and body; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer/dealer agreement authorizes a dealer to sell.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer” means any person, firm, corporation, or business entity that engages in the manufacturing of recreational vehicles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer/dealer agreement” means a written agreement or contract entered into between a manufacturer and a dealer that fixes the rights and responsibilities of the parties and pursuant to which the dealer sells new recreational vehicles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proprietary part” means any part manufactured by or for and sold exclusively by the manufacturer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recreational vehicle” means the category of motor vehicle described in s. 320.01(1)(b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transient customer” means a customer who is temporarily traveling through a dealer’s area of sales responsibility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Warrantor” means any person, firm, corporation, or business entity that gives a warranty in connection with a new recreational vehicle or parts, accessories, or components thereof. The term does not include service contracts, mechanical or other insurance, or extended warranties sold for separate consideration by a dealer or other person not controlled by a manufacturer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2007-258.</History></Section>