<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.08068" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Motorcycle specialty license plates.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 320.08053, the department shall develop a reduced dimensions specialty license plate for display on motorcycles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a specialty license plate to the owner or lessee of any motorcycle upon request and payment of the appropriate license taxes and fees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each request must be made annually to the department, accompanied by the following taxes and fees:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license tax required under s. 320.08.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license plate fee as required by s. 320.06(1)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A processing fee of $2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license plate annual use fee as required in subsection (4).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license plate annual use fee of $20 shall be collected for each motorcycle specialty license plate. Annual use fees shall be distributed to The Able Trust as custodial agent. The Able Trust may retain a maximum of 10 percent of the proceeds from the sale of the license plate for administrative costs. The Able Trust shall distribute the remaining funds as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent to the Brain and Spinal Cord Injury Program Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent to Prevent Blindness Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent to the Blind Services Foundation of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent to the Foundation for Vocational Rehabilitation to support the Personal Care Attendant Program pursuant to s. 413.402.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty percent to the Florida Association of Centers for Independent Living.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an owner or lessee to whom the department has issued a motorcycle specialty license plate acquires a replacement vehicle within the owner’s registration period, the department must authorize a transfer of the specialty license plate to the replacement vehicle in accordance with s. 320.0609. The annual use fee or processing fee may not be refunded.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license plate shall be 4 inches wide by 7 inches long and incorporate a red, white, and blue color scheme approved by the department and may bear the imprint of numerals from 1 to 999, inclusive, capital letters “A” through “Z,” or a combination thereof. The department shall determine the maximum number of characters, including numerals and letters. Motorcycle specialty license plates must be otherwise of the same material as standard license plates issued for any registration period. In small letters, the word “Florida” must appear at the top of the plate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue personalized prestige plates for license plates authorized in this section. Such plates shall be issued in accordance with applicable provisions contained in s. 320.0805.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-280; s. 2, ch. 2006-169; s. 36, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>