<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0320.3208" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspection and rejection by the dealer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a new recreational vehicle is damaged prior to transit to the dealer or is damaged in transit to the dealer when the carrier or means of transportation has been selected by the manufacturer or distributor, the dealer shall notify the manufacturer or distributor of the damage within the timeframe specified in the manufacturer/dealer agreement and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request from the manufacturer or distributor authorization to replace the components, parts, and accessories damaged or otherwise correct the damage; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reject the vehicle within the timeframe set forth in subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the manufacturer or distributor refuses or fails to authorize repair of such damage within 10 days after receipt of notification or if the dealer rejects the recreational vehicle because of damage, ownership of the new recreational vehicle reverts to the manufacturer or distributor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dealer shall exercise due care in custody of the damaged recreational vehicle, but the dealer shall have no other obligations, financial or otherwise, with respect to that recreational vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The timeframe for inspection and rejection by the dealer must be part of the manufacturer/dealer agreement and may not be less than 2 business days after the physical delivery of the recreational vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any recreational vehicle that has, at the time of delivery to the dealer, an unreasonable amount of miles on its odometer, as determined by the dealer, may be subject to rejection by the dealer and reversion of the vehicle to the manufacturer or distributor. In no instance shall a dealer deem an amount less than the distance between the dealer and the manufacturer’s factory or a distributor’s point of distribution, plus 100 miles, as unreasonable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2007-258.</History></Section>