<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0320.131" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary tags.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized and empowered to design, issue, and regulate the use of temporary tags to be designated “temporary tags” for use in the following cases:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where a dealer license plate may not be lawfully used.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a casual or private sale, including the sale of a marine boat trailer by a marine boat trailer dealer. A “casual or private sale” means any sale other than that by a licensed dealer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For certified common carriers or driveaway companies who transport motor vehicles, mobile homes, or recreational vehicles from one place to another for persons other than themselves.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For banks, credit unions, and other financial institutions which are not required to be licensed under the provisions of s. 320.27, s. 320.77, or s. 320.771, but need temporary tags for the purpose of demonstrating repossessions for sale.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where a motor vehicle is sold in this state to a resident of another state for registration therein and the motor vehicle is not required to be registered under the provisions of s. 320.38.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where a motor vehicle is required to be weighed or emission tested prior to registration or have a vehicle identification number verified. A temporary tag issued for any of these purposes shall be valid for 10 days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where an out-of-state resident, subject to registration in this state, must secure ownership documentation from the home state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a rental car company which possesses a motor vehicle dealer license and which may use temporary tags on vehicles offered for lease by such company in accordance with the provisions of rules established by the department. However, the original issuance date of a temporary tag shall be the date which determines the applicable license plate fee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the resolution of a consumer complaint where there is a need to issue more than two temporary tags, the department may do so.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While a personalized prestige or specialty license plate is being manufactured for use upon the motor vehicle. A temporary tag issued for this purpose shall be valid for 90 days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case where a permanent license plate cannot legally be issued to an applicant and a temporary license plate is not specifically authorized under the provisions of this section, the department shall have the discretion to issue or authorize agents or Florida licensed dealers to issue temporary license plates to applicants demonstrating a need for such temporary use.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For use by licensed dealers to transport motor vehicles and recreational vehicles from the dealer’s licensed location to an off-premise sales location and return. Temporary tags used for such purposes shall be issued to the licensed dealer who owns the vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Further, the department is authorized to disallow the purchase of temporary tags by licensed dealers, common carriers, or financial institutions in those cases where abuse has occurred.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to sell temporary tags, in addition to those listed above, to their agents and where need is demonstrated by a consumer complainant. The fee shall be $2 each. One dollar from each tag sold shall be deposited into the Brain and Spinal Cord Injury Program Trust Fund, with the remaining proceeds being deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund. Agents of the department shall sell temporary tags for $2 each and shall charge the service charge authorized by s. 320.04 per transaction, regardless of the quantity sold. Requests for purchase of temporary tags to the department or its agents shall be made, where applicable, on letterhead stationery and notarized. Except as specifically provided otherwise, a temporary tag shall be valid for 30 days, and no more than two shall be issued to the same person for the same vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or corporation who unlawfully issues or uses a temporary tag or violates this section or any rule adopted by the department to implement this section commits a noncriminal infraction, punishable as a moving violation as provided in chapter 318 in addition to other administrative action by the department. Using a temporary tag that has been expired for a period of 7 days or less is a noncriminal infraction, and is a nonmoving violation punishable as provided for in chapter 318.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Temporary tags shall be conspicuously displayed in the rear license plate bracket or, on vehicles requiring front display of license plates, on the front of the vehicle in the location where the metal license plate would normally be displayed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall designate specifications for the media upon which the temporary tag is printed. Such media shall be either nonpermeable or subject to weatherproofing so that it maintains its structural integrity, including graphic and data adhesion, in all weather conditions after being placed on a vehicle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly and willfully abuses or misuses temporary tag issuance to avoid registering a vehicle requiring registration pursuant to this chapter or chapter 319 commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly and willfully issues a temporary tag or causes another to issue a temporary tag to a fictitious person or entity to avoid disclosure of the true owner of a vehicle commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person authorized by this section to purchase and issue a temporary tag shall maintain records as required by this chapter or departmental rules, and such records shall be open to inspection by the department or its agents during reasonable business hours. Any person who knowingly and willfully fails to comply with this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall administer an electronic system for licensed motor vehicle dealers to use for issuing temporary tags. If a dealer fails to comply with the department’s requirements for issuing temporary tags using the electronic system, the department may deny, suspend, or revoke a license under s. 320.27(9)(b)16. upon proof that the licensee has failed to comply with the department’s requirements. The department may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall implement a secure print-on-demand electronic temporary tag registration, record retention, and issue system required for use by every department-authorized issuer of temporary tags by the end of the 2007-2008 fiscal year. Such system shall enable the department to issue, on demand, a temporary tag number in response to a request from the issuer by way of a secure electronic exchange of data and then enable the issuer to print the temporary tag <Reference Number="1" />that has all required information. A motor vehicle dealer licensed under this chapter <Reference Number="2" />may charge a fee to comply with this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To ensure the continuation of operations for issuers if a system outage occurs, the department shall allow the limited use of a backup manual issuance method during an outage which requires recordkeeping of information as determined by the department and which requires the timely electronic reporting of this information to the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules necessary to <Reference Number="3" />administer this subsection. Such rules may include exemptions from the requirements of this subsection as feasibly required to <Reference Number="3" />administer the program, as well as exemptions for issuers who do not require a dealer license under this chapter because of the type or size of vehicle being sold.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-4, ch. 59-348; s. 1, ch. 61-150; s. 6, ch. 65-190; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 195, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 72-46; s. 10, ch. 75-66; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 78-217; s. 4, ch. 78-225; s. 1, ch. 80-217; s. 3, ch. 82-97; s. 25, ch. 82-134; s. 38, ch. 83-318; s. 3, ch. 85-176; s. 1, ch. 87-401; s. 1, ch. 88-395; s. 9, ch. 90-329; s. 79, ch. 93-120; s. 2, ch. 94-142; s. 12, ch. 94-314; s. 74, ch. 94-353; s. 23, ch. 95-333; s. 41, ch. 96-413; s. 13, ch. 97-300; s. 33, ch. 99-248; s. 64, ch. 2005-164; s. 1, ch. 2008-71; s. 23, ch. 2008-176; s. 9, ch. 2009-206; s. 5, ch. 2010-161; s. 26, ch. 2010-162; s. 8, ch. 2011-3.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 23, ch. 2008-176. The amendment by s. 1, ch. 2008-71, uses the word “with” instead of the words “that has.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 23, ch. 2008-176. The amendment by s. 1, ch. 2008-71, uses the words “shall be authorized to” instead of the word “may.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="3">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 23, ch. 2008-176. The amendment by s. 1, ch. 2008-71, uses the word “implement” instead of the word “administer.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>