<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0030.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers, duties, and obligations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sheriffs, in their respective counties, in person or by deputy, shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute all process of the Supreme Court, circuit courts, county courts, and boards of county commissioners of this state, to be executed in their counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute such other writs, processes, warrants, and other papers directed to them, as may come to their hands to be executed in their counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attend all terms of the circuit court and county court held in their counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute all orders of the boards of county commissioners of their counties, for which services they shall receive such compensation, out of the county treasury, as said boards may deem proper.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be conservators of the peace in their counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suppress tumults, riots, and unlawful assemblies in their counties with force and strong hand when necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apprehend, without warrant, any person disturbing the peace, and carry that person before the proper judicial officer, that further proceedings may be had against him or her according to law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have authority to raise the power of the county and command any person to assist them, when necessary, in the execution of the duties of their office; and, whoever, not being physically incompetent, refuses or neglects to render such assistance, shall be punished by imprisonment in jail not exceeding 1 year, or by fine not exceeding $500.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be, ex officio, timber agents for their counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform such other duties as may be imposed upon them by law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sheriffs, in their respective counties, in person or by deputy, shall, at the will of the board of county commissioners, attend, in person or by deputy, all meetings of the boards of county commissioners of their counties, for which services they shall receive such compensation, out of the county treasury, as said boards may deem proper.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before January 1, 2002, every sheriff shall incorporate an antiracial or other antidiscriminatory profiling policy into the sheriff’s policies and practices, utilizing the Florida Police Chiefs Association Model Policy as a guide. Antiprofiling policies shall include the elements of definitions, traffic stop procedures, community education and awareness efforts, and policies for the handling of complaints from the public.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 4, 1845; ss. 1, 4, ch. 157, 1848; s. 9, ch. 1626, 1868; ss. 1, 2, ch. 1659, 1868; RS 650, 651, 653, 1241, 1242, 2583; GS 991, 992, 994, 1670, 1671, 3503; RGS 1804, 1805, 1807, 2875, 2876, 5388; CGL 2856, 2857, 2859, 4572, 4573, 7527; s. 4, ch. 22790, 1945; s. 4, ch. 73-334; s. 1, ch. 91-95; s. 179, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 2001-264.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 144.01-144.03, 30.16.</Text></Note></Section>