<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0030.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transportation and return of prisoners.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff of any county of the state, when required to go beyond the limits of this state to bring back a prisoner charged with any offense or who has been convicted of any crime in this state and has escaped, shall receive the actual and necessary expense on account of returning the prisoner to the state. Travel under this subsection is exempt from the provisions of s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sheriff of each county of the state is authorized to contract with private transport companies for the transportation of prisoners both within and beyond the limits of this state. Each prisoner shall be delivered to the transport company by a sheriff or other proper law enforcement official for transportation and then delivered by the same transport company to the proper sheriff or other law enforcement official upon arriving at the point of destination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any company transporting a prisoner pursuant to this section shall be considered an independent contractor and shall be solely liable for the prisoner while the prisoner is in the custody of the company. Any transport company contracting with a sheriff for the transportation of prisoners as provided for in this section shall be insured and shall provide no less than $100,000 in liability insurance with respect to the transporting of the prisoners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personnel employed by any transport company for the transportation of prisoners as provided for in this section are specifically exempted from:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any requirements of being appointed as deputy sheriffs.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing bond.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meeting requirements and training as provided by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission for law enforcement and correctional officers.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 5407, 1905; ss. 2, 5, ch. 7886, 1919; RGS 2893; s. 2, ch. 10091, 1925; CGL 4591; s. 2, ch. 20943, 1941; s. 1, ch. 77-154; s. 1, ch. 81-176; s. 4, ch. 83-167; s. 183, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>