<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0030.46" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sheriffs; motor vehicles color combination; badges; simulation prohibited; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The color combination of forest green and white is adopted as the official color for use on the motor vehicles and motorcycles used by the various sheriffs of Florida and their deputies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of uniformity and in aid of the recognition of their official identity by the public, a badge in the shape of a five-pointed star with a replica of the great seal of Florida with the map of Florida superimposed thereon inscribed in the center is designated as the official badge to be worn by the sheriffs and deputy sheriffs of all counties of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person other than the sheriffs of Florida and their deputies, to color or cause to be colored any motor vehicle or motorcycle the same or similar color combination prescribed herein; provided, however, that any municipal police department or other law enforcement agency or any private person or concern using the same or similar color combination as of the date of this act shall be permitted to continue to use such colors until such time as new colors are adopted by such agencies, or private person or concern.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person other than sheriffs and deputy sheriffs to wear an official sheriff’s badge as prescribed herein, or to wear a badge or insignia of such similarity to the official sheriff’s badge as to be indistinguishable therefrom at a distance of 20 feet; provided, nothing therein shall be construed to prevent members of any military, fraternal, or similar organization or any other law enforcement officer from wearing any insignia officially adopted or worn prior to the effective date of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any of the provisions of this act shall be a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, ch. 57-3; s. 13, ch. 71-136.</History></Section>