<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0030.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Review boards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each sheriff shall establish a review board to review, pursuant to appeals taken under ss. 30.071-30.079, terminations taken by the sheriff against regularly appointed deputy sheriffs for lawful off-duty political activity or for discriminatory reasons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of a review board shall be selected on the basis of fairness, objectivity, and impartiality. The board shall have no investigative powers and shall function in the capacity of a fact finder in an effort to arrive at a fair and equitable recommendation in all matters brought before it. A member shall not be involved in the issue under consideration. Membership on the board is voluntary and without remuneration. Members may not discuss matters to be heard before the board until the board convenes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A review board may receive verbal or written testimony concerning any matter considered relevant by the board and may receive any records, including, but not limited to, performance evaluations and disciplinary files.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The review board of an agency having 150 or more deputy sheriffs shall be comprised of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members selected by the sheriff from among the certified law enforcement officers within the sheriff’s jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members selected by the deputy sheriff who is appealing the termination action from among the certified law enforcement officers within the sheriff’s jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member selected by the other members of the board and acting as the chairperson of the board.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an impartial local chairperson cannot be agreed upon within 10 working days after the appeal is submitted, then the parties shall jointly request the American Arbitration Association to furnish a panel of seven names from which each party shall have the option, within 5 days of receipt, of striking three names in alternating fashion. The seventh or remaining name shall be the chairperson. The parties shall jointly notify the arbitrator of his or her selection. Either party may object to all names on the list, provided the objection is made prior to the commencement of the striking process. If this occurs, the objecting party may request the American Arbitration Association to furnish another list of arbitrators. No more than two lists may be requested. The costs of the arbitrator shall be shared by both parties.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The review board of an agency having fewer than 150 deputy sheriffs shall be comprised of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member selected by the sheriff from among the certified law enforcement officers within the sheriff’s jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member selected by the deputy sheriff who is appealing the termination from among the certified law enforcement officers within the sheriff’s jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member selected by the other members of the board and acting as the chairperson of the board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chairperson of a review board shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct each meeting using parliamentary rules of order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request that the deputy sheriff who is appealing provide the names of his or her witnesses, if any.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Schedule and provide written notice of each meeting to the Internal Affairs Bureau, witnesses, board members, and deputies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide copies of all charges to the board members.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The scope of the review board is limited to terminations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 94-143; s. 1328, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 95-155.</History></Section>