<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0030.072" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Actual, continuous service” means the time during which a deputy sheriff performs the duties and responsibilities of the position to which she or he is appointed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Deputy sheriff” means a law enforcement officer appointed by the sheriff and certified under chapter 943. The term does not include a person who performs managerial, confidential, or policymaking duties. Managerial, confidential, and policymaking appointees who are not covered by this act include the undersheriff, chief deputy, director, legal advisor, sheriff’s personal secretary or administrative assistant, or members of the sheriff’s personal staff who report to or work under the direct supervision of the sheriff or who assist the sheriff in the formulation of general or special orders or in the preparation of the fiscal year budget, or appointees whose duties primarily involve the management or operation of the sheriff’s office or a department or subdivision of that office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Probation” means a period of actual, continuous service following initial employment or following a promotion from a regular appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Regular appointment” means the employment status of a deputy sheriff who has satisfactorily completed probation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sheriff” means the constitutional officer elected in accordance with this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 94-143; s. 1325, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>