<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0476.214" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for suspending, revoking, or refusing to grant license or certificate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have the power to revoke or suspend any license, registration card, or certificate of registration issued pursuant to this act, or to reprimand, censure, deny subsequent licensure of, or otherwise discipline any holder of a license, registration card, or certificate of registration issued pursuant to this act, for any of the following causes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross malpractice or gross incompetency in the practice of barbering;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice by a person knowingly having an infectious or contagious disease; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commission of any of the offenses described in s. 476.194.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules relating to the suspension or revocation of licenses or certificates of registration under this section pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall keep a record of its disciplinary proceedings against holders of licenses or certificates of registration issued pursuant to this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue or renew a license or certificate of registration under this chapter to any person against whom or barbershop against which the board has assessed a fine, interest, or costs associated with investigation and prosecution until the person or barbershop has paid in full such fine, interest, or costs associated with investigation and prosecution or until the person or barbershop complies with or satisfies all terms and conditions of the final order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 21, 28, ch. 78-155; ss. 11, 13, 15, 25, 30, 34, 62, ch. 80-406; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 19, 20, ch. 85-297; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 98-323.</History></Section>