<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0476.044" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not apply to the following persons when practicing pursuant to their professional responsibilities and duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons authorized under the laws of this state to practice medicine, surgery, osteopathic medicine, chiropractic medicine, naturopathy, or podiatric medicine;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commissioned medical or surgical officers of the United States Armed Forces hospital service;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed nurses under the laws of this state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons practicing cosmetology under the laws of this state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons employed in federal, state, or local institutions, hospitals, or military bases as barbers whose practice is limited to the inmates, patients, or authorized military personnel of such institutions, hospitals, or bases;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who practice only shampooing as defined in s. 477.013 and whose practice is limited to the acts described therein; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons whose occupation or practice is confined solely to cutting, trimming, polishing, or cleansing the fingernails of any person when said cutting, trimming, polishing, or cleansing is done in a barbershop licensed pursuant to this chapter which is carrying on a regular and customary business of barbering, and such individual has been practicing the activities set forth in this subsection prior to October 1, 1985.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 28, ch. 78-155; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 19, 20, ch. 85-297; s. 9, ch. 87-69; s. 27, ch. 88-392; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 53, ch. 97-264; ss. 216, 284, ch. 98-166.</History></Section>