<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0480.0535" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Documents required while working in a massage establishment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to provide the department and law enforcement agencies the means to more effectively identify, investigate, and arrest persons engaging in human trafficking, a person employed by a massage establishment and any person performing massage therein must immediately present, upon the request of an investigator of the department or a law enforcement officer, valid government identification while in the establishment. A valid government identification for the purposes of this section is:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A valid, unexpired driver license issued by any state, territory, or district of the United States;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A valid, unexpired identification card issued by any state, territory, or district of the United States;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A valid, unexpired United States passport;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A naturalization certificate issued by the United States Department of Homeland Security;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A valid, unexpired alien registration receipt card (green card); or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A valid, unexpired employment authorization card issued by the United States Department of Homeland Security.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person operating a massage establishment must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediately present, upon the request of an investigator of the department or a law enforcement officer:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Valid government identification while in the establishment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the documentation specified in paragraph (1)(a) for each employee and any person performing massage in the establishment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that each employee and any person performing massage in the massage establishment is able to immediately present, upon the request of an investigator of the department or a law enforcement officer, valid government identification while in the establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates any provision of this section commits:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a first violation, a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second violation, a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a third or subsequent violation, a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2012-97.</History>
</Section>