<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0480.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Massage therapists; qualifications; licensure; endorsement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person is qualified for licensure as a massage therapist under this act who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 18 years of age or has received a high school diploma or graduate equivalency diploma;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed a course of study at a board-approved massage school or has completed an apprenticeship program that meets standards adopted by the board; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received a passing grade on an examination administered by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person desiring to be examined for licensure as a massage therapist shall apply to the department in writing upon forms prepared and furnished by the department. Such applicants shall be subject to the provisions of s. 480.046(1). Applicants may take an examination administered by the department only upon meeting the requirements of this section as determined by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon an applicant’s passing the examination and paying the initial licensure fee, the department shall issue to the applicant a license, valid until the next scheduled renewal date, to practice massage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing a minimum training program for apprentices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing for educational standards, examination, and certification for the practice of colonic irrigation, as defined in s. 480.033(6), by massage therapists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specifying licensing procedures for practitioners desiring to be licensed in this state who hold an active license and have practiced in any other state, territory, or jurisdiction of the United States or any foreign national jurisdiction which has licensing standards substantially similar to, equivalent to, or more stringent than the standards of this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 78-436; ss. 13, 15, 25, 30, 34, 52, 62, ch. 80-406; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 25, 47, ch. 82-179; s. 77, ch. 83-329; ss. 4, 12, 13, ch. 85-280; s. 61, ch. 87-225; s. 52, ch. 89-374; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 153, ch. 94-119; s. 152, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>