<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0480.033" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Massage Therapy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Massage” means the manipulation of the soft tissues of the human body with the hand, foot, arm, or elbow, whether or not such manipulation is aided by hydrotherapy, including colonic irrigation, or thermal therapy; any electrical or mechanical device; or the application to the human body of a chemical or herbal preparation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Massage therapist” means a person licensed as required by this act, who administers massage for compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Apprentice” means a person approved by the board to study massage under the instruction of a licensed massage therapist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Colonic irrigation” means a method of hydrotherapy used to cleanse the colon with the aid of a mechanical device and water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Establishment” means a site or premises, or portion thereof, wherein a massage therapist practices massage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensure” means the procedure by which a person, hereinafter referred to as a “practitioner,” applies to the board for approval to practice massage or to operate an establishment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board-approved massage school” means a facility which meets minimum standards for training and curriculum as determined by rule of the board and which is licensed by the Department of Education pursuant to chapter 1005 or the equivalent licensing authority of another state or is within the public school system of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 78-436; ss. 13, 15, 25, 30, 34, 50, 62, ch. 80-406; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 76, ch. 83-329; ss. 1, 12, 13, ch. 85-280; s. 50, ch. 89-374; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 169, ch. 94-218; s. 67, ch. 95-144; s. 149, ch. 97-264; s. 116, ch. 2001-277; s. 1025, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>