<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0343.63" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Central Florida Regional Transportation Authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created and established a body politic and corporate, an agency of the state, to be known as the “Central Florida Regional Transportation Authority,” hereinafter referred to as the “authority.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing board of the authority shall consist of five voting members as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chairs of the county commissions of Seminole, Orange, and Osceola Counties, or another member of the commission designated by the county chair, shall each serve as a representative on the board for the full extent of his or her term.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mayor of the City of Orlando, or a member of the Orlando City Council designated by the mayor, shall serve as a representative on the board for the full extent of his or her term.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Transportation shall appoint the district secretary, or his or her designee, for the district within which the area served by the authority is located and this member shall be a voting member.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vacancy during a term shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment and only for the balance of the unexpired term.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the authority shall not be entitled to compensation, but shall be reimbursed for travel expenses actually incurred in their duties as provided by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 89-351; s. 2, ch. 91-142; s. 8, ch. 91-418; s. 77, ch. 92-152; s. 3, ch. 93-103; s. 509, ch. 95-148; s. 22, ch. 2000-266; s. 1, ch. 2003-285.</History></Section>