<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0343.94" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bond financing authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to s. 11(f), Art. VII of the State Constitution, the Legislature approves bond financing by the Tampa Bay Area Regional Transportation Authority for construction of or improvements to commuter rail systems, transit systems, ferry systems, highways, bridges, toll collection facilities, interchanges to the system, and any other transportation facility appurtenant, necessary, or incidental to the system. Subject to terms and conditions of applicable revenue bond resolutions and covenants, such costs may be financed in whole or in part by revenue bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (2)(a) or paragraph (2)(b), whether currently issued or issued in the future or by a combination of such bonds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds may be issued on behalf of the authority pursuant to the State Bond Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alternatively, the authority may issue its own bonds pursuant to this part at such times and in such principal amount as, in the opinion of the authority, is necessary to provide sufficient moneys for achieving its purposes; however, such bonds may not pledge the full faith and credit of the state. Bonds issued by the authority pursuant to this paragraph or paragraph (a), whether on original issuance or on refunding, shall be authorized by resolution of the members thereof, may be either term or serial bonds, and shall bear such date or dates, mature at such time or times, not exceeding 40 years after their respective dates, bear interest at such rate or rates, be payable semiannually, be in such denominations, be in such form, either coupon or fully registered, carry such registration, exchangeability, and interchangeability privileges, be payable in such medium of payment and at such place or places, be subject to such terms of redemption, and be entitled to such priorities on the revenues, rates, fees, rentals, or other charges or receipts of the authority, including revenues from lease-purchase agreements, as such resolution or any resolution subsequent thereto may provide. The bonds shall be executed either by manual or facsimile signature by such officers as the authority shall determine; however, such bonds shall bear at least one signature that is manually executed thereon, and the coupons attached to such bonds shall bear the facsimile signature or signatures of such officer or officers as shall be designated by the authority and have the seal of the authority affixed, imprinted, reproduced, or lithographed thereon, all as may be prescribed in such resolution or resolutions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) shall be sold at public sale in the manner provided by the State Bond Act. However, if the authority, by official action at a public meeting, determines that a negotiated sale of such bonds is in the best interest of the authority, the authority may negotiate the sale of such bonds with the underwriter designated by the authority and the Division of Bond Finance within the State Board of Administration with respect to bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (a) or solely by the authority with respect to bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (b). The authority’s determination to negotiate the sale of such bonds may be based, in part, upon the written advice of the authority’s financial adviser. Pending the preparation of definitive bonds, interim certificates may be issued to the purchaser or purchasers of such bonds and may contain such terms and conditions as the authority may determine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority may issue bonds pursuant to paragraph (b) to refund any bonds previously issued regardless of whether the bonds being refunded were issued by the authority pursuant to this chapter or on behalf of the authority pursuant to the State Bond Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such resolution or resolutions authorizing any bonds hereunder may contain provisions that are part of the contract with the holders of such bonds, as to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pledging of all or any part of the revenues, fares, rates, fees, rentals, or other charges or receipts of the authority, derived by the authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The completion, improvement, operation, extension, maintenance, repair, or lease of the system and the duties of the authority and others, including the department, with reference thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the purposes to which the proceeds of the bonds, then or thereafter to be issued, or of any loan or grant by the United States or the state may be applied.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fixing, charging, establishing, and collecting of rates, fees, rentals, or other charges for use of the services and facilities constructed by the authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The setting aside of reserves or sinking funds or repair and replacement funds and the regulation and disposition thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the issuance of additional bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and provisions of any lease-purchase agreement, deed of trust, or indenture securing the bonds or under which the same may be issued.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other or additional agreements with the holders of the bonds which the authority may deem desirable and proper.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority may employ fiscal agents as provided by this part or the State Board of Administration may, upon request of the authority, act as fiscal agent for the authority in the issuance of any bonds that are issued pursuant to this part, and the State Board of Administration may, upon request of the authority, take over the management, control, administration, custody, and payment of any or all debt services or funds or assets now or hereafter available for any bonds issued pursuant to this part. The authority may enter into any deeds of trust, indentures, or other agreements with its fiscal agent, or with any bank or trust company within or without the state, as security for such bonds and may, under such agreements, sign and pledge all or any of the revenues, rates, fees, rentals, or other charges or receipts of the authority. Such deed of trust, indenture, or other agreement may contain such provisions as are customary in such instruments or as the authority authorizes, including, but without limitation, provisions as to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The completion, improvement, operation, extension, maintenance, repair, and lease of highway, bridge, and related transportation facilities and appurtenances and the duties of the authority and others with reference thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of funds and the safeguarding of funds on hand or on deposit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and remedies of the trustee and the holders of the bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and provisions of the bonds or the resolutions authorizing the issuance of the bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the bonds issued pursuant to this part are, and are hereby declared to be, negotiable instruments and have all the qualities and incidents of negotiable instruments under the law merchant and the negotiable instruments law of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this part, each project, building, or facility that has been financed by the issuance of bonds or other evidence of indebtedness under this part and any refinancing thereof are hereby approved as provided for in s. 11(f), Art. VII of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-254; s. 9, ch. 2011-64.</History>
</Section>