<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0343.975" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Complete and additional statutory authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers conferred by this part are supplemental to the existing powers of the board and the department. This part does not repeal any of the provisions of any other law, general, special, or local, but supplements such other laws in the exercise of the powers provided in this part and provides a complete method for the exercise of the powers granted in this part. The projects planned and constructed by the Tampa Bay Regional Transportation Authority shall comply with all applicable federal, state, and local laws. The extension and improvement of the system, and the issuance of bonds hereunder to finance all or part of the cost thereof, may be accomplished upon compliance with the provisions of this part without regard to or necessity for compliance with the provisions, limitations, or restrictions contained in any other general, special, or local law, including, but not limited to, s. 215.821. An approval of any bonds issued under this part by the qualified electors or qualified electors who are freeholders in the state or in any other political subdivision of the state is not required for the issuance of such bonds pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not repeal, rescind, or modify any other law relating to the State Board of Administration, the Department of Transportation, the Tampa-Hillsborough County Expressway Authority, or the Division of Bond Finance within the State Board of Administration; however, this part supersedes such other laws as are inconsistent with its provisions, including, but not limited to, s. 215.821.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not preclude the department from acquiring, holding, constructing, improving, maintaining, operating, or owning tolled or nontolled facilities funded and constructed from nonauthority sources that are part of the State Highway System within the geographical boundaries of the Tampa Bay Area Regional Transportation Authority.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-254.</History></Section>