<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0343.55" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of revenue bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority is authorized to borrow money as provided by the State Bond Act for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of any one or more projects of the South Florida Regional Transportation Authority. The principal of, and the interest on, such bonds shall be payable solely from revenues pledged for their payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the bonds of each issue shall be used solely for the payment of the cost of the projects for which such bonds shall have been issued, except as provided in the State Bond Act. Such proceeds shall be disbursed and used as provided in this part and in such manner and under such restrictions, if any, as the Division of Bond Finance may provide in the resolution authorizing the issuance of such bonds or in the trust agreement securing the same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority may issue, reissue, or redeem bonds that do not pledge the full faith and credit of the state in such principal amounts as, in the opinion of the authority, is necessary to provide sufficient moneys for achieving its corporate purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bonds of the authority, whether on original issuance or refunding, must be authorized by resolution of the authority after approval of the issuance of the bonds at a public hearing. These bonds may be term or serial bonds, shall bear such date or dates, mature at such time or times, bear interest at such rate or rates, at such times, be in such denominations, be in such form, coupon or fully registered, shall carry registration, have exchangeability and interchangeability privileges, be payable in such medium of payment and at such place or places, be subject to such terms of redemption and be entitled to such priorities on the revenues, rates, fees, rentals, or other charges or receipts of the authority as any resolution subsequent thereto may provide. The bonds must be executed by officers as the authority determines under the requirements of s. 279.06.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall sell the bonds at public sale by competitive bid. However, if the authority receives a written recommendation from a financial adviser and the authority determines, by official action, that a negotiated sale of the bonds is in the best interest of the authority, the authority may negotiate sale of the bonds with the underwriter designated by the authority, after a public hearing and by a two-thirds vote of all voting members of the authority. The authority shall provide specific findings in a resolution as to the reasons requiring the negotiated sale. This resolution shall incorporate and have attached the written recommendation of the financial adviser required by this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such resolution authorizing any bonds that do not pledge the full faith and credit of the sale may contain provisions that are part of the contract with the holders of the bonds as the authority determines proper. In addition, the authority may enter into a trust indenture or other agreement with its fiscal agent or with any bank or trust company within or without the state as security for such bonds and may, under an agreement, assign and pledge the revenues, rates, fees, rentals, tolls, or other charges or receipts of the authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bond that is issued pursuant to this part is a negotiable instrument and has all the qualities and incidents of a negotiable instrument under the laws governing merchants and negotiable instruments in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 89-351; s. 5, ch. 2003-159; s. 2, ch. 2007-255.</History></Section>