<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0155.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County hospitals; organization; officers; powers; bonds; travel expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The said trustees shall, within 10 days after their appointment, qualify by taking the oath of office and organize a board of hospital trustees by the election of one of their members as chair and one as secretary and treasurer and by the election of such other officers as they deem necessary. Such chair shall be executive officer of the board of trustees and shall enforce and carry out all the orders of the board of trustees contained in resolutions duly adopted and entered on the minute books of the meetings of the board of trustees. The chair shall preside at all meetings and countersign all vouchers and warrants issued by the secretary and treasurer hereinafter provided for. In the absence of the chair, vouchers and warrants may be countersigned by any other member of the board of trustees selected by the members of the board of trustees as chair pro tem. In the absence of the chair and chair pro tem, vouchers and warrants may be countersigned by the hospital administrator or another full-time employee of the hospital as designated by the members of the board of trustees. The chair, chair pro tem, and such other full-time employees as may be designated by the members of the board of trustees to countersign warrants or vouchers shall give bonds in a sum to be fixed by the board of county commissioners for the faithful performance of their duties in some reputable bonding company authorized to do business in the state, and said bonds shall be made payable to the Governor of Florida and the Governor’s successors in office. No member of said board of trustees shall receive any compensation for services as such trustee, but shall be reimbursed for travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 20905, 1941; s. 19, ch. 63-400; s. 1, ch. 76-21; s. 876, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>