<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0155.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">County hospitals; deposit of moneys; payments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys received for such hospital shall be deposited in any bank designated by the said board of trustees, and placed to the credit of the hospital fund and can be paid out only as bills for material supplies, equipment, wages, salaries, or other items of expense whatsoever shall have been audited by the secretary and treasurer and approved by a majority of the members of the board of trustees in regular session. When so approved by a majority of said members, upon vouchers issued by the secretary and treasurer, warrant may be drawn for same and when countersigned by the chair of said board of trustees or an individual designated by s. 155.07, shall be authenticated. Provided, it shall be unlawful to pay any money out of said hospital fund until the provisions of this section have been complied with.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of providing for the direct deposit of funds under the circumstances herein specified, the board of trustees is authorized to establish the form or forms of warrants, which are to be issued and countersigned as provided in this chapter, for payment or disbursement of moneys out of the hospital depository, and to change the form thereof from time to time as the board of trustees deems appropriate. If authorized in writing by the payee, county hospital warrants may provide for the direct deposit of funds to the account of the payee in any financial institution which is designated in writing by the payee and which has lawful authority to accept such deposits. The written authorization of the payee shall be filed with the board of trustees. Direct deposit of funds may be by any electronic or other medium approved by the board of trustees for such purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the board of trustees or any agent authorized by the board who has the authority to deposit or withdraw funds is authorized to transfer funds from one depository to another or within a depository or to another institution, and may transfer funds wherein the transfer does not represent an expenditure, advance, or reduction of cash assets. Such transfer may be made by electronic, telephonic, or other medium; and each transfer shall be confirmed in writing and signed by the designee of the board.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 20905, 1941; s. 1, ch. 76-21; s. 7, ch. 78-406; s. 2, ch. 82-104; s. 879, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>