<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0734.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Ancillary administration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a nonresident of this state dies leaving assets in this state, credits due from residents in this state, or liens on property in this state, a personal representative specifically designated in the decedent’s will to administer the Florida property shall be entitled to have ancillary letters issued, if qualified to act in Florida. Otherwise, the foreign personal representative of the decedent’s estate shall be entitled to have letters issued, if qualified to act in Florida. If the foreign personal representative is not qualified to act in Florida and the will names an alternate or successor who is qualified to act in Florida, the alternate or successor shall be entitled to have letters issued. Otherwise, those entitled to a majority interest of the Florida property may have letters issued to a personal representative selected by them who is qualified to act in Florida. If the decedent dies intestate and the foreign personal representative is not qualified to act in Florida, the order of preference for appointment of a personal representative as prescribed in this code shall apply. If ancillary letters are applied for by other than the domiciliary personal representative, prior notice shall be given to any domiciliary personal representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ancillary administration shall be commenced as provided by the Florida Probate Rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the will and any codicils are executed as required by the code, they shall be admitted to probate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ancillary personal representative shall give bond as do personal representatives generally. All proceedings for appointment and administration of the estate shall be as similar to those in original administrations as possible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless creditors’ claims are otherwise barred by s. 733.710, the ancillary personal representative shall cause a notice to creditors to be served and published according to the requirements of chapter 733. Claims not filed in accordance with chapter 733 shall be barred as provided in s. 733.702.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the payment of all expenses of administration and claims against the estate, the court may order the remaining property held by the ancillary personal representative transferred to the foreign personal representative or distributed to the beneficiaries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ancillary personal representatives shall have the same rights, powers, and authority as other personal representatives in Florida to manage and settle estates; to sell, lease, or mortgage local property; and to raise funds for the payment of debts, claims, and devises in the domiciliary jurisdiction. No property shall be sold, leased, or mortgaged to pay a debt or claim that is barred by any statute of limitation or of nonclaim of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 98, ch. 75-220; s. 43, ch. 77-87; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1029, ch. 97-102; s. 171, ch. 2001-226.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 734.31.</Text></Note></Section>