<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0734.104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Foreign wills; admission to record; effect on title.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authenticated copy of the will of a nonresident that devises real property in this state, or any right, title, or interest in the property, may be admitted to record in any county of this state where the property is located at any time after 2 years from the death of the decedent or at any time after the domiciliary personal representative has been discharged if there has been no proceeding to administer the estate of the decedent in this state, provided:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The will was executed as required by chapter 732; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The will has been admitted to probate in the proper court of any other state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition to admit a foreign will to record may be filed by any person and shall be accompanied by authenticated copies of the foreign will, the petition for probate, and the order admitting the will to probate. If no petition is required as a prerequisite to the probate of a will in the jurisdiction where the will of the nonresident was probated, upon proof by affidavit or certificate that no petition is required, an authenticated copy of the will may be admitted to record without an authenticated copy of a petition for probate, and the order admitting the will to record in this state shall recite that no petition was required in the jurisdiction of original probate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that the requirements of this section have been met, it shall enter an order admitting the foreign will to record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When admitted to record, the foreign will shall be as valid and effectual to pass title to real property and any right, title, or interest therein as if the will had been admitted to probate in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 74-106; s. 98, ch. 75-220; s. 45, ch. 77-87; s. 229, ch. 77-104; s. 15, ch. 79-221; s. 274, ch. 79-400; s. 11, ch. 89-340; s. 173, ch. 2001-226.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 736.06.</Text></Note></Section>