<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0734.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Foreign personal representative.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal representatives who produce authenticated copies of probated wills or letters of administration duly obtained in any state or territory of the United States may maintain actions in the courts of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal representatives appointed in any state or country may be sued in this state concerning property in this state and may defend actions or proceedings brought in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Debtors who have not received a written demand for payment from a personal representative or curator appointed in this state within 90 days after appointment of a personal representative in any other state or country, and whose property in Florida is subject to a mortgage or other lien securing the debt held by the foreign personal representative, may pay the foreign personal representative after the expiration of 90 days from the date of appointment of the foreign personal representative. Thereafter, a satisfaction of the mortgage or lien executed by the foreign personal representative, with an authenticated copy of the letters or other evidence of authority attached, may be recorded in the public records. The satisfaction shall be an effective discharge of the mortgage or lien, irrespective of whether the debtor making payment had received a written demand before paying the debt.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 655.936, all persons indebted to the estate of a decedent, or having possession of personal property belonging to the estate, who have received no written demand from a personal representative or curator appointed in this state for payment of the debt or the delivery of the property are authorized to pay the debt or to deliver the personal property to the foreign personal representative after the expiration of 90 days from the date of appointment of the foreign personal representative.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 98, ch. 75-220; s. 1028, ch. 97-102; s. 170, ch. 2001-226; s. 110, ch. 2002-1; s. 16, ch. 2007-74.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 734.30.</Text></Note></Section>