<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0028.223" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Probate records; recordation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the circuit shall record all wills and codicils admitted to probate, orders revoking the probate of any wills and codicils, letters of administration, orders affecting or describing real property, final orders, orders of final discharge, and orders of guardianship filed in the clerk’s office. No other petitions, pleadings, papers, or other orders relating to probate matters shall be recorded except on the written direction of the court. The direction may be by incorporation in the order of the words “To be recorded,” or words to that effect. Failure to record an order or a judgment shall not affect its validity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk shall record all instruments under this section in Official Records and index them in the same manner as prescribed in s. 28.222.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All records of a court of this state heretofore exercising probate jurisdiction shall be placed, and remain, in the custody of the clerk and shall be the records of the circuit court. The circuit court may exercise judicial cognizance and power over them as it may over its own records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified transcripts of the whole or any part of probate or administration proceedings in any court of this state or of any foreign state or country may be recorded. If the certified copy is not a part of a pending probate proceeding in the court, the person causing it to be recorded shall pay the costs of recordation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recording of any instrument required or permitted to be recorded under this section in a pending probate or administration proceeding in the county shall be included in the fees prescribed in s. 28.2401.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 74-106; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 161, ch. 95-147; s. 20, ch. 95-401.</History></Section>