<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0028.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petitions and records of dissolution of marriage; additional charges.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a party petitions for a dissolution of marriage, in addition to the filing charges in s. 28.241, the clerk shall collect and receive:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charge of $5. On a monthly basis, the clerk shall transfer the moneys collected pursuant to this paragraph to the Department of Revenue for deposit in the Child Welfare Training Trust Fund created in s. 402.40.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charge of $5. On a monthly basis, the clerk shall transfer the moneys collected pursuant to this paragraph to the Department of Revenue for deposit in the Displaced Homemaker Trust Fund created in s. 446.50. If a petitioner does not have sufficient funds with which to pay this fee and signs an affidavit so stating, all or a portion of the fee shall be waived subject to a subsequent order of the court relative to the payment of the fee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charge of $55. On a monthly basis, the clerk shall transfer the moneys collected pursuant to this paragraph to the Department of Revenue for deposit in the Domestic Violence Trust Fund. Such funds which are generated shall be directed to the Department of Children and Family Services for the specific purpose of funding domestic violence centers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A charge of $32.50. On a monthly basis, the clerk shall transfer the moneys collected pursuant to this paragraph as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount of $7.50 to the Department of Revenue for deposit in the Displaced Homemaker Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount of $25 to the Department of Revenue for deposit in the General Revenue Fund.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a final judgment of dissolution of marriage for filing, and in addition to the filing charges in s. 28.241, the clerk may collect and receive a service charge of up to $10.50 pursuant to s. 382.023 for the recording and reporting of such final judgment of dissolution of marriage to the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 67-520; s. 2, ch. 70-134; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 1, ch. 73-300; s. 9, ch. 83-217; s. 103, ch. 86-220; s. 1, ch. 87-145; s. 25, ch. 87-387; s. 7, ch. 88-98; s. 2, ch. 88-181; s. 12, ch. 94-134; s. 12, ch. 94-135; s. 54, ch. 96-418; s. 82, ch. 97-237; s. 14, ch. 98-403; s. 13, ch. 99-2; s. 5, ch. 99-243; s. 4, ch. 2001-122; s. 25, ch. 2003-402; s. 3, ch. 2004-251; s. 14, ch. 2004-265.</History></Section>