<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0028.241" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filing fees for trial and appellate proceedings.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing fees are due at the time a party files a pleading to initiate a proceeding or files a pleading for relief. Reopen fees are due at the time a party files a pleading to reopen a proceeding if at least 90 days have elapsed since the filing of a final order or final judgment with the clerk. If a fee is not paid upon the filing of the pleading as required under this section, the clerk shall pursue collection of the fee pursuant to s. 28.246.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in sub-subparagraph b. and subparagraph 2., the party instituting any civil action, suit, or proceeding in the circuit court shall pay to the clerk of that court a filing fee of up to $395 in all cases in which there are not more than five defendants and an additional filing fee of up to $2.50 for each defendant in excess of five. Of the first $280 in filing fees, $80 must be remitted by the clerk to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund, $195 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the State Courts Revenue Trust Fund, $3.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission and used to fund the Florida Clerks of Court Operations Corporation created in s. 28.35, and $1.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Administrative Trust Fund within the Department of Financial Services to fund clerk budget reviews conducted by the Department of Financial Services. One third of any filing fees collected by the clerk of the circuit court in excess of $100 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The party instituting any civil action, suit, or proceeding in the circuit court under chapter 39, chapter 61, chapter 741, chapter 742, chapter 747, chapter 752, or chapter 753 shall pay to the clerk of that court a filing fee of up to $295 in all cases in which there are not more than five defendants and an additional filing fee of up to $2.50 for each defendant in excess of five. Of the first $180 in filing fees, $80 must be remitted by the clerk to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund, $95 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the State Courts Revenue Trust Fund, $3.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission and used to fund the Florida Clerks of Court Operations Corporation created in s. 28.35, and $1.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Administrative Trust Fund within the Department of Financial Services to fund clerk budget reviews conducted by the Department of Financial Services.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An additional filing fee of $4 shall be paid to the clerk. The clerk shall remit $3.50 to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Court Education Trust Fund and shall remit 50 cents to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission to fund clerk education. An additional filing fee of up to $18 shall be paid by the party seeking each severance that is granted. The clerk may impose an additional filing fee of up to $85 for all proceedings of garnishment, attachment, replevin, and distress. Postal charges incurred by the clerk of the circuit court in making service by certified or registered mail on defendants or other parties shall be paid by the party at whose instance service is made. Additional fees, charges, or costs may not be added to the filing fees imposed under this section, except as authorized in this section or by general law.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the fees prescribed in subparagraph 1., a party instituting a civil action in circuit court relating to real property or mortgage foreclosure shall pay a graduated filing fee based on the value of the claim.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party shall estimate in writing the amount in controversy of the claim upon filing the action. For purposes of this subparagraph, the value of a mortgage foreclosure action is based upon the principal due on the note secured by the mortgage, plus interest owed on the note and any moneys advanced by the lender for property taxes, insurance, and other advances secured by the mortgage, at the time of filing the foreclosure. The value shall also include the value of any tax certificates related to the property. In stating the value of a mortgage foreclosure claim, a party shall declare in writing the total value of the claim, as well as the individual elements of the value as prescribed in this sub-subparagraph.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In its order providing for the final disposition of the matter, the court shall identify the actual value of the claim. The clerk shall adjust the filing fee if there is a difference between the estimated amount in controversy and the actual value of the claim and collect any additional filing fee owed or provide a refund of excess filing fee paid.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The party shall pay a filing fee of:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three hundred and ninety-five dollars in all cases in which the value of the claim is $50,000 or less and in which there are not more than five defendants. The party shall pay an additional filing fee of up to $2.50 for each defendant in excess of five. Of the first $280 in filing fees, $275 must be remitted by the clerk to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund, $3.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission and used to fund the Florida Clerks of Court Operations Corporation created in s. 28.35, and $1.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Administrative Trust Fund within the Department of Financial Services to fund clerk budget reviews conducted by the Department of Financial Services;</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nine hundred dollars in all cases in which the value of the claim is more than $50,000 but less than $250,000 and in which there are not more than five defendants. The party shall pay an additional filing fee of up to $2.50 for each defendant in excess of five. Of the first $785 in filing fees, $780 must be remitted by the clerk to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund, $3.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission and used to fund the Florida Clerks of Court Operations Corporation described in s. 28.35, and $1.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Administrative Trust Fund within the Department of Financial Services to fund clerk budget reviews conducted by the Department of Financial Services; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One thousand nine hundred dollars in all cases in which the value of the claim is $250,000 or more and in which there are not more than five defendants. The party shall pay an additional filing fee of up to $2.50 for each defendant in excess of five. Of the first $1,785 in filing fees, $1,010 must be remitted by the clerk to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund, $770 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the State Courts Revenue Trust Fund, $3.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission to fund the Florida Clerks of Court Operations Corporation created in s. 28.35, and $1.50 must be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Administrative Trust Fund within the Department of Financial Services to fund clerk budget reviews conducted by the Department of Financial Services.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An additional filing fee of $4 shall be paid to the clerk. The clerk shall remit $3.50 to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Court Education Trust Fund and shall remit 50 cents to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Clerks of the Court Trust Fund within the Justice Administrative Commission to fund clerk education. An additional filing fee of up to $18 shall be paid by the party seeking each severance that is granted. The clerk may impose an additional filing fee of up to $85 for all proceedings of garnishment, attachment, replevin, and distress. Postal charges incurred by the clerk of the circuit court in making service by certified or registered mail on defendants or other parties shall be paid by the party at whose instance service is made. Additional fees, charges, or costs may not be added to the filing fees imposed under this section, except as authorized in this section or by general law.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party reopening any civil action, suit, or proceeding in the circuit court shall pay to the clerk of court a filing fee set by the clerk in an amount not to exceed $50. For purposes of this section, a case is reopened after all appeals have been exhausted or time to file an appeal from a final order or final judgment has expired. A reopen fee may be assessed by the clerk for any motion filed by any party at least 90 days after a final order or final judgment has been filed with the clerk in the initial case. A reservation of jurisdiction by a court does not cause a case to remain open for purposes of this section or exempt a party from paying a reopen fee. A party is exempt from paying the fee for any of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A writ of garnishment;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A writ of replevin;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A distress writ;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A writ of attachment;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motion for rehearing filed within 10 days;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motion for attorney’s fees filed within 30 days after entry of a judgment or final order;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motion for dismissal filed after a mediation agreement has been filed;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A disposition of personal property without administration;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any probate case prior to the discharge of a personal representative;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any guardianship pleading prior to discharge;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any mental health pleading;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motions to withdraw by attorneys;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motions exclusively for the enforcement of child support orders;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for credit of child support;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Notice of Intent to Relocate and any order issuing as a result of an uncontested relocation;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="16">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stipulations and motions to enforce stipulations;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="17">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Responsive pleadings; </Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="18">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cases in which there is no initial filing fee; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="19">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motions for contempt.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party in addition to a party described in sub-subparagraph (a)1.a. who files a pleading in an original civil action in circuit court for affirmative relief by cross-claim, counterclaim, counterpetition, or third-party complaint shall pay the clerk of court a fee of $395. A party in addition to a party described in sub-subparagraph (a)1.b. who files a pleading in an original civil action in circuit court for affirmative relief by cross-claim, counterclaim, counterpetition, or third-party complaint shall pay the clerk of court a fee of $295. The clerk shall remit the fee to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party in addition to a party described in subparagraph (a)2. who files a pleading in an original civil action in circuit court for affirmative relief by cross-claim, counterclaim, counterpetition, or third-party complaint shall pay the clerk of court a graduated fee of:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three hundred and ninety-five dollars in all cases in which the value of the pleading is $50,000 or less;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nine hundred dollars in all cases in which the value of the pleading is more than $50,000 but less than $250,000; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One thousand nine hundred dollars in all cases in which the value of the pleading is $250,000 or more.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The clerk shall remit the fees collected under this subparagraph to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of court shall collect a service charge of $10 for issuing an original, a certified copy, or an electronic certified copy of a summons. The clerk shall assess the fee against the party seeking to have the summons issued.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the institution of any appellate proceeding from any lower court to the circuit court of any such county, including appeals filed by a county or municipality as provided in s. 34.041(5), or from the circuit court to an appellate court of the state, the clerk shall charge and collect from the party or parties instituting such appellate proceedings a filing fee not to exceed $280 for filing a notice of appeal from the county court to the circuit court and, in addition to the filing fee required under s. 25.241 or s. 35.22, $100 for filing a notice of appeal from the circuit court to the district court of appeal or to the Supreme Court. If the party is determined to be indigent, the clerk shall defer payment of the fee. The clerk shall remit the first $80 to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A filing fee may not be imposed upon a party for responding by pleading, motion, or other paper to a civil or criminal action, suit, proceeding, or appeal in a circuit court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees prescribed in this section do not include the service charges required by law for the clerk as provided in s. 28.24 or by other sections of the Florida Statutes. Filing fees authorized by this section may not be added to any civil penalty imposed by chapter 316 or chapter 318.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing fees for the institution or reopening of any civil action, suit, or proceeding in county court shall be charged and collected as provided in s. 34.041.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From each attorney appearing pro hac vice, the clerk of the circuit court shall collect a fee of $100 for deposit into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section authorizes the assessment of a filing fee if the assessment is otherwise prohibited by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, ch. 26931, 1951; ss. 3, 4, 5, ch. 29749, 1955; ss. 1, 2, ch. 57-322; s. 1, ch. 63-47; s. 1, ch. 63-43; s. 6, ch. 70-134; s. 1, ch. 74-154; s. 4, ch. 75-124; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 3, ch. 77-284; s. 2, ch. 82-168; s. 2, ch. 82-205; s. 10, ch. 83-217; s. 122, ch. 86-220; s. 4, ch. 87-145; s. 1, ch. 87-231; s. 2, ch. 88-176; s. 6, ch. 89-290; s. 1, ch. 90-181; s. 69, ch. 90-271; s. 3, ch. 91-152; s. 162, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 96-209; s. 1, ch. 96-350; s. 14, ch. 96-354; s. 1, ch. 97-155; s. 12, ch. 99-277; s. 6, ch. 2001-122; s. 2, ch. 2002-55; ss. 31, 32, ch. 2003-402; s. 19, ch. 2004-265; s. 3, ch. 2006-245; s. 8, ch. 2008-111; ss. 5, 20, ch. 2009-61; s. 1, ch. 2009-204; s. 11, ch. 2010-162; s. 1, ch. 2011-133; s. 4, ch. 2012-100; s. 1, ch. 2012-138.</History>
</Section>