<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0028.2401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service charges and filing fees in probate matters.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except when otherwise provided, the clerk may impose service charges or filing fees for the following services or filings, not to exceed the following amounts:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for the opening of any estate of one document or more, including, but not limited to, petitions and orders to approve settlement of minor’s claims; to open a safe-deposit box; to enter rooms and places; for the determination of heirs, if not formal administration; and for a foreign guardian to manage property of a nonresident; but not to include issuance of letters or order of summary administration<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$230</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Charge for caveat<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$40</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for petition and order to admit foreign wills, authenticated copies, exemplified copies, or transcript to record<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$230</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for disposition of personal property without administration<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$230</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for summary administration<EmDash />estates valued at $1,000 or more<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$340</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for summary administration<EmDash />estates valued at less than $1,000<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$230</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for formal administration, guardianship, ancillary, curatorship, or conservatorship proceedings<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$395</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for guardianship proceedings of person only<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$230</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for veterans’ guardianship pursuant to chapter 744<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$230</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Charge for exemplified certificates<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$7</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fee for petition for determination of incompetency<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$230</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The clerk shall remit $115 of each filing fee collected under paragraphs (a), (c)-(i), and (k) to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the State Courts Revenue Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application by the clerk and a showing of extraordinary circumstances, the service charges or filing fees set forth in this section may be increased in an individual matter by order of the circuit court before which the matter is pending, to more adequately compensate for the services performed or filings made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An additional service charge of $4 on petitions seeking summary administration, formal administration, ancillary administration, guardianship, curatorship, and conservatorship shall be paid to the clerk. The clerk shall transfer $3.50 to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Court Education Trust Fund and shall transfer 50 cents to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Department of Financial Services’ Administrative Trust Fund to fund clerk education. No additional fees, charges, or costs shall be added to the service charges or filing fees imposed under this section, except as authorized by general law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recording shall be required for all petitions opening and closing an estate; petitions regarding real estate; and orders, letters, bonds, oaths, wills, proofs of wills, returns, and such other papers as the judge shall deem advisable to record or that shall be required to be recorded under the Florida Probate Code.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 1981, 1874; s. 2, ch. 3888, 1889; RS 1592, 1596; GS 2056, 2060; RGS 3347, 3351; CGL 5200, 5204; s. 1, ch. 19174, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 2877(115); s. 1, ch. 21960, 1943; s. 1, ch. 28152, 1953; s. 1, ch. 65-430; s. 1, ch. 72-397; s. 16, ch. 73-333; s. 2, ch. 77-284; s. 2, ch. 78-367; s. 13, ch. 79-400; s. 25, ch. 81-259; s. 3, ch. 87-145; s. 5, ch. 91-152; s. 1, ch. 93-268; s. 2, ch. 96-209; s. 5, ch. 2001-122; s. 29, ch. 2003-402; s. 2, ch. 2004-5; s. 17, ch. 2004-265; s. 7, ch. 2008-111; s. 4, ch. 2009-61.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 36.17.</Text></Note></Section>