<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0028.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Records; destruction; reproduction; electronic recordkeeping.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section and s. 28.31 is to make available for the use of the clerks of the circuit court of the several counties of the state sufficient space to enable them to efficiently administer the affairs of office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the circuit court of each county of the state is authorized to destroy and dispose of public records pursuant to the rules adopted by the Division of Library and Information Services of the Department of State pursuant to s. 257.36.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each clerk of the circuit court is authorized to photograph, microphotograph, or reproduce on film, or to maintain in an electronic recordkeeping system, any public record that the clerk may select. Such photographs, microphotographs, or other reproductions on film or reproductions from an electronic recordkeeping system shall be admissible in evidence with the same force and effect as the originals. Duly certified or authenticated reproductions of such photographs, microphotographs, reproductions on film, or reproductions from an electronic recordkeeping system shall be admitted in evidence equally with the original photographs, microphotographs, reproductions on film, or reproductions from an electronic recordkeeping system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clerk of the circuit court shall follow procedures for electronic recordkeeping in accordance with rules adopted by the Division of Library and Information Services of the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except when otherwise provided by law or applicable rule, a document that is submitted to the clerk of the circuit court by electronic transmission is deemed filed when the document is received and the date and time are acknowledged by the clerk, as opposed to the date and time of transmission. The clerk is not liable for malfunctions or errors occurring in the transmission of documents for filing by electronic means.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 25433, 1949; s. 8, ch. 69-82; s. 6, ch. 94-348.</History></Section>