<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.41" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of directors of district.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petitions to nominate candidates for directors of the watershed improvement district may be filed with the board of supervisors of the soil and water conservation district in which the watershed improvement district is situated. No such nominating petition shall be accepted by the board unless it is signed by at least 10 owners of land lying within the watershed improvement district or by a majority of such owners if there be less than 10. Such owners may sign more than one nominating petition to nominate more than one candidate for director. No person shall be eligible to be a director unless she or he is an owner of land within the watershed improvement district in which she or he seeks election.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after a watershed improvement district is established, the board of supervisors of the soil and water conservation district in which the watershed improvement district is situated, or the joint board if more than one district is affected, shall cause an election to be held for the election of a board of three directors of the watershed improvement district. Due notice of such election shall be given by the board to supervisors. At such election each owner of land lying within the watershed improvement district shall be entitled to cast one vote, in person or by proxy, for each acre or fractional part thereof of land within the watershed improvement district belonging to such owner, except that only one vote may be cast for each such acre or fractional part thereof regardless of whether the legal title thereto is held in single or multiple ownership. The three persons receiving the highest number of votes shall be declared elected as directors. The first board of directors shall determine by lot from among its membership one member to serve a term of 3 years, one member to serve a term of 2 years, and one member to serve a term of 1 year; thereafter, as these initial terms expire, the members of the board of directors shall be elected for terms of 3 years. Vacancies occurring before the expiration of a term shall be filled for the unexpired term by appointment by the remaining members of the board of directors with the approval of the board of supervisors. The board of directors shall, under the supervision of the board of supervisors, be the governing body of the watershed improvement district. The board of directors shall annually elect from its membership a chair and vice chair.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director shall receive compensation for her or his service at the rate of $10 per day for those days on which she or he renders services pursuant to this chapter. A director shall also be entitled to expenses in the same amount and extent as provided for public officers and employees of the state in s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 69-235; s. 930, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>