<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.19" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications and tenure of supervisors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of the district shall consist of five supervisors, elected as provided hereinabove.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisors shall designate a chair and may, from time to time, change such designation by majority vote. The term of office of each supervisor shall be 4 years, except that two supervisors shall be elected to serve for initial terms of 2 years, respectively, from the date of their election as provided in this chapter. A supervisor shall hold office until her or his successor has been elected and qualified. The selection of successors to fill an unexpired term shall be in accordance with s. 582.18(2). Selection for a full term in a newly created district shall be by election of the qualified electors of the district. A majority of the supervisors shall constitute a quorum and the concurrence of a majority of the supervisors in any matter within their duties shall be required for its determination. A supervisor shall receive no compensation for her or his services, but she or he shall, with approval of the supervisors of the district, be reimbursed for travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisors may utilize the services of the county agricultural agents and the facilities of the county agricultural agents’ offices insofar as practicable and feasible and may employ such additional employees and agents, permanent and temporary, as they may require, and determine their qualifications, duties and compensation. The supervisors may delegate to their chair, to one or more supervisors, or to one or more agents, or employees such powers and duties as they may deem proper. The supervisors shall furnish to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, upon request, copies of such rules, regulations, orders, contracts, forms and other documents as they shall adopt or employ, and such other information concerning their activities as it may require in the performance of its duties under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisors shall provide for the execution of surety bonds for all employees and officers who shall be entrusted with funds or property; shall provide for the keeping of a full and accurate record of all proceedings and of all resolutions, regulations, and others issued or adopted; and shall provide for an annual audit of the accounts of receipts and disbursements. Any supervisors may be removed by the Governor of this state upon notice and hearing, for neglect of duty or malfeasance in office, but for no other reason.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisors may invite the legislative body of any municipality or county located within or near the territory comprised within the district to designate a representative to advise and consult with the supervisors of the district on all questions of program and policy which may affect the property, water supply, or other interest of such municipality or county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 18144, 1937; s. 5, ch. 19473, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(478); s. 3, ch. 28094, 1953; s. 19, ch. 63-400; s. 3, ch. 67-207; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 74-53; s. 926, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>