<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hearing upon question of creation; notice, etc.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after such a petition has been filed with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, it shall cause due notice to be given of a proposed hearing upon the question of the desirability and necessity, in the interest of the public health, safety, and welfare, of the creation of such district, upon the question of the appropriate boundaries to be assigned to such district, upon the propriety of the petition and other proceedings taken under this chapter, and upon all questions relevant to such inquiries. All owners and occupiers of land within the limits of the territory described in the petition, and of lands within any territory considered for addition to such described territory, and all other interested parties, shall have the right to attend such hearings and to be heard. If it shall appear upon the hearing that it may be desirable to include within the proposed district territory outside of the area within which due notice of the hearing has been given, the hearing shall be adjourned and due notice of further hearing shall be given throughout the entire area considered for inclusion in the district and such further hearing held. After such hearing, if the department shall determine, upon the facts presented at such hearing and upon such other relevant facts and information as may be available that there is need, in the interest of the public health, safety, and welfare, for a soil and water conservation district to function in the territory considered at the hearing, it shall make and record such determination, and shall define, by metes and bounds or by legal subdivisions, the boundaries of such district. In making such determination and in defining such boundaries, the department shall give due weight and consideration to the topography of the area considered and of the state, the composition of soils therein, the distribution of erosion, the prevailing land use practices, the desirability and necessity of including within the boundaries the particular lands under consideration and the benefits such lands may receive from being included within such boundaries, the relation of the proposed area to existing watersheds and agricultural regions, and to other soil and water conservation districts already organized or proposed for organization under the provisions of this chapter, and such other physical, geographical, and economic factors as are relevant, having due regard to the legislative determinations set forth in this chapter. The territory to be included within such boundaries need not be contiguous. If the department shall determine after such hearing, after due consideration of the said relevant facts, that there is no need for a soil and water conservation district to function in the territory considered at the hearing, it shall make and record such determination and shall deny the petition. After 6 months shall have expired from the date of the denial of any such petition, subsequent petitions covering the same or substantially the same territory may be filed as aforesaid and new hearings held and determinations made thereon.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 18144, 1937; s. 3, ch. 19473, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(476); s. 3, ch. 67-207; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106.</History></Section>