<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.44" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Levy of taxes; procedure, etc.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of a district is authorized to levy annually a uniform ad valorem tax on all taxable property in the district as determined for county taxing purposes, not to exceed the amount necessary to provide the funds necessary for the purpose of maintaining, operating, and administering such district and obtaining necessary rights-of-way for the works of the district; however, such tax shall not exceed the rate of 3 mills on the dollar of the assessed value of such property or such rate approved by the qualified electors of the district pursuant to s. 582.36. The district shall be deemed a district within the purview of former ss. 193.03 and 193.031, whether within the purview and intention of such sections or not, for the purposes of the assessment, collection, and distribution of the taxes herein provided for. Upon the equalization of the county tax rolls, the governing board of the district shall be furnished with the same information furnished by the property appraiser to the taxing authorities of the county and taxing districts for use in determining the millages to be imposed by them. Upon the determination by the board of the taxing district of the millages to be imposed by it, it shall forthwith notify the boards of county commissioners of the counties wherein the district lies, who shall include such millages in their directives to the property appraisers. Upon receipt of these millages, the property appraisers shall impose and assess such taxes in the usual manner, to be collected and distributed in the usual manner. For purposes of taxation, the district shall be treated as a taxing district. Such district tax assessments shall be liens against the properties assessed as is provided for in s. 197.122. The taxes of the district, when distributed in the usual manner, shall be paid into the depository of the district to the credit of the district to be expended in the usual manner for like district. Expenditures from such funds shall be made with the approval of the board of supervisors of the soil and water conservation district or districts in which the watershed improvement district is situated on requisition by the chair or vice chair of the board of directors of the watershed improvement district.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 69-235; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 201, ch. 77-104; s. 36, ch. 82-226; s. 216, ch. 85-342; s. 931, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>