<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wherever used or referred to in this chapter unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District” or “soil conservation district” or “soil and water conservation district” means a governmental subdivision of this state, and a body corporate and politic, organized in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, for the purpose, with the powers, and subject to the provisions set forth in this chapter. The term “district” or “soil conservation district,” when used in this chapter, means and includes a “soil and water conservation district.” All districts heretofore or hereafter organized under this chapter shall be known as soil and water conservation districts and shall have all the powers set out herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supervisor” means one of the members of the governing body of a district, elected in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Council” means the Soil and Water Conservation Council.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commissioner” means Commissioner of Agriculture.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Landowner” or “owner of land” includes any person who shall hold legal or equitable title to any lands lying within a district organized under the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land occupier” or “occupier of land” includes any person, other than the owner, who shall be in possession of any lands lying within a district organized under the provisions of this chapter, whether as lessee, renter, tenant, or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified elector” includes any person qualified to vote in general elections under the constitution and statutes of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Due notice,” in addition to notice required pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120, means notice published at least twice, with an interval of at least 7 days between the two publication dates, in a newspaper or other publication of general circulation within the appropriate area or, if no such publication of general circulation be available, by posting at a reasonable number of conspicuous places within the appropriate area, such posting to include, where possible, posting at public places where it may be customary to post notices concerning county or municipal affairs generally. At any hearing held pursuant to such notice, at the time and place designated in such notice, adjournment may be made from time to time without the necessity of renewing such notice for such adjourned dates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrative officer” means the administrative officer of soil and water conservation created by s. 582.09.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 18144, 1937; s. 1, ch. 19473, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(474); s. 1, ch. 65-334; s. 1, ch. 67-207; s. 1, ch. 70-392; s. 1, ch. 74-53; s. 6, ch. 78-95; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-129; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 1, 3, 4, ch. 87-25; s. 5, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>