<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.34" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petition for establishment; provisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owners of the major portion of land lying within the limits of a proposed watershed improvement district may file a petition with the supervisors of the soil and water conservation district in which the proposed watershed improvement district is situated asking that a watershed improvement district be organized to function in the area described in the petition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed name of the watershed improvement district.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That there is need, in the interest of the public health, safety, and welfare for a watershed improvement district to function in the area described in the petition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the area proposed to be organized as a watershed improvement district, which description shall be deemed sufficient if generally accurate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the land within the area described in the petition is contiguous and is situated in the same watershed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum millage rate, including not more than 1 mill for maintenance, expressed in mills on each dollar of assessed valuation at which taxes may be levied for any 1 fiscal year for the purposes of the watershed improvement district or to amortize indebtedness or bonds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request that the area described in the petition be established as a watershed improvement district.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land lying within the limits of one watershed improvement district shall not be included in another watershed improvement district.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 69-235.</History></Section>