<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Referendum for creation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services has made and recorded a determination that there is need, in the interest of the public health, safety, and welfare, for the organization of a district in a particular territory and has defined the boundaries thereof, it shall consider the question whether the operation of a district within such boundaries with the powers conferred upon soil and water conservation districts in this chapter is administratively practicable and feasible. To assist the department in the determination of such administrative practicability and feasibility, the department, within a reasonable time after entry of the finding that there is need for the organization of the proposed district and the determination of the boundaries thereof, shall hold a referendum within the proposed district upon the proposition of the creation of the district, and cause due notice of such referendum to be given. The question shall be submitted by ballots upon which the words “For creation of a soil and water conservation district of the lands below described and lying in the County (ies) of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, (and) <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />” and “Against creation of a soil and water conservation district of the lands below described and lying in the County (ies) of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> (and) <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />” shall appear with a square before each proposition and a direction to insert an X mark in the square before one or the other of said propositions as the voter may favor or oppose creation of such district. The ballot shall set forth the boundaries of such proposed district as determined by the department. All owners of lands lying within the boundaries of the territory, as determined by the department, shall be eligible to vote in such referendum. Only such landowners shall be eligible to vote.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 18144, 1937; s. 3, ch. 19473, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(476); s. 3, ch. 67-207; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106.</History></Section>