<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Adoption of land use regulations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisors of any district shall have authority to formulate regulations governing the use of lands within the district in the interest of conserving soil and soil resources, and preventing and controlling soil erosion. The supervisors may conduct such public meetings and public hearings upon tentative regulations as may be necessary to assist them in this work. The supervisors shall not have authority to adopt such land use regulations until after they shall have caused due notice to be given of their intention to conduct a referendum for submission of such regulations to the owners of lands lying within the boundaries of the district, for their indication of approval or disapproval of such proposed regulations, and until after the supervisors have considered the result of such referendum. Copies of such proposed regulations shall be available for the inspection of all eligible voters during the period between publication of such notice and the date of the referendum. The notices of the referendum shall recite the contents of such proposed regulations, or shall state where copies of such proposed regulations may be examined. The question shall be submitted by ballots, upon which the words “For approval of proposed land use regulations for the conservation of soil and prevention of erosion” and “Against approval of proposed land use regulations for conservation of soil and prevention of erosion” shall appear, with a square before each proposition and a direction to insert an X mark in the square before one or the other of said propositions as the voter may favor or oppose approval of such proposed regulations. The supervisors shall supervise such referendum, shall prescribe appropriate regulations governing the conduct thereof, and shall publish the result thereof. All owners of lands within the district shall be eligible to vote in such referendum. Only such landowners shall be eligible to vote. No informalities in the conduct of such referendum or in any matters relating thereto shall invalidate said referendum or the result thereof if notice thereof shall have been given substantially as herein provided and said referendum shall have been fairly conducted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervisors shall not adopt such proposed regulations unless at least a majority of the votes cast in such referendum shall have been cast for approval of the said proposed regulations. The approval of the proposed regulations by a majority of the votes cast in such referendum shall not be deemed to require the supervisors to adopt such proposed regulations. Land use regulations adopted pursuant to the provisions of this section by the supervisors of any district shall be binding and obligatory upon all owners and occupiers of land within such districts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Land use regulations adopted pursuant to the provisions of this section shall not be amended, supplemented, or repealed except in accordance with the procedure prescribed in this section for adoption of land use regulations. Referenda of adoption, amendment, supplementation, or repeal of land use regulations shall not be held more often than once in 6 months.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 18144, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(480); s. 6, ch. 78-95.</History></Section>