<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0582.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of soil and water conservation districts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any 10 percent of owners of land lying within the limits of the territory proposed to be organized into a district may file a petition with the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, asking that a soil and water conservation district be organized to function in the territory described in the petition. Such petition shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed name of said district.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That there is need, in the interest of the public health, safety, and welfare, for a soil and water conservation district to function in the territory described in the petition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the territory proposed to be organized as a district, which description shall not be required to be given by metes and bounds or by legal subdivisions, but shall be deemed sufficient if generally accurate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request that the department duly define the boundaries for such district; that a referendum be held within the territory so defined on the question of the creation of a soil and water conservation district in such territory; and that the department determine that such a district be created.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where more than one petition is filed covering parts of the same territory the department may consolidate all or any petitions.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 18144, 1937; s. 3, ch. 19473, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(476); s. 3, ch. 67-207; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 2003-97.</History></Section>