<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0823.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Places and groups engaged in criminal gang-related activity declared a nuisance; may be abated and enjoined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever shall erect, establish, continue, or maintain, own or lease any building, booth, tent or place which tends to annoy the community or injure the health of the community, or become manifestly injurious to the morals or manners of the people as described in s. 823.01, or any house or place of prostitution, assignation, lewdness or place or building where games of chance are engaged in violation of law or any place where any law of the state is violated, shall be deemed guilty of maintaining a nuisance, and the building, erection, place, tent or booth and the furniture, fixtures, and contents are declared a nuisance. All such places or persons shall be abated or enjoined as provided in ss. 60.05 and 60.06.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the terms “criminal gang,” “criminal gang member,” “criminal gang associate,” and “criminal gang-related activity” have the same meanings as provided in s. 874.03.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A criminal gang, criminal gang member, or criminal gang associate who engages in the commission of criminal gang-related activity is a public nuisance. Any and all such persons shall be abated or enjoined as provided in ss. 60.05 and 60.06.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of a location on two or more occasions by a criminal gang, criminal gang members, or criminal gang associates for the purpose of engaging in criminal gang-related activity is a public nuisance. Such use of a location as a public nuisance shall be abated or enjoined as provided in ss. 60.05 and 60.06.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this subsection shall prevent a local governing body from adopting and enforcing laws consistent with this chapter relating to criminal gangs and gang violence. Where local laws duplicate or supplement this chapter, this chapter shall be construed as providing alternative remedies and not as preempting the field.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state, through the Department of Legal Affairs or any state attorney, or any of the state’s agencies, instrumentalities, subdivisions, or municipalities having jurisdiction over conduct in violation of a provision of this chapter may institute civil proceedings under this subsection. In any action brought under this subsection, the circuit court shall proceed as soon as practicable to the hearing and determination. Pending final determination, the circuit court may at any time enter such injunctions, prohibitions, or restraining orders, or take such actions, including the acceptance of satisfactory performance bonds, as the court may deem proper.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 7367, 1917; RGS 5639; CGL 7832; s. 24, ch. 57-1; s. 66, ch. 74-383; s. 1, ch. 75-24; s. 41, ch. 75-298; s. 4, ch. 2008-238.</History></Section>