<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0410.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Multidisciplinary center on elderly living environments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURPOSE.<EmDash />The necessity for ongoing information on housing and living arrangements needed by the elderly mandates that there should be a central effort to produce data on the subject and, based on the data collected, to develop plans for meeting such current and future needs in the State of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Reference Number="1" />BOARD OF REGENTS’ RESPONSIBILITIES.<EmDash />In order to ensure continuing sound programs on housing and living arrangements for the elderly, the <Reference Number="1" />Board of Regents shall develop a proposal and establish a multidisciplinary center on independent housing and other living environments for the elderly at one or more of the state universities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACTIVITIES.<EmDash />Each multidisciplinary center established pursuant to this section shall consist of a collaboration of academic disciplines including programs in architecture, anthropology, gerontology, economics, geography, law, medicine, psychology, and sociology to meet the following objectives:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a centralized state resource for identification, collection, analysis, and distribution of information on elderly living environments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as the catalyst for identification and promotion of necessary research on elderly living environments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop cooperation and collaboration with both public and private agencies and organizations, educational centers and programs, and individuals throughout the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide opportunities for professional development.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop models for elderly living environments.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL REPORTS.<EmDash />Each multidisciplinary center established by the <Reference Number="1" />Board of Regents shall submit a report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 1, 1989, and by January 1 of each year thereafter. These annual reports shall include information relating to the activities of the center, including collaborative efforts with community and academic organizations, statewide data on the housing related needs of the elderly, and findings and recommendations from research projects relating to housing of the elderly.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 88-376.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abolished by s. 3, ch. 2001-170.</Text></Note></Section>