<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0410.502" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Housing and living arrangements; special needs of the elderly; services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs shall provide services related to housing and living arrangements which meet the special needs of the elderly. Such services shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing counseling concerning housing problems and alternate living arrangements when appropriate to the individual’s needs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinating with the Department of Economic Opportunity to gather and maintain data on living arrangements which meet the special needs of the elderly and to disseminate such information to the public. Such information shall include types of facilities, cost of care, services provided, and possible sources of help in meeting the cost of care for indigent individuals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting, through the Department of Elderly Affairs staff activities and area agencies on aging, the development of a variety of living arrangements through public and private auspices to meet the various needs and desires of the elderly, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Foster homes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisted living facilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Homes for special services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shared housing or other such group living arrangements for independent living.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continuing care facilities which offer all levels of care, including independent living units, personal care, home health care supports, and skilled nursing home care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retirement communities for independent communal living, to be developed in conjunction with the Department of Economic Opportunity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other innovative living arrangements.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Demonstration projects must be used advisedly to test the extent to which these and other innovative housing and living arrangements do meet the basic and special needs of the elderly.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 86-192; s. 34, ch. 95-210; s. 195, ch. 99-8; s. 304, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>