<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0739.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delivery or filing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsections (2) through (12), delivery of a disclaimer may be effected by personal delivery, first-class mail, or any other method that results in its receipt. A disclaimer sent by first-class mail shall be deemed to have been delivered on the date it is postmarked. Delivery by any other method shall be effective upon receipt by the person to whom the disclaimer is to be delivered under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer of an interest created under the law of intestate succession or an interest created by will, other than an interest in a testamentary trust:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclaimer must be delivered to the personal representative of the decedent’s estate; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no personal representative is serving when the disclaimer is sought to be delivered, the disclaimer must be filed with the clerk of the court in any county where venue of administration would be proper.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer of an interest in a testamentary trust:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclaimer must be delivered to the trustee serving when the disclaimer is delivered or, if no trustee is then serving, to the personal representative of the decedent’s estate; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no personal representative is serving when the disclaimer is sought to be delivered, the disclaimer must be filed with the clerk of the court in any county where venue of administration of the decedent’s estate would be proper.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer of an interest in an inter vivos trust:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclaimer must be delivered to the trustee serving when the disclaimer is delivered;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no trustee is then serving, it must be filed with the clerk of the court in any county where the filing of a notice of trust would be proper; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the disclaimer is made before the time the instrument creating the trust becomes irrevocable, the disclaimer must be delivered to the grantor of the revocable trust or the transferor of the interest or to such person’s legal representative.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer of an interest created by a beneficiary designation made before the time the designation becomes irrevocable, the disclaimer must be delivered to the person making the beneficiary designation or to such person’s legal representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer of an interest created by a beneficiary designation made after the time the designation becomes irrevocable, the disclaimer must be delivered to the person obligated to distribute the interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer by a surviving holder of jointly held property, or by the surviving tenant in property held as a tenancy by the entirety, the disclaimer must be delivered to the person to whom the disclaimed interest passes or, if such person cannot reasonably be located by the disclaimant, the disclaimer must be delivered as provided in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer by an object, or taker in default of exercise, of a power of appointment at any time after the power was created:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclaimer must be delivered to the holder of the power or to the fiduciary acting under the instrument that created the power; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no fiduciary is serving when the disclaimer is sought to be delivered, the disclaimer must be filed with a court having authority to appoint the fiduciary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer by an appointee of a nonfiduciary power of appointment:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclaimer must be delivered to the holder, the personal representative of the holder’s estate, or the fiduciary under the instrument that created the power; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no fiduciary is serving when the disclaimer is sought to be delivered, the disclaimer must be filed with a court having authority to appoint the fiduciary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer by a fiduciary of a power over a trust or estate, the disclaimer must be delivered as provided in subsection (2), subsection (3), or subsection (4) as if the power disclaimed were an interest in property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a disclaimer of a power exercisable by an agent, other than a power exercisable by a fiduciary over a trust or estate, the disclaimer must be delivered to the principal or the principal’s representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), delivery of a disclaimer of an interest in or relating to real estate shall be presumed upon the recording of the disclaimer in the office of the clerk of the court of the county or counties where the real estate is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fiduciary or other person having custody of the disclaimed interest is not liable for any otherwise proper distribution or other disposition made without actual notice of the disclaimer or, if the disclaimer is barred under s. 739.402, for any otherwise proper distribution or other disposition made in reliance on the disclaimer, if the distribution or disposition is made without actual knowledge of the facts constituting the bar of the right to disclaim.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-108.</History></Section>