<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0739.104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Power to disclaim; general requirements; when irrevocable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may disclaim, in whole or in part, conditionally or unconditionally, any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment. A person may disclaim the interest or power even if its creator imposed a spendthrift provision or similar restriction on transfer or a restriction or limitation on the right to disclaim. A disclaimer shall be unconditional unless the disclaimant explicitly provides otherwise in the disclaimer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With court approval, a fiduciary may disclaim, in whole or part, any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment, except that a disclaimer of a power arising under s. 739.201(4) does not require court approval. Without court approval, a fiduciary may disclaim, in whole or in part, any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment, if and to the extent that the instrument creating the fiduciary relationship explicitly grants the fiduciary the right to disclaim. In the absence of a court-appointed guardian, notwithstanding anything in chapter 744 to the contrary, without court approval, a natural guardian under s. 744.301 may disclaim on behalf of a minor child of the natural guardian, in whole or in part, any interest in or power over property, including a power of appointment, which the minor child is to receive solely as a result of another disclaimer, but only if the disclaimed interest or power does not pass to or for the benefit of the natural guardian as a result of the disclaimer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be effective, a disclaimer must be in writing, declare the writing as a disclaimer, describe the interest or power disclaimed, and be signed by the person making the disclaimer and witnessed and acknowledged in the manner provided for deeds of real estate to be recorded in this state. In addition, for a disclaimer to be effective, an original of the disclaimer must be delivered or filed in the manner provided in s. 739.301.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A partial disclaimer may be expressed as a fraction, percentage, monetary amount, term of years, limitation of a power, or any other interest or estate in the property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A disclaimer becomes irrevocable when any conditions to which the disclaimant has made the disclaimer subject are satisfied and when the disclaimer is delivered or filed pursuant to s. 739.301 or it becomes effective as provided in ss. 739.201-739.207, whichever occurs later.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A disclaimer made under this chapter is not a transfer, assignment, or release.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-108; s. 103, ch. 2006-1; s. 14, ch. 2009-115.</History></Section>