<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0739.202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclaimer of rights of survivorship in jointly held property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the death of a holder of jointly held property:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the deceased holder’s lifetime, the deceased holder could have unilaterally regained a portion of the property attributable to the deceased holder’s contributions without the consent of any other holder, another holder may disclaim, in whole or in part, a fractional share of that portion of the property attributable to the deceased holder’s contributions determined by dividing the number one by the number of joint holders alive immediately after the death of the holder to whose death the disclaimer relates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all other jointly held property, another holder may disclaim, in whole or in part, a fraction of the whole of the property the numerator of which is one and the denominator of which is the product of the number of joint holders alive immediately before the death of the holder to whose death the disclaimer relates multiplied by the number of joint holders alive immediately after the death of the holder to whose death the disclaimer relates.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A disclaimer under subsection (1) takes effect as of the death of the holder of jointly held property to whose death the disclaimer relates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An interest in jointly held property disclaimed by a surviving holder of the property passes as if the disclaimant predeceased the holder to whose death the disclaimer relates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2005-108.</History></Section>