<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0860.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Outboard motors; identification numbers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall adopt rules specifying the locations and manner in which serial numbers for outboard motors shall be affixed. In adopting such rules, the department shall consider the adequacy of voluntary industry standards, the current state of technology, and the overall purpose of reducing vessel and motor thefts in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any outboard motor manufactured after October 1, 1985, which is for sale in the state shall comply with the serial number rules promulgated by the department. Any person, firm, or corporation which sells or offers for sale any outboard boat motor manufactured after October 1, 1985, which does not comply with this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to possess any outboard boat motor with the knowledge that the serial number required by subsection (1) has been removed, erased, defaced, or otherwise altered to prevent identification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to knowingly possess, manufacture, sell or exchange, offer to sell or exchange, supply in blank, or give away any counterfeit manufacturer’s outboard motor serial number plate or decal used for the purpose of identification of any outboard motor; to authorize, direct, aid in exchange, or give away such counterfeit manufacturer’s outboard motor serial number plate or decal; or to conspire to do any of the foregoing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the serial numbers required by this section to identify ownership of an outboard motor do not exist or have been removed, erased, defaced, or otherwise altered to prevent identification and its true identity cannot be determined, the outboard motor may be seized as contraband property by a law enforcement agency and shall be subject to forfeiture pursuant to ss. 932.701-932.704. Such outboard motor may not be sold or used to propel a vessel on the waters of the state unless the department is directed by written order of a court of competent jurisdiction to issue to the outboard motor a replacement identifying number which shall be affixed to the outboard motor and shall thereafter be used for identification purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 83-102; s. 1, ch. 84-129; s. 2, ch. 86-73; s. 476, ch. 94-356; s. 125, ch. 2002-20.</History></Section>