<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0860.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Operation of aircraft while intoxicated or in careless or reckless manner; penalty.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To operate an aircraft in the air or on the ground or water while under the influence of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alcoholic beverages;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any substance controlled under chapter 893;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any chemical substance set forth in s. 877.111; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To operate an aircraft in the air or on the ground or water in a careless or reckless manner so as to endanger the life or property of another.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any prosecution charging careless or reckless operation of aircraft in violation of this section, the court, in determining whether the operation was careless or reckless, shall consider the standards for safe operation of aircraft as prescribed by federal statutes or regulations governing aeronautics.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of this section shall constitute a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of any court in which there is a conviction for violation of this statute to report such conviction to the Federal Aviation Administration for its guidance and information with respect to the pilot’s certificate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1-4, ch. 25259, 1949; s. 1096, ch. 71-136; ss. 1, 2A, ch. 71-282; s. 32, ch. 73-331; s. 5, ch. 83-187; s. 15, ch. 2010-117.</History>
</Section>