<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0604.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties; injunctive relief; administrative fines.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dealer in agricultural products who violates the provisions of ss. 604.15-604.34, or who interferes with an agent of the department in the enforcement of ss. 604.15-604.34, is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, and for a second or subsequent offense is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the remedies provided in this chapter and notwithstanding the existence of any adequate remedy at law, when the department has probable cause to believe that any person, partnership, corporation, or other business entity has violated any provision of this chapter or any rule adopted pursuant thereto, the department may issue and deliver to such person, partnership, corporation, or other business entity a notice to cease and desist from such violation. For the purpose of enforcing a cease and desist order, the department may file a proceeding in the name of the state seeking issuance of an injunction or writ of mandamus against any person, partnership, corporation, or other business entity who violates any provisions of such order, and such injunction shall be issued without bond.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the penalties provided in this section, the department may, after notice and hearing, impose a fine not exceeding $2,500 for the violation of any of the provisions of ss. 604.15-604.34 or the rules adopted thereunder against any dealer in agricultural products; such fine, when imposed and paid, shall be deposited by the department into the General Inspection Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any administrative order has been made and entered by the department imposing a fine pursuant to this subsection, the order shall specify the amount of the fine and a time limit of no more than 15 days for the payment thereof. Upon the failure of the dealer involved to pay the fine within that time, the dealer’s license as dealer in agricultural products shall be subject to suspension or revocation and a fine not to exceed $100 a day shall be imposed on the dealer while the dealer is in violation of such order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 20678, 1941; s. 3, ch. 23812, 1947; s. 29, ch. 29737, 1955; s. 4, ch. 57-139; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 632, ch. 71-136; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 12, 14, ch. 79-238; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 5, ch. 84-347; s. 8, ch. 85-36; ss. 6, 9, 10, ch. 90-161; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1001, ch. 97-103; s. 10, ch. 2005-206.</History></Section>