<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0604.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application; form; contents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every dealer in agricultural products desiring to transact business within the state directly with a Florida producer, a producer’s agent or representative, or a negotiating broker shall, prior to transacting any business as such, file an application for such license with the department. The license shall be renewed annually on its anniversary date. The application shall be on a form furnished by the department and, together with such other information as the department shall require, shall state:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The kind or kinds of agricultural products the applicant proposes to handle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name or title of the person, partnership, corporation, or other business entity and the name and mailing address of each owner, partner, officer, or managing agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of buyers or other local agents of the applicant, if any.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cities and towns within which places of business of the applicant will be located, together with the street or mailing address of each.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The federal employer’s identification number of the applicant, if any.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary mailing address and physical address for each place of business. A dealer in agricultural products must have on file with the department the address of the dealer’s primary place of business prior to engaging in business as a dealer in agricultural products in this state. Prior to changing the address of the primary place of business, the dealer must notify the department of the address of the new primary place of business. All documents relating to the provisions of ss. 604.15-604.34 and chapter 120 shall be served to the last address of record; to a corporation’s registered agent or the registered agent’s substitute; in the absence of a registered agent, to an owner, officer, partner, employee, or managing agent of the business entity; or as designated by the applicant in the applicant’s application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dollar amount of business done by a renewal applicant with Florida producers and their agents or representatives during the month in which the maximum dollar amount of agricultural products was purchased or handled as a dealer in agricultural products or the dollar amount of business estimated to be done by a first-time applicant with Florida producers and their agents or representatives during the month in which the estimated maximum dollar amount of agricultural products will be purchased or handled as a dealer in agricultural products.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 20678, 1941; s. 1, ch. 61-412; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 5, 12, 14, ch. 79-238; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 9, 10, ch. 90-161; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 2005-206.</History></Section>