<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0604.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited agricultural association; articles of association, name.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of association shall be subscribed by three or more persons, and shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the association and the location of the principal place of business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose for which the association is formed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term for which the association is to exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By what officers the business, or businesses, of the association is to be conducted, and the names of the officers who are to conduct the business, or businesses, until their successors shall have qualified. Officers shall be members of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number, to be not less than three, of the association’s managing committee members. Managing committee members shall be members of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fact that the members are not to be held personally liable for any of the claims against or the indebtedness and obligations of the association.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the proposed association shall be different from that of any other limited agricultural association in the state and shall include the words “Limited Agricultural Association,” or the letters “LAA,” to indicate that it is a limited agricultural association as distinguished from a natural person, firm, copartnership or corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 20620, 1941; s. 994, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>