<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Building Code Administrators and Inspectors Board.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Business and Professional Regulation the Florida Building Code Administrators and Inspectors Board. Members shall be appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. Members shall be appointed for 4-year terms. No member shall serve more than two consecutive 4-year terms, nor serve for more than 11 years on the board. To ensure continuity of board policies, the Governor shall initially appoint one member for a 1-year term, two members for 2-year terms, two members for 3-year terms, and two members for 4-year terms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall consist of nine members, as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is an architect licensed pursuant to chapter 481, an engineer licensed pursuant to chapter 471, or a contractor licensed pursuant to chapter 489.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members serving as building code administrators.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members serving as building code inspectors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member serving as a plans examiner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member who is a representative of a city or a charter county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two consumer members who are not, and have never been, members of a profession regulated under this part, chapter 481, chapter 471, or chapter 489. One of the consumer members must be a person with a disability or a representative of an organization which represents persons with disabilities.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">None of the board members described in paragraph (a) or paragraph (f) may be an employee of a municipal, county, or state governmental agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 93-166; s. 51, ch. 94-119; s. 150, ch. 94-218; s. 3, ch. 98-419; s. 128, ch. 2000-153; s. 14, ch. 2000-372.</History></Section>