<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.209" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant applying for a license as an occupational therapist or as an occupational therapy assistant shall file a written application, accompanied by the application for licensure fee prescribed in s. 468.221, on forms provided by the department, showing to the satisfaction of the board that she or he:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is of good moral character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed the academic requirements of an educational program in occupational therapy recognized by the board, with concentration in biologic or physical science, psychology, and sociology, and with education in selected manual skills. Such a program shall be accredited by the American Occupational Therapy Association’s Accreditation Council for Occupational Therapy Education, or its successor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed a period of supervised fieldwork experience at a recognized educational institution or a training program approved by the educational institution where she or he met the academic requirements. For an occupational therapist, a minimum of 6 months of supervised fieldwork experience is required. For an occupational therapy assistant, a minimum of 2 months of supervised fieldwork experience is required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed an examination conducted or adopted by the board as provided in s. 468.211.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant who has practiced as a state-licensed or American Occupational Therapy Association-certified occupational therapy assistant for 4 years and who, prior to January 24, 1988, completed a minimum of 6 months of supervised occupational-therapist-level fieldwork experience may take the examination to be licensed as an occupational therapist without meeting the educational requirements for occupational therapists made otherwise applicable under paragraph (1)(b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board determines that an applicant is qualified to be licensed by endorsement under s. 468.213, the board may issue the applicant a temporary permit to practice occupational therapy until the next board meeting at which license applications are to be considered, but not for a longer period of time. Only one temporary permit by endorsement shall be issued to an applicant, and it shall not be renewable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board determines that the applicant has not passed an examination, which examination is recognized by the board, to determine competence to practice occupational therapy and is not qualified to be licensed by endorsement, but has otherwise met all the requirements of this section and has made application for the next scheduled examination, the board may issue the applicant a temporary permit allowing her or him to practice occupational therapy under the supervision of a licensed occupational therapist until notification of the results of the examination. An individual who has passed the examination may continue to practice occupational therapy under her or his temporary permit until the next meeting of the board. An individual who has failed the examination shall not continue to practice occupational therapy under her or his temporary permit; and such permit shall be deemed revoked upon notification to the board of the examination results and the subsequent, immediate notification by the board to the applicant of the revocation. Only one temporary permit by examination shall be issued to an applicant, and it shall not be renewable. However, applicants enrolled in a full-time advanced master’s occupational therapy education program who have completed all requirements for licensure except examination shall, upon written request, be granted a temporary permit valid for 6 months even if that period extends beyond the next examination, provided the applicant has not failed the examination. This permit shall remain valid only while the applicant remains a full-time student and, upon written request, shall be renewed once for an additional 6 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant seeking reentry into the profession who has not been in active practice within the last 5 years must, prior to applying for licensure, submit to the board documentation of continuing education as prescribed by rule.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 75-179; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 2, ch. 78-18; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 12, 13, ch. 84-4; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 277, ch. 97-103; s. 125, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>