<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.525" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each controlling person licensed by the department shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be of good moral character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have the education, managerial, or business experience to successfully operate or be a controlling person of an employee leasing company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, “good moral character” means a personal history of honesty, trustworthiness, fairness, a good reputation for fair dealings, and respect for the rights of others and for the laws of this state and nation. A thorough background investigation of the individual’s good moral character shall be instituted by the department. Such investigation shall require:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The submission of fingerprints, for processing through appropriate law enforcement agencies, by the applicant and the examination of police records by the board.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other investigation of the individual as the board may deem necessary.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may deny an application for licensure or renewal citing lack of good moral character. Conviction of a crime within the last 7 years shall not automatically bar any applicant or licensee from obtaining a license or continuing as a licensee. The board shall consider the type of crime committed, the crime’s relevancy to the employee leasing industry, the length of time since the conviction and any other factors deemed relevant by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employee leasing company licensed by the department shall have a registered agent for service of process in this state and at least one licensed controlling person. In addition, each licensed employee leasing company shall comply with the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employment relationship with workers provided by the employee leasing company to a client company shall be established by written agreement between the leasing company and the client, and written notice of that relationship shall be given by the employee leasing company to each worker who is assigned to perform services at the client company’s worksite.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for an initial employee leasing company license shall have a tangible accounting net worth of not less than $50,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for initial or renewal license of an employee leasing company license or employee leasing company group shall have an accounting net worth or shall have guaranties, letters of credit, or other security acceptable to the board in sufficient amounts to offset any deficiency. A guaranty will not be acceptable to satisfy this requirement unless the applicant submits sufficient evidence to satisfy the board that the guarantor has adequate resources to satisfy the obligation of the guaranty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employee leasing company shall maintain an accounting net worth and positive working capital, as determined in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, or shall have guaranties, letters of credit, or other security acceptable to the board in sufficient amounts to offset any deficiency. A guaranty will not be acceptable to satisfy this requirement unless the licensee submits sufficient evidence, as defined by rule, that the guarantor has adequate resources to satisfy the obligation of the guaranty. In determining the amount of working capital, a licensee shall include adequate reserves for all taxes and insurance, including plans of self-insurance or partial self-insurance for claims incurred but not paid and for claims incurred but not reported. Compliance with the requirements of this paragraph is subject to verification by department or board audit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employee leasing company or employee leasing company group shall submit annual financial statements audited by an independent certified public accountant, with the application and within 120 days after the end of each fiscal year, in a manner and time prescribed by the board, provided however, that any employee leasing company or employee leasing company group with gross Florida payroll of less than $2.5 million during any fiscal year may submit financial statements reviewed by an independent certified public accountant for that year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall notify the department or board in writing within 30 days after any change in the application or status of the license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employee leasing company or employee leasing company group shall maintain accounting and employment records relating to all employee leasing activities for a minimum of 3 calendar years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee leasing company’s contractual arrangements with its client companies shall satisfy the following conditions, whereby the leasing company:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves a right of direction and control over leased employees assigned to the client’s location. However, a client may retain such sufficient direction and control over the leased employees as is necessary to conduct the client’s business and without which the client would be unable to conduct its business, discharge any fiduciary responsibility that it may have, or comply with any applicable licensure, regulatory, or statutory requirement of the client.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assumes responsibility for the payment of wages to the leased employees without regard to payments by the client to the leasing company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assumes full responsibility for the payment of payroll taxes and collection of taxes from payroll on leased employees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retains authority to hire, terminate, discipline, and reassign the leased employees. However, the client company may have the right to accept or cancel the assignment of any leased employee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retains a right of direction and control over management of safety, risk, and hazard control at the worksite or sites affecting its leased employees, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Responsibility for performing safety inspections of client equipment and premises.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Responsibility for the promulgation and administration of employment and safety policies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Responsibility for the management of workers’ compensation claims, claims filings, and related procedures.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has given written notice of the relationship between the employee leasing company and the client company to each leased employee it assigns to perform services at the client’s worksite.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 7, 17, ch. 91-93; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 37, ch. 94-119; s. 20, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>