<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.617" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Joint building code inspection department; other arrangements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part shall prohibit any local jurisdiction, school board, community college board, state university, or state agency from entering into and carrying out contracts with any other local jurisdiction or educational board under which the parties agree to create and support a joint building code inspection department for conforming to the provisions of this part. In lieu of a joint building code inspection department, any local jurisdiction may designate a building code inspector from another local jurisdiction to serve as a building code inspector for the purposes of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part shall prohibit local governments, school boards, community college boards, state universities, or state agencies from contracting with persons certified pursuant to this part to perform building code inspections or plan reviews. An individual or entity may not inspect or examine plans on projects in which the individual or entity designed or permitted the projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part shall prohibit any county or municipal government, school board, community college board, state university, or state agency from entering into any contract with any person or entity for the provision of building code inspection services regulated under this part, and notwithstanding any other statutory provision, such county or municipal governments may enter into contracts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part prohibits any building code inspector, plans examiner, or building code administrator holding a limited certificate who is employed by a jurisdiction within a small county as defined in s. 339.2818 from providing building code inspection, plans review, or building code administration services to another jurisdiction within a small county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 93-166; s. 3, ch. 96-298; s. 73, ch. 96-388; s. 5, ch. 98-419; s. 35, ch. 2000-141; s. 17, ch. 2000-372; s. 2, ch. 2007-227.</History></Section>