<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.621" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the disciplinary actions in subsection (2) may be taken:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating or failing to comply with any provision of this part, or a valid rule or lawful order of the board or department pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining certification through fraud, deceit, or perjury.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly assisting any person practicing contrary to the provisions of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The building code adopted by the enforcement authority of that person.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been convicted of a felony against this state or the United States, or of a felony in another state that would have been a felony had it been committed in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been convicted of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of building code administration or inspection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record that the certificateholder knows to be false, or knowingly inducing another to file a false report or record, or knowingly failing to file a report or record required by state or local law, or knowingly impeding or obstructing such filing, or knowingly inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to properly enforce applicable building codes or permit requirements within this state which the certificateholder knows are applicable or committing willful misconduct, gross negligence, gross misconduct, repeated negligence, or negligence resulting in a significant danger to life or property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuing a building permit to a contractor, or any person representing himself or herself as a contractor, without obtaining the contractor’s certificate or registration number, where such a certificate or registration is required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to lawfully execute the duties and responsibilities specified in this part and ss. 553.73, 553.781, 553.79, and 553.791.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing building code inspection services under s. 553.791 without satisfying the insurance requirements of that section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obstructing an investigation or providing or inducing another to provide forged documents, false forensic evidence, or false testimony to a local or state board or member thereof or to a licensing investigator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accepting labor, services, or materials at no charge or at a noncompetitive rate from any person who performs work that is under the enforcement authority of the enforcement official and who is not an immediate family member of the enforcement official. The term “immediate family member” includes a spouse, child, parent, sibling, grandparent, aunt, uncle, or first cousin of the person or the person’s spouse or any person who resides in the primary residence of the enforcement official.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board finds any person guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of an application for certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permanent revocation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suspension of a certificate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $5,000 for each separate offense. Such fine must be rationally related to the gravity of the violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the certificateholder on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the board may impose, including alteration of performance level.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfactory completion of continuing education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a citation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where a certificate is suspended, placed on probation, or has conditions imposed, the board shall reinstate the certificate of a disciplined building code administrator, plans examiner, or building code inspector upon proof the disciplined individual has complied with all terms and conditions set forth in the final order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may be allowed to apply for certification under this part for a minimum of 5 years after the date of revocation of any certificate issued pursuant to this part. The board may by rule establish additional criteria for certification following revocation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 93-166; s. 9, ch. 98-287; s. 8, ch. 99-254; s. 9, ch. 99-386; s. 118, ch. 2000-141; s. 19, ch. 2000-372; s. 35, ch. 2001-186; s. 4, ch. 2001-372; s. 3, ch. 2005-147; s. 2, ch. 2005-216; s. 4, ch. 2007-227.</History></Section>