<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0468.832" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the disciplinary actions in subsection (2) may be taken:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of this part or s. 455.227(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to procure a license to practice home inspection services by bribery or fraudulent misrepresentation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice home inspection services revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction that directly relates to the practice of home inspection services or the ability to practice home inspection services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record that the licensee knows to be false, willfully failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports or records shall include only those that are signed in the capacity of a licensed home inspector.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner that is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in fraud or deceit, or negligence, incompetency, or misconduct, in the practice of home inspection services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a licensed home inspector; violating any provision of this chapter, a rule of the department, or a lawful order of the department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing; or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing on a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to meet any standard of practice adopted by rule of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department finds any home inspector guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of an application for licensure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $5,000 for each count or separate offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the home inspector on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the department may specify.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restriction of the authorized scope of practice by the home inspector.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other sanction imposed under this part, in any final order that imposes sanctions, the department may assess costs related to the investigation and prosecution of the case.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2007-235; s. 123, ch. 2008-4; s. 51, ch. 2009-195; ss. 21, 43, ch. 2010-106; s. 13, ch. 2010-176.</History>
</Section>