<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.368" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part may not be construed to prevent or restrict the practice, service, or activities of:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person licensed in this state by any other law from engaging in the profession or occupation for which he or she is licensed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any legally qualified person in the state or another state or territory who is employed by the United States Government or any agency thereof while such person is discharging his or her official duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A friend or family member who is providing respiratory care services to an ill person and who does not represent himself or herself to be a respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual providing respiratory care services in an emergency who does not represent himself or herself as a respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual employed to deliver, assemble, set up, or test equipment for use in a home, upon the order of a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459. This subsection does not, however, authorize the practice of respiratory care without a license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual certified or registered as a pulmonary function technologist who is credentialed by the National Board for Respiratory Care for performing cardiopulmonary diagnostic studies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any student who is enrolled in an accredited respiratory care program approved by the board, while performing respiratory care as an integral part of a required course.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery of incidental respiratory care to noninstitutionalized persons by surrogate family members who do not represent themselves as registered or certified respiratory care therapists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual credentialed by the Underseas Hyperbaric Society in hyperbaric medicine or its equivalent as determined by the board, while performing related duties. This subsection does not, however, authorize the practice of respiratory care without a license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 84-252; s. 10, ch. 86-60; s. 6, ch. 87-553; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 297, ch. 97-103; s. 143, ch. 97-264; s. 3, ch. 2004-299.</History></Section>