<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.516" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Practice requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee under this part shall not implement a dietary plan for a condition for which the patient is under the active care of a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459, without the oral or written dietary order of the referring physician. In the event the licensee is unable to obtain authorization or consultation after a good faith effort to obtain it from the physician, the licensee may use professional discretion in providing nutrition services until authorization or consultation is obtained from the physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall refer a patient to a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 upon the recognition of a condition within the scope of practice as authorized under chapter 458 or chapter 459, unless the patient has been referred by or is currently being treated by a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee under this part shall not implement a dietary plan for a chiropractic condition for which the patient is under the active care of a chiropractic physician licensed under chapter 460, without the oral or written dietary order of the referring chiropractic physician. In the event the licensee is unable to obtain authorization or consultation after a good faith effort to obtain it from the chiropractic physician, the licensee may use professional discretion in providing nutrition services until authorization or consultation is obtained from the chiropractic physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall refer a patient to a chiropractic physician licensed under chapter 460 upon the recognition of a condition within the scope of practice as authorized under chapter 460, unless the patient has been referred or is currently being treated by a chiropractic physician licensed under chapter 460.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 16, 20, ch. 88-236; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 17, ch. 96-367.</History></Section>