<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.603" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building code administrator” or “building official” means any of those employees of municipal or county governments with building construction regulation responsibilities who are charged with the responsibility for direct regulatory administration or supervision of plan review, enforcement, or inspection of building construction, erection, repair, addition, remodeling, demolition, or alteration projects that require permitting indicating compliance with building, plumbing, mechanical, electrical, gas, fire prevention, energy, accessibility, and other construction codes as required by state law or municipal or county ordinance. This term is synonymous with “building official” as used in the administrative chapter of the Standard Building Code and the South Florida Building Code. One person employed by each municipal or county government as a building code administrator or building official and who is so certified under this part may be authorized to perform any plan review or inspection for which certification is required by this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building code inspector” means any of those employees of local governments or state agencies with building construction regulation responsibilities who themselves conduct inspections of building construction, erection, repair, addition, or alteration projects that require permitting indicating compliance with building, plumbing, mechanical, electrical, gas, fire prevention, energy, accessibility, and other construction codes as required by state law or municipal or county ordinance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Florida Building Code Administrators and Inspectors Board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate” means a certificate of qualification issued by the department as provided in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Categories of building code inspectors” include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine that buildings and structures are constructed in accordance with the provisions of the governing building codes and state accessibility laws.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Coastal construction inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine that buildings and structures are constructed to resist near-hurricane and hurricane velocity winds in accordance with the provisions of the governing building code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial electrical inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine the electrical safety of commercial buildings and structures by inspecting for compliance with the provisions of the National Electrical Code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residential electrical inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine the electrical safety of one and two family dwellings and accessory structures by inspecting for compliance with the applicable provisions of the governing electrical code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mechanical inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine that the mechanical installations and systems for buildings and structures are in compliance with the provisions of the governing mechanical code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plumbing inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine that the plumbing installations and systems for buildings and structures are in compliance with the provisions of the governing plumbing code.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“One and two family dwelling inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine that one and two family dwellings and accessory structures are constructed in accordance with the provisions of the governing building, plumbing, mechanical, accessibility, and electrical codes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electrical inspector” means a person who is qualified to inspect and determine the electrical safety of commercial and residential buildings and accessory structures by inspecting for compliance with the provisions of the National Electrical Code.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plans examiner” means a person who is qualified to determine that plans submitted for purposes of obtaining building and other permits comply with the applicable building, plumbing, mechanical, electrical, gas, fire prevention, energy, accessibility, and other applicable construction codes. Categories of plans examiners include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building plans examiner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plumbing plans examiner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mechanical plans examiner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electrical plans examiner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Building code enforcement official” or “enforcement official” means a licensed building code administrator, building code inspector, or plans examiner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 93-166; s. 50, ch. 94-119; s. 149, ch. 94-218; s. 1, ch. 98-419; s. 12, ch. 2000-372.</History></Section>