<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.518" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for disciplinary action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this part, any board or agency rule adopted pursuant thereto, or any lawful order of the board or agency previously entered in a disciplinary hearing held pursuant to this part, or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the agency. The provisions of this paragraph also apply to any order or subpoena previously issued by the Department of Health during its period of regulatory control over this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to engage in dietetics and nutrition practice or nutrition counseling with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness or use of alcohol, drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other type of material or as a result of any mental or physical condition.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee whose license is suspended or revoked pursuant to this paragraph shall, at reasonable intervals, be given an opportunity to demonstrate that he or she can resume the competent practice of dietetics and nutrition or nutrition counseling with reasonable skill and safety to patients.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the record of the proceeding nor the orders entered by the board in any proceeding under this paragraph may be used against a licensee in any other proceeding.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to procure or procuring a license to practice dietetics and nutrition or nutrition counseling by fraud or material misrepresentation of material fact.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice dietetics and nutrition or nutrition counseling revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure by the licensing authority of another state, district, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of dietetics and nutrition or nutrition counseling or the ability to practice dietetics and nutrition or nutrition counseling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record that the licensee knows to be false, willfully failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports or records include only those that are signed in the capacity of a licensed dietitian/nutritionist or licensed nutrition counselor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner that is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing an act of fraud or deceit, or of negligence, incompetency, or misconduct in the practice of dietetics and nutrition or nutrition counseling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing with a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Treating or undertaking to treat human ailments by means other than by dietetics and nutrition practice or nutrition counseling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to maintain acceptable standards of practice as set forth by the board and the council in rules adopted pursuant to this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging directly or indirectly in the dividing, transferring, assigning, rebating, or refunding of fees received for professional services, or profiting by means of a credit or other valuable consideration, such as an unearned commission, discount, or gratuity, with any person referring a patient or with any relative or business associate of the referring person. Nothing in this part prohibits the members of any regularly and properly organized business entity that is composed of licensees under this part and recognized under the laws of this state from making any division of their total fees among themselves as they determine necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising, by or on behalf of a licensee under this part, any method of assessment or treatment which is experimental or without generally accepted scientific validation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall reissue the license of a disciplined dietitian/nutritionist or nutrition counselor upon certification by the board that the disciplined dietitian/nutritionist or nutrition counselor has complied with all of the terms and conditions set forth in the final order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 18, 20, ch. 88-236; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 205, ch. 94-119; s. 19, ch. 96-367; s. 94, ch. 98-166; s. 41, ch. 2001-277; s. 17, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>