<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.45615" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Provision of illegal inducements to athletes prohibited; penalties; license suspension.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates s. 468.456(1)(f) is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, s. 775.084, s. 775.089, or s. 775.091.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regardless of whether adjudication is withheld, any person convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, the violation described in subsection (1) shall not employ, utilize, or otherwise collaborate with a licensed or unlicensed athlete agent in Florida to illegally recruit or solicit student athletes. Any person who violates the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, s. 775.084, s. 775.089, or s. 775.091.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regardless of whether adjudication is withheld, any person who knowingly actively assists in the illegal recruitment or solicitation of student athletes for a person who has been convicted or found guilty of, or entered a plea of nolo contendere to, a violation of this section is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, s. 775.084, s. 775.089, or s. 775.091.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalties provided in this section, the court may suspend the license of the person pending the outcome of any administrative action against the person by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An athlete agent, with the intent to induce a student athlete to enter into an agent contract, may not:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give any materially false or misleading information or make a materially false promise or representation;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnish anything of value to a student athlete before the student athlete enters into the agent contract; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnish anything of value to any individual other than the student athlete or another athlete agent.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An athlete agent may not intentionally:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate contact with a student athlete unless licensed under this part;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refuse or fail to retain or permit inspection of the records required to be retained by s. 468.4565;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide materially false or misleading information in an application for licensure;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Predate or postdate an agent contract;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to give notice of the existence of an agent contract as required by s. 468.454(6); or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to notify a student athlete before the student athlete signs or otherwise authenticates an agent contract for a sport that the signing or authentication may make the student athlete ineligible to participate as a student athlete in that sport.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An athlete agent who violates this subsection commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 70, ch. 2000-356; s. 5, ch. 2002-24.</History></Section>