<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.389" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts shall be grounds for the disciplinary activities provided in subsections (2) and (3):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of any law relating to trade or commerce of this state or of the state in which an auction is conducted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresentation of property for sale at auction or making false promises concerning the use, value, or condition of such property by an auctioneer or auction business or by anyone acting as an agent of or with the consent of the auctioneer or auction business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to account for or to pay or return, within a reasonable time not to exceed 30 days, money or property belonging to another which has come into the control of an auctioneer or auction business through an auction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">False, deceptive, misleading, or untruthful advertising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any conduct in connection with a sales transaction which demonstrates bad faith or dishonesty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using or permitting the use of false bidders, cappers, or shills.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making any material false statement on a license application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commingling money or property of another person with his or her own. Every auctioneer and auction business shall maintain a separate trust or escrow account in an insured bank or savings and loan association located in this state in which shall be deposited all proceeds received for another person through an auction sale.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal or neglect of any auctioneer or other receiver of public moneys to pay the moneys so received into the State Treasury at the times and under the regulations prescribed by law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a statute or administrative rule regulating practice under this part or a lawful disciplinary order of the board or the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice a comparable profession revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against by another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice or the ability to practice the profession of auctioneering.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board finds any person guilty of any of the prohibited acts set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to certify to the department an application for licensure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each count or separate offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the auctioneer on probation for a period of time and subject to conditions as the board may specify, including requiring the auctioneer to successfully complete the licensure examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirement that the person in violation make restitution to each consumer affected by that violation. Proof of such restitution shall be a signed and notarized release executed by the consumer or the consumer’s estate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to pay a fine within a reasonable time, as prescribed by board rule, may be grounds for disciplinary action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may file for an injunction or bring any other appropriate civil action against anyone who violates this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 14, ch. 86-119; s. 8, ch. 87-210; s. 62, ch. 91-137; s. 11, ch. 91-156; ss. 6, 16, ch. 91-207; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 19, ch. 94-119; s. 11, ch. 97-94; s. 303, ch. 97-103; s. 14, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>