<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.223" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice occupational therapy unless such person is licensed pursuant to ss. 468.201-468.225;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use, in connection with his or her name or place of business, the words “occupational therapist,” “licensed occupational therapist,” “occupational therapist registered,” “occupational therapy assistant,” “licensed occupational therapy assistant,” “certified occupational therapy assistant”; the letters “O.T.,” “L.O.T.,” “O.T.R.,” “O.T.A.,” “L.O.T.A.,” or “C.O.T.A.”; or any other words, letters, abbreviations, or insignia indicating or implying that he or she is an occupational therapist or an occupational therapy assistant or, in any way, orally or in writing, in print or by sign, directly or by implication, to represent himself or herself as an occupational therapist or an occupational therapy assistant unless the person is a holder of a valid license issued pursuant to ss. 468.201-468.225;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as his or her own the license of another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly give false or forged evidence to the board or a member thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a license which has been suspended, revoked, or placed on inactive or delinquent status;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ unlicensed persons to engage in the practice of occupational therapy; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conceal information relative to any violation of ss. 468.201-468.225.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 75-179; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 12, 13, ch. 84-4; s. 3, ch. 90-22; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 196, ch. 94-119; s. 281, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>