<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.8095" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Practitioner and resident identification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee or person registered with the department shall post a license or registration and a recent photograph of the licensee or registrant at each facility where patients are seen by the licensee or registrant in a manner determined by the board by rule. This requirement does not extend to areas where the licensee or registrant may visit and normally does not treat patients. The posted license or registration must be valid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee or person registered with the department shall post in close proximity to the posted license or registration a notice stating the department’s Consumer Services Unit address, Internet website, and telephone number. The notice shall state that a patient may file a complaint of unlicensed or substandard practice by contacting the Consumer Services Unit. A single notice may be used for multiple licensees or registrants in a facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During patient contact, each licensee or person registered with the department shall prominently wear an identification tag or badge with the name, recent photograph, and license or registration number, as applicable, of the licensee or registrant. The size and appearance of the identification tag or badge shall be determined by the board by rule. Persons licensed in more than one practice field under this part may list both license numbers. Licensees or registrants working in facilities requiring the wearing of a specific identification tag may substitute the identification tag or badge required by this subsection with the facility’s design as determined by the board.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2008-121.</History></Section>