<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.719" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary actions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to include the athletic trainer’s name and license number in any advertising, including, but not limited to, business cards and letterhead, related to the practice of athletic training. Advertising shall not include clothing or other novelty items.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing incompetency or misconduct in the practice of athletic training.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing fraud or deceit in the practice of athletic training.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing negligence, gross negligence, or repeated negligence in the practice of athletic training.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While practicing athletic training, being unable to practice athletic training with reasonable skill and safety to athletes by reason of illness or use of alcohol or drugs or as a result of any mental or physical condition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 95-388; s. 103, ch. 98-166; s. 7, ch. 99-349; s. 137, ch. 99-397; s. 161, ch. 2000-160; s. 27, ch. 2000-318; s. 42, ch. 2001-277; s. 18, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>