<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.524" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employee leasing company and each controlling person required to be licensed shall file with the department a complete written application accompanied by a nonrefundable application fee not to exceed $250. Each employee leasing company and employee leasing company group application must list on the application each owner who has an interest of 10 percent or more in the company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may require information and certifications necessary to determine that the applicant is of good moral character and meets other licensure requirements of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for licensure of an employee leasing company group that qualifies for group licensure must contain the information required by this section for each member of the group.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant or licensee is ineligible to reapply for a license for a period of 1 year following final agency action on the denial or revocation of a license applied for or issued under this part. This time restriction does not apply to administrative denials or revocations entered because:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or licensee has made an inadvertent error or omission on the application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The experience documented to the board was insufficient at the time of the previous application;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is unable to complete the criminal background investigation because of insufficient information from the Florida Department of Law Enforcement, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or any other applicable law enforcement agency;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or licensee has failed to submit required fees; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant or licensed employee leasing company has been deemed ineligible for a license because of the lack of good moral character of an individual or individuals when such individual or individuals are no longer employed in a capacity that would require their licensing under this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 6, 17, ch. 91-93; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 35, ch. 94-119.</History></Section>