<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.309" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certificate; duration; renewal; reversion to inactive status; members of Armed Forces and spouses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate issued in accordance with this part expires as specified in rules adopted by the department which establish a procedure for the biennial renewal of certificates. A certificate shall be renewed by the department for a period of 2 years upon payment of a renewal fee in an amount not to exceed $75 and upon submission of a renewal application containing such information as the department deems necessary to show that the applicant for renewal is a certificateholder in good standing and has completed any continuing education requirements that the department establishes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sixty days before the end of the biennium, the department shall mail a notice of renewal to the last known address of the certificateholder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each certificateholder shall notify the department in writing of his or her current mailing address and place of practice. Notwithstanding any other law, service by regular mail to a certificateholder’s last reported mailing address constitutes adequate and sufficient notice of any official departmental communication to the certificateholder.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing a procedure for the biennial renewal of certificates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, by rule, prescribe continuing education requirements, not to exceed 24 hours each licensure period, as a condition for renewal of a certificate. The criteria for approval of continuing education providers, courses, and programs shall be as specified by the department. Continuing education, which may be required for persons certified under this part, may be obtained through home study courses approved by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any certificate that is not renewed by its expiration date shall automatically be placed in an expired status, and the certificateholder may not practice radiologic technology or perform the duties of a radiologist assistant until the certificate has been reactivated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificateholder in good standing remains in good standing when he or she becomes a member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty without paying renewal fees or accruing continuing education credits as long as he or she is a member of the Armed Forces on active duty and for a period of 6 months after discharge from active duty, if he or she is not engaged in practicing radiologic technology or performing the duties of a radiologist assistant in the private sector for profit. The certificateholder must pay a renewal fee and complete continuing education not to exceed 12 classroom hours to renew the certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificateholder who is in good standing remains in good standing if he or she is absent from the state because of his or her spouse’s active duty with the Armed Forces of the United States. The certificateholder remains in good standing without paying renewal fees or completing continuing education as long as his or her spouse is a member of the Armed Forces on active duty and for a period of 6 months after the spouse’s discharge from active duty, if the certificateholder is not engaged in practicing radiologic technology or performing the duties of a radiologist assistant in the private sector for profit. The certificateholder must pay a renewal fee and complete continuing education not to exceed 12 classroom hours to renew the certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificateholder may resign his or her certification by submitting to the department a written, notarized resignation on a form specified by the department. The resignation automatically becomes effective upon the department’s receipt of the resignation form, at which time the certificateholder’s certification automatically becomes null and void and may not be reactivated or renewed or used to practice radiologic technology or to perform the duties of a radiologist assistant. A certificateholder who has resigned may become certified again only by reapplying to the department for certification as a new applicant and meeting the certification requirements pursuant to s. 468.304 or s. 468.3065. Any disciplinary action that had been imposed on the certificateholder prior to his or her resignation shall be tolled until he or she again becomes certified. Any disciplinary action proposed at the time of the certificateholder’s resignation shall be tolled until he or she again becomes certified.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 78-383; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 18, 19, ch. 84-269; s. 8, ch. 88-310; s. 4, ch. 91-145; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 287, ch. 97-103; s. 59, ch. 99-397; s. 43, ch. 2004-350; s. 8, ch. 2006-139.</History></Section>