<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dietetics” means the integration and application of the principles derived from the sciences of nutrition, biochemistry, food, physiology, and management and from the behavioral and social sciences to achieve and maintain a person’s health throughout the person’s life. It is an integral part of preventive, diagnostic, curative, and restorative health care of individuals, groups, or both.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dietetics and nutrition practice” shall include assessing nutrition needs and status using appropriate data; recommending appropriate dietary regimens, nutrition support, and nutrient intake; improving health status through nutrition research, counseling, and education; and developing, implementing, and managing nutrition care systems, which includes, but is not limited to, evaluating, modifying, and maintaining appropriate standards of high quality in food and nutrition care services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dietetic technician” means a person who assists in the provision of dietetic and nutrition services under the supervision of a qualified professional.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed dietitian/nutritionist” means a person licensed pursuant to s. 468.509.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed nutrition counselor” means a person licensed pursuant to s. 468.51.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nutrition assessment” means the evaluation of the nutrition needs of individuals or groups, using appropriate data to determine nutrient needs or status and make appropriate nutrition recommendations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nutrition counseling” means advising and assisting individuals or groups on appropriate nutrition intake by integrating information from the nutrition assessment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preprofessional experience component” means a planned and continuous supervised practice experience in dietetics or nutrition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registered dietitian” means an individual registered with the Commission on Dietetic Registration, the accrediting body of the American Dietetic Association.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 20, ch. 88-236; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 144, ch. 94-218; s. 3, ch. 96-367.</History></Section>