<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.531" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person or entity shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice or offer to practice as an employee leasing company, an employee leasing company group, or a controlling person unless such person or entity is licensed pursuant to this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice or offer to practice as an employee leasing company or employee leasing company group unless all controlling persons thereof are licensed pursuant to this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the name or title “licensed employee leasing company,” “employee leasing company,” “employee leasing company group,” “professional employer,” “professional employer organization,” “controlling person,” or words that would tend to lead one to believe that such person or entity is registered pursuant to this part, when such person or entity has not registered pursuant to this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as his or her own or his or her entity’s own the license of another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly give false or forged evidence to the board or a member thereof; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a license that has been suspended or revoked.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity that violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 17, ch. 91-93; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 44, ch. 94-119; s. 310, ch. 97-103; s. 22, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>