<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0468.1695" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by examination.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed as a nursing home administrator shall apply to the department to take the licensure examination. The examination shall be given at least two times a year and shall include, but not be limited to, questions on the subjects of nursing home administration such as:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicable standards of nursing home health and safety;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal, state, and local health and safety laws and rules;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General administration;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Psychology of patient care;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Principles of medical care;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal and social care;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Therapeutic and supportive care and services in long-term care;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Departmental organization and management;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community interrelationships; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminology.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The board may, by rule, adopt use of a national examination in lieu of part or all of the examination required by this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall examine each applicant who the board certifies has completed the application form and remitted an examination fee set by the board not to exceed $250 and who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a baccalaureate degree from an accredited college or university and majored in health care administration, health services administration, or an equivalent major, or has credit for at least 60 semester hours in subjects, as prescribed by rule of the board, which prepare the applicant for total management of a nursing home; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has fulfilled the requirements of a college-affiliated or university-affiliated internship in nursing home administration or of a 1,000-hour nursing home administrator-in-training program prescribed by the board; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a baccalaureate degree from an accredited college or university; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has fulfilled the requirements of a 2,000-hour nursing home administrator-in-training program prescribed by the board; or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has 1 year of management experience allowing for the application of executive duties and skills, including the staffing, budgeting, and directing of resident care, dietary, and bookkeeping departments within a skilled nursing facility, hospital, hospice, assisted living facility with a minimum of 60 licensed beds, or geriatric residential treatment program and, if such experience is not in a skilled nursing facility, has fulfilled the requirements of a 1,000-hour nursing home administrator-in-training program prescribed by the board.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license to practice nursing home administration to any applicant who successfully completes the examination in accordance with this section and otherwise meets the requirements of this part. The department shall not issue a license to any applicant who is under investigation in this state or another jurisdiction for an offense which would constitute a violation of s. 468.1745 or s. 468.1755. Upon completion of the investigation, the provisions of s. 468.1755 shall apply.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may by rule establish a preceptor certification and recertification fee not to exceed $100 which shall be remitted by those individuals seeking board approval to act as preceptors in administrator-in-training programs as prescribed by the board. Said fee may be charged at the time of application for initial certification and at the time of application for recertification. The board may by rule establish a trainee application fee not to exceed $500 to defray the costs of the board’s supervision of the administrator-in-training program, to be remitted by those individuals seeking to undergo a board prescribed administrator-in-training program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-227; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 13, 14, 16, 17, ch. 86-223; s. 17, ch. 88-205; s. 68, ch. 89-374; s. 23, ch. 90-134; s. 3, ch. 90-345; s. 61, ch. 91-137; s. 10, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 31, ch. 92-173; s. 5, ch. 93-259; s. 193, ch. 94-119; s. 40, ch. 95-210; s. 122, ch. 97-264; s. 25, ch. 99-394; s. 125, ch. 2000-153; s. 84, ch. 2001-277; s. 43, ch. 2012-160.</History>
</Section>