<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.432" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure of community association managers and community association management firms; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person shall not manage or hold herself or himself out to the public as being able to manage a community association in this state unless she or he is licensed by the department in accordance with the provisions of this part. However, nothing in this part prohibits any person licensed in this state under any other law or court rule from engaging in the profession for which she or he is licensed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As of January 1, 2009, a community association management firm or other similar organization responsible for the management of more than 10 units or a budget of $100,000 or greater shall not engage or hold itself out to the public as being able to engage in the business of community association management in this state unless it is licensed by the department as a community association management firm in accordance with the provisions of this part.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community association management firm or other similar organization desiring to be licensed as a community association management firm shall apply to the department on a form approved by the department, together with the application and licensure fees required by s. 468.435(1)(a) and (c). Each community association management firm applying for licensure under this subsection must be actively registered and authorized to do business in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant shall designate on its application a licensed community association manager who shall be required to respond to all inquiries from and investigations by the department or division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed community association management firm shall notify the department within 30 days after any change of information contained in the application upon which licensure is based.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community association management firm licenses shall expire on September 30 of odd-numbered years and shall be renewed every 2 years. An application for renewal shall be accompanied by the renewal fee as required by s. 468.435(1)(d).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall license each applicant whom the department certifies as meeting the requirements of this subsection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the license of at least one individual active community association manager member is not in force, the license of the community association management firm or other similar organization is canceled automatically during that time.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any community association management firm or other similar organization agrees by being licensed that it will employ only licensed persons in the direct provision of community association management services as described in s. 468.431(3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 14, ch. 87-343; s. 2, ch. 89-155; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 4, ch. 96-291; s. 1114, ch. 97-103; s. 3, ch. 2008-28; s. 58, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>