<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.311" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Violations; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each of the following acts constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing radiologic technology or performing the duties of a radiologist assistant without holding an active certificate to do so.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using or attempting to use a certificate which has been suspended or revoked.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The willful practice of radiologic technology or the willful performance of the duties of a radiologist assistant by a student without a direct supervisor being present.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly allowing a student to practice radiologic technology or perform the duties of a radiologist assistant without a direct supervisor being present.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining or attempting to obtain a certificate under this part through bribery or fraudulent misrepresentation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using any name or title specified in s. 468.302(2) or any other name or title which implies that a person is certified to practice radiologic technology or to perform the duties of a radiologist assistant, unless such person is duly certified as provided in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly concealing information relating to the enforcement of this part or rules adopted pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employing, for the purpose of applying ionizing radiation to, or otherwise practicing radiologic technology or any of the duties of a radiologist assistant on, any human being, any individual who is not certified under the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 78-383; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 12, 18, 19, ch. 84-269; s. 98, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 11, ch. 2006-139.</History></Section>