<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.217" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Denial of or refusal to renew license; suspension and revocation of license and other disciplinary measures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to obtain, obtaining, or renewing a license to practice occupational therapy by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentation, or through an error of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice occupational therapy revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of occupational therapy or to the ability to practice occupational therapy. A plea of nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction for the purposes of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">False, deceptive, or misleading advertising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising, practicing, or attempting to practice under a name other than one’s own name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department any person who the licensee knows is in violation of this part or of the rules of the department or of the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, or advising any unlicensed person to practice occupational therapy contrary to this part or to a rule of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a licensed occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing or inducing another person to do so. Such reports or records include only those which are signed in the capacity as a licensed occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying or receiving any commission, bonus, kickback, or rebate to or from, or engaging in any split-fee arrangement in any form whatsoever with, a physician, organization, agency, or person, either directly or indirectly, for patients referred to providers of health care goods and services, including, but not limited to, hospitals, nursing homes, clinical laboratories, ambulatory surgical centers, or pharmacies. The provisions of this paragraph shall not be construed to prevent an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant from receiving a fee for professional consultation services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence within a patient-therapist relationship for purposes of engaging a patient in sexual activity. A patient is presumed to be incapable of giving free, full, and informed consent to sexual activity with the patient’s occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making deceptive, untrue, or fraudulent representations in the practice of occupational therapy or employing a trick or scheme in the practice of occupational therapy if such scheme or trick fails to conform to the generally prevailing standards of treatment in the occupational therapy community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soliciting patients, either personally or through an agent, through the use of fraud, intimidation, undue influence, or a form of overreaching or vexatious conduct. A “solicitation” is any communication which directly or implicitly requests an immediate oral response from the recipient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to keep written records justifying the course of treatment of the patient, including, but not limited to, patient histories, examination results, and test results.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on the patient or client in such a manner as to exploit the patient or client for financial gain of the licensee or of a third party which includes, but is not limited to, the promoting or selling of services, goods, appliances, or drugs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing professional services which have not been duly authorized by the patient or client, or his or her legal representative, except as provided in s. 768.13.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross or repeated malpractice or the failure to practice occupational therapy with that level of care, skill, and treatment which is recognized by a reasonably prudent similar occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant as being acceptable under similar conditions and circumstances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing any procedure which, by the prevailing standards of occupational therapy practice in the community, would constitute experimentation on a human subject without first obtaining full, informed, and written consent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or offering to practice beyond the scope permitted by law or accepting and performing professional responsibilities which the licensee knows or has reason to know that he or she is not competent to perform.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice occupational therapy with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness or use of alcohol, drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other type of material or as a result of any mental or physical condition. In enforcing this paragraph, the department shall have, upon probable cause, authority to compel an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant to submit to a mental or physical examination by physicians designated by the department. The failure of an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant to submit to such examination when so directed constitutes an admission of the allegations against him or her, upon which a default and final order may be entered without the taking of testimony or presentation of evidence, unless the failure was due to circumstances beyond his or her control. An occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant affected under this paragraph shall at reasonable intervals be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that he or she can resume the competent practice of occupational therapy with reasonable skill and safety to patients. In any proceeding under this paragraph, neither the record of proceedings nor the orders entered by the board shall be used against an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant in any other proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating professional responsibilities to a person when the licensee who is delegating such responsibilities knows or has reason to know that such person is not qualified by training, experience, or licensure to perform them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a lawful order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="w"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conspiring with another licensee or with any other person to commit an act, or committing an act, which would tend to coerce, intimidate, or preclude another licensee from lawfully advertising his or her services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="x"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may not reinstate the license of an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant, or cause a license to be issued to a person it has deemed unqualified, until such time as the board is satisfied that such person has complied with all the terms and conditions set forth in the final order and is capable of safely engaging in the practice of occupational therapy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 75-179; s. 36, ch. 78-95; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 7, 12, 13, ch. 84-4; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 280, ch. 97-103; s. 39, ch. 2001-277; s. 15, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>