<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.1115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision of this part shall be construed to limit the practice of persons licensed in this state from engaging in the professions for which they are licensed, so long as they do not hold themselves out to the public as possessing a license or certificate issued pursuant to this part or use a title protected by this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this part shall not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Students actively engaged in a training program, if such persons are acting under the direct supervision of a licensed speech-language pathologist or a licensed audiologist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons practicing a licensed profession or operating within the scope of their profession, such as doctors of medicine, clinical psychologists, nurses, or hearing aid specialists, who are properly licensed under the laws of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons certified in the areas of speech-language impairment or hearing impairment in this state under chapter 1012 when engaging in the profession for which they are certified, or any person under the direct supervision of such a certified person, or of a licensee under this chapter, when the person under such supervision is performing hearing screenings in a school setting for prekindergarten through grade 12.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Laryngectomized individuals, rendering guidance and instruction to other laryngectomized individuals, who are under the supervision of a speech-language pathologist licensed under this part or of a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 and qualified to perform this surgical procedure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons licensed by another state as speech-language pathologists or audiologists who provide services within the applicable scope of practice set forth in s. 468.1125(6) or (7) for no more than 5 calendar days per month or 15 calendar days per year under the direct supervision of a Florida-licensed speech-language pathologist or audiologist. A person whose state of residence does not license speech-language pathologists or audiologists may also qualify for this exemption, if the person holds a certificate of clinical competence from the American Speech-Language and Hearing Association and meets all other requirements of this paragraph. In either case, the board shall hold the supervising Florida licensee fully accountable for the services provided by the out-of-state licensee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonlicensed persons working in a hospital setting who provide newborn infant hearing screenings, so long as training, clinical interpretation of the screenings, and the protocol for followup of infants who fail in-hospital screenings are provided by a licensed audiologist.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 31, ch. 90-134; s. 21, ch. 90-341; ss. 1, 10, ch. 90-345; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 267, ch. 97-103; s. 111, ch. 97-264; s. 1014, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>