<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.517" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not knowingly:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage in dietetics and nutrition practice or nutrition counseling for remuneration unless the person is licensed under this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the name or title “dietitian,” “licensed dietitian,” “nutritionist,” “licensed nutritionist,” “nutrition counselor,” or “licensed nutrition counselor,” or any other words, letters, abbreviations, or insignia indicating or implying that he or she is a dietitian, nutritionist, or nutrition counselor, or otherwise hold himself or herself out as such, unless the person is the holder of a valid license issued under this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present as his or her own the license of another;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give false or forged evidence to the board or a member thereof;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a license that has been suspended, revoked, or placed on inactive or delinquent status;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ unlicensed persons to engage in dietetics and nutrition practice or nutrition counseling; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conceal information relative to any violation of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 17, 20, ch. 88-236; s. 100, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 204, ch. 94-119; s. 18, ch. 96-367.</History></Section>