<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.3095" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inactive status; reactivation; automatic suspension; reinstatement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificateholder may request that his or her certificate be placed in an inactive status by making application to the department and paying a fee in an amount set by the department not to exceed $50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate that has been expired for less than 10 years may be reactivated upon payment of the biennial renewal fee and a late renewal fee, not to exceed $100, and submission of a reactivation application containing any information that the department deems necessary to show that the applicant is a certificateholder in good standing and has met the requirements for continuing education. The department shall prescribe, by rule, continuing education requirements as a condition of reactivating a certificate. The continuing education requirements for reactivating a certificate may not exceed 10 classroom hours for each year the certificate was expired and may not exceed 100 classroom hours for all years in which the certificate was expired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate that has been inactive for less than 10 years may be reactivated by meeting all of the requirements of paragraph (a) for expired certificates, except for payment of the fee for late renewal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate that has been inactive or expired for 10 years or more automatically becomes null and void and may not be reactivated, renewed, or used to practice radiologic technology or to perform the duties of a radiologist assistant. A certificateholder whose certificate has become null and void may become certified again only by reapplying to the department as a new applicant and meeting the requirements of s. 468.304 or s. 468.3065.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an expired or inactive certificate is reactivated, the reactivated certificate expires on the last day of the certificateholder’s birth month and shall be valid for at least 12 months but no more than 24 months. However, if the reactivating certificateholder already holds a regular, active certificate in a different category under this part, the reactivated certificate shall be combined with and expire on the same date as the existing certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 19, ch. 84-269; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 288, ch. 97-103; s. 44, ch. 2004-350; s. 9, ch. 2006-139.</History></Section>