<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examination for licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person applying for licensure shall, in addition to demonstrating his or her eligibility in accordance with the requirements of s. 468.209, make application to the board or the appropriate examining entity for examination, upon a form and in such a manner as the board or the examining entity prescribes. Such application shall be accompanied by the nonrefundable fee prescribed by s. 468.221 or by a fee established by the examining entity. A person who fails an examination may make application for reexamination accompanied by the prescribed fee; such person shall also reapply to the board for licensure in the manner prescribed in s. 468.209.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant for licensure under this act shall be examined in a manner determined by the board in a written examination to test his or her knowledge of the basic and clinical sciences relating to occupational therapy and occupational therapy theory and practice, including the applicant’s professional skills and judgment in the utilization of occupational therapy techniques and methods, and such other subjects as the board may deem useful to determine the applicant’s fitness to practice. The board shall establish standards for acceptable performance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicants for licensure shall be examined at such times and places and under such supervision as the board may determine. Examinations shall be given at least twice each year at such places within this state as the board may determine, and the board shall give reasonable public notice of such examinations in accordance with its rules at least 60 days prior to their administration and shall notify by mail each individual examination applicant of the time and place of their administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may, by rule, adopt the use of a national examination in lieu of part or all of the examination required by this section; and a reasonable passing score shall be set by rule of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicants may obtain their examination scores and review their papers in accordance with such rules as the board may establish.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an applicant fails to pass the examination in three attempts, the applicant shall not be eligible for reexamination unless the applicant completes additional education or training requirements prescribed by the board. An applicant who has completed the additional education or training requirements prescribed by the board may take the examination on two more occasions. If the applicant has failed to pass the examination after five attempts, the applicant is no longer eligible to take the examination.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 75-179; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 12, 13, ch. 84-4; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 278, ch. 97-103; s. 126, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>