<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.811" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a registration or license or for disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to procure a license by fraudulent misrepresentation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure in another state or jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of or pleading nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, in any jurisdiction, a crime that directly relates to the practice of orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics, including violations of federal laws or regulations regarding orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing a report, claim, or record that the licensee knows is false; intentionally or negligently failing to file a report, claim, or record required by state or federal law; willfully impeding or obstructing such filing; or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports, claims, or records include only reports, claims, or records that are signed in a person’s capacity as a licensee under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of an order of the board, agency, or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing or failure to comply with a subpoena issued by the board, agency, or department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing with a revoked, suspended, or inactive license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross or repeated malpractice or the failure to deliver orthotic, prosthetic, or pedorthic services with that level of care and skill which is recognized by a reasonably prudent licensed practitioner with similar professional training as being acceptable under similar conditions and circumstances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to provide written notice of any applicable warranty for an orthosis, prosthesis, or pedorthic device that is provided to a patient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making deceptive, untrue, or fraudulent representations in the licensed or unlicensed practice of orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics or practicing as an orthotic fitter or an orthotic fitter assistant without a licensed physician’s written prescription. The repair, replacement, adjustment, or servicing of any existing orthosis may be performed without an additional prescription from the patient’s physician, unless the original prescription states otherwise.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 97-284; s. 105, ch. 98-166; s. 163, ch. 2000-160; s. 27, ch. 2000-318; s. 43, ch. 2001-277; s. 19, ch. 2005-240; s. 10, ch. 2008-121.</History></Section>