<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.1705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by endorsement; temporary license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who, upon applying to the department and remitting a fee set by the board not to exceed $500, demonstrates to the board that he or she:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets one of the following requirements:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid active license to practice nursing home administration in another state of the United States, provided that the current requirements for licensure in that state are substantially equivalent to, or more stringent than, current requirements in this state; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the qualifications for licensure in s. 468.1695; and</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed a national examination which is substantially equivalent to, or more stringent than, the examination given by the department;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed an examination on the laws and rules of this state governing the administration of nursing homes; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has worked as a fully licensed nursing home administrator for 2 years within the 5-year period immediately preceding the application by endorsement.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">National examinations for licensure as a nursing home administrator shall be presumed to be substantially equivalent to, or more stringent than, the examination and requirements in this state, unless found otherwise by rule of the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue a license by endorsement or a temporary license to any applicant who is under investigation in this or another state for any act which would constitute a violation of this part until such time as the investigation is complete and disciplinary proceedings have been terminated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary license may be issued one time only to an applicant who has filed an application for licensure by endorsement and has paid the fee for the next laws and rules examination offered in this state, and who meets all of the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has filed an application for a temporary license and paid a fee not to exceed $750.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the requirements of subsection (1) or s. 468.1695.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has worked as a fully licensed nursing home administrator for 2 years within the 5-year period immediately preceding application for a temporary license.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A temporary license shall be valid for the nursing home administrator applicant only at the facility for which it is issued and shall not be transferred to another facility or to another applicant. An applicant shall not be eligible to reapply for a temporary license or an extension of a temporary license. The applicant must take and pass the next laws and rules examination offered in this state following issuance of a temporary license. The temporary license is valid until the results of the examination are certified by the board and the applicant is notified.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-227; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 9, 42, ch. 82-179; s. 91, ch. 83-218; ss. 37, 119, ch. 83-329; ss. 7, 16, 17, ch. 86-223; s. 39, ch. 89-162; s. 24, ch. 90-134; s. 4, ch. 90-345; s. 61, ch. 91-137; s. 10, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 273, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>