<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.520" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicant” means a business or individual seeking to be licensed under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Employee Leasing Companies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee leasing” means an arrangement whereby a leasing company assigns its employees to a client and allocates the direction of and control over the leased employees between the leasing company and the client. The term does not include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary help arrangement, whereby an organization hires its own employees and assigns them to a client to support or supplement the client’s workforce in special work situations such as employee absences, temporary skill shortages, seasonal workloads, and special assignments and projects.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An arrangement in which an organization employs only one category of employees and assigns them to a client to perform a function inherent to that category and which function is separate and divisible from the primary business of the client.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facilities staffing arrangement, whereby an organization assigns its employees to staff, in whole or in part, a specific client function or functions, on an ongoing, indefinite basis, provided that the total number of individuals assigned by that organization under such arrangements comprises no more than 50 percent of the workforce at a client’s worksite and provided further that no more than 20 percent of the individuals assigned to staff a particular client function were employed by the client immediately preceding the commencement of the arrangement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An arrangement in which an organization assigns its employees only to a commonly controlled company or group of companies as defined in s. 414 of the Internal Revenue Code and in which the organization does not hold itself out to the public as an employee leasing company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A home health agency licensed under chapter 400, unless otherwise engaged in business as an employee leasing company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care services pool licensed under s. 400.980, unless otherwise engaged in business as an employee leasing company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee leasing company” means a sole proprietorship, partnership, corporation, or other form of business entity engaged in employee leasing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Client company” means a person or entity which contracts with an employee leasing company and is provided employees pursuant to that contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Controlling person” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any natural person who possesses, directly or indirectly, the power to direct or cause the direction of the management or policies of any employee leasing company, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct or indirect control of 50 percent or more of the voting securities of the employee leasing company; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The general power to endorse any negotiable instrument payable to or on behalf of the employee leasing company or to cause the direction of the management or policies of any employee leasing company; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any natural person employed, appointed, or authorized by an employee leasing company to enter into a contractual relationship with a client company on behalf of the employee leasing company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 17, ch. 91-93; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 31, ch. 94-119; s. 145, ch. 94-218; s. 104, ch. 2000-349.</History></Section>