<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.1685" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of board and department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the function and duty of the board, together with the department, to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this part conferring duties upon the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, impose, and enforce specific standards within the scope of the general qualifications established by this part which must be met by individuals in order to receive licenses as nursing home administrators. These standards shall be designed to ensure that nursing home administrators are individuals of good character and otherwise suitable and, by training or experience in the field of institutional administration, qualified to serve as nursing home administrators.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop by appropriate techniques, including examinations and investigations, a method for determining whether an individual meets such standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue licenses to qualified individuals meeting the standards of the board and revoke or suspend licenses previously issued by the board when the individual holding such license is determined to have failed to conform substantially to the requirements of such standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and carry out procedures, by rule, designed to ensure that licensed nursing home administrators will comply with standards adopted by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive, investigate, and take appropriate action with respect to any charge or complaint filed with the department to the effect that a licensed nursing home administrator has failed to comply with the requirements or standards adopted by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct a continuing study and investigation of nursing homes and administrators of nursing homes in order to improve the standards imposed for the licensing of such administrators and the procedures and methods for enforcing such standards with respect to administrators of nursing homes who have been licensed as such.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Set up procedures by rule for advising and acting together with the Department of Health and other boards of other health professions in matters affecting procedures and methods for effectively enforcing the purpose of this part and the administration of chapters 400 and 429.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-227; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 16, 17, ch. 86-223; s. 61, ch. 91-137; s. 10, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 132, ch. 98-200; s. 228, ch. 99-8; s. 93, ch. 2006-197.</History></Section>