<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.505" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part may be construed as prohibiting or restricting the practice, services, or activities of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person licensed in this state under chapter 457, chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, chapter 462, chapter 463, part I of chapter 464, chapter 465, chapter 466, chapter 480, chapter 490, or chapter 491, when engaging in the profession or occupation for which he or she is licensed, or of any person employed by and under the supervision of the licensee when rendering services within the scope of the profession or occupation of the licensee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person employed as a dietitian by the government of the United States, if the person engages in dietetics solely under direction or control of the organization by which the person is employed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person employed as a cooperative extension home economist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person pursuing a course of study leading to a degree in dietetics and nutrition from a program or school accredited pursuant to s. 468.509(2), if the activities and services constitute a part of a supervised course of study and if the person is designated by a title that clearly indicates the person’s status as a student or trainee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person fulfilling the supervised experience component of s. 468.509, if the activities and services constitute a part of the experience necessary to meet the requirements of s. 468.509.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dietitian or nutritionist from another state practicing dietetics or nutrition incidental to a course of study when taking or giving a postgraduate course or other course of study in this state, provided such dietitian or nutritionist is licensed in another jurisdiction or is a registered dietitian or holds an appointment on the faculty of a school accredited pursuant to s. 468.509(2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who markets or distributes food, food materials, or dietary supplements, or any person who engages in the explanation of the use and benefits of those products or the preparation of those products, if that person does not engage for a fee in dietetics and nutrition practice or nutrition counseling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who markets or distributes food, food materials, or dietary supplements, or any person who engages in the explanation of the use of those products or the preparation of those products, as an employee of an establishment permitted pursuant to chapter 465.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An educator who is in the employ of a nonprofit organization approved by the council; a federal, state, county, or municipal agency, or other political subdivision; an elementary or secondary school; or an accredited institution of higher education the definition of which, as provided in s. 468.509(2), applies to other sections of this part, insofar as the activities and services of the educator are part of such employment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who provides weight control services or related weight control products, provided the program has been reviewed by, consultation is available from, and no program change can be initiated without prior approval by a licensed dietitian/nutritionist, a dietitian or nutritionist licensed in another state that has licensure requirements considered by the council to be at least as stringent as the requirements for licensure under this part, or a registered dietitian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person employed by a hospital licensed under chapter 395, by a nursing home licensed under part II of chapter 400, by an assisted living facility licensed under chapter 429, or by a continuing care facility certified under chapter 651, if the person is employed in compliance with the laws and rules adopted thereunder regarding the operation of its dietetic department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person employed by a nursing facility exempt from licensing under s. 395.002(12), or a person exempt from licensing under s. 464.022.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person employed as a dietetic technician.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this part may be construed to prohibit or limit any person from the free dissemination of information, or from conducting a class or seminar or giving a speech, related to nutrition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this part have no application to the practice of the religious tenets of any church in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, an individual registered by the Commission on Dietetic Registration of the American Dietetic Association has the right to use the title “Registered Dietitian” and the designation “R.D.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 20, ch. 88-236; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 86, ch. 92-289; s. 41, ch. 95-210; s. 5, ch. 96-367; s. 39, ch. 98-89; s. 63, ch. 98-171; s. 127, ch. 2000-153; s. 134, ch. 2000-318; s. 94, ch. 2006-197; s. 179, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>