<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.1245" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Itemized listing of prices; delivery of hearing aid; receipt; guarantee; packaging; disclaimer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to delivery of services or products to a prospective purchaser, a licensee shall disclose, upon request by the prospective purchaser, an itemized listing of prices, which listing shall include separate price estimates for each service component and each product. Provision of such itemized listing of prices shall not be predicated on the prospective purchaser’s payment of any charge or agreement to purchase any service or product.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensee who fits and sells a hearing aid shall, at the time of delivery, provide the purchaser with a receipt containing the seller’s signature, the address of his or her regular place of business, and his or her license or certification number, if applicable, together with the brand, model, manufacturer or manufacturer’s identification code, and serial number of the hearing aid furnished and the amount charged for the hearing aid. The receipt also shall specify whether the hearing aid is new, used, or rebuilt, and shall specify the length of time and other terms of the guarantee and by whom the hearing aid is guaranteed. When the client has requested an itemized list of prices, the receipt shall also provide an itemization of the total purchase price, including, but not limited to, the cost of the aid, ear mold, batteries, and other accessories, and the cost of any services. Notice of the availability of this service must be displayed in a conspicuous manner in the office. The receipt also shall state that any complaint concerning the hearing aid and its guarantee, if not reconciled with the licensee from whom the hearing aid was purchased, should be directed by the purchaser to the department. The address and telephone number of such office shall be stated on the receipt.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No hearing aid may be sold to any person unless both the packaging containing the hearing aid and the contract provided pursuant to subsection (2) carry the following disclaimer in 10-point or larger type: “A hearing aid will not restore normal hearing, nor will it prevent further hearing loss.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 14, 31, ch. 90-134; s. 21, ch. 90-341; ss. 1, 10, ch. 90-345; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 105, ch. 92-149; s. 331, ch. 94-119; s. 4, ch. 94-160; s. 269, ch. 97-103; s. 118, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>