<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.365" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary grounds and actions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring, attempting to procure, or renewing a license as provided by this part by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentation, or through an error of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having licensure, certification, registration, or other authority, by whatever name known, to deliver respiratory care services revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, certification, registration, or other authority to deliver respiratory care services by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to respiratory care services or to the ability to deliver such services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully making or filing a false report or record, willfully failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, or willfully impeding or obstructing such filing or inducing another person to do so. Such reports or records include only those reports or records which require the signature of a respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist licensed pursuant to this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Circulating false, misleading, or deceptive advertising.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unprofessional conduct, which includes, but is not limited to, any departure from, or failure to conform to, acceptable standards related to the delivery of respiratory care services, as set forth by the board in rules adopted pursuant to this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging or attempting to engage in the possession, sale, or distribution of controlled substances, as set forth by law, for any purpose other than a legitimate purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully failing to report any violation of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a lawful order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in the delivery of respiratory care services with a revoked, suspended, or inactive license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permitting, aiding, assisting, procuring, or advising any person who is not licensed pursuant to this part, contrary to this part or to any rule of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist licensed pursuant to this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accepting and performing professional responsibilities which the licensee knows, or has reason to know, she or he is not competent to perform.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating professional responsibilities to a person when the licensee delegating such responsibilities knows, or has reason to know, that such person is not qualified by training, experience, or licensure to perform them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross or repeated malpractice or the failure to deliver respiratory care services with that level of care, skill, and treatment which is recognized by a reasonably prudent respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist with similar professional training as being acceptable under similar conditions and circumstances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying or receiving any commission, bonus, kickback, or rebate to or from, or engaging in any split-fee arrangement in any form whatsoever with, a person, organization, or agency, either directly or indirectly, for goods or services rendered to patients referred by or to providers of health care goods and services, including, but not limited to, hospitals, nursing homes, clinical laboratories, ambulatory surgical centers, or pharmacies. The provisions of this paragraph shall not be construed to prevent the licensee from receiving a fee for professional consultation services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence within a respiratory care relationship for the purpose of engaging a patient in sexual activity. A patient is presumed to be incapable of giving free, full, and informed consent to sexual activity with the patient’s respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making deceptive, untrue, or fraudulent representations in the delivery of respiratory care services or employing a trick or scheme in the delivery of respiratory care services if such a scheme or trick fails to conform to the generally prevailing standards of other licensees within the community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soliciting patients, either personally or through an agent, through the use of fraud, deception, or otherwise misleading statements or through the exercise of intimidation or undue influence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to keep written respiratory care records justifying the reason for the action taken by the licensee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on the patient in such a manner as to exploit the patient for the financial gain of the licensee or a third party, which includes, but is not limited to, the promoting or selling of services, goods, appliances, or drugs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing professional services which have not been duly ordered by a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459 and which are not in accordance with protocols established by the hospital, other health care provider, or the board, except as provided in ss. 743.064, 766.103, and 768.13.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="w"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to deliver respiratory care services with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness or use of alcohol, drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other type of material as a result of any mental or physical condition. In enforcing this paragraph, the department shall, upon probable cause, have authority to compel a respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist to submit to a mental or physical examination by physicians designated by the department. The cost of examination shall be borne by the licensee being examined. The failure of a respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist to submit to such an examination when so directed constitutes an admission of the allegations against her or him, upon which a default and a final order may be entered without the taking of testimony or presentation of evidence, unless the failure was due to circumstances beyond her or his control. A respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist affected under this paragraph shall at reasonable intervals be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that she or he can resume the competent delivery of respiratory care services with reasonable skill and safety to her or his patients. In any proceeding under this paragraph, neither the record of proceedings nor the orders entered by the board shall be used against a respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist in any other proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="x"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall not reinstate licensure, or cause a license to be issued to a person it has deemed unqualified, until such time as it is satisfied that such person has complied with all the terms and conditions set forth in the final order and that the respiratory care practitioner or respiratory therapist is capable of safely engaging in the delivery of respiratory care services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may, by rule, establish guidelines for the disposition of disciplinary cases involving specific types of violations. Such guidelines may include minimum and maximum fines, periods of supervision on probation, or conditions upon probation or reissuance of a license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 84-252; s. 8, ch. 86-60; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 38, ch. 95-144; s. 295, ch. 97-103; s. 141, ch. 97-264; s. 85, ch. 98-166; s. 182, ch. 99-397; s. 144, ch. 2000-160; s. 40, ch. 2001-277; s. 16, ch. 2005-240.</History></Section>