<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0468.8414" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall license any applicant who the department certifies is qualified to practice mold assessment or mold remediation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall certify for licensure any applicant who satisfies the requirements of s. 468.8413, who has passed the licensing examination, and who has documented training in water, mold, and respiratory protection. The department may refuse to certify any applicant who has violated any of the provisions of this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall certify as qualified for a license by endorsement an applicant who is of good moral character, who has the insurance coverage required under s. 468.8421, and who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is qualified to take the examination as set forth in s. 468.8413 and has passed a certification examination offered by a nationally recognized organization that certifies persons in the specialty of mold assessment or mold remediation that has been approved by the department as substantially equivalent to the requirements of this part and s. 455.217; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid license to practice mold assessment or mold remediation issued by another state or territory of the United States if the criteria for issuance of the license were substantially the same as the licensure criteria that is established by this part as determined by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who is under investigation in another state for any act that would constitute a violation of this part or chapter 455 until such time as the investigation is complete and disciplinary proceedings have been terminated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2007-235; s. 27, ch. 2010-106; s. 19, ch. 2010-176.</History>
</Section>