<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0468.8324" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grandfather clause.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who performs home inspection services may qualify for licensure as a home inspector under this part if the person submits an application to the department postmarked on or before July 1, 2012, which shows that the applicant:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possesses certification as a one- and two-family dwelling inspector issued by the International Code Council or the Southern Building Code Congress International;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been certified as a one- and two-family dwelling inspector by the Florida Building Code Administrators and Inspectors Board under part XII of this chapter; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Possesses a Division I contractor license under part I of chapter 489.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant may not qualify for licensure under this section if he or she has had a home inspector license or a license in any related field revoked at any time or suspended within the previous 5 years or has been assessed a fine that exceeds $500 within the previous 5 years. For purposes of this subsection, a license in a related field includes, but is not limited to, licensure in real estate, construction, mold-related services, or building code administration or inspection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for licensure under this section must comply with the criminal history, good moral character, and insurance requirements of this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2007-235; s. 22, ch. 2010-106; s. 14, ch. 2010-176; s. 10, ch. 2011-222.</History>
</Section>