<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.1215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Speech-language pathology assistant and audiology assistant; certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a certificate as a speech-language pathology assistant to each applicant who the board certifies has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the application form and remitted the required fees, including a nonrefundable application fee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Earned a bachelor’s degree from a college or university accredited by a regional association of colleges and schools recognized by the Department of Education which includes at least 24 semester hours of coursework as approved by the board at an institution accredited by an accrediting agency recognized by the Council for Higher Education Accreditation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a certificate as an audiology assistant to each applicant who the board certifies has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the application form and remitted the required fees, including a nonrefundable application fee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Earned a high school diploma or its equivalent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An audiologist or speech-language pathologist who employs a speech-language assistant or audiology assistant must provide the assistant with a plan approved by the board for on-the-job training and must maintain responsibility for all services performed by the assistant. The board, by rule, shall establish minimum education and on-the-job training and supervision requirements for certification as a speech-language pathology assistant or audiology assistant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not apply to any student, intern, or trainee performing speech-language pathology or audiology services while completing the supervised clinical experience as required in s. 468.1155.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 31, ch. 90-134; s. 21, ch. 90-341; ss. 1, 10, ch. 90-345; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 26, ch. 94-310; s. 117, ch. 97-264; s. 128, ch. 99-397; s. 115, ch. 2001-277; s. 4, ch. 2006-83.</History></Section>