<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0468.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Basic X-ray machine operator” means a person who is employed by a licensed practitioner to perform certain radiographic functions, specifically excluding nuclear medicine and radiation therapy procedures, under the direct supervision of that practitioner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Basic X-ray machine operator-podiatric medicine” means a person who is employed by and under the direct supervision of a licensed podiatric physician to perform only those radiographic functions that are within the scope of practice of a podiatric physician licensed pursuant to chapter 461, specifically excluding nuclear medicine and radiation therapy procedures.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate” means a certification granted and issued by the department under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificateholder” means any person who holds a certificate under this part that authorizes that person to use radiation on human beings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Council” means the Advisory Council on Radiation Protection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct supervision” means supervision and control by a licensed practitioner who assumes legal liability for the services rendered by the basic X-ray machine operator or basic X-ray machine operator-podiatric medicine, which supervision requires the physical presence of the licensed practitioner for consultation and direction of the actions of the basic X-ray machine operator or basic X-ray machine operator-podiatric medicine.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Educational program” means training or education, including either a didactic or a clinical practicum, or both, which has a specified objective, planned activities for students, and suitable methods for measuring student attainment, which program is offered, sponsored, or approved by an organization or institution that is able to meet or enforce these criteria and which program is subject to approval by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General radiographer” means a person who is employed and certificated in radiography, other than a basic X-ray machine operator or basic X-ray machine operator-podiatric medicine.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General supervision” means supervision whereby a practitioner authorizes the services to be performed by the radiologic technologist, which supervision, except in cases of emergency, requires the easy availability or physical presence of the licensed practitioner for consultation and direction of the actions of the radiologic technologist.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed practitioner” means a person who is licensed or otherwise authorized by law to practice medicine, podiatric medicine, chiropody, osteopathic medicine, naturopathy, or chiropractic medicine in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“National organization” means a professional association or registry, approved by the department, that examines, registers, certifies, or approves individuals and educational programs relating to operators of sources of radiation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, corporation, partnership, firm, association, trust, estate, public or private institution, group, agency, political subdivision of this state or any other state, or political subdivision of any agency thereof and any legal successor, representative, agent, or agency of the foregoing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiation” means X rays and gamma rays, alpha and beta particles, high-speed electrons, neutrons, and other nuclear particles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiologic technologist” means a person, other than a licensed practitioner, who is qualified by education, training, or experience, as more specifically defined in s. 468.302(3)(d)-(g), to use radiation on human beings under the specific direction and general supervision of a licensed practitioner in each particular case.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiologist” means a physician specializing in radiology certified by or eligible for certification by the American Board of Radiology or the American Osteopathic Board of Radiology, the British Royal College of Radiology, or the Canadian College of Physicians and Surgeons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiologist assistant” means a person, other than a licensed practitioner, who is qualified by education and certification, as set forth in s. 468.304, as an advanced-level radiologic technologist who works under the supervision of a radiologist to enhance patient care by assisting the radiologist in the medical imaging environment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Specialty technologist” means a person, other than a licensed practitioner, who is qualified by education and certification, as set forth in s. 468.304, to use radiation on human beings under the specific direction and general supervision of a licensed practitioner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 78-383; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 18, 19, ch. 84-269; s. 1, ch. 88-310; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 73, ch. 97-237; s. 51, ch. 97-264; ss. 211, 281, ch. 98-166; s. 2, ch. 2006-139; s. 91, ch. 2008-6; s. 1, ch. 2012-168.</History>
</Section>