<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0468.3101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary grounds and actions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may make or require to be made any investigations, inspections, evaluations, and tests, and require the submission of any documents and statements, which it considers necessary to determine whether a violation of this part has occurred. The following acts shall be grounds for disciplinary action as set forth in this section:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring, attempting to procure, or renewing a certificate by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentation, or through an error of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a voluntary or mandatory certificate to practice radiologic technology or to perform the duties of a radiologist assistant revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including being denied certification, by a national organization; by a specialty board recognized by the department; or by a certification authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, in any jurisdiction of a crime that directly relates to the practice of radiologic technology or to the performance of the duties of a radiologist assistant, or to the ability to practice radiologic technology or the ability to perform the duties of a radiologist assistant. Pleading nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction for the purpose of this provision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, in any jurisdiction of a crime against a person. Pleading nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction for the purposes of this provision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a false report or record that the certificateholder knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, or willfully impeding or obstructing such filing or inducing another to do so. Such reports or records include only those reports or records which are signed in the capacity of the certificateholder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in unprofessional conduct, which includes, but is not limited to, any departure from, or the failure to conform to, the standards of practice of radiologic technology or the standards of practice for radiologist assistants as established by the department, in which case actual injury need not be established.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice radiologic technology or to perform the duties of a radiologist assistant with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness or use of alcohol, drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or other materials or as a result of any mental or physical condition. A certificateholder affected under this paragraph shall, at reasonable intervals, be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that he or she can resume the competent practice of his or her certified profession with reasonable skill and safety.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department any person who the certificateholder knows is in violation of this part or of the rules of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this part, any rule of the department, or any lawful order of the department previously entered in a disciplinary proceeding or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employing, for the purpose of applying ionizing radiation or otherwise practicing radiologic technology or performing the duties of a radiologist assistant on a human being, any individual who is not certified under the provisions of this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Testing positive for any drug, as defined in s. 112.0455, on any confirmed preemployment or employer-required drug screening when the certificateholder does not have a lawful prescription and legitimate medical reason for using such drug.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department in writing within 30 days after the certificateholder has had a voluntary or mandatory certificate to practice radiologic technology or to perform the duties of a radiologist assistant revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including being denied certification, by a national organization, by a specialty board recognized by the department, or by a certification authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been found guilty of, regardless of adjudication, or pleading guilty or nolo contendere to, any offense prohibited under s. 435.04 or similar statute of another jurisdiction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to comply with the recommendations of the department’s impaired practitioner program for treatment, evaluation, or monitoring. A letter from the director of the impaired practitioner program that the certificateholder is not in compliance shall be considered conclusive proof under this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds any person or firm guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to approve an application for certification.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation or suspension of a certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each count or separate offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issuance of a reprimand.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement of the certificateholder on probation for such period of time and subject to such conditions as the department may specify, including requiring the certificateholder to submit to treatment, to undertake further relevant education or training, to take an examination, or to work under the supervision of a licensed practitioner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not reinstate a person’s certificate, or cause a certificate to be issued to a person it has deemed unqualified, until such time as the department is satisfied that such person has complied with all the terms and conditions set forth in the final order and is capable of safely engaging in the practice of his or her certified profession.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, by rule, establish guidelines for the disposition of disciplinary cases involving specific types of violations. Such guidelines may include minimum and maximum fines, periods of suspension or probation, or conditions of probation or reissuance of a certificate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final disciplinary action taken against a certificateholder in another jurisdiction, whether voluntary or mandatory, shall be considered conclusive proof of grounds for a disciplinary proceeding under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may revoke approval of a continuing education provider and its approved courses if the provider’s certification has been revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against by a national organization; by a specialty board recognized by the department; or by a certification authority of another state, territory, or country. The department may establish by rule additional guidelines and criteria for the discipline of continuing education providers, including, but not limited to, revoking approval of a continuing education provider or a continuing education course and refusing to approve a continuing education provider or continuing education course.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 19, ch. 84-269; s. 9, ch. 88-310; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 289, ch. 97-103; s. 74, ch. 97-237; s. 45, ch. 2004-350; s. 10, ch. 2006-139; s. 52, ch. 2010-114.</History>
</Section>