<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this act shall be construed as preventing or restricting the practice, services, or activities of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person licensed in this state by any other law from engaging in the profession or occupation for which he or she is licensed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person employed as an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant by the United States, if such person provides occupational therapy solely under the direction or control of the organization by which he or she is employed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person pursuing a course of study leading to a degree or certificate in occupational therapy at an accredited or approved educational program, if such activities and services constitute a part of a supervised course of study and if such a person is designated by a title which clearly indicates his or her status as a student or trainee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person fulfilling the supervised fieldwork experience requirements of s. 468.209, if such activities and services constitute a part of the experience necessary to meet the requirements of that section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision of this act shall be construed to prohibit physicians, physician assistants, nurses, physical therapists, osteopathic physicians or surgeons, clinical psychologists, speech-language pathologists, or audiologists from using occupational therapy as a part of or incidental to their profession, when they practice their profession under the statutes applicable to their profession.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 75-179; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 12, 13, ch. 84-4; s. 4, ch. 90-22; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 282, ch. 97-103; s. 128, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>