<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.393" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Surcharge to license fee; assessments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of licensure under s. 468.385, s. 468.3851, or s. 468.3852, each licensee shall pay, in addition to an application and license fee, a surcharge in an amount to be determined by the board, not to exceed $300, which shall be deposited in the Auctioneer Recovery Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the total amount in the Auctioneer Recovery Fund, including principal and interest, exceeds $500,000 at the end of the state fiscal year after the payment of all claims and expenses, the amount in excess of $500,000 shall remain in the fund for benefit of the licensees in tolling the surcharge until such time as the surcharge shall need replenishing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After October 1, 1995, if the total amount in the Auctioneer Recovery Fund, including principal and interest, is less than $200,000 at the end of the fiscal year after the payment of all claims and expenses, the board shall assess, in addition to any other fees under s. 468.3852, a surcharge against a licensee at the time of initial licensure or at the time of license renewal, according to the following formula in order to maintain the fund at $500,000:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the amount remaining in the fund at the end of the state fiscal year after all expenses and claims have been paid.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subtract the amount determined under paragraph (a) from $500,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the number of initial licenses and license renewals in the fiscal year that precedes the current fiscal year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Divide the amount determined under paragraph (b) by the number determined under paragraph (c).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall assess the surcharge described in subsection (3) against each licensee who receives an initial license or receives a renewal license during the fiscal year that follows the year in which the amount remaining in the fund was less than $200,000.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 17, ch. 91-207; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 130, ch. 92-149.</History></Section>