<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.456" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts shall be grounds for the disciplinary actions provided for in subsection (3):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of any law relating to the practice as an athlete agent including, but not limited to, violations of this part and chapter 455 and any rules promulgated thereunder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to account for or to pay, within a reasonable time, not to exceed 30 days, assets belonging to another which have come into the control of the athlete agent in the course of conducting business as an athlete agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any conduct as an athlete agent which demonstrates bad faith or dishonesty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commingling money or property of another person with the athlete agent’s money or property. Every athlete agent shall maintain a separate trust or escrow account in an insured bank or savings and loan association located in this state in which shall be deposited all proceeds received for another person through the athlete agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accepting as a client a student athlete referred by and in exchange for any consideration made to an employee of or a coach for a college or university located in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offering anything of value to any person to induce a student athlete to enter into an agreement by which the agent will represent the student athlete. However, negotiations regarding the agent’s fee shall not be considered an inducement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly providing financial benefit from the licensee’s conduct of business as an athlete agent to another athlete agent whose license to practice as an athlete agent is suspended or has been permanently revoked within the previous 5 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing mismanagement or misconduct as an athlete agent which causes financial harm to a student athlete or college or university.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to include the athlete agent’s name and license number in any advertising related to the business of an athlete agent. Advertising shall not include clothing or other novelty items.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publishing or causing to be published false or misleading information or advertisements, or giving any false information or making false promises to a student athlete concerning employment or financial services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating or aiding and abetting another person to violate the rules of the athletic conference or collegiate athletic association governing a student athlete or student athlete’s college or university.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having contact, as prohibited by this part, with a student athlete.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postdating agent contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having an athlete agent certification acted against by a professional athletic club or association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being employed to illegally recruit or solicit student athletes by being utilized by or otherwise collaborating with a person known to have been convicted or found guilty of, or to have entered a plea of nolo contendere to, a violation of s. 468.45615, regardless of adjudication.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not prohibit an athlete agent from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sending to a student athlete written materials provided that the athlete agent simultaneously sends an identical copy of such written materials to the athletic director, or the director’s designee, of the college or university in which the student athlete is enrolled or to which the student athlete has provided a written intent to participate in intercollegiate athletics; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Otherwise contacting a student athlete, provided that the student athlete initiates the contact with the athlete agent and the athlete agent gives prior notice, as provided for by rule of the department, to the college or university in which the student athlete is enrolled or to which the student athlete has provided a written intent to participate in intercollegiate athletics.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department finds any person guilty of any of the prohibited acts set forth in subsection (1), the department may enter an order imposing one or more of the penalties provided for in s. 455.227, and an administrative fine not to exceed $25,000 for each separate offense. In addition to any other penalties or disciplinary actions provided for in this part, the department shall suspend or revoke the license of any athlete agent licensed under this part who violates paragraph (1)(f) or paragraph (1)(o) or s. 468.45615.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 88-229; s. 1, ch. 89-296; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 7, ch. 95-307; s. 89, ch. 98-166; s. 148, ch. 2000-160; s. 69, ch. 2000-356; s. 4, ch. 2002-24.</History></Section>