<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Association” means the Florida Occupational Therapy Association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Occupational Therapy Practice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Occupational therapist” means a person licensed to practice occupational therapy as defined in this act and whose license is in good standing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Occupational therapy” means the use of purposeful activity or interventions to achieve functional outcomes.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Achieving functional outcomes” means to maximize the independence and the maintenance of health of any individual who is limited by a physical injury or illness, a cognitive impairment, a psychosocial dysfunction, a mental illness, a developmental or a learning disability, or an adverse environmental condition.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assessment” means the use of skilled observation or the administration and interpretation of standardized or nonstandardized tests and measurements to identify areas for occupational therapy services.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Occupational therapy services include, but are not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The assessment, treatment, and education of or consultation with the individual, family, or other persons.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interventions directed toward developing daily living skills, work readiness or work performance, play skills or leisure capacities, or enhancing educational performance skills.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing for the development of: sensory-motor, perceptual, or neuromuscular functioning; range of motion; or emotional, motivational, cognitive, or psychosocial components of performance.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">These services may require assessment of the need for use of interventions such as the design, development, adaptation, application, or training in the use of assistive technology devices; the design, fabrication, or application of rehabilitative technology such as selected orthotic devices; training in the use of assistive technology; orthotic or prosthetic devices; the application of physical agent modalities as an adjunct to or in preparation for purposeful activity; the use of ergonomic principles; the adaptation of environments and processes to enhance functional performance; or the promotion of health and wellness.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of devices subject to 21 C.F.R. s. 801.109 and identified by the board is expressly prohibited except by an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant who has received training as specified by the board. The board shall adopt rules to carry out the purpose of this provision.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Occupational therapy aide” means a person who assists in the practice of occupational therapy, who works under the direct supervision of a licensed occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant, and whose activities require a general understanding of occupational therapy pursuant to board rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Occupational therapy assistant” means a person licensed to assist in the practice of occupational therapy, who works under the supervision of an occupational therapist, and whose license is in good standing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, partnership, unincorporated organization, or corporate body, except that only an individual may be licensed under this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supervision” means responsible supervision and control, with the licensed occupational therapist providing both initial direction in developing a plan of treatment and periodic inspection of the actual implementation of the plan. Such plan of treatment shall not be altered by the supervised individual without prior consultation with, and the approval of, the supervising occupational therapist. The supervising occupational therapist need not always be physically present or on the premises when the assistant is performing services; however, except in cases of emergency, supervision shall require the availability of the supervising occupational therapist for consultation with and direction of the supervised individual.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 75-179; s. 1, ch. 78-18; s. 333, ch. 81-259; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 12, 13, ch. 84-4; s. 1, ch. 90-22; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 107, ch. 92-149; s. 123, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>