<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.454" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contracts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent contract must be in a record, signed or otherwise authenticated by the parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent contract must state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and method of calculating the consideration to be paid by the student athlete for services to be provided by the athlete agent and any other consideration the agent has received or will receive from any other source under the contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of any person not listed in the licensure application who will be compensated because the student athlete signed the agent contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any expenses that the student athlete agrees to reimburse;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the services to be provided to the student athlete;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration of the contract; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of execution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent contract must contain, in close proximity to the signature of the student athlete, a conspicuous notice in boldface type in capital letters stating:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">WARNING TO STUDENT ATHLETE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">IF YOU SIGN THE CONTRACT:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush">1. YOU MAY LOSE YOUR ELIGIBILITY TO COMPETE AS A STUDENT ATHLETE IN YOUR SPORT;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush">2. IF YOU HAVE AN ATHLETIC DIRECTOR, WITHIN 72 HOURS AFTER ENTERING INTO THE CONTRACT, YOU AND YOUR ATHLETE AGENT MUST NOTIFY YOUR ATHLETIC DIRECTOR; AND</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceBelow="true">3. YOU MAY CANCEL THIS CONTRACT WITHIN 14 DAYS AFTER SIGNING IT. HOWEVER, CANCELLATION OF THIS CONTRACT MAY NOT REINSTATE YOUR ELIGIBILITY.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent contract that does not conform to this section is voidable by the student athlete. If a student athlete voids an agent contract, the student athlete is not required to pay any consideration or return any consideration received from the athlete agent to induce the student athlete to enter into the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The athlete agent shall give a record of the signed or authenticated agent contract to the student athlete at the time of execution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 72 hours after entering into an agent contract or before the next scheduled athletic event in which the student athlete may participate, whichever occurs first, the athlete agent must give notice in a record of the existence of the contract to the athletic director of the educational institution at which the student athlete is enrolled or the athlete agent has reasonable grounds to believe the student athlete intends to enroll.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 72 hours after entering into an agent contract or before the next athletic event in which the student athlete may participate, whichever occurs first, the student athlete must inform the athletic director of the educational institution at which the student athlete is enrolled that he or she has entered into an agent contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student athlete may cancel an agent contract by giving notice of the cancellation to the athlete agent in a record within 14 days after the contract is signed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student athlete may not waive the right to cancel an agent contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a student athlete cancels an agent contract, the student athlete is not required to pay any consideration or return any consideration received from the athlete agent to induce the student athlete to enter into the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An athlete agent shall not enter into an agent contract that purports to or takes effect at a future time after the student athlete no longer has remaining eligibility to participate in intercollegiate athletics. Such a contract is void and unenforceable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agent contract between a student athlete and a person not licensed under this part is void and unenforceable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 5, 6, ch. 88-229; s. 1, ch. 89-296; s. 99, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 95-307; s. 3, ch. 2002-24.</History></Section>