<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.803" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License, registration, and examination requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license to practice orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics, or a registration for a resident to practice orthotics or prosthetics, to qualified applicants. Licenses shall be granted independently in orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics, but a person may be licensed in more than one such discipline, and a prosthetist-orthotist license may be granted to persons meeting the requirements for both a prosthetist and an orthotist license. Registrations shall be granted independently in orthotics or prosthetics, and a person may be registered in both fields at the same time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for registration, examination, or licensure must apply to the department on a form prescribed by the board for consideration of board approval. Each initial applicant shall submit a set of fingerprints to the department on a form and under procedures specified by the department, along with payment in an amount equal to the costs incurred by the department for state and national criminal history checks of the applicant. The department shall submit the fingerprints provided by an applicant to the Department of Law Enforcement for a statewide criminal history check, and the Department of Law Enforcement shall forward the fingerprints to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for a national criminal history check of the applicant. The board shall screen the results to determine if an applicant meets licensure requirements. The board shall consider for examination, registration, or licensure each applicant who the board verifies:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has submitted the completed application and the fingerprint forms and has paid the applicable application fee, not to exceed $500, and the cost of the state and national criminal history checks. The application fee and cost of the criminal history checks shall be nonrefundable;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is of good moral character;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 18 years of age or older; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the appropriate educational preparation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person seeking to attain the required orthotics or prosthetics experience in this state must be approved by the board and registered as a resident by the department. Although a registration may be held in both practice fields, the board shall not approve a second registration until at least 1 year after the issuance of the first registration. Notwithstanding subsection (2), an applicant who has been approved by the board and registered by the department in one practice field may apply for registration in the second practice field without an additional state or national criminal history check during the period in which the first registration is valid. Each registration is valid for 2 years from the date of issuance unless otherwise revoked by the department upon recommendation of the board. The board shall set a registration fee not to exceed $500 to be paid by the applicant. A registration may be renewed once by the department upon recommendation of the board for a period no longer than 1 year, as such renewal is defined by the board by rule. The registration renewal fee shall not exceed one-half the current registration fee. To be considered by the board for approval of registration as a resident, the applicant must have:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Bachelor of Science or higher-level postgraduate degree in Orthotics and Prosthetics from a regionally accredited college or university recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs or, at a minimum, a bachelor’s degree from a regionally accredited college or university and a certificate in orthotics from a program recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs, or its equivalent, as determined by the board; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Bachelor of Science or higher-level postgraduate degree in Orthotics and Prosthetics from a regionally accredited college or university recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs or, at a minimum, a bachelor’s degree from a regionally accredited college or university and a certificate in prosthetics from a program recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs, or its equivalent, as determined by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may develop and administer a state examination for an orthotist or a prosthetist license, or the board may approve the existing examination of a national standards organization. The examination must be predicated on a minimum of a baccalaureate-level education and formalized specialized training in the appropriate field. Each examination must demonstrate a minimum level of competence in basic scientific knowledge, written problem solving, and practical clinical patient management. The board shall require an examination fee not to exceed the actual cost to the board in developing, administering, and approving the examination, which fee must be paid by the applicant. To be considered by the board for examination, the applicant must have:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an examination in orthotics:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Bachelor of Science or higher-level postgraduate degree in Orthotics and Prosthetics from a regionally accredited college or university recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs or, at a minimum, a bachelor’s degree from a regionally accredited college or university and a certificate in orthotics from a program recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs, or its equivalent, as determined by the board; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An approved orthotics internship of 1 year of qualified experience, as determined by the board, or an orthotic residency program recognized by the board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an examination in prosthetics:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Bachelor of Science or higher-level postgraduate degree in Orthotics and Prosthetics from a regionally accredited college or university recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs or, at a minimum, a bachelor’s degree from a regionally accredited college or university and a certificate in prosthetics from a program recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs, or its equivalent, as determined by the board; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An approved prosthetics internship of 1 year of qualified experience, as determined by the board, or a prosthetic residency program recognized by the board.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements in subsection (2), to be licensed as:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An orthotist, the applicant must pay a license fee not to exceed $500 and must have:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Bachelor of Science or higher-level postgraduate degree in Orthotics and Prosthetics from a regionally accredited college or university, or a bachelor’s degree with a certificate in orthotics from a program recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs, or its equivalent, as determined by the board;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appropriate internship of 1 year of qualified experience, as determined by the board, or a residency program recognized by the board;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the mandatory courses; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Passed the state orthotics examination or the board-approved orthotics examination.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prosthetist, the applicant must pay a license fee not to exceed $500 and must have:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Bachelor of Science or higher-level postgraduate degree in Orthotics and Prosthetics from a regionally accredited college or university, or a bachelor’s degree with a certificate in prosthetics from a program recognized by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs, or its equivalent, as determined by the board;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An internship of 1 year of qualified experience, as determined by the board, or a residency program recognized by the board;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the mandatory courses; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Passed the state prosthetics examination or the board-approved prosthetics examination.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An orthotic fitter, the applicant must pay a license fee not to exceed $500 and must have:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A high school diploma or its equivalent;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minimum of 40 hours of training in orthotics education, as approved by the board;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two years of supervised experience in orthotics acquired after completion of the required education, as approved by the board; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the mandatory courses.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An orthotic fitter assistant, the applicant must pay a license fee not to exceed $500 and must have:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A high school diploma or its equivalent;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minimum of 40 hours of training in orthotics education, as approved by the board; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the mandatory courses.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pedorthist, the applicant must pay a license fee not to exceed $500 and must have:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A high school diploma or its equivalent;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minimum of 120 hours of training, as approved by the board;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An internship of 80 hours of qualified working experience, as determined by the board; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the mandatory courses.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 97-284; s. 15, ch. 2003-2; s. 4, ch. 2008-121.</History></Section>