<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.1755" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any provision of s. 456.072(1) or s. 468.1745(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to procure a license to practice nursing home administration by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentation, or through an error of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license to practice nursing home administration revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another state, territory, or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which relates to the practice of nursing home administration or the ability to practice nursing home administration. Any plea of nolo contendere shall be considered a conviction for purposes of this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report or record which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to impede or obstruct such filing. Such reports or records shall include only those which are signed in the capacity of a licensed nursing home administrator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizing the discharge or transfer of a resident for a reason other than those provided in ss. 400.022 and 400.0255.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising goods or services in a manner which is fraudulent, false, deceptive, or misleading in form or content.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraud or deceit, negligence, incompetence, or misconduct in the practice of nursing home administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of a lawful order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the board or department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing with a revoked, suspended, inactive, or delinquent license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repeatedly acting in a manner inconsistent with the health, safety, or welfare of the patients of the facility in which he or she is the administrator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice nursing home administration with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness, drunkenness, use of drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other material or substance or as a result of any mental or physical condition. In enforcing this paragraph, upon a finding of the State Surgeon General or his or her designee that probable cause exists to believe that the licensee is unable to serve as a nursing home administrator due to the reasons stated in this paragraph, the department shall have the authority to issue an order to compel the licensee to submit to a mental or physical examination by a physician designated by the department. If the licensee refuses to comply with such order, the department’s order directing such examination may be enforced by filing a petition for enforcement in the circuit court where the licensee resides or serves as a nursing home administrator. The licensee against whom the petition is filed shall not be named or identified by initials in any public court records or documents, and the proceedings shall be closed to the public. The department shall be entitled to the summary procedure provided in s. 51.011. A licensee affected under this paragraph shall have the opportunity, at reasonable intervals, to demonstrate that he or she can resume the competent practice of nursing home administration with reasonable skill and safety to patients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully or repeatedly violating any of the provisions of the law, code, or rules of the licensing or supervising authority or agency of the state or political subdivision thereof having jurisdiction of the operation and licensing of nursing homes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying, giving, causing to be paid or given, or offering to pay or to give to any person a commission or other valuable consideration for the solicitation or procurement, either directly or indirectly, of nursing home usage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully permitting unauthorized disclosure of information relating to a patient or his or her records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discriminating with respect to patients, employees, or staff on account of race, religion, color, sex, or national origin.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to implement an ongoing quality assurance program directed by an interdisciplinary team that meets at least every other month.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall reissue the license of a disciplined licensee upon certification by the board that the disciplined licensee has complied with all of the terms and conditions set forth in the final order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-227; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 11, 16, 17, ch. 86-223; s. 61, ch. 91-137; s. 10, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 10, 192, ch. 94-119; s. 275, ch. 97-103; s. 80, ch. 98-166; s. 21, ch. 99-394; s. 138, ch. 2000-160; s. 27, ch. 2000-318; ss. 38, 83, ch. 2001-277; s. 14, ch. 2005-240; s. 90, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>