<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dietitian/nutritionist; temporary permit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary permit to practice dietetics and nutrition may be issued by the board on the filing of an application, payment of a temporary permit fee, and the submission of evidence of the successful completion of the educational requirement under s. 468.509. The initial application shall be signed by the supervising licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person practicing under a temporary permit shall be under the supervision and direction of a licensed dietitian/nutritionist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary permit shall expire 1 year from the date of issuance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One extension of a temporary permit may be granted for good cause shown.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board determines that an applicant is qualified to be licensed by endorsement under s. 468.513, the board may issue the applicant a temporary permit to practice dietetics and nutrition until the next board meeting at which license applications are to be considered, but not for a longer period of time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the board determines that an applicant has not passed an examination recognized by the board and is not qualified to be licensed by endorsement, but has otherwise met all the requirements of s. 468.509 and has made application for the next scheduled examination, the board may issue the applicant a temporary permit allowing him or her to practice dietetics and nutrition under the supervision of a licensed dietitian/nutritionist until notification of the results of the examination.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 20, ch. 88-236; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 12, ch. 96-367.</History></Section>