<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.366" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties for violations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a violation of law for any person, including any firm, association, or corporation, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell or fraudulently obtain, attempt to obtain, or furnish to any person a diploma, license, or record, or aid or abet in the sale, procurement, or attempted procurement thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver respiratory care services, as defined by this part or by rule of the board, under cover of any diploma, license, or record that was illegally or fraudulently obtained or signed or issued unlawfully or under fraudulent representation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver respiratory care services, as defined by this part or by rule of the board, unless such person is duly licensed to do so under the provisions of this part or unless such person is exempted pursuant to s. 468.368.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use, in connection with his or her name, any designation tending to imply that he or she is a respiratory care practitioner or a respiratory therapist, duly licensed under the provisions of this part, unless he or she is so licensed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertise an educational program as meeting the requirements of this part, or conduct an educational program for the preparation of respiratory care practitioners or respiratory therapists, unless such program has been approved by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly employ unlicensed persons in the delivery of respiratory care services, unless exempted by this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly conceal information relative to any violation of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of this section is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 84-252; s. 9, ch. 86-60; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 296, ch. 97-103; s. 142, ch. 97-264; s. 58, ch. 2000-318.</History></Section>