<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.382" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Auction business” means a sole proprietorship, partnership, or corporation which in the regular course of business arranges, manages, sponsors, advertises, promotes, or carries out auctions, employs auctioneers to conduct auctions in its facilities, or uses or allows the use of its facilities for auctions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Auctioneer” means any person licensed pursuant to this part who holds a valid Florida auctioneer license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Apprentice” means any person who is being trained as an auctioneer by a licensed auctioneer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Florida Board of Auctioneers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Livestock” means any animal included in the definition of “livestock” by s. 585.01 or s. 588.13.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agricultural product” means the natural products from a farm, nursery, grove, orchard, vineyard, garden, or apiary, including livestock, tobacco, and vegetables and includes those agricultural products as defined in chapter 618.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Absolute auction” means an auction that requires no minimum opening bid that limits the sale other than to the highest bidder.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 14, ch. 86-119; s. 66, ch. 90-321; s. 62, ch. 91-137; s. 11, ch. 91-156; s. 1, ch. 91-207; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 92-206; s. 3, ch. 92-291; s. 136, ch. 94-218; s. 10, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>