<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.3855" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Apprenticeship training requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An auctioneer may not sponsor more than three apprentices at one time. Any auctioneer who serves as a sponsor must have held an active, valid license for 3 consecutive years preceding the date on which that auctioneer is named as sponsor of the apprentice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any auctioneer who undertakes the sponsorship of an apprentice shall ensure that the apprentice receives training as required by board rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An apprentice must actively participate in auction sales as required by board rule, and a record of each auction for which participation credit is claimed must be made as required by board rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apprentices are prohibited from conducting any auction without the prior express written consent of the sponsor. The apprentice’s sponsor must be present at the auction site at any time the apprentice is actively participating in the conduct of the auction. If the apprentice’s sponsor cannot attend a particular auction, the sponsor may appoint a qualified auctioneer who meets the requirements of board rule to attend the auction in his or her place. Prior written consent must be given by the apprentice’s sponsor for each substitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each apprentice and sponsor shall file reports as required by board rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sponsor may not authorize an apprentice to conduct an auction or act as principal auctioneer unless the sponsor has determined that the apprentice has received adequate training to do so.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sponsor shall be responsible for any acts or omissions of the apprentice which constitute a violation of law in relation to the conduct of an auction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All apprentice applications shall be valid for a period of 6 months after board approval. Any applicant who fails to complete the licensure process within that time shall be required to make application as a new applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensed apprentice who wishes to change the sponsor under whom he or she is licensed must submit a new application and application fee. However, a new license fee shall not be required and credit shall be awarded for training received or any period of apprenticeship served under the previous sponsor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit for training received or any period of apprenticeship served shall not be allowed unless it occurred under the supervision of the sponsor under whose supervision the apprentice is licensed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2000-356.</History></Section>