<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.352" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Respiratory Care.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified respiratory therapist” means any person licensed pursuant to this part who is certified by the National Board for Respiratory Care or its successor; who is employed to deliver respiratory care services, under the order of a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459, in accordance with protocols established by a hospital or other health care provider or the board; and who functions in situations of unsupervised patient contact requiring individual judgment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Critical care” means care given to a patient in any setting involving a life-threatening emergency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct supervision” means practicing under the direction of a licensed, registered, or certified respiratory therapist who is physically on the premises and readily available, as defined by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician supervision” means supervision and control by a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 who assumes the legal liability for the services rendered by the personnel employed in his or her office. Except in the case of an emergency, physician supervision requires the easy availability of the physician within the office or the physical presence of the physician for consultation and direction of the actions of the persons who deliver respiratory care services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of respiratory care” or “respiratory therapy” means the allied health specialty associated with the cardiopulmonary system that is practiced under the orders of a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 and in accordance with protocols, policies, and procedures established by a hospital or other health care provider or the board, including the assessment, diagnostic evaluation, treatment, management, control, rehabilitation, education, and care of patients in all care settings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registered respiratory therapist” means any person licensed under this part who is registered by the National Board for Respiratory Care or its successor, and who is employed to deliver respiratory care services under the order of a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459, in accordance with protocols established by a hospital or other health care provider or the board, and who functions in situations of unsupervised patient contact requiring individual judgment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Respiratory care practitioner” means any person licensed under this part who is employed to deliver respiratory care services, under direct supervision, pursuant to the order of a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Respiratory care services” includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation and disease management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diagnostic and therapeutic use of respiratory equipment, devices, or medical gas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration of drugs, as duly ordered or prescribed by a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 and in accordance with protocols, policies, and procedures established by a hospital or other health care provider or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiation, management, and maintenance of equipment to assist and support ventilation and respiration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Diagnostic procedures, research, and therapeutic treatment and procedures, including measurement of ventilatory volumes, pressures, and flows; specimen collection and analysis of blood for gas transport and acid/base determinations; pulmonary-function testing; and other related physiological monitoring of cardiopulmonary systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cardiopulmonary rehabilitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cardiopulmonary resuscitation, advanced cardiac life support, neonatal resuscitation, and pediatric advanced life support, or equivalent functions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insertion and maintenance of artificial airways and intravascular catheters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Education of patients, families, the public, or other health care providers, including disease process and management programs and smoking prevention and cessation programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiation and management of hyperbaric oxygen.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 84-252; s. 2, ch. 86-60; s. 2, ch. 87-553; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 135, ch. 94-218; s. 291, ch. 97-103; s. 130, ch. 97-264; s. 176, ch. 99-397; s. 109, ch. 2001-277; s. 1, ch. 2004-299.</History></Section>