<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.812" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions from licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or chapter 461;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person performing services for the Federal Government, if the person provides orthotic, prosthetic, or pedorthic care solely under the direction or control of the organization by which that person is employed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student, fellow, or trainee in orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics pursuing a course of study at a regionally accredited college or university or working in a recognized training center or research facility, provided the activities and services are part of a regular course of study under a supervisor licensed under this part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An instructor in a regionally accredited university or college, while performing regularly assigned work under the curriculum of such a school; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person engaged exclusively in the fabrication of orthoses, pedorthic devices, or prostheses as defined in this part, provided there is no patient contact.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not require an additional license of, or regulate the practice of, any other licensed health care professional within the state, or prevent a qualified member of any other profession or any person employed under the supervision of such a licensed professional from doing work of a nature consistent with that person’s training, as long as the person does not hold himself or herself out to the public as a licensee under this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 97-284; s. 123, ch. 99-397; s. 11, ch. 2008-121; s. 4, ch. 2009-202.</History></Section>