<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Occupational Therapy Practice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the department the Board of Occupational Therapy Practice, composed of seven members appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members shall be licensed occupational therapists in good standing in this state who are residents of this state and have been engaged in the practice of occupational therapy for at least 4 years immediately prior to their appointment. One member shall be a licensed occupational therapy assistant in good standing in this state who is a resident of the state and has been engaged in the practice of occupational therapy for at least 4 years immediately prior to the appointment. Two members shall be consumers who are residents of the state who are not connected with the practice of occupational therapy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days after the effective date of this act, the Governor shall appoint the board as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members for terms of 2 years each.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members for terms of 3 years each.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members for terms of 4 years each.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As the terms of the members expire, the Governor shall appoint successors for terms of 4 years and such members shall serve until their successors are appointed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All provisions of chapter 456 relating to activities of the board shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 75-179; s. 171, ch. 77-104; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 3, 12, 13, ch. 84-4; s. 2, ch. 90-22; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 124, ch. 97-264; s. 82, ch. 98-166; s. 140, ch. 2000-160.</History></Section>