<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.1125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Audiologist” means a person licensed under this part to practice audiology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified audiology assistant” means a person who is certified under this part to perform audiology services under the direct supervision of an audiologist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified speech-language pathology assistant” means a person who is certified under this part to perform speech pathology services under the direct supervision of a speech pathologist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of audiology” means the application of principles, methods, and procedures for the prevention, identification, evaluation, consultation, habilitation, rehabilitation, instruction, treatment, and research, relative to hearing and the disorders of hearing, and to related language and speech disorders. “Disorders” are defined to include any and all conditions, whether of organic or nonorganic origin, peripheral or central, that impede the normal process of human communication, including, but not limited to, disorders of auditory sensitivity, acuity, function, or processing, or damage to the integrity of the physiological system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any audiologist who has complied with the provisions of this part may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer, render, plan, direct, conduct, consult, or supervise services to individuals or groups of individuals who have or are suspected of having disorders of hearing, including prevention, identification, evaluation, treatment, consultation, habilitation, rehabilitation, instruction, and research.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate in hearing conservation, evaluation of noise environment, and noise control.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct and interpret tests of vestibular function and nystagmus, electrophysiologic auditory-evoked potentials, central auditory function, and calibration of measurement equipment used for such purposes.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Habilitate and rehabilitate, including, but not limited to, hearing aid evaluation, prescription, preparation, fitting and dispensing, assistive listening device selection and orientation, auditory training, aural habilitation, aural rehabilitation, speech conservation, and speechreading.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fabricate earmolds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate tinnitus.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include speech and language screening, limited to a pass/fail determination for identifying individuals with disorders of communication.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of speech-language pathology” means the application of principles, methods, and procedures for the prevention, identification, evaluation, treatment, consultation, habilitation, rehabilitation, instruction, and research, relative to the development and disorders of human communication; to related oral and pharyngeal competencies; and to behavior related to disorders of human communication. “Disorders” are defined to include any and all conditions, whether of organic or nonorganic origin, that impede the normal process of human communication, including, but not limited to, disorders and related disorders of speech, phonology, articulation, fluency, voice, accent, verbal and written language and related nonoral/nonverbal forms of language, cognitive communication, auditory and visual processing, memory and comprehension, interactive communication, mastication, deglutition, and other oral, pharyngeal, and laryngeal sensorimotor competencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any speech-language pathologist who has complied with the provisions of this part may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offer, render, plan, direct, conduct, and supervise services to individuals or groups of individuals who have or are suspected of having disorders of human communication, including identification, evaluation, treatment, consultation, habilitation, rehabilitation, amelioration, instruction, and research.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the need for personal alternatives or augmentative systems, and recommend and train for the utilization of such systems.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform a hearing screening, limited to a pass/fail determination, for the purpose of initial identification of communication disorders.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Speech-language pathologist” means a person licensed under this part to practice speech pathology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct supervision” means responsible supervision and control by a licensed speech-language pathologist who shall assume legal liability for the services rendered by any certified speech-language pathology assistant under the licensee’s supervision, or responsible supervision and control by a licensed audiologist who shall assume legal liability for the services rendered by any certified audiology assistant under the licensee’s supervision. Direct supervision shall require the physical presence of the licensed speech-language pathologist for consultation and direction of the actions of the certified speech-language pathology assistant, or the physical presence of the licensed audiologist for consultation and direction of the actions of the certified audiology assistant, unless the assistant is acting under protocols established by the board. The board shall establish rules further defining direct supervision of a certified speech-language pathology assistant or a certified audiology assistant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 31, ch. 90-134; s. 21, ch. 90-341; ss. 1, 10, ch. 90-345; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 101, ch. 92-149; s. 130, ch. 94-218; s. 112, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>