<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0468.358" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by endorsement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure as a certified respiratory therapist shall be granted by endorsement to an individual who holds the “Certified Respiratory Therapist” credential issued by the National Board for Respiratory Care or an equivalent credential acceptable to the board. Licensure by this mechanism requires verification by oath and submission of evidence satisfactory to the board that such credential is held.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure as a registered respiratory therapist shall be granted by endorsement to an individual who holds the “Registered Respiratory Therapist” credential issued by the National Board for Respiratory Care or an equivalent credential acceptable to the board. Licensure by this mechanism requires verification by oath and submission of evidence satisfactory to the board that such credential is held.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who has been granted licensure, certification, registration, or other authority, by whatever name known, to deliver respiratory care services in another state or country may petition the board for consideration for licensure in this state and, upon verification by oath and submission of evidence of licensure, certification, registration, or other authority acceptable to the board, may be granted licensure by endorsement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure shall not be granted by endorsement as provided in this section without the submission of a proper application and the payment of the requisite fees therefor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, ch. 84-252; s. 6, ch. 86-60; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 135, ch. 97-264; s. 112, ch. 2001-277.</History></Section>