<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0210.276" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Surcharge on tobacco products.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A surcharge is levied upon all tobacco products in this state and upon any person engaged in business as a distributor of tobacco products at the rate of 60 percent of the wholesale sales price. The surcharge shall be levied at the time the distributor:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Brings or causes to be brought into this state from without the state tobacco products for sale;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes, manufactures, or fabricates tobacco products in this state for sale in this state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ships or transports tobacco products to retailers in this state, to be sold by those retailers. A surcharge may not be levied on tobacco products shipped or transported outside this state for sale or use outside this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A surcharge is imposed upon the use or storage by consumers of tobacco products in this state and upon such consumers at the rate of 60 percent of the wholesale sales price. The surcharge imposed by this subsection does not apply if the surcharge imposed by subsection (1) on such tobacco products has been paid. This surcharge does not apply to the use or storage of tobacco products in quantities of less than 1 pound in the possession of any one consumer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any tobacco product with respect to which a surcharge has once been imposed under this section is not again subject to surcharge under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No surcharge shall be imposed by this section upon tobacco products not within the taxing power of the state under the Commerce Clause of the United States Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemptions provided for cigarettes under s. 210.04(4) also apply to tobacco products subject to a surcharge under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surcharge levied under this section shall be administered, collected, and enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed under s. 210.30.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenue produced from the surcharge levied under this section shall be deposited into the Health Care Trust Fund within the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2009-79.</History>
</Section>