<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0210.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination of tax on failure to file a return.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a dealer fails to file any return required under this part, or having filed an incorrect or insufficient return, fails to file a correct or sufficient return, as the case may require, within 10 days after the giving of notice to the dealer by the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco that such return or corrected or sufficient return is required, the division shall determine the amount of tax due by such dealer any time within 3 years after the making of the earliest sale included in such determination and give written notice of such determination to such dealer. Such a determination shall finally and irrevocably fix the tax unless the dealer against whom it is assessed shall, within 30 days after the giving of notice of such determination, apply to the division for a hearing. Judicial review shall not be granted unless the amount of tax stated in the decision, with penalties thereon, if any, shall have been first deposited with the division, and an undertaking or bond filed in the court in which such cause may be pending in such amount and with such sureties as the court shall approve, conditioned that if such proceeding be dismissed or the decision of the division confirmed, the applicant for review will pay all costs and charges which may accrue against the applicant in the prosecution of the proceeding. At the option of the applicant, such undertaking or bond may be in an additional sum sufficient to cover the tax, penalties, costs, and charges aforesaid, in which event the applicant shall not be required to pay such tax and penalties precedent to the granting of such review by such court.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 21946, 1943; s. 13, ch. 22645, 1945; s. 1, ch. 26320, 1949; s. 1, ch. 63-512; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 9, ch. 78-95; s. 10, ch. 87-86; s. 1097, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>