<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0210.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cigarette surcharge levied; collection.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A surcharge, in addition to all other taxes of every kind levied by law, is levied upon the sale, receipt, purchase, possession, consumption, handling, distribution, and use of cigarettes in this state, in the following amounts, except as otherwise provided in subsections (2)-(5), for cigarettes of standard dimensions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon all cigarettes weighing not more than 3 pounds per thousand, 5 cents on each cigarette.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon all cigarettes weighing more than 3 pounds per thousand and not more than 6 inches long, 10 cents on each cigarette.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon all cigarettes weighing more than 3 pounds per thousand and more than 6 inches long, 20 cents on each cigarette.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The descriptions of cigarettes contained in subsection (1) are declared to be standard as to dimensions for the purpose of levying a surcharge as provided in this section. If any cigarette is received, purchased, possessed, sold, offered for sale, given away, or used which is of a size other than those standard dimensions, the cigarette is subject to a surcharge at the rate of 4.2 cents on each cigarette.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When cigarettes as described in paragraph (1)(a) are packed in varying quantities of 20 cigarettes or fewer, except the manufacturer’s free samples authorized under s. 210.04(9), the following rates shall govern:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Packages containing 10 cigarettes or fewer require a surcharge of 50 cents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Packages containing more than 10 but not more than 20 cigarettes require a surcharge of $1.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When cigarettes as described in paragraph (1)(b) are packed in varying quantities of 20 cigarettes or fewer, except the manufacturer’s free samples authorized under s. 210.04(9), the following rates shall govern:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Packages containing 10 cigarettes or fewer require a surcharge of $1.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Packages containing more than 10 but not more than 20 cigarettes require a surcharge of $2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When cigarettes as described in paragraph (1)(c) are packed in varying quantities of 20 cigarettes or fewer, except the manufacturer’s free samples authorized under s. 210.04(9), the following rates shall govern:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Packages containing 10 cigarettes or fewer require a surcharge of $2.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Packages containing more than 10 but not more than 20 cigarettes require a surcharge of $4.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This surcharge shall be paid by the dealer to the division for deposit and distribution as hereinafter provided upon the first sale or transaction within the state, whether such sale or transfer is to the ultimate purchaser or consumer. The seller or dealer shall collect the surcharge from the purchaser or consumer, and the purchaser or consumer shall pay the surcharge to the seller. The seller or dealer is responsible for the collection of the surcharge and payment of the surcharge to the division. All surcharges are due not later than the 10th day of the month following the calendar month in which they were incurred, and thereafter shall bear interest at the rate of 1 percent per month. If the amount of surcharge due for a given period is assessed without allocating it to any particular month, the interest begins accruing on the date of the assessment. Whenever cigarettes are shipped from outside the state to anyone other than a distributing agent or wholesale dealer, the person receiving the cigarettes is responsible for the surcharge on the cigarettes and payment of the surcharge to the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the legislative intent that the surcharge on cigarettes be uniform throughout the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surcharge levied under this section shall be administered, collected, and enforced in the same manner as the tax imposed under s. 210.02.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenue produced from the surcharge levied under this section shall be deposited into the Health Care Trust Fund within the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2009-79.</History>
</Section>