<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0210.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Warrant for collection of taxes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to all other remedies for the collection of any taxes due under the provisions of this part, the division may issue a warrant under its official seal, which warrant may be filed by the division in the office of the clerk of the circuit court of any county where the delinquent taxpayer owns property. Upon presentation of the warrant, the clerk of the circuit court shall enter it in the judgment docket. The name of the person mentioned in the warrant, the amount of the tax and penalties for which the warrant was issued, and the date such copy was filed shall be included in the record of the warrant. The clerk shall be allowed the same fees as are allowed by law for similar services rendered in judgment execution proceedings. The warrant issued by the division may then be directed to the sheriff of any county commanding that sheriff to levy upon and sell the goods and chattels of the specified delinquent person found within the sheriff’s jurisdiction, for the payment of the amount of such delinquency plus a penalty equal to 50 percent of the amount thereof, and interest on the total at 1 percent per month and the cost of executing the warrant, and to return such warrant to the division and to pay it the money collected by virtue thereof within 60 days after receipt of such warrant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the warrant docketed pursuant to subsection (1) shall become a lien upon the title to or the interest in real or personal property of the person against whom the warrant is issued. The sheriff to whom any such warrant is directed shall proceed upon the warrant in all respects and with like effect and in the same manner as prescribed by law in respect to executions issued against goods and chattels upon judgments by a court of record, and the sheriff shall be entitled to the same fees for his or her services in executing the warrant to be collected in the same manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the discretion of the division, a warrant of like terms, force, and effect may be issued and directed to any officer or employee of the division; and in the execution thereof such officer or employee shall have all the power conferred by law upon sheriffs, but shall be entitled to no fee or compensation in excess of the actual expenses paid in the performance of such duty. If a warrant is returned not satisfied in full, the division may from time to time issue new warrants and shall also have the same remedies to enforce the amount due thereunder as if the state had recovered judgment therefor and execution thereon had been returned satisfied.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 21946, 1943; s. 14, ch. 22645, 1945; s. 1, ch. 26320, 1949; s. 6, ch. 29884, 1955; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 8, ch. 76-261; s. 11, ch. 79-11; s. 9, ch. 82-118; s. 11, ch. 87-86; s. 1098, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>