<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0210.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation or suspension of permit.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco is given full power and authority to revoke the permit of any person receiving a permit to engage in business under this part or chapter 569 for violation of any of the provisions of this part or chapter 569.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall revoke the permit or permits of any person who would be ineligible to obtain a new license or renew a license by reason of any of the conditions for permitting provided in s. 210.15(1)(c)1.-6.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may suspend for a reasonable period of time or revoke, in its discretion, the permits issued under the provisions of this part or chapter 569 to any person who has violated any other provision of this part or chapter 569.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the discretion of the wholesale dealer making the sale, credit for the sale of tobacco products may be extended to a retail dealer that has been issued a permit pursuant to chapter 569. Upon submission of proof to the division by a wholesale dealer, the division shall suspend or deny the renewal of a retail permit to any person or, if a corporation, to any officer or stockholder of the corporation who has failed to satisfy the terms of a civil judgment obtained against the person, corporation, officer, or stockholder for failure to pay for tobacco products purchased from a wholesale dealer. The permit shall remain suspended until the retail dealer submits proof to the division that it has entered into an agreed payment plan with the wholesale dealer or satisfied the civil judgment in full.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person whose permit for any place of business has been revoked shall engage in business under this part or chapter 569 at such place of business after such revocation until a new permit is issued. No person whose permit for any place of business has been revoked shall be permitted to have said permit renewed, or to obtain an additional cigarette permit for any other place of business, for a period of 2 years after the date such revocation becomes final.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the suspension or revocation of permits, the division may impose civil penalties against holders of permits for violations of this part or rules and regulations relating thereto. No civil penalty so imposed shall exceed $2,500 for each offense, and all amounts collected shall be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the General Revenue Fund. If the holder of the permit fails to pay the civil penalty, his or her permit shall be suspended for such period of time as the division may specify.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 21946, 1943; s. 15, ch. 22645, 1945; s. 1, ch. 26320, 1949; s. 1, ch. 63-512; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-159; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 9, ch. 78-95; ss. 2, 3, ch. 78-351; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 13, ch. 87-86; s. 2, ch. 91-97; s. 1100, ch. 95-147; s. 180, ch. 2003-261; s. 9, ch. 2005-228; s. 1, ch. 2012-72.</History>
</Section>