<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0280.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for public depositors; notice to public depositors and governmental units; loss of protection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other requirement specified in this chapter, public depositors shall comply with the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each official custodian of moneys that meet the definition of a public deposit under s. 280.02 shall ensure such moneys are placed in a qualified public depository unless the moneys are exempt under the laws of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each depositor, asserting that moneys meet the definition of a public deposit provided in s. 280.02 and are not exempt under the laws of this state, is responsible for any research or defense required to support such assertion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 1998, each public depositor shall take the following actions for each public deposit account:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the name of the public depositor is on the account or certificate or other form provided to the public depositor by the qualified public depository in a manner sufficient to identify that the account is a Florida public deposit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute a form prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer for identification of each public deposit account and obtain acknowledgment of receipt on the form from the qualified public depository at the time of opening the account. Such public deposit identification and acknowledgment form shall be replaced with a current form as required in subsection (3). A public deposit account existing before July 1, 1998, must have a form completed before September 30, 1998.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain the current public deposit identification and acknowledgment form as a valuable record. Such form is mandatory for filing a claim with the Chief Financial Officer upon default or insolvency of a qualified public depository.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public depositor shall review the Chief Financial Officer’s published list of qualified public depositories and ascertain the status of depositories used. A public depositor shall, for status changes of depositories:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute a replacement public deposit identification and acknowledgment form, as described in subsection (2), for each public deposit account when there is a merger, acquisition, name change, or other event which changes the account name, account number, or name of the qualified public depository.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Move and close public deposit accounts when an institution is not included in the authorized list of qualified public depositories or is shown as withdrawing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever public deposits are in a qualified public depository that has been declared to be in default or insolvent, each public depositor shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the Chief Financial Officer immediately by telecommunication after receiving notice of the default or insolvency from the receiver of the depository with subsequent written confirmation and a copy of the notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to the Chief Financial Officer for each public deposit, within 30 days after the date of official notification from the Chief Financial Officer, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim form and agreement, as prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer, executed under oath, accompanied by proof of authority to execute the form on behalf of the public depositor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A completed public deposit identification and acknowledgment form, as described in subsection (2).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of the insurance afforded the deposit pursuant to the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public depositor shall confirm annually that public deposit information as of the close of business on September 30 has been provided by each qualified public depository and is in agreement with public depositor records. Such confirmation shall include the federal employer identification number of the qualified public depository, the name on the deposit account record, the federal employer identification number on the deposit account record, and the account number, account type, and actual account balance on deposit. Public depositors shall request such confirmation information from qualified public depositories on or before the fifth calendar day of October and shall allow until October 31 to receive such information. Any discrepancy found in the confirmation process shall be reconciled before November 30.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public depositor shall submit, not later than November 30, an annual report to the Chief Financial Officer which shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The official name, mailing address, and federal employer identification number of the public depositor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Verification that confirmation of public deposit information as of September 30, as described in subsection (5), has been completed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public deposit information in a report format prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer. The manner of required filing may be as a signed writing or electronic data transmission, at the discretion of the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Confirmation that a current public deposit identification and acknowledgment form, as described in subsection (2), has been completed for each public deposit account and is in the possession of the public depositor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notices relating to the public deposits program shall be mailed to public depositors and governmental units from a list developed annually from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public depositors that filed an annual report under subsection (6).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Governmental units existing on September 30 that had no public deposits but filed an annual report stating “no public deposits”.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Governmental units established during the year that filed an annual report as a new governmental unit or otherwise furnished in writing to the Chief Financial Officer its official name, address, and federal employer identification number.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a public depositor does not comply with this section on each public deposit account, the protection from loss provided in s. 280.18 is not effective as to that public deposit account.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 87-409; s. 12, ch. 88-185; s. 24, ch. 91-244; s. 16, ch. 96-216; s. 18, ch. 98-409; s. 305, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>