<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0280.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Withdrawal from public deposits program; return of pledged collateral.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository may withdraw from the public deposits program by giving written notice to the Chief Financial Officer. The contingent liability, required collateral, and reporting requirements of the depository withdrawing from the program shall continue for a period of 12 months after the effective date of the withdrawal, except that the filing of reports may no longer be required when the average monthly balance of public deposits is equal to zero. Notice of withdrawal shall be mailed or delivered in sufficient time to be received by the Chief Financial Officer at least 30 days before the effective date of withdrawal. The Chief Financial Officer shall timely publish the withdrawal notice in the Florida Administrative Weekly which shall constitute notice to all depositors. The withdrawing depository shall not receive or retain public deposits after the effective date of the withdrawal until such time as it again becomes a qualified public depository. The Chief Financial Officer shall, upon request, return to the depository that portion of the collateral pledged that is in excess of the required collateral as reported on the current public depository monthly report. Losses of interest or other accumulations, if any, because of withdrawal under this section shall be assessed and paid as provided in s. 280.09.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository which has been disqualified pursuant to s. 280.051 shall not receive or retain public deposits after the effective date of the disqualification. Notice of and procedures for disqualification shall be made in accordance with ss. 280.052 and 280.053. The Chief Financial Officer shall, upon request, return to the depository that portion of the collateral pledged that is in excess of the required collateral as reported on the current public depository monthly report. Losses of interest or other accumulation, if any, because of disqualification shall be paid as provided in s. 280.09(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository which is required to withdraw from the public deposits program pursuant to s. 280.05(1)(b) shall not receive or retain public deposits after the effective date of withdrawal. The contingent liability, required collateral, and reporting requirements of the withdrawing depository shall continue until the effective date of withdrawal. Notice of withdrawal (order of discontinuance) from the Chief Financial Officer shall be mailed to the qualified public depository by registered or certified mail. Penalties incurred because of withdrawal from the public deposits program shall be the responsibility of the withdrawing depository.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 81-285; s. 13, ch. 83-122; s. 5, ch. 86-84; s. 17, ch. 87-409; s. 10, ch. 88-185; s. 10, ch. 90-357; s. 20, ch. 91-244; s. 13, ch. 96-216; s. 40, ch. 99-13; s. 13, ch. 2001-230; s. 302, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>