<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0280.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cease and desist order; corrective order; administrative penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer may issue a cease and desist order and a corrective order upon determining that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository has requested and obtained a release of pledged collateral without approval of the Chief Financial Officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank, savings association, or other financial institution is holding public deposits without a certificate of qualification issued by the Chief Financial Officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository pledges, deposits, or arranges for the issuance of unacceptable collateral;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A custodian has released pledged collateral without approval of the Chief Financial Officer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository or a custodian has not furnished to the Chief Financial Officer, when the Chief Financial Officer requested, a power of attorney or bond power or bond assignment form required by the bond agent or bond trustee for each issue of registered certificated securities pledged and registered in the name, or nominee name, of the qualified public depository or custodian; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository; a bank, savings association, or other financial institution; or a custodian has committed any other violation of this chapter or any rule adopted pursuant to this chapter that the Chief Financial Officer determines may be remedied by a cease and desist order or corrective order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any qualified public depository or other bank, savings association, or financial institution or custodian that violates a cease and desist order or corrective order of the Chief Financial Officer is subject to an administrative penalty not exceeding $1,000 for each violation of the order. Each day the violation of the order continues constitutes a separate violation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 87-409; s. 7, ch. 88-185; s. 7, ch. 2001-230; s. 294, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>