<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0280.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public Deposits Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to facilitate the administration of this chapter, there is created the Public Deposits Trust Fund, hereafter in this section designated “the fund.” The proceeds from the sale of securities or draw on letters of credit held as collateral or from any assessment pursuant to s. 280.08 shall be deposited into the fund. Any administrative penalty collected pursuant to this chapter shall be deposited into the Treasury Administrative and Investment Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer is authorized to pay any losses to public depositors from the fund, and there are hereby appropriated from the fund such sums as may be necessary from time to time to pay the losses. The term “losses,” for purposes of this chapter, shall also include losses of interest or other accumulations to the public depositor as a result of penalties for early withdrawal required by Depository Institution Deregulatory Commission Regulations or applicable successor federal laws or regulations because of suspension or disqualification of a qualified public depository by the Chief Financial Officer pursuant to s. 280.05 or because of withdrawal from the public deposits program pursuant to s. 280.11. In that event, the Chief Financial Officer is authorized to assess against the suspended, disqualified, or withdrawing public depository, in addition to any amount authorized by any other provision of this chapter, an administrative penalty equal to the amount of the early withdrawal penalty and to pay that amount over to the public depositor as reimbursement for such loss. Any money in the fund estimated not to be needed for immediate cash requirements shall be invested pursuant to s. 17.61.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-122; s. 6, ch. 85-259; s. 4, ch. 86-84; s. 17, ch. 87-331; s. 15, ch. 87-409; s. 9, ch. 88-185; s. 18, ch. 91-244; s. 11, ch. 96-216; s. 39, ch. 99-13; s. 11, ch. 2001-230; s. 300, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>