<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0280.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of merger, acquisition, or consolidation; change of name or address.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a qualified public depository is merged into, acquired by, or consolidated with a bank, savings bank, or savings association that is not a qualified public depository:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resulting institution shall automatically become a qualified public depository subject to the requirements of the public deposits program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contingent liability of the former institution shall be a liability of the resulting institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public deposits and associated collateral of the former institution shall be public deposits and collateral of the resulting institution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resulting institution shall, within 90 calendar days after the effective date of the merger, acquisition, or consolidation, deliver to the Chief Financial Officer:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation in its name as required for participation in the public deposits program; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written notice of intent to withdraw from the program as provided in s. 280.11 and a proposed effective date of withdrawal which shall be within 180 days after the effective date of the acquisition, merger, or consolidation of the former institution.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the resulting institution does not meet qualifications to become a qualified public depository or does not submit required documentation within 90 calendar days after the effective date of the merger, acquisition, or consolidation, the Chief Financial Officer shall initiate mandatory withdrawal actions as provided in s. 280.11 and shall set an effective date of withdrawal that is within 180 days after the effective date of the acquisition, merger, or consolidation of the former institution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a qualified public depository disposes of any of its Florida public deposits or collateral securing such deposits in a manner not covered by subsection (1), the qualified public depository originally holding the public deposits shall be responsible for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensuring the institution receiving such public deposits becomes a qualified public depository and meets collateral requirements with the Chief Financial Officer as part of the transaction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notifying the Chief Financial Officer within 30 calendar days after the final approval by the appropriate regulator.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A qualified public depository that fails to meet such responsibilities shall continue to collateralize and report such public deposits until the receiving institution becomes a qualified public depository and collateralizes the deposits or the deposits are returned to the governmental unit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The qualified public depository shall notify the Chief Financial Officer of any acquisition or merger within 30 calendar days after the final approval of the acquisition or merger by its appropriate regulator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collateral subject to a collateral agreement may not be released by the Chief Financial Officer or the custodian until the assumed liability is evidenced by the deposit of collateral pursuant to the collateral agreement of the successor entity. The reporting requirement and pledge of collateral will remain in force until the Chief Financial Officer determines that the liability no longer exists. The surviving or new qualified public depository shall be responsible and liable for all of the liabilities and obligations of each qualified public depository merged with or acquired by it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each qualified public depository shall report any change of name and address to the Chief Financial Officer on a form provided by the Chief Financial Officer regardless of whether the name change is a result of an acquisition, merger, or consolidation. Notification of such change must be made within 30 calendar days after the effective date of the change.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall adopt rules establishing procedures for mergers, acquisitions, consolidations, and changes in name and address, providing forms, and clarifying terms.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 83-122; s. 16, ch. 87-409; s. 9, ch. 90-357; s. 19, ch. 91-244; s. 12, ch. 96-216; s. 12, ch. 2001-230; s. 301, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>