<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0280.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for suspension or disqualification of a qualified public depository.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified public depository may be suspended or disqualified or both if the Chief Financial Officer determines that the qualified public depository has:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violated any of the provisions of this chapter or any rule adopted by the Chief Financial Officer pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted reports containing inaccurate or incomplete information regarding public deposits or collateral for such deposits, capital accounts, or the calculation of required collateral.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to maintain required collateral.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grossly misstated the market value of the securities pledged as collateral.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to pay any administrative penalty.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to furnish the Chief Financial Officer with prompt and accurate information, or failed to allow inspection and verification of any information, dealing with public deposits or dealing with the exact status of its capital accounts, or any other financial information that the Chief Financial Officer determines necessary to verify compliance with this chapter or any rule adopted pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to furnish the Chief Financial Officer, when the Chief Financial Officer requested, with a power of attorney or bond power or other bond assignment form required by the bond agent, bond trustee, or other transferor for each issue of registered certificated securities pledged.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to furnish any agreement, report, form, or other information required to be filed pursuant to s. 280.16, or when requested by the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted reports signed by an unauthorized individual.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted reports without a certified or verified signature, or both, if required by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Released a security without notice or approval.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to execute or have the custodian execute a public depository pledge agreement prior to using a custodian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failed to give notification as required by s. 280.10.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 87-409; s. 6, ch. 88-185; s. 13, ch. 91-244; s. 8, ch. 96-216; s. 5, ch. 2001-230; s. 290, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>