<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0280.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements of qualified public depositories; confidentiality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other requirements specified in this chapter, qualified public depositories shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take the following actions for each public deposit account:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the account as a “Florida public deposit” on the deposit account record with the name of the public depositor or provide a unique code for the account for such designation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the form prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer for acknowledgment of receipt of each public deposit account is presented to the qualified public depository by the public depositor opening an account, the qualified public depository shall execute and return the completed form to the public depositor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the acknowledgment of receipt form is presented to the qualified public depository by the public depositor due to a change of account name, account number, or qualified public depository name on an existing public deposit account, the qualified public depository shall execute and return the completed form to the public depositor within 45 calendar days after such presentation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the acknowledgment of receipt form is presented to the qualified public depository by the public depositor on an account existing before July 1, 1998, the qualified public depository shall execute and return the completed form to the public depositor within 45 calendar days after such presentation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 days after the end of each calendar month, or when requested by the Chief Financial Officer, submit to the Chief Financial Officer a written report, under oath, indicating the average daily balance of all public deposits held by it during the reported month, required collateral, a detailed schedule of all securities pledged as collateral, selected financial information, and any other information that the Chief Financial Officer determines necessary to administer this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to each public depositor annually, not later than October 30, the following information on all open accounts identified as a “Florida public deposit” for that public depositor as of September 30, to be used for confirmation purposes: the federal employer identification number of the qualified public depository, the name on the deposit account record, the federal employer identification number on the deposit account record, and the account number, account type, and actual account balance on deposit. Any discrepancy found in the confirmation process shall be reconciled before November 30.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to the Chief Financial Officer annually, not later than November 30, a report of all public deposits held for the credit of all public depositors at the close of business on September 30. Such annual report shall consist of public deposit information in a report format prescribed by the Chief Financial Officer. The manner of required filing may be as a signed writing or electronic data transmission, at the discretion of the Chief Financial Officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to the Chief Financial Officer not later than the date required to be filed with the federal agency:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the quarterly Consolidated Reports of Condition and Income, and any amended reports, required by the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 1811 et seq., if such depository is a bank; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the Thrift Financial Report, and any amended reports, required to be filed with the Office of Thrift Supervision if such depository is a savings and loan association.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following forms must be made under oath:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement of contingent liability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collateral control agreements and letter of credit agreements.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information contained in a report of a qualified public depository required under this chapter or any rule adopted under this chapter, together with any information required of a financial institution that is not a qualified public depository, shall, if made confidential by any law of the United States or of this state, be considered confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and not subject to dissemination to anyone other than the Chief Financial Officer under the provisions of this chapter; however, it is the responsibility of each qualified public depository and each financial institution from which information is required to inform the Chief Financial Officer of information that is confidential and the law providing for the confidentiality of that information, and the Chief Financial Officer does not have a duty to inquire into whether information is confidential.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 81-285; s. 16, ch. 83-122; s. 7, ch. 85-259; s. 6, ch. 86-84; s. 20, ch. 87-409; s. 11, ch. 88-185; s. 1, ch. 89-265; s. 23, ch. 91-244; s. 15, ch. 96-216; s. 129, ch. 96-406; s. 17, ch. 98-409; s. 15, ch. 2001-230; s. 304, ch. 2003-261; s. 22, ch. 2005-2.</History></Section>