<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0119.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Actual cost of duplication” means the cost of the material and supplies used to duplicate the public record, but does not include labor cost or overhead cost associated with such duplication.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means any state, county, district, authority, or municipal officer, department, division, board, bureau, commission, or other separate unit of government created or established by law including, for the purposes of this chapter, the Commission on Ethics, the Public Service Commission, and the Office of Public Counsel, and any other public or private agency, person, partnership, corporation, or business entity acting on behalf of any public agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Criminal intelligence information” means information with respect to an identifiable person or group of persons collected by a criminal justice agency in an effort to anticipate, prevent, or monitor possible criminal activity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Criminal investigative information” means information with respect to an identifiable person or group of persons compiled by a criminal justice agency in the course of conducting a criminal investigation of a specific act or omission, including, but not limited to, information derived from laboratory tests, reports of investigators or informants, or any type of surveillance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Criminal intelligence information” and “criminal investigative information” shall not include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time, date, location, and nature of a reported crime.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, sex, age, and address of a person arrested or of the victim of a crime except as provided in s. 119.071(2)(h).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time, date, and location of the incident and of the arrest.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The crime charged.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documents given or required by law or agency rule to be given to the person arrested, except as provided in s. 119.071(2)(h), and, except that the court in a criminal case may order that certain information required by law or agency rule to be given to the person arrested be maintained in a confidential manner and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until released at trial if it is found that the release of such information would:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be defamatory to the good name of a victim or witness or would jeopardize the safety of such victim or witness; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impair the ability of a state attorney to locate or prosecute a codefendant.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Informations and indictments except as provided in s. 905.26.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “active” shall have the following meaning:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal intelligence information shall be considered “active” as long as it is related to intelligence gathering conducted with a reasonable, good faith belief that it will lead to detection of ongoing or reasonably anticipated criminal activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal investigative information shall be considered “active” as long as it is related to an ongoing investigation which is continuing with a reasonable, good faith anticipation of securing an arrest or prosecution in the foreseeable future.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In addition, criminal intelligence and criminal investigative information shall be considered “active” while such information is directly related to pending prosecutions or appeals. The word “active” shall not apply to information in cases which are barred from prosecution under the provisions of s. 775.15 or other statute of limitation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Criminal justice agency” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement agency, court, or prosecutor;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other agency charged by law with criminal law enforcement duties;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agency having custody of criminal intelligence information or criminal investigative information for the purpose of assisting such law enforcement agencies in the conduct of active criminal investigation or prosecution or for the purpose of litigating civil actions under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organization Act, during the time that such agencies are in possession of criminal intelligence information or criminal investigative information pursuant to their criminal law enforcement duties; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Custodian of public records” means the elected or appointed state, county, or municipal officer charged with the responsibility of maintaining the office having public records, or his or her designee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Data processing software” means the programs and routines used to employ and control the capabilities of data processing hardware, including, but not limited to, operating systems, compilers, assemblers, utilities, library routines, maintenance routines, applications, and computer networking programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Duplicated copies” means new copies produced by duplicating, as defined in s. 283.30.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exemption” means a provision of general law which provides that a specified record or meeting, or portion thereof, is not subject to the access requirements of s. 119.07(1), s. 286.011, or s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Information technology resources” means data processing hardware and software and services, communications, supplies, personnel, facility resources, maintenance, and training.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Paratransit” has the same meaning as provided in s. 427.011.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proprietary software” means data processing software that is protected by copyright or trade secret laws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public records” means all documents, papers, letters, maps, books, tapes, photographs, films, sound recordings, data processing software, or other material, regardless of the physical form, characteristics, or means of transmission, made or received pursuant to law or ordinance or in connection with the transaction of official business by any agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Redact” means to conceal from a copy of an original public record, or to conceal from an electronic image that is available for public viewing, that portion of the record containing exempt or confidential information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sensitive,” for purposes of defining agency-produced software that is sensitive, means only those portions of data processing software, including the specifications and documentation, which are used to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect, process, store, and retrieve information that is exempt from s. 119.07(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collect, process, store, and retrieve financial management information of the agency, such as payroll and accounting records; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Control and direct access authorizations and security measures for automated systems.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-125; s. 2, ch. 73-98; s. 3, ch. 75-225; ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-187; s. 8, ch. 85-53; s. 1, ch. 88-188; s. 5, ch. 93-404; s. 5, ch. 93-405; s. 5, ch. 95-207; s. 6, ch. 95-296; s. 10, ch. 95-398; s. 40, ch. 96-406; s. 2, ch. 97-90; s. 3, ch. 2004-335; s. 43, ch. 2005-251; s. 1, ch. 2008-57.</History></Section>