<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0119.0712" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Executive branch agency-specific exemptions from inspection or copying of public records.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH.<EmDash />All personal identifying information contained in records relating to an individual’s personal health or eligibility for health-related services held by the Department of Health is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution, except as otherwise provided in this subsection. Information made confidential and exempt by this subsection shall be disclosed:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the express written consent of the individual or the individual’s legally authorized representative.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a medical emergency, but only to the extent necessary to protect the health or life of the individual.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By court order upon a showing of good cause.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a health research entity, if the entity seeks the records or data pursuant to a research protocol approved by the department, maintains the records or data in accordance with the approved protocol, and enters into a purchase and data-use agreement with the department, the fee provisions of which are consistent with s. 119.07(4). The department may deny a request for records or data if the protocol provides for intrusive follow-back contacts, has not been approved by a human studies institutional review board, does not plan for the destruction of confidential records after the research is concluded, is administratively burdensome, or does not have scientific merit. The agreement must restrict the release of any information that would permit the identification of persons, limit the use of records or data to the approved research protocol, and prohibit any other use of the records or data. Copies of records or data issued pursuant to this paragraph remain the property of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAY SAFETY AND MOTOR VEHICLES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, the term “motor vehicle record” means any record that pertains to a motor vehicle operator’s permit, motor vehicle title, motor vehicle registration, or identification card issued by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal information, including highly restricted personal information as defined in 18 U.S.C. s. 2725, contained in a motor vehicle record is confidential pursuant to the federal Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994, 18 U.S.C. ss. 2721 et seq. Such information may be released only as authorized by that act; however, information received pursuant to that act may not be used for mass commercial solicitation of clients for litigation against motor vehicle dealers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Emergency contact information contained in a motor vehicle record is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without the express consent of the person to whom such emergency contact information applies, the emergency contact information contained in a motor vehicle record may be released only to law enforcement agencies for purposes of contacting those listed in the event of an emergency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules to carry out the purposes of this subsection and the federal Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994, 18 U.S.C. ss. 2721 et seq. Rules adopted by the department may provide for the payment of applicable fees and, prior to the disclosure of personal information pursuant to this subsection or the federal Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994, 18 U.S.C. ss. 2721 et seq., may require the meeting of conditions by the requesting person for the purposes of obtaining reasonable assurance concerning the identity of such requesting person, and, to the extent required, assurance that the use will be only as authorized or that the consent of the person who is the subject of the personal information has been obtained. Such conditions may include, but need not be limited to, the making and filing of a written application in such form and containing such information and certification requirements as the department requires.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OFFICE OF FINANCIAL REGULATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following information held by the Office of Financial Regulation before, on, or after July 1, 2011, is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information received from another state or federal regulatory, administrative, or criminal justice agency that is otherwise confidential or exempt pursuant to the laws of that state or pursuant to federal law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information that is received or developed by the office as part of a joint or multiagency examination or investigation with another state or federal regulatory, administrative, or criminal justice agency. The office may obtain and use the information in accordance with the conditions imposed by the joint or multiagency agreement. This exemption does not apply to information obtained or developed by the office that would otherwise be available for public inspection if the office had conducted an independent examination or investigation under Florida law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15 and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2016, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-185; s. 1, ch. 2001-108; ss. 1, 2, ch. 2004-62; s. 7, ch. 2004-335; ss. 32, 33, ch. 2005-251; s. 1, ch. 2006-199; s. 1, ch. 2007-94; ss. 1, 2, ch. 2009-153; s. 1, ch. 2011-88.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Additional exemptions from the application of this section appear in the General Index to the Florida Statutes under the heading “Public Records.”</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Former s. 119.07(6)(aa), (cc).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>