<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0119.0711" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Executive branch agency exemptions from inspection or copying of public records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an agency of the executive branch of state government seeks to acquire real property by purchase or through the exercise of the power of eminent domain, all appraisals, other reports relating to value, offers, and counteroffers must be in writing and are exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution until execution of a valid option contract or a written offer to sell that has been conditionally accepted by the agency, at which time the exemption shall expire. The agency shall not finally accept the offer for a period of 30 days in order to allow public review of the transaction. The agency may give conditional acceptance to any option or offer subject only to final acceptance by the agency after the 30-day review period. If a valid option contract is not executed, or if a written offer to sell is not conditionally accepted by the agency, then the exemption shall expire at the conclusion of the condemnation litigation of the subject property. An agency of the executive branch may exempt title information, including names and addresses of property owners whose property is subject to acquisition by purchase or through the exercise of the power of eminent domain, from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution to the same extent as appraisals, other reports relating to value, offers, and counteroffers. For the purpose of this subsection, the term “option contract” means an agreement of an agency of the executive branch of state government to purchase real property subject to final agency approval. This subsection has no application to other exemptions from s. 119.07(1) which are contained in other provisions of law and shall not be construed to be an express or implied repeal thereof.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 85-18; s. 1, ch. 86-21; s. 1, ch. 89-29; ss. 19, 25, ch. 95-398; s. 7, ch. 2004-335; ss. 30, 31, ch. 2005-251; s. 1, ch. 2008-145.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Additional exemptions from the application of this section appear in the General Index to the Florida Statutes under the heading “Public Records.”</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Former s. 119.07(6)(n), (q).</Text></Note></Section>