<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0119.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative review of exemptions from public meeting and public records requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Open Government Sunset Review Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section provides for the review and repeal or reenactment of an exemption from s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution and s. 119.07(1) or s. 286.011. This act does not apply to an exemption that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is required by federal law; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applies solely to the Legislature or the State Court System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the 5th year after enactment of a new exemption or substantial amendment of an existing exemption, the exemption shall be repealed on October 2nd of the 5th year, unless the Legislature acts to reenact the exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A law that enacts a new exemption or substantially amends an existing exemption must state that the record or meeting is:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exempt from s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exempt from s. 119.07(1) or s. 286.011; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed at the end of 5 years and that the exemption must be reviewed by the Legislature before the scheduled repeal date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, an exemption is substantially amended if the amendment expands the scope of the exemption to include more records or information or to include meetings as well as records. An exemption is not substantially amended if the amendment narrows the scope of the exemption.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is not intended to repeal an exemption that has been amended following legislative review before the scheduled repeal of the exemption if the exemption is not substantially amended as a result of the review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By June 1 in the year before the repeal of an exemption under this section, the Office of Legislative Services shall certify to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives the language and statutory citation of each exemption scheduled for repeal the following year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An exemption that is not identified and certified to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives is not subject to legislative review and repeal under this section. If the office fails to certify an exemption that it subsequently determines should have been certified, it shall include the exemption in the following year’s certification after that determination.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of the review process, the Legislature shall consider the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What specific records or meetings are affected by the exemption?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whom does the exemption uniquely affect, as opposed to the general public?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">What is the identifiable public purpose or goal of the exemption?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Can the information contained in the records or discussed in the meeting be readily obtained by alternative means? If so, how?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is the record or meeting protected by another exemption?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are there multiple exemptions for the same type of record or meeting that it would be appropriate to merge?</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An exemption may be created, revised, or maintained only if it serves an identifiable public purpose, and the exemption may be no broader than is necessary to meet the public purpose it serves. An identifiable public purpose is served if the exemption meets one of the following purposes and the Legislature finds that the purpose is sufficiently compelling to override the strong public policy of open government and cannot be accomplished without the exemption:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allows the state or its political subdivisions to effectively and efficiently administer a governmental program, which administration would be significantly impaired without the exemption;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protects information of a sensitive personal nature concerning individuals, the release of which information would be defamatory to such individuals or cause unwarranted damage to the good name or reputation of such individuals or would jeopardize the safety of such individuals. However, in exemptions under this subparagraph, only information that would identify the individuals may be exempted; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protects information of a confidential nature concerning entities, including, but not limited to, a formula, pattern, device, combination of devices, or compilation of information which is used to protect or further a business advantage over those who do not know or use it, the disclosure of which information would injure the affected entity in the marketplace.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records made before the date of a repeal of an exemption under this section may not be made public unless otherwise provided by law. In deciding whether the records shall be made public, the Legislature shall consider whether the damage or loss to persons or entities uniquely affected by the exemption of the type specified in subparagraph (6)(b)2. or subparagraph (6)(b)3. would occur if the records were made public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 768.28 or any other law, neither the state or its political subdivisions nor any other public body shall be made party to any suit in any court or incur any liability for the repeal or revival and reenactment of an exemption under this section. The failure of the Legislature to comply strictly with this section does not invalidate an otherwise valid reenactment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 95-217; s. 25, ch. 98-136; s. 37, ch. 2005-251; s. 15, ch. 2006-1; s. 5, ch. 2012-51.</History>
</Section>