<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.078" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bylaws of homeowners’ associations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order for a homeowners’ association to exercise the rights provided in s. 723.071, the bylaws of the association shall provide for the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The directors of the association and the operation shall be governed by the bylaws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bylaws shall provide and, if they do not, shall be deemed to include, the following provisions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The form of administration of the association shall be described, providing for the titles of the officers and for a board of directors and specifying the powers, duties, manner of selection and removal, and compensation, if any, of officers and board members. Unless otherwise provided in the bylaws, the board of directors shall be composed of five members. The board of directors shall have a president, secretary, and treasurer who shall perform the duties of those offices customarily performed by officers of corporations, and these officers shall serve without compensation and at the pleasure of the board of directors. The board of directors may appoint and designate other officers and grant them those duties it deems appropriate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. Decisions shall be made by a majority of members represented at a meeting at which a quorum is present. In addition, provision shall be made in the bylaws for definition and use of proxy. Any proxy given shall be effective only for the specific meeting for which originally given and any lawfully adjourned meetings thereof. In no event shall any proxy be valid for a period longer than 120 days after the date of the first meeting for which it was given. Every proxy shall be revocable at any time at the pleasure of the member executing it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meetings of the board of directors shall be open to all members, and notice of meetings shall be posted in a conspicuous place upon the park property at least 48 hours in advance, except in an emergency. Notice of any meeting in which assessments against members are to be considered for any reason shall specifically contain a statement that assessments will be considered and the nature of such assessments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members shall meet at least once each calendar year, and the meeting shall be the annual meeting. All members of the board of directors shall be elected at the annual meeting unless the bylaws provide for staggered election terms or for their election at another meeting. The bylaws shall not restrict any member desiring to be a candidate for board membership from being nominated from the floor. The bylaws shall provide the method for calling the meetings of the members, including annual meetings. The method shall provide at least 14 days’ written notice to each member in advance of the meeting and require the posting in a conspicuous place on the park property of a notice of the meeting at least 14 days prior to the meeting. The right to receive written notice of membership meetings may be waived in writing by a member. Unless waived, the notice of the annual meeting shall be sent by mail to each member, and the mailing constitutes notice. An officer of the association shall provide an affidavit affirming that the notices were mailed or hand delivered in accordance with the provisions of this section to each member at the address last furnished to the corporation. These meeting requirements do not prevent members from waiving notice of meetings or from acting by written agreement without meetings, if allowed by the bylaws.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Minutes of all meetings of members and of the board of directors shall be kept in a businesslike manner and shall be available for inspection by members, or their authorized representatives, and board members at reasonable times. The association shall retain these minutes for a period of not less than 7 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The share or percentage of, and manner of sharing, assessments and expenses for each member shall be stated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the bylaws provide for adoption of an annual budget by the members, the board of directors shall mail a meeting notice and copies of the proposed annual budget of expenses to the members not less than 30 days prior to the meeting at which the budget will be considered. If the bylaws provide that the budget may be adopted by the board of directors, the members shall be given written notice of the time and place at which the meeting of the board of directors to consider the budget will be held. The meeting shall be open to the members. If the bylaws do not provide for adoption of an annual budget, this paragraph shall not apply.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The method by which the bylaws may be amended consistent with the provisions of this chapter shall be stated. If the bylaws fail to provide a method of amendment, the bylaws may be amended by the board of directors and approved by a majority of the membership. No bylaw shall be revised or amended by reference to its title or number only.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officers and directors of the association have a fiduciary relationship to the members.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of the board of directors may be recalled and removed from office with or without cause by the vote of or agreement in writing by a majority of all members. A special meeting of the members to recall a member or members of the board of directors may be called by 10 percent of the members giving notice of the meeting as required for a meeting of members, and the notice shall state the purpose of the meeting.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bylaws may provide the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method of adopting and of amending administrative rules and regulations governing the details of the operation and use of the park property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restrictions on, and requirements respecting, the use and maintenance of mobile homes located within the park, and the use of the park property, which restrictions and requirements are not inconsistent with the articles of incorporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other provisions not inconsistent with this chapter or with other documents governing the park property or mobile homes located therein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors may, in any event, propose a budget to the members at a meeting of members or in writing, and, if the budget or proposed budget is approved by the members at the meeting or by a majority of their whole number in writing, that budget shall be adopted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner of collecting from the members their shares of the expenses for maintenance of the park property shall be stated. Assessments shall be made against members not less frequently than quarterly, in amounts no less than are required to provide funds in advance for payments of all of the anticipated current operating expenses and for all of the unpaid operating expense previously incurred.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No amendment may change the proportion or percentage by which members share in the assessments and expenses as initially established unless all the members affected by such change approve the amendment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon purchase of the mobile home park, the association organized under this chapter may convert to a condominium, cooperative, or subdivision. The directors shall have the authority to amend and restate the articles of incorporation and bylaws in order to comply with the requirements of chapter 718, chapter 719, or other applicable sections of the Florida Statutes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 723.075(1), upon purchase of the park by the association, and conversion of the association to a condominium, cooperative, or subdivision, the mobile home owners who were members of the association prior to the conversion and who no longer meet the requirements for membership, as established by the amended or restated articles of incorporation and bylaws, shall no longer be members of the converted association. Mobile home owners, as defined in this chapter, who no longer are eligible for membership in the converted association may form an association pursuant to s. 723.075.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80; s. 61, ch. 85-62; s. 14, ch. 92-148.</History></Section>