<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prospectus or offering circular.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prospectus or offering circular, which is required to be provided by s. 723.011, must contain the following information:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The front cover or the first page must contain only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the mobile home park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statements in conspicuous type:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THIS PROSPECTUS CONTAINS VERY IMPORTANT INFORMATION REGARDING YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS AND YOUR FINANCIAL OBLIGATIONS IN LEASING A MOBILE HOME LOT. MAKE SURE THAT YOU READ THE ENTIRE DOCUMENT AND SEEK LEGAL ADVICE IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS REGARDING THE INFORMATION SET FORTH IN THIS DOCUMENT.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THE STATEMENTS CONTAINED HEREIN ARE ONLY SUMMARY IN NATURE. A PROSPECTIVE LESSEE SHOULD REFER TO ALL REFERENCES, ALL EXHIBITS HERETO, THE CONTRACT DOCUMENTS, AND SALES MATERIALS.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ORAL REPRESENTATIONS SHOULD NOT BE RELIED UPON AS CORRECTLY STATING THE REPRESENTATIONS OF THE PARK OWNER OR OPERATOR. REFER TO THIS PROSPECTUS (OFFERING CIRCULAR) AND ITS EXHIBITS FOR CORRECT REPRESENTATIONS.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UPON DELIVERY OF THE PROSPECTUS TO A PROSPECTIVE LESSEE, THE RENTAL AGREEMENT IS VOIDABLE BY THE LESSEE FOR A PERIOD OF 15 DAYS.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The next page must contain all statements required to be in conspicuous type in the prospectus or offering circular in a summary form.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate index of the contents and exhibits of the prospectus.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning on the first page of the text, the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address or location of the mobile home park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person authorized to receive notices and demands on the park owner’s behalf.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the mobile home park property, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of lots in each section, the approximate size of each lot, the setback requirements, and the minimum separation distance between mobile homes as required by law.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maximum number of lots that will use shared facilities of the park; and, if the maximum number of lots will vary, a description of the basis for variation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the recreational and other common facilities, if any, that will be used by the mobile home owners, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of buildings and each room thereof and its intended purposes, location, approximate floor area, and capacity in numbers of people.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each swimming pool, as to its general location, approximate size and depths, and approximate deck size and capacity and whether heated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All other facilities and permanent improvements which will serve the mobile home owners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general description of the items of personal property available for use by the mobile home owners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general description of the days and hours that facilities will be available for use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to whether all improvements are complete and, if not, their estimated completion dates.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The arrangements for management of the park and maintenance and operation of the park property and of other property that will serve the mobile home owners and the nature of the services included.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of all improvements, whether temporary or permanent, which are required to be installed by the mobile home owner as a condition of his or her occupancy in the park.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner in which utility and other services, including, but not limited to, sewage and waste disposal, cable television, water supply, and storm drainage, will be provided, and the person or entity furnishing them. The services and the lot rental amount or user fees charged by the park owner for the services provided by the park owner shall also be disclosed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An explanation of the manner in which the lot rental amount will be raised, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notification of the mobile home owner at least 90 days in advance of the increase.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosure of any factors which may affect the lot rental amount, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Water rates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sewer rates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Waste disposal rates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance costs, including costs of deferred maintenance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management costs.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property taxes.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Major repairs or improvements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other fees, costs, entrance fees, or charges to which the mobile home owner may be subjected.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosure of the manner in which the pass-through charges will be assessed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosure of all user fees currently charged for services offered which the homeowner may elect to incur and the manner in which the fees will be increased.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The park rules and regulations and an explanation of the manner in which park rules or regulations will be set, changed, or promulgated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement describing the existing zoning classification of the park property and permitted uses under such classification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the nature and type of zoning under which the mobile home park operates, the name of the zoning authority which has jurisdiction over the land comprising the mobile home park, and, if applicable, a detailed description of any definite future plans which the park owner has for changes in the use of the land comprising the mobile home park.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of the following, to the extent they are applicable, as exhibits:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ground lease or other underlying leases of the mobile home park or a summary of the contents of the lease or leases when copies of the same have been filed with the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the mobile home park lot layout showing the location of the recreational areas and other common areas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All covenants and restrictions and zoning which will affect the use of the property and which are not contained in the foregoing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the rental agreement or agreements to be offered for rental of mobile home lots.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80; s. 5, ch. 86-162; s. 12, ch. 88-147; s. 914, ch. 97-102; s. 4, ch. 2001-227.</History></Section>