<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sale of mobile home parks.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a mobile home park owner offers a mobile home park for sale, she or he shall notify the officers of the homeowners’ association created pursuant to ss. 723.075-723.079 of the offer, stating the price and the terms and conditions of sale.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mobile home owners, by and through the association defined in s. 723.075, shall have the right to purchase the park, provided the home owners meet the price and terms and conditions of the mobile home park owner by executing a contract with the park owner within 45 days, unless agreed to otherwise, from the date of mailing of the notice and provided they have complied with ss. 723.075-723.079. If a contract between the park owner and the association is not executed within such 45-day period, then, unless the park owner thereafter elects to offer the park at a price lower than the price specified in her or his notice to the officers of the homeowners’ association, the park owner has no further obligations under this subsection, and her or his only obligation shall be as set forth in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the park owner thereafter elects to offer the park at a price lower than the price specified in her or his notice to the home owners, the home owners, by and through the association, will have an additional 10 days to meet the price and terms and conditions of the park owner by executing a contract.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a mobile home park owner receives a bona fide offer to purchase the park that she or he intends to consider or make a counteroffer to, the park owner’s only obligation shall be to notify the officers of the homeowners’ association that she or he has received an offer and disclose the price and material terms and conditions upon which she or he would consider selling the park and consider any offer made by the home owners, provided the home owners have complied with ss. 723.075-723.079. The park owner shall be under no obligation to sell to the home owners or to interrupt or delay other negotiations and shall be free at any time to execute a contract for the sale of the park to a party or parties other than the home owners or the association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in subsections (1) and (2), the term “notify” means the placing of a notice in the United States mail addressed to the officers of the homeowners’ association. Each such notice shall be deemed to have been given upon the deposit of the notice in the United States mail.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in subsection (1), the term “offer” means any solicitation by the park owner to the general public.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any sale or transfer to a person who would be included within the table of descent and distribution if the park owner were to die intestate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transfer by gift, devise, or operation of law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transfer by a corporation to an affiliate. As used herein, the term “affiliate” means any shareholder of the transferring corporation; any corporation or entity owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by the transferring corporation; or any other corporation or entity owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by any shareholder of the transferring corporation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transfer by a partnership to any of its partners.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any conveyance of an interest in a mobile home park incidental to the financing of such mobile home park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any conveyance resulting from the foreclosure of a mortgage, deed of trust, or other instrument encumbering a mobile home park or any deed given in lieu of such foreclosure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any sale or transfer between or among joint tenants or tenants in common owning a mobile home park.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any exchange of a mobile home park for other real property, whether or not such exchange also involves the payment of cash or other boot.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchase of a mobile home park by a governmental entity under its powers of eminent domain.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80; s. 929, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>