<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.054" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of mobile home owners to peaceably assemble; right to communicate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision contained in any bylaw, rental agreement, regulation, or rule pertaining to a mobile home park shall infringe upon the right of the mobile home owners to peaceably assemble in an open public meeting for any lawful purpose, at reasonable times and in a reasonable manner, in the common areas or recreational areas of the mobile home park.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision contained in any bylaw, rental agreement, regulation, or rule pertaining to a mobile home park shall infringe upon the right of the mobile home owners or tenants to communicate or assemble among themselves, at reasonable times and in a reasonable manner, for the purpose of discussing any problems relative to the mobile home park. Such discussions may be held in the common areas or recreational areas of the park, including halls or centers, or in any resident’s mobile home. In addition, the park owner or developer may not unreasonably restrict the use of any facility, including the use of utilities, when requested.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No provision contained in any bylaw, rental agreement, regulation, or rule pertaining to a mobile home park shall prohibit any mobile home owner from canvassing mobile home owners for the purposes described in this subsection. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “canvassing” includes an oral or written request; the distribution, circulation, posting, or publication of a notice; or a general announcement requesting the payment of membership dues or other matters relevant to the membership of the park association, federation, or organization. Such canvassing shall be done at a reasonable time or times and in a reasonable manner. It is the intent of the Legislature, through the enactment of this subsection, to prohibit any owner, developer, or manager of a mobile home park from prohibiting free communication among mobile home owners or tenants in the guise of regulations or rules restricting or limiting canvassing for association, federation, or organization dues or other association, federation, or organization matters.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80.</History></Section>