<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclosure prior to rental of a mobile home lot; prospectus, filing, approval.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a mobile home park containing 26 or more lots, the park owner shall file a prospectus with the division. Prior to entering into an enforceable rental agreement for a mobile home lot, the park owner shall deliver to the homeowner a prospectus approved by the division. This subsection does not invalidate those lot rental agreements for which an approved prospectus was required to be delivered and which was delivered on or before July 1, 1986, if the mobile home park owner had:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filed a prospectus with the division prior to entering into the lot rental agreement;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Made a good faith effort to correct deficiencies cited by the division by responding within the time limit set by the division, if one was set; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delivered the approved prospectus to the mobile home owner within 45 days of approval by the division.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This paragraph does not preclude the finding that a lot rental agreement is invalid on other grounds and does not limit any rights of a mobile home owner or preclude a mobile home owner from seeking any remedies allowed by this chapter, including a determination that the lot rental agreement or any part thereof is unreasonable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall determine whether the proposed prospectus or offering circular is adequate to meet the requirements of this chapter and shall notify the park owner by mail, within 45 days after receipt of the document, that the division has found that the prospectus or offering circular is adequate or has found specified deficiencies. If the division does not make either finding within 45 days, the prospectus shall be deemed to have been found adequate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filings for mobile home parks in which lots have not been offered for lease prior to June 4, 1984, shall be accompanied by a filing fee of $10 per lot offered for lease by the park owner; however, the fee shall not be less than $100.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filings for mobile home parks in which lots have been offered for lease prior to the effective date of this chapter shall be accompanied by a filing fee as follows:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a park in which there are 26-50 lots: $100.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a park in which there are 51-100 lots: $150.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a park in which there are 101-150 lots: $200.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a park in which there are 151-200 lots: $250.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a park in which there are 201 or more lots: $300.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall maintain copies of each prospectus and all amendments to each prospectus which are considered adequate by the division. The division shall provide copies of documents requested in writing under this subsection within 10 days after the written request is received.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The park owner shall furnish a copy of the prospectus or offering circular together with all of the exhibits thereto to each prospective lessee. Delivery shall be made prior to execution of the lot rental agreement or at the time of occupancy, whichever occurs first. Upon delivery of a prospectus to a prospective lessee, the lot rental agreement is voidable by the lessee for a period of 15 days. However, the park owner is not required to furnish a copy of the prospectus or offering circular if the tenancy is a renewal of a tenancy and the mobile home owner has previously received the prospectus or offering circular.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prospectus or offering circular together with its exhibits is a disclosure document intended to afford protection to homeowners and prospective homeowners in the mobile home park. The purpose of the document is to disclose the representations of the mobile home park owner concerning the operations of the mobile home park.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With regard to a tenancy in existence on the effective date of this chapter, the prospectus or offering circular offered by the mobile home park owner shall contain the same terms and conditions as rental agreements offered to all other mobile home owners residing in the park on the effective date of this act, excepting only rent variations based upon lot location and size, and shall not require any mobile home owner to install any permanent improvements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mobile home park owner may request that the homeowner sign a receipt indicating that the homeowner has received a copy of the prospectus, the rules and regulations, and other pertinent documents so long as any such documents are clearly identified in the receipt itself. Such a receipt shall indicate nothing more than that the documents identified herein have been received by the mobile home owner. The receipt, if requested, shall be signed at the time of delivery of the identified documents. If the homeowner refuses to sign the receipt, the park owner shall still deliver to the homeowner a copy of the prospectus, rules and regulations, and any other documents which otherwise would have been delivered upon execution of the receipt. However, the homeowner shall thereafter be barred from claiming that the park owner has failed to deliver such documents. The refusal of the homeowner to sign the receipt shall under no circumstances constitute a ground for eviction of the homeowner or of a mobile home or for the imposition of any other penalty.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80; s. 4, ch. 86-162; s. 11, ch. 88-147; s. 5, ch. 90-198; s. 1, ch. 96-394; s. 3, ch. 2001-227.</History></Section>