<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0723.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Eviction; grounds, proceedings.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home park owner may evict a mobile home owner, a mobile home tenant, a mobile home occupant, or a mobile home only on one or more of the following grounds:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonpayment of the lot rental amount. If a mobile home owner or tenant, whichever is responsible, fails to pay the lot rental amount when due and if the default continues for 5 days after delivery of a written demand by the mobile home park owner for payment of the lot rental amount, the park owner may terminate the tenancy. However, if the mobile home owner or tenant, whichever is responsible, pays the lot rental amount due, including any late charges, court costs, and attorney’s fees, the court may, for good cause, deny the order of eviction, if such nonpayment has not occurred more than twice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conviction of a violation of a federal or state law or local ordinance, if the violation is detrimental to the health, safety, or welfare of other residents of the mobile home park. The mobile home owner or mobile home tenant must vacate the premises within 7 days after the date the notice to vacate is delivered. This paragraph constitutes grounds to deny an initial tenancy of a purchaser of a home under paragraph (e) or to evict an unapproved occupant of a home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of a park rule or regulation, the rental agreement, or this chapter.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the first violation of any properly promulgated rule or regulation, rental agreement provision, or this chapter which is found by any court of competent jurisdiction to have been an act that endangered the life, health, safety, or property of the park residents or employees or the peaceful enjoyment of the mobile home park by its residents, the mobile home park owner may terminate the rental agreement, and the mobile home owner, tenant, or occupant must vacate the premises within 7 days after the notice to vacate is delivered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second violation of the same properly promulgated rule or regulation, rental agreement provision, or this chapter within 12 months, the mobile home park owner may terminate the tenancy if she or he has given the mobile home owner, tenant, or occupant written notice, within 30 days after the first violation, which specified the actions of the mobile home owner, tenant, or occupant that caused the violation and gave the mobile home owner, tenant, or occupant 7 days to correct the noncompliance. The mobile home owner, tenant, or occupant must have received written notice of the ground upon which she or he is to be evicted at least 30 days prior to the date on which she or he is required to vacate. A second violation of a properly promulgated rule or regulation, rental agreement provision, or this chapter within 12 months of the first violation is unequivocally a ground for eviction, and it is not a defense to any eviction proceeding that a violation has been cured after the second violation. Violation of a rule or regulation, rental agreement provision, or this chapter more than 1 year after the first violation of the same rule or regulation, rental agreement provision, or this chapter does not constitute a ground for eviction under this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A properly promulgated rule or regulation may not be arbitrarily applied and used as a ground for eviction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Change in use of the land comprising the mobile home park, or the portion thereof from which mobile homes are to be evicted, from mobile home lot rentals to some other use, if:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The park owner gives written notice to the homeowners’ association formed and operating under ss. 723.075-723.079 of its right to purchase the mobile home park, if the land comprising the mobile home park is changing use from mobile home lot rentals to a different use, at the price and under the terms and conditions set forth in the written notice.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall be delivered to the officers of the homeowners’ association by United States mail. Within 45 days after the date of mailing of the notice, the homeowners’ association may execute and deliver a contract to the park owner to purchase the mobile home park at the price and under the terms and conditions set forth in the notice. If the contract between the park owner and the homeowners’ association is not executed and delivered to the park owner within the 45-day period, the park owner is under no further obligation to the homeowners’ association except as provided in sub-subparagraph b.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the park owner elects to offer or sell the mobile home park at a price lower than the price specified in her or his initial notice to the officers of the homeowners’ association, the homeowners’ association has an additional 10 days to meet the revised price, terms, and conditions of the park owner by executing and delivering a revised contract to the park owner.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The park owner is not obligated under this subparagraph or s. 723.071 to give any other notice to, or to further negotiate with, the homeowners’ association for the sale of the mobile home park to the homeowners’ association after 6 months after the date of the mailing of the initial notice under sub-subparagraph a.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The park owner gives the affected mobile home owners and tenants at least 6 months’ notice of the eviction due to the projected change in use and of their need to secure other accommodations.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice of eviction due to a change in use of the land must include in a font no smaller than the body of the notice the following statement:</Text>
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">YOU MAY BE ENTITLED TO COMPENSATION FROM THE FLORIDA MOBILE HOME RELOCATION TRUST FUND, ADMINISTERED BY THE FLORIDA MOBILE HOME RELOCATION CORPORATION (FMHRC). FMHRC CONTACT INFORMATION IS AVAILABLE FROM THE FLORIDA DEPARTMENT OF BUSINESS AND PROFESSIONAL REGULATION.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The park owner may not give a notice of increase in lot rental amount within 90 days before giving notice of a change in use.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the purchaser, prospective tenant, or occupant of a mobile home situated in the mobile home park to be qualified as, and to obtain approval to become, a tenant or occupant of the home, if such approval is required by a properly promulgated rule. If a purchaser or prospective tenant of a mobile home situated in the mobile home park occupies the mobile home before such approval is granted, the mobile home owner or mobile home tenant must vacate the premises within 7 days after the date the notice of the failure to be approved for tenancy is delivered.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of eviction for a change in use, homeowners must object to the change in use by petitioning for administrative or judicial remedies within 90 days after the date of the notice or they will be barred from taking any subsequent action to contest the change in use. This subsection does not prevent any homeowner from objecting to a zoning change at any time.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home park owner applying for the removal of a mobile home owner, tenant, or occupant or a mobile home shall file, in the county court in the county where the mobile home lot is situated, a complaint describing the lot and stating the facts that authorize the removal of the mobile home owner, tenant, or occupant or the mobile home. The park owner is entitled to the summary procedure provided in s. 51.011, and the court shall advance the cause on the calendar.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for the notice to the officers of the homeowners’ association under subparagraph (1)(d)1., any notice required by this section must be in writing, and must be posted on the premises and sent to the mobile home owner and tenant or occupant, as appropriate, by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, addressed to the mobile home owner and tenant or occupant, as appropriate, at her or his last known address. Delivery of the mailed notice shall be deemed given 5 days after the date of postmark.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80; s. 11, ch. 86-162; ss. 7, 8, ch. 87-117; ss. 2, 3, 4, ch. 87-150; s. 16, ch. 88-147; s. 3, ch. 91-66; s. 12, ch. 92-148; s. 925, ch. 97-102; s. 6, ch. 2001-227; s. 7, ch. 2003-263; s. 1, ch. 2007-47; s. 2, ch. 2011-105.</History>
</Section>