<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.0751" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mobile home subdivision homeowners’ association.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that no homeowners’ association has been created pursuant to ss. 720.301-720.312 to operate a mobile home subdivision, the owners of lots in such mobile home subdivision shall be authorized to create a mobile home subdivision homeowners’ association in the manner prescribed in ss. 723.075, 723.076, and 723.078 which shall have the powers and duties, to the extent applicable, set forth in ss. 723.002(2) and 723.074.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rights granted to the owners of lots in a mobile home subdivision in ss. 723.002(2) and 723.074 may be exercised through an association created or authorized pursuant to this section for the owners of lots who are members of the mobile home subdivision homeowners’ association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that the owners of lots in a mobile home subdivision share common areas, recreational facilities, roads, and other amenities with the owners of mobile homes in a mobile home park and the mobile home owners have created a mobile home owners’ association pursuant to ss. 723.075-723.079, said mobile home owners’ association shall be the authorized representative of owners of lots in said mobile home subdivision provided:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the mobile home owners’ association have, by majority vote, authorized the inclusion of subdivision lot owners in the mobile home park homeowners’ association; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owners of lots in the mobile home subdivision are entitled to vote only on matters that effect their rights contained in ss. 723.002(2) and 723.074.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 99-382; s. 57, ch. 2000-258.</History></Section>