<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.072" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Affidavit of compliance with statutory requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A park owner may at any time record, in the official records of the county where a mobile home park is situated, an affidavit in which the park owner certifies that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With reference to an offer by him or her for the sale of such park, he or she has complied with the provisions of s. 723.071(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With reference to an offer received by him or her for the purchase of such park, or with reference to a counteroffer which he or she intends to make, or has made, for the sale of such park, he or she has complied with the provisions of s. 723.071(2);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding his or her compliance with the provisions of either subsection (1) or subsection (2) of s. 723.071, no contract has been executed for the sale of such park between himself or herself and the park homeowners’ association;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsections (1) and (2) of s. 723.071 are inapplicable to a particular sale or transfer of such park by him or her, and compliance with such subsections is not required; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A particular sale or transfer of such park is exempted from the provisions of this section and s. 723.071.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any party acquiring an interest in a mobile home park, and any and all title insurance companies and attorneys preparing, furnishing, or examining any evidence of title, have the absolute right to rely on the truth and accuracy of all statements appearing in such affidavit and are under no obligation to inquire further as to any matter or fact relating to the park owner’s compliance with the provisions of s. 723.071.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the purpose and intention of this section to preserve the marketability of title to mobile home parks, and, accordingly, the provisions of this section shall be liberally construed in order that all persons may rely on the record title to mobile home parks.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80; s. 60, ch. 85-62; s. 930, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>