<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.06116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payments to the Florida Mobile Home Relocation Corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a mobile home owner is required to move due to a change in use of the land comprising a mobile home park as set forth in s. 723.061(1)(d), the mobile home park owner shall, upon such change in use, pay to the Florida Mobile Home Relocation Corporation for deposit in the Florida Mobile Home Relocation Trust Fund $2,750 for each single-section mobile home and $3,750 for each multisection mobile home for which a mobile home owner has made application for payment of moving expenses. The mobile home park owner shall make the payments required by this section and by s. 723.0612(7) to the corporation within 30 days after receipt from the corporation of the invoice for payment. Failure to make such payment within the required time period shall result in a late fee being imposed.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If payment is not submitted within 30 days after receipt of the invoice, a 10-percent late fee shall be assessed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If payment is not submitted within 60 days after receipt of the invoice, a 15-percent late fee shall be assessed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If payment is not submitted within 90 days after receipt of the invoice, a 20-percent late fee shall be assessed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any payment received 120 days or more after receipt of the invoice shall include a 25-percent late fee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home park owner is not required to make the payment prescribed in subsection (1), nor is the mobile home owner entitled to compensation under s. 723.0612(1), when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mobile home park owner moves a mobile home owner to another space in the mobile home park or to another mobile home park at the park owner’s expense;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home owner is vacating the premises and has informed the mobile home park owner or manager before the change in use notice has been given; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mobile home owner abandons the mobile home as set forth in s. 723.0612(7).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mobile home owner has a pending eviction action for nonpayment of lot rental amount pursuant to s. 723.061(1)(a) which was filed against him or her prior to the mailing date of the notice of change in use of the mobile home park given pursuant to s. 723.061(1)(d).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section and s. 723.0612(7) are enforceable by the corporation by action in a court of appropriate jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action brought by the corporation to collect payments assessed under this chapter, the corporation may file and maintain such action in Leon County. If the corporation is a party in any other action, venue for such action shall be in Leon County.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2001-231; s. 105, ch. 2002-1; s. 2, ch. 2002-27; s. 10, ch. 2003-263; s. 2, ch. 2007-47.</History></Section>