<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0723.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Homeowners’ associations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to exercise the rights provided in s. 723.071, the mobile home owners shall form an association in compliance with this section and ss. 723.077, 723.078, and 723.079, which shall be a corporation for profit or not for profit and of which not less than two-thirds of all of the mobile home owners within the park shall have consented, in writing, to become members or shareholders. Upon such consent by two-thirds of the mobile home owners, all consenting mobile home owners in the park and their successors shall become members of the association and shall be bound by the provisions of the articles of incorporation, the bylaws of the association, and such restrictions as may be properly promulgated pursuant thereto. The association shall have no member or shareholder who is not a bona fide owner of a mobile home located in the park. Upon incorporation and service of the notice described in s. 723.076, the association shall become the representative of the mobile home owners in all matters relating to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that any homeowners’ association properly created pursuant to chapter 715 prior to the effective date of this act be deemed an association created pursuant to the provisions of this section and have all rights and powers granted under this section and ss. 723.077 and 723.079. Any inconsistency in the provisions of the charter of such previously created homeowners’ association shall be deemed amended to conform herewith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), if a portion of the park contains concrete block homes occupying lots under 99-year leases, those homeowners may be part of the association and may serve on the board of directors of the association based on the percentage of lots containing concrete block homes to the total number of mobile home lots in the park.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-80; s. 2, ch. 2008-45.</History></Section>