<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0903.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction of trial court to admit to bail; duties and responsibilities of Department of Corrections.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a person is held to answer by a trial court judge, the court having jurisdiction to try the defendant shall, before indictment, affidavit, or information is filed, have jurisdiction to hear and decide all preliminary motions regarding bail and production or impounding of all articles, writings, moneys, or other exhibits expected to be used at the trial by either the state or the defendant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall have the authority on the request of a circuit court when a person charged with a noncapital crime or bailable offense is held, to make an investigation and report to the court, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circumstances of the accused’s family, employment, financial resources, character, mental condition, and length of residence in the community;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accused’s record of convictions, of appearance at court proceedings, of flight to avoid prosecution, or failure to appear at court proceedings; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other facts that may be needed to assist the court in its determination of the indigency of the accused and whether she or he should be released on her or his own recognizance.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall not be bound by the recommendations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 46, ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(46); s. 1, ch. 67-151; s. 21, ch. 70-339; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 5, ch. 75-301; s. 13, ch. 77-120; s. 22, ch. 79-3; s. 1474, ch. 97-102; s. 30, ch. 2004-11.</History></Section>