<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.182" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retirement annuities authorized for city and county personnel.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Municipalities and counties are authorized to purchase annuities for all municipal and county personnel with 25 or more years of creditable service who have reached age 50 and have applied for retirement under the Florida Retirement System. No such annuity shall provide for more than the total difference in retirement income between the retirement benefit based on average monthly compensation and creditable service as of the member’s early retirement date and the early retirement benefit. Municipalities and counties may also purchase annuities for members of the Florida Retirement System who have out-of-state service in another state or country which is documented as valid by the appropriate city or county. Such annuities may be based on no more than 5 years of out-of-state service and may equal, but not exceed, the benefits that would be payable under the Florida Retirement System if credit for out-of-state service was authorized under that system. Municipalities and counties are authorized to invest funds, purchase annuities, or provide local supplemental retirement programs for purposes of providing annuities for city or county personnel. All retirement annuities shall comply with s. 14, Art. X of the State Constitution.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 96-368; s. 1, ch. 2005-135; s. 23, ch. 2011-68.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>