<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Participation in the system.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPULSORY PARTICIPATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in the Florida Retirement System is compulsory for all officers and employees, except elected officers who meet the requirements of s. 121.052(3), who are employed on or after December 1, 1970, by an employer other than those referred to in paragraph (2)(b). Each officer or employee, as a condition of employment, becomes a member of the system on the date of employment, except that a person who is retired from any state retirement system and is reemployed on or after December 1, 1970, may not renew his or her membership in any state retirement system except as provided in s. 121.091(4)(h) for a person who recovers from disability, as provided in s. 121.053 for a person who is elected to public office, and, effective July 1, 1991, as provided in s. 121.122 for all other retirees.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Officers and employees of the University Athletic Association, Inc., a nonprofit association connected with the University of Florida, employed on and after July 1, 1979, may not participate in any state-supported retirement system.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person appointed on or after July 1, 1989, to a faculty position in a college at the J. Hillis Miller Health Center at the University of Florida or the Medical Center at the University of South Florida which has a faculty practice plan adopted by rule by the <Reference Number="1" />Board of Regents may not participate in the Florida Retirement System. Effective July 1, 2008, any person appointed to a faculty position, including clinical faculty, in a college at a state university that has a faculty practice plan authorized by the Board of Governors may not participate in the Florida Retirement System. A faculty member so appointed shall participate in the optional retirement program for the State University System notwithstanding s. 121.35(2)(a). For purposes of this subparagraph, the term:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Faculty position” means a position assigned the principal responsibility of teaching, research, or public service activities or administrative responsibility directly related to the academic mission of the college.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Clinical faculty” means a faculty position appointment in conjunction with a professional position in a hospital or other clinical environment at a college.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Faculty practice plan” includes professional services to patients, institutions, or other parties which are rendered by the clinical faculty employed by a college that has a faculty practice plan at a state university authorized by the Board of Governors.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After June 30, 1978, the compulsory participation provisions of paragraph (a) shall not be construed to require participation in the Florida Retirement System by a member of an existing system who is reemployed after terminating employment, or who otherwise interrupts his or her employment under an existing system, provided the member leaves his or her accumulated contributions on deposit under the existing system. Such member shall continue to have membership in the existing system upon reemployment or resumption of employment and shall not be permitted to become a member of the Florida Retirement System, except by transferring to the Florida Retirement System as authorized by paragraph (2)(a) or s. 121.052 or by being reemployed after terminating employment and receiving a refund of his or her accumulated contributions made to the existing system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After June 30, 1983, a member of an existing system who is reemployed after terminating employment shall have at the time of reemployment the option of selecting to remain in the existing retirement system or to transfer to the Florida Retirement System. Failure to submit such selection in writing to the Department of Management Services within 6 months of reemployment shall result in compulsory membership in the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After June 30, 1988, the provisions of subparagraph 1. shall not apply to a member of an existing system who is reemployed within 12 months after terminating employment. Such member shall continue to have membership in the existing system upon reemployment and shall not be permitted to become a member of the Florida Retirement System, except by transferring to that system as provided in ss. 121.052 and 121.055.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons are not eligible to participate in the Florida Retirement System:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employees of a not-for-profit corporation or association created by the Board of County Commissioners of Palm Beach County for the purpose of owning, operating, or managing a public bus transit system formerly operated or managed by a private corporation subject to 49 U.S.C. s. 5333(b).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who perform services as a consultant or an independent contractor, as defined by the division.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OPTIONAL PARTICIPATION.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee who is a member of an existing system, except any officer or employee of any nonprofit professional association or corporation, may elect, if eligible, to become a member of this system at any time between April 15, 1971, and June 1, 1971, inclusive, by notifying his or her employer in writing of the desire to transfer membership from the existing system to this system. Any officer or employee who was a member of an existing system on December 1, 1970, and who did not elect to become a member of this system shall continue to be covered under the existing system subject to the provisions of s. 121.045. A person who has retired under any state retirement system shall not be eligible to transfer to the Florida Retirement System created by this chapter subsequent to such retirement. Any officer or employee who, prior to July 1, 1947, filed a written rejection of membership in a state retirement system and who continues employment without participating in the Florida Retirement System may withdraw the rejection in writing and, if otherwise eligible, participate in the Florida Retirement System and purchase prior service in accordance with this chapter. Any former member of an existing system who was permitted to transfer to the Florida Retirement System while employed by the University Athletic Association, Inc., a nonprofit association connected with the University of Florida, during this or subsequent transfer periods, contrary to the provisions of this paragraph, is hereby confirmed as a member of the Florida Retirement System, the provisions of this paragraph to the contrary notwithstanding. Any officer or employee of the University Athletic Association, Inc., employed prior to July 1, 1979, who was a member of the Florida Retirement System and who chose in writing on a University Athletic Association Plan Participation Election form, between July 1, 1979, and March 31, 1980, inclusively, to terminate his or her participation in the Florida Retirement System shall hereby have such termination of participation confirmed and declared irrevocable retroactive to the date Florida Retirement System retirement contributions ceased to be reported for such officer or employee. The following specific conditions shall apply to any such officer or employee whose participation was so terminated: The officer or employee shall retain all creditable service earned in the Florida Retirement System through the month that retirement contributions ceased to be reported and no creditable service shall be earned after such month; the officer or employee shall not be eligible for disability retirement or death in line of duty benefits if such occurred after the date that participation terminated; and, the officer or employee may participate in the Florida Retirement System in the future only if employed by a participating employer in a regularly established position.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member transferring from the existing system under chapter 238 shall retain rights to survivor benefits under that chapter through November 30, 1975, or until fully insured for disability benefits under social security, whichever is the earliest date, and thereafter no such rights shall exist.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee who is a member of an existing system on April 15, 1972, and who was eligible to transfer to this system under the provisions of subparagraph 1., but who elected to remain in the existing system, may elect, if eligible under the Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. s. 418(d)(6)(F), to become a member of this system at any time between April 15, 1972, and June 30, 1972, inclusive, by notifying his or her employer in writing of the desire to transfer membership from an existing system to this system. Such transfer shall be subject to the following conditions:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons electing to transfer to the Florida Retirement System under this subparagraph shall be transferred on July 1, 1972, and shall thereafter be subject to the provisions of the Florida Retirement System retroactively to November 30, 1970, and at retirement have their benefits calculated in accordance with the provisions of s. 121.091.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social security coverage incidental to such elective membership in the Florida Retirement System shall be effective November 30, 1970, and all amounts required from a member for retroactive social security coverage shall, at the time such election is made, be deducted from the individual account of the member, and the difference between the amount remaining in the individual account of such member and the total amount which such member would have contributed had he or she become a member of the Florida Retirement System on November 30, 1970, shall be paid into the system trust fund and added to the member’s individual account prior to July 1, 1975, or by his or her date of retirement, if earlier. Interest at the rate of 8 percent per annum, compounded annually until paid, shall be charged on any balance remaining unpaid on said date.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is appropriated out of the system trust fund into the <Reference Number="2" />Social Security Contribution Trust Fund the amount required by federal laws and regulations to be contributed with respect to social security coverage for the years after November 30, 1970, of the members of an existing system who transfer to the Florida Retirement System in accordance with this subparagraph and who qualify for retroactive social security coverage. The amount paid from this appropriation with respect to the employees of any employer shall be charged to the employing agency. There shall be credited against this charge the difference between the matching contributions actually made for the affected employees from November 30, 1970, to June 30, 1972, and the amount of matching contributions that would have been required under the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The net amounts charged the employing agencies for employees transferring to the Florida Retirement System under this subparagraph shall be paid to the system trust fund prior to July 1, 1975. Interest at the rate of 8 percent per annum, compounded annually until paid, shall be charged on any balance remaining unpaid on said date.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator shall request such modification of the state’s agreement with the Social Security Administration, or any referendum required under the Social Security Act governing social security coverage, as may be required to implement the provisions of this law. Retroactive social security coverage for service with an employer prior to November 30, 1970, shall not be provided for any member who was not covered under the agreement as of November 30, 1970.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee who was a member of an existing system on December 1, 1970, and who is still a member of an existing system, except any officer or employee of any nonprofit professional association or corporation, may elect, if eligible, to become a member of this system at any time between September 1, 1974, and November 30, 1974, inclusive, by notifying his or her employer in writing of the desire to transfer membership from the existing system to this system. This decision to transfer or not to transfer shall become irrevocable on November 30, 1974. All members electing to transfer during the transfer period shall become members of the Florida Retirement System on January 1, 1975, and shall be subject to the provisions of the Florida Retirement System on and after that date. Any officer or employee who was a member of an existing system on December 1, 1970, and who does not elect to become a member of this system shall continue to be covered under the existing system, subject to the provisions of s. 121.045. Any member transferring from the Teachers’ Retirement System of Florida under chapter 238 to the Florida Retirement System on January 1, 1975, shall retain rights to survivor benefits under chapter 238 from January 1, 1975, through December 31, 1979, or until fully insured for disability benefits under the Social Security Act, whichever is the earliest date, and thereafter no such rights shall exist.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any officer or employee who was a member of an existing system on December 1, 1970, and who is still a member of an existing system, except any officer or employee of any nonprofit professional association or corporation, may elect, if eligible, to become a member of this system at any time between January 2, 1982, and May 31, 1982, inclusive, by notifying his or her employer in writing of the desire to transfer membership from the existing system to this system. This decision to transfer or not to transfer shall become irrevocable on May 31, 1982. All members electing to transfer during the transfer period shall become members of the Florida Retirement System on July 1, 1982, and shall be subject to the provisions of the Florida Retirement System on and after that date. Any officer or employee who was a member of an existing system on December 1, 1970, and who does not elect to become a member of this system shall continue to be covered under the existing system, subject to the provisions of s. 121.045. Any member transferring from the Teachers’ Retirement System under chapter 238 to the Florida Retirement System on January 1, 1979, shall retain rights to survivor benefits under chapter 238 from January 1, 1979, through December 31, 1983, or until fully insured for disability benefits under the federal Social Security Act, whichever is the earliest date, and thereafter no such rights shall exist. Any such member transferring to the Florida Retirement System on July 1, 1982, shall retain rights to survivor benefits under chapter 238 from July 1, 1982, through June 30, 1987, or until fully insured for disability benefits under the federal Social Security Act, whichever is the earliest date, and thereafter no such rights shall exist.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any deficit, as determined by the state actuary, accruing to the Survivors’ Benefit Trust Fund of the Teachers’ Retirement System and resulting from the passage of chapter 78-308, Laws of Florida, and chapter 80-242, Laws of Florida, shall become an obligation of the Florida Retirement System Trust Fund.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any active member of an existing system who was not employed in a covered position during a time when transfer to the Florida Retirement System was allowed as described in rule 22B-1.004(2)(a), Florida Administrative Code, or as provided in paragraph (1)(c) of this section, may elect, if eligible, to become a member of this system at any time between January 1, 1991, and May 29, 1991, inclusive, by notifying his or her employer in writing of the desire to transfer membership from the existing system to this system. The decision to transfer or not to transfer shall become irrevocable on May 29, 1991. Failure to notify the employer shall result in compulsory membership in the existing system. All members electing to transfer during the transfer period shall become members of the Florida Retirement System on July 1, 1991, and shall be subject to the provisions of the Florida Retirement System on and after that date. Any member so transferring from the existing system under chapter 238 to the Florida Retirement System on July 1, 1991, shall retain rights to survivor benefits under that chapter from July 1, 1991, through June 30, 1996, or until fully insured for benefits under the federal Social Security Act, whichever is the earliest date, and thereafter no such rights shall exist.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Reference Number="3"/>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of any municipality, metropolitan planning organization, or special district in the state may elect to participate in the Florida Retirement System upon proper application to the administrator and may cover all of its units as approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the administrator. The department shall adopt rules establishing procedures for the submission of documents necessary for such application. Before being approved for participation in the system, the governing body of a municipality, metropolitan planning organization, or special district that has a local retirement system must submit to the administrator a certified financial statement showing the condition of the local retirement system within 3 months before the proposed effective date of membership in the Florida Retirement System. The statement must be certified by a recognized accounting firm that is independent of the local retirement system. All required documents necessary for extending Florida Retirement System coverage must be received by the department for consideration at least 15 days before the proposed effective date of coverage. If the municipality, metropolitan planning organization, or special district does not comply with this requirement, the department may require that the effective date of coverage be changed.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality, metropolitan planning organization, or special district that has an existing retirement system covering the employees in the units that are to be brought under the Florida Retirement System may participate only after holding a referendum in which all employees in the affected units have the right to participate. Only those employees electing coverage under the Florida Retirement System by affirmative vote in the referendum are eligible for coverage under this chapter, and those not participating or electing not to be covered by the Florida Retirement System shall remain in their present systems and are not eligible for coverage under this chapter. After the referendum is held, all future employees are compulsory members of the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of joining the Florida Retirement System, the governing body of a municipality, metropolitan planning organization, or special district complying with subparagraph 1. may elect to provide, or not provide, benefits based on past service of officers and employees as described in s. 121.081(1). However, if such employer elects to provide past service benefits, such benefits must be provided for all officers and employees of its covered group.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once this election is made and approved it may not be revoked, except pursuant to subparagraphs 5. and 6., and all present officers and employees electing coverage and all future officers and employees are compulsory members of the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subparagraph 6., the governing body of a hospital licensed under chapter 395 which is governed by the board of a special district as defined in s. 189.403 or by the board of trustees of a public health trust created under s. 154.07, hereinafter referred to as “hospital district,” and which participates in the Florida Retirement System, may elect to cease participation in the system with regard to future employees in accordance with the following:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 30 days and at least 7 days before adopting a resolution to partially withdraw from the system and establish an alternative retirement plan for future employees, a public hearing must be held on the proposed withdrawal and proposed alternative plan.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From 7 to 15 days before such hearing, notice of intent to withdraw, specifying the time and place of the hearing, must be provided in writing to employees of the hospital district proposing partial withdrawal and must be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the area affected, as provided by ss. 50.011-50.031. Proof of publication must be submitted to the Department of Management Services.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a hospital district seeking to partially withdraw from the system must, before such hearing, have an actuarial report prepared and certified by an enrolled actuary, as defined in s. 112.625, illustrating the cost to the hospital district of providing, through the retirement plan that the hospital district is to adopt, benefits for new employees comparable to those provided under the system.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon meeting all applicable requirements of this subparagraph, and subject to subparagraph 6., partial withdrawal from the system and adoption of the alternative retirement plan may be accomplished by resolution duly adopted by the hospital district board. The hospital district board must provide written notice of such withdrawal to the division by mailing a copy of the resolution to the division, postmarked by December 15, 1995. The withdrawal shall take effect January 1, 1996.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following the adoption of a resolution under sub-subparagraph 5.d., all employees of the withdrawing hospital district who were members of the system before January 1, 1996, shall remain as members of the system for as long as they are employees of the hospital district, and all rights, duties, and obligations between the hospital district, the system, and the employees remain in full force and effect. Any employee who is hired or appointed on or after January 1, 1996, may not participate in the system, and the withdrawing hospital district has no obligation to the system with respect to such employees.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Reference Number="3"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employees of public community colleges or charter technical career centers sponsored by public community colleges, designated in s. 1000.21(3), who are members of the Regular Class of the Florida Retirement System and who comply with the criteria set forth in this paragraph and s. 1012.875 may, in lieu of participating in the Florida Retirement System, elect to withdraw from the system altogether and participate in the State Community College System Optional Retirement Program provided by the employing agency under s. 1012.875.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Through June 30, 2001, the cost to the employer for benefits under the optional retirement program equals the normal cost portion of the employer retirement contribution which would be required if the employee were a member of the pension plan’s Regular Class, plus the portion of the contribution rate required by s. 112.363(8) which would otherwise be assigned to the Retiree Health Insurance Subsidy Trust Fund.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2001, through June 30, 2011, each employer shall contribute on behalf of each member of the optional program an amount equal to 10.43 percent of the employee’s gross monthly compensation. The employer shall deduct an amount for the administration of the program.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2011, through June 30, 2012, each member shall contribute an amount equal to the employee contribution required under s. 121.71(3). The employer shall contribute on behalf of each program member an amount equal to the difference between 10.43 percent of the employee’s gross monthly compensation and the employee’s required contribution based on the employee’s gross monthly compensation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2012, each member shall contribute an amount equal to the employee contribution required under s. 121.71(3). The employer shall contribute on behalf of each program member an amount equal to the difference between 8.15 percent of the employee’s gross monthly compensation and the employee’s required contribution based on the employee’s gross monthly compensation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer shall contribute an additional amount to the Florida Retirement System Trust Fund equal to the unfunded actuarial accrued liability portion of the Regular Class contribution rate.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decision to participate in the optional retirement program is irrevocable as long as the employee holds a position eligible for participation, except as provided in subparagraph 3. Any service creditable under the Florida Retirement System is retained after the member withdraws from the system; however, additional service credit in the system may not be earned while a member of the optional retirement program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee who has elected to participate in the optional retirement program shall have one opportunity, at the employee’s discretion, to transfer from the optional retirement program to the pension plan of the Florida Retirement System or to the investment plan established under part II of this chapter, subject to the terms of the applicable optional retirement program contracts.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the employee chooses to move to the investment plan, any contributions, interest, and earnings creditable to the employee under the optional retirement program are retained by the employee in the optional retirement program, and the applicable provisions of s. 121.4501(4) govern the election.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the employee chooses to move to the pension plan of the Florida Retirement System, the employee shall receive service credit equal to his or her years of service under the optional retirement program.</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost for such credit is the amount representing the present value of the employee’s accumulated benefit obligation for the affected period of service. The cost shall be calculated as if the benefit commencement occurs on the first date the employee becomes eligible for unreduced benefits, using the discount rate and other relevant actuarial assumptions that were used to value the Florida Retirement System Pension Plan liabilities in the most recent actuarial valuation. The calculation must include any service already maintained under the pension plan in addition to the years under the optional retirement program. The present value of any service already maintained must be applied as a credit to total cost resulting from the calculation. The division must ensure that the transfer sum is prepared using a formula and methodology certified by an enrolled actuary.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must transfer from his or her optional retirement program account and from other employee moneys as necessary, a sum representing the present value of the employee’s accumulated benefit obligation immediately following the time of such movement, determined assuming that attained service equals the sum of service in the pension plan and service in the optional retirement program.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in the optional retirement program is limited to employees who satisfy the following eligibility criteria:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee is otherwise eligible for membership or renewed membership in the Regular Class of the Florida Retirement System, as provided in s. 121.021(11) and (12) or s. 121.122.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee is employed in a full-time position classified in the Accounting Manual for Florida’s Public Community Colleges as:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instructional; or</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Executive Management, Instructional Management, or Institutional Management and the community college determines that recruiting to fill a vacancy in the position is to be conducted in the national or regional market, and the duties and responsibilities of the position include the formulation, interpretation, or implementation of policies, or the performance of functions that are unique or specialized within higher education and that frequently support the mission of the community college.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee is employed in a position not included in the Senior Management Service Class of the Florida Retirement System as described in s. 121.055.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the program are subject to the same reemployment limitations, renewed membership provisions, and forfeiture provisions applicable to regular members of the Florida Retirement System under ss. 121.091(9), 121.122, and 121.091(5), respectively. A member who receives a program distribution funded by employer and required employee contributions is deemed to be retired from a state-administered retirement system if the member is subsequently employed with an employer that participates in the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligible community college employees are compulsory members of the Florida Retirement System until, pursuant to s. 1012.875, a written election to withdraw from the system and participate in the optional retirement program is filed with the program administrator and received by the division.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community college employee whose program eligibility results from initial employment shall be enrolled in the optional retirement program retroactive to the first day of eligible employment. The employer and employee retirement contributions paid through the month of the employee plan change shall be transferred to the community college to the employee’s optional program account, and, effective the first day of the next month, the employer shall pay the applicable contributions based upon subparagraph 1.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community college employee whose program eligibility is due to the subsequent designation of the employee’s position as one of those specified in subparagraph 4., or due to the employee’s appointment, promotion, transfer, or reclassification to a position specified in subparagraph 4., must be enrolled in the program on the first day of the first full calendar month that such change in status becomes effective. The employer and employee retirement contributions paid from the effective date through the month of the employee plan change must be transferred to the community college to the employee’s optional program account, and, effective the first day of the next month, the employer shall pay the applicable contributions based upon subparagraph 1.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2003, through December 31, 2008, any member of the optional retirement program who has service credit in the pension plan of the Florida Retirement System for the period between his or her first eligibility to transfer from the pension plan to the optional retirement program and the actual date of transfer may, during employment, transfer to the optional retirement program a sum representing the present value of the accumulated benefit obligation under the defined benefit retirement program for the period of service credit. Upon transfer, all service credit previously earned under the pension plan during this period is nullified for purposes of entitlement to a future benefit under the pension plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a charter school or a charter technical career center may elect to participate in the system upon proper application to the administrator and shall cover its units as approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the administrator. Once this election is made and approved, it may not be revoked, and all present officers and employees selecting coverage under this chapter and all future officers and employees shall be compulsory members of the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, any independent participating agency that has failed to report the employees of a dependent governmental entity within its jurisdiction for membership in the Florida Retirement System as required under this chapter shall enroll in the system, effective July 1, 1996, all employees filling a regularly established position who are not currently participating in a retirement plan provided by the dependent entity. Employees of the dependent entity participating in such a retirement plan on July 1, 1996, may remain in that plan or participate in the Florida Retirement System and shall make such election in writing. Such employees are eligible to claim past service as provided in s. 121.081. All eligible employees hired on or after July 1, 1996, by any such dependent entity shall be compulsory members of the Florida Retirement System. Any independent participating agency shall be responsible for identifying all such dependent governmental entities within its jurisdiction and for providing to the division a list of all employees of such entities as of July 1, 1997.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an employer that participates in the Florida Retirement System undertakes the transfer, merger, or consolidation of governmental services or assumes the functions and activities of an employing governmental entity that was not an employer under the system, the employer must notify the department at least 60 days before such action and provide documentation as required by the department. The transfer, merger, or consolidation of governmental services or assumption of governmental functions and activities must occur between public employers. The current or former employer may pay the employees’ past service cost, unless prohibited under this chapter. This subparagraph does not apply to the transfer, merger, or consolidation of governmental services or assumption of functions and activities of a public entity under a leasing agreement having a coemployer relationship. Employers and employees of a public governmental employer whose service is covered by a leasing agreement under s. 110.191, any other leasing agreement, or a coemployer relationship are not eligible to participate in the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the agency to which a member’s employing unit is transferred, merged, or consolidated does not participate in the Florida Retirement System, a member may elect in writing to remain in the Florida Retirement System or to transfer to the local retirement system operated by the agency. If the agency does not participate in a local retirement system, the member shall continue membership in the Florida Retirement System. In either case, membership continues for as long as the member is employed by the agency to which his or her unit was transferred, merged, or consolidated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Reference Number="3"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SOCIAL SECURITY COVERAGE.<EmDash />Social security coverage shall be provided for all officers and employees who become members under subsection (1) or subsection (2). Any modification of the present agreement with the Social Security Administration, or referendum required under the Social Security Act, for the purpose of providing social security coverage for any member shall be requested by the state agency in compliance with the applicable provisions of the Social Security Act governing such coverage. However, retroactive social security coverage for service before December 1, 1970, with the employer may not be provided for a member who was not covered under the agreement as of November 30, 1970. The employer-paid employee contributions specified in s. 121.71(3) are subject to taxes imposed under the Federal Insurance Contributions Act, 26 U.S.C. ss. 3101-3128.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INFORMATION REQUIRED.<EmDash />The employer and employee shall furnish the administrator with such information as he or she may request for the proper enrollment of officers and employees in the system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RIGHTS LIMITED.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in the system shall not give any member the right to be retained in the employ of the employer or, upon dismissal, to have any right or interest in the fund other than herein provided.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member who is convicted by a court of competent jurisdiction of causing a shortage in a public account, when such shortage is certified by the Auditor General or a certified public accountant, may not retire or receive any benefits under this chapter so long as such shortage exists.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SEASONAL STATE EMPLOYMENT; BLIND VENDING FACILITY OPERATORS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seasonal state employment shall be included under this chapter, and the time limit and procedure for claiming same as set forth in s. 122.07 shall continue under this chapter for those members transferring to this system and for all new members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All blind or partially sighted persons employed or licensed by the Division of Blind Services as vending facility operators on or after December 1, 1970, and prior to July 1, 1996, are hereby declared to be state employees within the meaning of this chapter, and all vending facility operators licensed and employed during that period shall be compulsory members of the Florida Retirement System in compliance with this chapter for as long as the member is a vending facility operator, except as provided in subparagraph 3.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Blindness shall not be deemed a retirement disability within the provisions of this chapter for such members as are contemplated by this paragraph.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vending facility operator as described in subparagraph 1. may elect, on or before July 31, 1996, to withdraw from the Florida Retirement System as provided in s. 413.051(11). The election to withdraw shall take effect as of July 1, 1996, and the decision to withdraw is irrevocable. A vending facility operator who withdraws from the Florida Retirement System as provided in this subparagraph shall retain all creditable service earned in the Florida Retirement System through the month that retirement contributions ceased to be reported, and no creditable service shall be earned as a vending facility operator after such month. However, any such person may participate in the Florida Retirement System in the future if employed by a participating employer in a covered position.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All blind or partially sighted persons employed or licensed by the Division of Blind Services as vending facility operators on or after July 1, 1996, shall be independent contractors within the meaning of this chapter and shall not be eligible for membership in the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">JOINT REPRESENTATIVES; FEDERAL CIVIL SERVICE.<EmDash />All state and county cooperative extension personnel holding appointments by the United States Department of Agriculture for extension work in agriculture and home economics in the state shall be joint representatives of the University of Florida and the United States Department of Agriculture unless otherwise expressly provided in the project agreement. Such personnel shall be deemed governed by the requirements of Federal Civil Service, as written in the agreement between the University of Florida and the United States Department of Agriculture. Such personnel so governed by the requirements of Federal Civil Service shall be prohibited from participating in any retirement or social security program or act administered by the state except those members covered under s. 238.13, as of November 30, 1970.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DIVISION OF REHABILITATION AND LIQUIDATION EMPLOYEES MEMBERSHIP.<EmDash />Effective July 1, 1994, the regular receivership employees of the Division of Rehabilitation and Liquidation of the Department of Financial Services who are assigned to established positions and are subject to established rules and regulations regarding discipline, pay, classification, and time and attendance are hereby declared to be state employees within the meaning of this chapter and shall be compulsory members in compliance with this chapter, the provisions of s. 216.011(1)(dd)2., notwithstanding. Employment performed before July 1, 1994, as such a receivership employee may be claimed as creditable retirement service upon payment by the employee or employer of contributions required in s. 121.081(1), as applicable for the period claimed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DUAL EMPLOYMENT.<EmDash />A member may not participate in more than one state-administered retirement system, plan, or class of membership simultaneously. Pursuant thereto:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any member who is not eligible to participate in the Elected Officers’ Class, but who is simultaneously employed in two or more positions covered by different Florida Retirement System classes:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The member must participate in the membership class for the position in which he or she is employed the majority of the time: the Regular Class, Senior Management Service Class, Special Risk Class, or Special Risk Administrative Support Class; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the employment is split equally between or among positions, the member may choose any single class of membership for which he or she is eligible, whether or not the positions are full-time positions. The member’s choice must be made in writing and remains in effect as long as the member is employed equally in two or more positions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contributions shall be made and creditable service shall be determined as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member is participating in the Regular Class, retirement contributions shall be made on the total salary the member has received for all covered employment, and at retirement the member’s average final compensation shall be calculated on the total salary received from all covered employment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the member is participating in the Senior Management Service Class, Special Risk Class, or Special Risk Administrative Support Class, retirement contributions shall be made only on the salary received in the designated class of membership. At retirement, the member’s average final compensation shall be based only on the salary received in the designated class of membership for any period, including any period of dual employment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 70-112; s. 1, ch. 72-182; s. 1, ch. 72-340; s. 1, ch. 72-344; s. 1, ch. 73-268; s. 3, ch. 74-302; s. 1, ch. 75-152; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 21, ch. 77-259; s. 2, ch. 77-469; s. 3, ch. 78-308; s. 1, ch. 79-375; s. 1, ch. 79-377; s. 2, ch. 80-242; s. 2, ch. 81-214; s. 60, ch. 81-259; s. 4, ch. 83-76; s. 2, ch. 85-246; s. 7, ch. 88-382; s. 34, ch. 89-207; s. 2, ch. 89-260; s. 16, ch. 89-367; s. 7, ch. 90-274; s. 68, ch. 92-136; s. 5, ch. 94-259; s. 1423, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 95-277; s. 16, ch. 95-392; s. 3, ch. 96-186; s. 5, ch. 96-368; s. 3, ch. 96-423; s. 18, ch. 97-180; s. 11, ch. 98-73; s. 2, ch. 98-138; s. 3, ch. 98-302; s. 53, ch. 99-2; s. 2, ch. 99-9; s. 29, ch. 99-255; s. 6, ch. 99-392; s. 5, ch. 2000-169; s. 3, ch. 2000-347; s. 18, ch. 2001-60; s. 6, ch. 2001-262; s. 898, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2003-260; s. 140, ch. 2003-261; s. 9, ch. 2004-5; s. 2, ch. 2007-92; s. 7, ch. 2007-196; s. 19, ch. 2008-4; s. 4, ch. 2008-139; s. 7, ch. 2009-21; s. 3, ch. 2009-209; s. 7, ch. 2011-68; s. 1, ch. 2012-146.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abolished by s. 3, ch. 2001-170.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="2">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Social Security Contribution Trust Fund was terminated by s. 1, ch. 2004-234.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note Reference="3">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>