<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0121.122" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Renewed membership in system.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 121.053, effective July 1, 1991, through June 30, 2010, any retiree of a state-administered retirement system who is initially reemployed in a regularly established position with a covered employer, including an elective public office that does not qualify for the Elected Officer’s Class, shall be enrolled as a compulsory member of the Regular Class of the Florida Retirement System. Effective July 1, 1997, through June 30, 2010, any retiree of a state-administered retirement system who is initially reemployed in a position included in the Senior Management Service Class shall be enrolled as a compulsory member of the Senior Management Service Class of the Florida Retirement System as provided in s. 121.055. A retiree is entitled to receive an additional retirement benefit, subject to the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such member must resatisfy the age and service requirements as provided in this chapter for initial membership under the system, unless such member elects to participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program in lieu of the Senior Management Service Class, as provided in s. 121.055(6).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such member is not entitled to disability benefits as provided in s. 121.091(4).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such member must meet the reemployment after retirement limitations as provided in s. 121.091(9), as applicable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon renewed membership or reemployment of a retiree, the employer of such member shall pay the applicable employer contributions as required by ss. 112.363, 121.71, 121.74, and 121.76.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such member is entitled to purchase additional retirement credit in the Regular Class or the Senior Management Service Class, as applicable, for any postretirement service performed in a regularly established position as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For regular class service prior to July 1, 1991, by paying the Regular Class applicable employee and employer contributions for the period being claimed, plus 4 percent interest compounded annually from first year of service claimed until July 1, 1975, and 6.5 percent interest compounded thereafter, until full payment is made to the Florida Retirement System Trust Fund; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For Senior Management Service Class prior to June 1, 1997, as provided in s. 121.055(1)(j).</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The contribution for postretirement service between July 1, 1985, and July 1, 1991, for which the reemployed retiree contribution was paid, shall be the difference between such contribution and the total applicable contribution for the period being claimed, plus interest. The employer of such member may pay the applicable employer contribution in lieu of the member. If a member does not wish to claim credit for all of the postretirement service for which he or she is eligible, the service the member claims must be the most recent service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No creditable service for which credit was received, or which remained unclaimed, at retirement may be claimed or applied toward service credit earned following renewed membership. However, service earned as an elected officer with renewed membership in the Elected Officers’ Class may be used in conjunction with creditable service earned under this section, provided the applicable vesting requirements and other existing statutory conditions required by this chapter are met.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other limitations provided in this section, a participant of the State University System Optional Retirement Program, the State Community College Optional Retirement Program, or the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program who terminated employment and commenced receiving a distribution under the optional program, who initially renews membership as required by this section upon reemployment after retirement, and who had previously earned creditable Florida Retirement System service that was not included in any retirement benefit may include such previous service toward vesting and service credit in the second career benefit provided under renewed membership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A renewed member who is not receiving the maximum health insurance subsidy provided in s. 112.363 is entitled to earn additional credit toward the maximum health insurance subsidy. Any additional subsidy due because of such additional credit may be received only at the time of payment of the second career retirement benefit. The total health insurance subsidy received by a retiree receiving benefits from initial and renewed membership may not exceed the maximum allowed in s. 112.363.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retiree of a state-administered retirement system who is initially reemployed in a regularly established position on or after July 1, 2010, may not be enrolled as a renewed member.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 90-274; s. 8, ch. 92-122; s. 9, ch. 93-193; s. 6, ch. 93-285; s. 14, ch. 97-180; s. 12, ch. 98-138; s. 10, ch. 98-413; s. 7, ch. 99-9; s. 12, ch. 99-392; s. 21, ch. 2000-151; s. 12, ch. 2009-209; s. 7, ch. 2012-222.</History></Section>