<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cost-of-living adjustment of benefits.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to provide cost-of-living adjustments to the monthly benefits payable to retired members of state-supported retirement systems.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “initial benefit” means the first monthly benefit payable to a retiree or beneficiary in accordance with the laws governing the determination of such benefit at the time of retirement or earlier death.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commencing July 1, 1987, the benefit of each retiree and annuitant whose effective retirement date is before July 1, 2011, shall be adjusted annually on July 1 as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those retirees and annuitants who have never received a cost-of-living adjustment under this section, the amount of the monthly benefit payable for the 12-month period commencing on the adjustment date shall be the amount of the member’s initial benefit plus an amount equal to a percentage of the member’s initial benefit; this percentage is derived by dividing the number of months the member has received an initial benefit by 12, and multiplying the result by 3.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those retirees and annuitants who have received a cost-of-living adjustment under this subsection, the adjusted monthly benefit shall be the amount of the monthly benefit being received on June 30 immediately preceding the adjustment date plus an amount equal to 3 percent of this benefit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For members whose effective retirement date is on or after July 1, 2011, the benefit of each retiree and annuitant shall be adjusted annually on July 1 as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those retirees and annuitants who have never received a cost-of-living adjustment under this subsection, the amount of the monthly benefit payable for the 12-month period commencing on the adjustment date shall be the amount of the member’s initial benefit plus an amount equal to a percentage of the member’s initial benefit. This percentage is derived by dividing the number of months the member has received an initial benefit by 12, and multiplying the result by the factor calculated pursuant to paragraph (c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those retirees and annuitants who have received a cost-of-living adjustment under this subsection, the adjusted monthly benefit shall be the amount of the monthly benefit being received on June 30 immediately preceding the adjustment date plus an amount determined by multiplying the benefit by the factor calculated pursuant to paragraph (c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall calculate a cost-of-living factor for each retiree and beneficiary retiring on or after July 1, 2011. This factor shall equal the product of 3 percent multiplied by the quotient of the sum of the member’s service credit earned for service before July 1, 2011, divided by the sum of the member’s total service credit earned.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the availability of funding and the Legislature enacting sufficient employer contributions specifically for the purpose of funding the expiration of the cost-of-living adjustment specified in subsection (4), in accordance with s. 14, Art. X of the State Constitution, the cost-of-living adjustment formula provided for in subsection (4) shall expire effective June 30, 2016, and the benefit of each retiree and annuitant shall be adjusted on each July 1 thereafter, as provided in subsection (3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In no event shall a retiree’s or annuitant’s monthly retirement benefit be reduced, by the application of this section, below the benefit he or she was receiving as of July 1, 1970, or at the date of retirement, if later, nor shall the benefit be reduced below the minimum monthly benefit provided him or her under s. 112.362.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial benefit of a retiree who elected an optional form of benefit payment which provided for a percentage of the benefit to be continued to a beneficiary after his or her death shall be reduced at the death of the retiree by application of the stated percentage.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds necessary to pay for the cost-of-living adjustment provided by this section are hereby annually appropriated from the System Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this subsection is to establish a supplemental cost-of-living adjustment for certain retirees and beneficiaries who receive monthly retirement benefits under the provisions of this chapter and the existing systems consolidated therein, s. 112.05 for certain state officers and employees, and s. 238.171 for certain elderly incapacitated teachers.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On July 1, 1996, each such retiree retiring prior to July 1, 1976, and each annuitant of such a retiree, who had 25 or more years of service, who is neither receiving nor eligible to receive social security benefits, and whose monthly benefit as of July 1, 1996, is less than $1,000, shall, upon application to the administrator, receive a supplemental cost-of-living adjustment. Such supplemental cost-of-living adjustment shall be applied by adjusting the retiree’s or annuitant’s monthly benefit to an amount equal to the sum of the monthly benefit being received on July 1, 1996, plus a percentage of the July 1, 1996, benefit. This percentage shall equal the product of 1 percent multiplied by the number of complete years that have elapsed between the member’s date of retirement and July 1, 1996. However, if the supplemental cost-of-living adjustment plus the July 1, 1996, monthly benefit would exceed $1,000, the adjustment shall be reduced to an amount which would result in a monthly benefit equal to $1,000.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for the supplemental cost-of-living adjustment provided by this subsection shall include certification by the retiree or annuitant that he or she is not receiving, and is not eligible to receive, social security benefits and shall include written authorization for the department to have access to information from the Social Security Administration concerning his or her entitlement to, or eligibility for, social security benefits. Such supplemental cost-of-living adjustment shall not be paid unless and until the application requirements of this paragraph are met.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 70-112; s. 8, ch. 74-302; s. 4, ch. 80-242; s. 6, ch. 81-307; s. 37, ch. 83-217; s. 11, ch. 84-266; s. 1, ch. 87-534; s. 774, ch. 95-147; s. 8, ch. 96-368; s. 38, ch. 99-255; s. 17, ch. 2011-68.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>