<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0121.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Senior Management Service Class.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby established a separate class of membership within the Florida Retirement System to be known as the “Senior Management Service Class,” which shall become effective February 1, 1987.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in the Senior Management Service Class shall be limited to and compulsory for any member of the Florida Retirement System who holds a position in the Senior Management Service of the State of Florida, established by part III of chapter 110, unless such member elects, within the time specified herein, to participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program as established in subsection (6).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Reference Number="1" /><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 2., effective January 1, 1990, participation in the Senior Management Service Class is compulsory for the president of each community college, the manager of each participating municipality or county, and all appointed district school superintendents. Effective January 1, 1994, additional positions may be designated for inclusion in the Senior Management Service Class if:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Positions to be included in the class are designated by the local agency employer. Notice of intent to designate positions for inclusion in the class must be published once a week for 2 consecutive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation published in the county or counties affected, as provided in chapter 50.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Up to 10 nonelective full-time positions may be designated for each local agency employer reporting to the department; for local agencies with 100 or more regularly established positions, additional nonelective full-time positions may be designated, not to exceed 1 percent of the regularly established positions within the agency.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each position added to the class must be a managerial or policymaking position filled by an employee who is not subject to continuing contract and serves at the pleasure of the local agency employer without civil service protection, and who:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Heads an organizational unit; or</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has responsibility to effect or recommend personnel, budget, expenditure, or policy decisions in his or her areas of responsibility.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of participation in the Senior Management Service Class, members of the Senior Management Service Class, pursuant to subparagraph 1., may withdraw from the Florida Retirement System altogether. The decision to withdraw from the system is irrevocable as long as the employee holds the position. Any service creditable under the Senior Management Service Class shall be retained after the member withdraws from the system; however, additional service credit in the Senior Management Service Class may not be earned after such withdrawal. Such members are not eligible to participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 2006, through June 30, 2006, an employee who has withdrawn from the Florida Retirement System under subparagraph 2. has one opportunity to elect to participate in the pension plan or the investment plan.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the employee elects to participate in the investment plan, membership shall be prospective, and the applicable provisions of s. 121.4501(4) govern the election.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the employee elects to participate in the pension plan, the employee shall, upon payment to the system trust fund of the amount calculated under sub-sub-subparagraph (I), receive service credit for prior service based upon the time during which the employee had withdrawn from the system.</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost for such credit shall be an amount representing the actuarial accrued liability for the affected period of service. The cost shall be calculated using the discount rate and other relevant actuarial assumptions that were used to value the pension plan liabilities in the most recent actuarial valuation. The calculation must include any service already maintained under the pension plan in addition to the period of withdrawal. The actuarial accrued liability attributable to any service already maintained under the pension plan shall be applied as a credit to the total cost resulting from the calculation. The division must ensure that the transfer sum is prepared using a formula and methodology certified by an actuary.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must transfer a sum representing the net cost owed for the actuarial accrued liability in sub-sub-subparagraph (I) immediately following the time of such movement, determined assuming that attained service equals the sum of service in the pension plan and the period of withdrawal.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 1990, participation in the Senior Management Service Class shall be compulsory for up to 75 nonelective positions at the level of committee staff director or higher or equivalent managerial or policymaking positions within the House of Representatives, as selected by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, up to 50 nonelective positions at the level of committee staff director or higher or equivalent managerial or policymaking positions within the Senate, as selected by the President of the Senate, all staff directors of joint committees and service offices of the Legislature, the Auditor General and up to 9 managerial or policymaking positions within his or her office as selected by the Auditor General, and the executive director of the Commission on Ethics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in this class shall be compulsory, except as provided in subparagraph 3., for any legislative employee who holds a position designated for coverage in the Senior Management Service Class, and such participation shall continue until the employee terminates employment in a covered position.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of participation in the Senior Management Service Class, at the discretion of the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, such members may participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program as established in subsection (6).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 1991, participation in the Senior Management Service Class shall be compulsory for any member of the Florida Retirement System in a position that has been designated eligible for inclusion in the Executive Service of the State University System or who holds a position as president of a state university, unless such member elects, pursuant to s. 121.35, to participate in the optional retirement program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 1991, participation in the Senior Management Service Class shall be compulsory for the number of senior managers who have policymaking authority with the State Board of Administration, as determined by the Governor, Chief Financial Officer, and Attorney General acting as the State Board of Administration, unless such member elects to participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program as established in subsection (6) in lieu of participation in the Senior Management Service Class. Such election shall be made in writing and filed with the division and the personnel officer of the State Board of Administration within 90 days after becoming eligible for membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 1997:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 3., an elected state officer eligible for membership in the Elected Officers’ Class under s. 121.052(2)(a), (b), or (c) who elects membership in the Senior Management Service Class under s. 121.052(3)(c) may, within 6 months after assuming office or within 6 months after this act becomes a law for serving elected state officers, elect to participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program, as provided in subsection (6), in lieu of membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 3., an elected officer of a local agency employer eligible for membership in the Elected Officers’ Class under s. 121.052(2)(d) who elects membership in the Senior Management Service Class under s. 121.052(3)(c) may, within 6 months after assuming office, or within 6 months after this act becomes a law for serving elected officers of a local agency employer, elect to withdraw from the Florida Retirement System, as provided in subparagraph (b)2., in lieu of membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retiree of a state-administered retirement system who is initially reemployed in a regularly established position on or after July 1, 2010, as an elected official eligible for the Elected Officers’ Class may not be enrolled in renewed membership in the Senior Management Service Class or in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program as provided in subsection (6), and may not withdraw from the Florida Retirement System as a renewed member as provided in subparagraph (b)2., as applicable, in lieu of membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 1996, participation in the Senior Management Service Class shall be compulsory for any member of the Florida Retirement System employed with the Department of Military Affairs in the positions of the Adjutant General, Assistant Adjutant General-Army, Assistant Adjutant General-Air, State Quartermaster, Director of Military Personnel, Director of Administration, and additional directors as designated by the agency head, not to exceed a total of 10 positions. In lieu of participation in the Senior Management Service Class, such members may participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program as established in subsection (6).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 3., effective January 1, 1994, participation in the Senior Management Service Class shall be compulsory for the State Courts Administrator and the Deputy State Courts Administrators, the Clerk of the Supreme Court, the Marshal of the Supreme Court, the Executive Director of the Justice Administrative Commission, the capital collateral regional counsel, the clerks of the district courts of appeals, the marshals of the district courts of appeals, and the trial court administrator and the Chief Deputy Court Administrator in each judicial circuit. Effective January 1, 1994, additional positions in the offices of the state attorney and public defender in each judicial circuit may be designated for inclusion in the Senior Management Service Class of the Florida Retirement System, provided that:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Positions to be included in the class shall be designated by the state attorney or public defender, as appropriate. Notice of intent to designate positions for inclusion in the class shall be published once a week for 2 consecutive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation published in the county or counties affected, as provided in chapter 50.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One nonelective full-time position may be designated for each state attorney and public defender reporting to the Department of Management Services; for agencies with 200 or more regularly established positions under the state attorney or public defender, additional nonelective full-time positions may be designated, not to exceed 0.5 percent of the regularly established positions within the agency.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each position added to the class must be a managerial or policymaking position filled by an employee who serves at the pleasure of the state attorney or public defender without civil service protection, and who:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Heads an organizational unit; or</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has responsibility to effect or recommend personnel, budget, expenditure, or policy decisions in his or her areas of responsibility.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in this class shall be compulsory, except as provided in subparagraph 3., for any judicial employee who holds a position designated for coverage in the Senior Management Service Class, and such participation shall continue until the employee terminates employment in a covered position. Effective January 1, 2001, participation in this class is compulsory for assistant state attorneys, assistant statewide prosecutors, assistant public defenders, and assistant capital collateral regional counsel. Effective January 1, 2002, participation in this class is compulsory for assistant attorneys general.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of participation in the Senior Management Service Class, such members, excluding assistant state attorneys, assistant public defenders, assistant statewide prosecutors, assistant attorneys general, and assistant capital collateral regional counsel, may participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program as established in subsection (6).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 2., effective July 1, 1999, participation in the Senior Management Service Class is compulsory for any member of the Florida Retirement System who is employed as the Deputy Chief Judge of Compensation Claims or as a judge of compensation claims with the Office of the Judges of Compensation Claims within the Division of Administrative Hearings.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of participating in the Senior Management Service Class, the Deputy Chief Judge of Compensation Claims or a judge of compensation claims may participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program established under subsection (6).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as may otherwise be provided, a member of the Senior Management Service Class may purchase additional retirement credit in such class for creditable service within the purview of the Senior Management Service Class retroactive to February 1, 1987, and may upgrade retirement credit for such service, to the extent of 2 percent of the member’s average monthly compensation as specified in paragraph (4)(d) for such service. Contributions for upgrading the additional Senior Management Service credit must be equal to the difference in the employer and, if applicable, employee contributions paid and the Senior Management Service Class contribution rate as a percentage of gross salary in effect for the period being claimed, plus interest thereon at the rate of 6.5 percent a year, compounded annually until the date of payment. This service credit may be purchased by the employer on behalf of the member.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any state attorney or public defender in the Elected Officers’ Class who has creditable service as an assistant state attorney or assistant public defender may upgrade retirement credit for such service in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (j).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each metropolitan planning organization that has opted to become part of the Florida Retirement System, participation in the Senior Management Service Class shall be compulsory for the executive director or staff director of that metropolitan planning organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in this class shall cease when the member terminates employment in an eligible position. Once a position is designated as eligible for inclusion in the class, that position shall not be removed from the class unless the duties and responsibilities of the position change substantially and therefore no longer meet the requirements provided in this section for participation in the class, except as provided in paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 1997, each local agency employer may between July 1, 1997, and December 31, 1997, reassess its designation of positions for inclusion in the Senior Management Service Class as provided in paragraph (1)(b), and may request removal from the class of any such positions that it deems appropriate. Such removal of any previously designated positions shall be effective on the first day of the month following written notification of removal to the division prior to January 1, 1998.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following table states the required retirement contribution rates for members of the Senior Management Service Class and their employers in terms of a percentage of the member’s gross compensation. A change in the contribution rate is effective with the first salary paid on or after the beginning date of the change. Contributions shall be made for each pay period and are in addition to the contributions required for social security and the Retiree Health Insurance Subsidy Trust Fund.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Table Width="100" SpaceAbove="false" SpaceBelow="true"><ColumnDefinitions><Column Width="60" /><Column Width="20" /><Column Width="20" /></ColumnDefinitions><Header><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">Dates of Contribution<NewLine /> Rate Changes</Font></Text></Cell><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom" HorizontalAlign="Center"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">Members</Font></Text></Cell><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom" HorizontalAlign="Center"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">Employers</Font></Text></Cell></Row><Row><Cell></Cell></Row></Header><Body><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">July 1, 2001, through June 30, 2002</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">0%</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">11.73%</Font></Text></Cell></Row></Body></Table></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2002, the required retirement contribution rate shall be as specified in s. 121.71.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer paying the salary of a member of the Senior Management Service Class shall contribute an amount as specified in this section or s. 121.71, as appropriate, which shall constitute the entire employer retirement contribution with respect to such member. The employer shall also withhold one-half of the entire contribution of the member required for social security coverage. Effective July 1, 2011, each member shall pay employee contributions as specified in s. 121.71.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon termination of employment from all participating employers for 3 calendar months for any reason other than retirement pursuant to s. 121.021(39)(c), a member may receive a refund of all contributions he or she has made to the pension plan, subject to the restrictions otherwise provided in this chapter. Partial refunds are not permitted. The refund shall not include any interest earnings on the contributions for a member of the pension plan. Employer contributions made on behalf of the member are not refundable. A member may not receive a refund of employee contributions if a pending or an approved qualified domestic relations order is filed against the member’s retirement account. By obtaining a refund of contributions, a member waives all rights under the Florida Retirement System and the health insurance subsidy provided under s. 112.363 to the service credit represented by the refunded contributions, except the right to purchase his or her prior service credit in accordance with s. 121.081(2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following table states the required employer contribution on behalf of each member of the Senior Management Service Class in terms of a percentage of the member’s gross compensation. Such contribution constitutes the entire health insurance subsidy contribution with respect to each such member. A change in the contribution rate is effective with the first salary paid on or after the beginning date of the change. The retiree health insurance subsidy contribution rate is as follows:</Text><Table Width="100" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><ColumnDefinitions><Column Width="80" /><Column Width="20" /></ColumnDefinitions><Header><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">Dates of Contribution<NewLine /> Rate Changes</Font></Text></Cell><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom" HorizontalAlign="Center"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">Contribution<NewLine />Rate</Font></Text></Cell></Row><Row><Cell></Cell></Row></Header><Body><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">October 1, 1987, through December 31, 1988</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">0.24%</Font></Text></Cell></Row><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">January 1, 1989, through December 31, 1993</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">0.48%</Font></Text></Cell></Row><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">January 1, 1994, through December 31, 1994</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">0.56%</Font></Text></Cell></Row><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">January 1, 1995, through June 30, 1998</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">0.66%</Font></Text></Cell></Row><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">July 1, 1998, through June 30, 2001</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">0.94%</Font></Text></Cell></Row><Row><Cell VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">Effective July 1, 2001</Font></Text></Cell><Cell HorizontalAlign="Center" VerticalAlign="Bottom"><Text xml:space="preserve"><Font xml:space="preserve" Size="8">1.11%</Font></Text></Cell></Row></Body></Table><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Such contributions and accompanying payroll data are due and payable no later than the 5th working day of the month immediately following the month during which the payroll period ended and shall be deposited by the administrator in the Retiree Health Insurance Subsidy Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The definitions set forth in s. 121.021 and all other provisions of this chapter shall apply to the Senior Management Service Class, except the definitions and provisions in conflict with, or superseded or modified by, the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service in an eligible position before February 1, 1987, or after January 31, 1987, shall satisfy the requirement of attaining the normal retirement date as defined in s. 121.021(29) for a Senior Management Service Class member, if the employee is a member of the Senior Management Service Class after January 31, 1987. A member of this class who fails to complete the years of creditable service required for vesting in an eligible position must satisfy the requirements for the normal retirement date for a regular member as provided in s. 121.021(29) and vesting as provided in s. 121.021(45).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average final compensation of a member of this class shall be as defined in s. 121.021(24).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the Senior Management Service Class shall receive retirement credit at the rate of 2 percent of average final compensation for each year of service in such class after January 31, 1987.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the Senior Management Service Class shall retain all rights and creditable service accumulated in the Florida Retirement System prior to membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program.</Font><EmDash />The Department of Management Services shall establish a Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program under which contracts providing retirement, death, and disability benefits may be purchased for those employees who elect to participate in the optional annuity program. The benefits to be provided for or on behalf of participants in such optional annuity program shall be provided through individual contracts or individual certificates issued for group annuity contracts, which may be fixed, variable, or a combination thereof, in accordance with s. 401(a) of the Internal Revenue Code. Any such individual contract or certificate shall state the annuity plan on its face page, and shall include, but not be limited to, a statement of ownership, the contract benefits, annuity income options, limitations, expense charges, and surrender charges, if any. The employing agency shall contribute, as provided in this section, toward the purchase of such optional benefits which shall be fully and immediately vested in the participants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Retirement service credit.</Font><EmDash />An eligible employee who is a member of the Florida Retirement System or an existing retirement system at the time of his or her election to participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program shall retain all retirement service credit earned under the retirement system from which he or she transferred; however, no additional service credit in the Florida Retirement System or existing retirement system shall be earned while the employee participates in the optional annuity program, nor shall the employee be eligible for disability retirement under the Florida Retirement System or existing retirement system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Participation.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An eligible employee who is employed on or before February 1, 1987, may elect to participate in the optional annuity program in lieu of participating in the Senior Management Service Class. Such election must be made in writing and filed with the department and the personnel officer of the employer on or before May 1, 1987. An eligible employee who is employed on or before February 1, 1987, and who fails to make an election to participate in the optional annuity program by May 1, 1987, shall be deemed to have elected membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 6., an employee who becomes eligible to participate in the optional annuity program by reason of initial employment commencing after February 1, 1987, may, within 90 days after the date of commencing employment, elect to participate in the optional annuity program. Such election must be made in writing and filed with the personnel officer of the employer. An eligible employee who does not within 90 days after commencing employment elect to participate in the optional annuity program shall be deemed to have elected membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is appointed to a position in the Senior Management Service Class and who is a member of an existing retirement system or the Special Risk or Special Risk Administrative Support Classes of the Florida Retirement System may elect to remain in such system or class in lieu of participating in the Senior Management Service Class or optional annuity program. Such election must be made in writing and filed with the department and the personnel officer of the employer within 90 days after such appointment. An eligible employee who fails to make an election to participate in the existing system, the Special Risk Class of the Florida Retirement System, the Special Risk Administrative Support Class of the Florida Retirement System, or the optional annuity program shall be deemed to have elected membership in the Senior Management Service Class.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 5., an employee’s election to participate in the optional annuity program is irrevocable if the employee continues to be employed in an eligible position and continues to meet the eligibility requirements set forth in this paragraph.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective from July 1, 2002, through September 30, 2002, an active employee in a regularly established position who has elected to participate in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program has one opportunity to choose to move from the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program to the Florida Retirement System Pension Plan.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election must be made in writing and must be filed with the department and the personnel officer of the employer before October 1, 2002, or, in the case of an active employee who is on a leave of absence on July 1, 2002, within 90 days after the conclusion of the leave of absence. This election is irrevocable.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee shall receive service credit under the pension plan equal to his or her years of service under the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program. The cost for such credit is the amount representing the present value of that employee’s accumulated benefit obligation for the affected period of service.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must transfer the total accumulated employer contributions and earnings on deposit in his or her Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program account. If the transferred amount is not sufficient to pay the amount due, the employee must pay a sum representing the remainder of the amount due. The employee may not retain any employer contributions or earnings from the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program account.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retiree of a state-administered retirement system who is initially reemployed on or after July 1, 2010, may not renew membership in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Contributions.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Through June 30, 2001, each employer shall contribute on behalf of each member of the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program an amount equal to the normal cost portion of the employer retirement contribution which would be required if the member were a Senior Management Service Class member of the Florida Retirement System Pension Plan, plus the portion of the contribution rate required in s. 112.363(8) that would otherwise be assigned to the Retiree Health Insurance Subsidy Trust Fund.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2001, through June 30, 2011, each employer shall contribute on behalf of each member of the optional annuity program an amount equal to 12.49 percent of the employee’s gross monthly compensation.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2011, through June 30, 2012, each member of the optional annuity program shall contribute an amount equal to the employee contribution required under s. 121.71(3). The employer shall contribute on behalf of such employee an amount equal to the difference between 12.49 percent of the employee’s gross monthly compensation and the amount equal to the employee’s required contribution based on the employee’s gross monthly compensation.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2012, each member of the optional annuity program shall contribute an amount equal to the employee contribution required under <Reference Number="2" />s. 121.73. The employer shall contribute on behalf of such employee an amount equal to the difference between 9.27 percent of the employee’s gross monthly compensation and the amount equal to the employee’s required contribution based on the employee’s gross monthly compensation.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deduct an amount approved by the Legislature to provide for the administration of this program. Payment of the contributions, including contributions made by the employee, shall be made by the employer to the department, which shall forward the contributions to the designated company or companies contracting for payment of benefits for the member under the program.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employer shall contribute on behalf of each member of the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program an amount equal to the unfunded actuarial accrued liability portion of the employer contribution which would be required for members of the Senior Management Service Class in the Florida Retirement System. This contribution shall be paid to the department for transfer to the Florida Retirement System Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An Optional Annuity Program Trust Fund shall be established in the State Treasury and administered by the department to make payments to provider companies on behalf of the optional annuity program members, and to transfer the unfunded liability portion of the state optional annuity program contributions to the Florida Retirement System Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contributions required for social security by each employer and employee, in the amount required for social security coverage as now or hereafter may be provided by the federal Social Security Act shall be maintained for each member of the Senior Management Service retirement program and are in addition to the retirement contributions specified in this paragraph.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the optional annuity program may contribute by way of salary reduction or deduction a percentage amount of the employee’s gross compensation not to exceed the percentage amount contributed by the employer to the optional annuity program. Payment of the employee’s contributions shall be made by the employer to the department, which shall forward the contributions to the designated company or companies contracting for payment of benefits for the member under the program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Benefits.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Benefits under the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program are payable only to members of the program, or their beneficiaries as designated by the member in the contract with the provider company, and must be paid by the designated company in accordance with the terms of the annuity contract applicable to the member. A member must be terminated from all employment relationships with Florida Retirement System employers for 3 calendar months to begin receiving the employer-funded and employee-funded benefit. The department may authorize a distribution of up to 10 percent of the member’s account after being terminated from employment with all participating employers for 1 calendar month if the member has reached the normal retirement date as defined in s. 121.021. The department may adopt rules to implement this subparagraph. The member must meet the definition of termination in s. 121.021(39) beginning the month after receiving a benefit, including a distribution. Benefits funded by employer and employee contributions are payable under the terms of the contract to the member, his or her beneficiary, or his or her estate, in addition to:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lump-sum payment to the beneficiary upon the death of the member;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cash-out of a de minimis account upon the request of a former member who has been terminated for a minimum of 6 calendar months from the employment that entitled him or her to optional annuity program participation. Such cash-out must be a complete liquidation of the account balance with that company and is subject to the Internal Revenue Code;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mandatory distribution of a de minimis account of a former member who has been terminated for a minimum of 6 calendar months from the employment that entitled him or her to optional annuity program participation as authorized by the department; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lump-sum direct rollover distribution whereby all accrued benefits, plus interest and investment earnings, are paid from the member’s account directly to the custodian of an eligible retirement plan, as defined in s. 402(c)(8)(B) of the Internal Revenue Code, on behalf of the member.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program, benefits, including employee contributions, are not payable for employee hardships, unforeseeable emergencies, loans, medical expenses, educational expenses, purchase of a principal residence, payments necessary to prevent eviction or foreclosure on an employee’s principal residence, or any other reason except a requested distribution for retirement, a mandatory de minimis distribution authorized by the administrator, or a required minimum distribution provided pursuant to the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The benefits payable to any person under the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program, and any contribution accumulated under such program, are not subject to assignment, execution, or attachment or to any legal process whatsoever.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraph 5., a member who terminates employment and receives a distribution, including a rollover or trustee-to-trustee transfer, funded by employer and required employee contributions is a retiree of a state-administered retirement system. A retiree of a state-administered retirement system who is initially reemployed in a regularly established position on or after July 1, 2010, is not eligible to be enrolled in renewed membership.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member who receives optional annuity program benefits funded by employer and employee contributions as a mandatory distribution of a de minimis account authorized by the department is not considered a retiree.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">As used in this paragraph, a “de minimis account” means an account with a provider company containing employer and employee contributions and accumulated earnings of not more than $5,000 made under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Administration.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program authorized by this section shall be administered by the department. The department shall designate one or more provider companies from which annuity contracts may be purchased under the program and shall approve the form and content of the contracts. The department shall sign a contract with each of the provider companies and shall evaluate the performance of the provider companies on a continuing basis. The department may terminate the services of a provider company for reasons stated in the contract. The department shall adopt rules establishing its responsibilities and the responsibilities of employers in administering the optional annuity program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 1997, the State Board of Administration shall review and make recommendations to the department on the acceptability of all investment products proposed by provider companies of the optional annuity program before such products are offered through annuity contracts to the participants and may advise the department of any changes deemed necessary to ensure that the optional annuity program offers an acceptable mix of investment products. The department shall make the final determination as to whether an investment product will be approved for the program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of each contract applicable to a participant in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program shall be contained in a written program description which shall include a report of pertinent financial and actuarial information on the solvency and actuarial soundness of the program and the benefits applicable to the participant. Such description shall be furnished by the company or companies to each participant in the program and to the department upon commencement of participation in the program and annually thereafter.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall ensure that each participant in the Senior Management Service Optional Annuity Program is provided an accounting of the total contribution and the annual contribution made by and on behalf of such participants.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Dual employment.</Font><EmDash />A participant in the optional annuity program may not participate in more than one state-administered retirement system, plan, or class simultaneously. The following shall apply to a participant who is or becomes dually employed:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A participant who is or becomes dually employed in two or more positions covered by the Florida Retirement System, one of which is eligible for the optional annuity program and one of which is not, shall make one of the following choices:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remain a member of the optional annuity program, in which case contributions shall be paid as required only on the salary earned in the position eligible for the optional annuity program during the period of dual employment;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Elect, within 90 days after becoming dually employed, membership in the Regular Class of the Florida Retirement System in lieu of the optional annuity program, in which case contributions shall be paid as required on the total salary received for all employment, and, at retirement, the member’s average final compensation used to calculate any benefits for which he or she becomes eligible under the Florida Retirement System shall be based on all salary reported for all covered positions during the period of dual employment; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If dually employed in an elected office eligible for the Elected Officers’ Class, select, within 6 months after assuming office, membership in the Elected Officers’ Class, in which case, participation in the optional annuity program shall cease for the period of dual employment, retirement contributions shall be paid as required only on the salary earned as an elected officer, and, at retirement, the member’s benefit under the Florida Retirement System shall be based only on the salary received as an elected officer for the period of dual employment.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When such member ceases to be dually employed, he or she shall make one of the following choices:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the position in which he or she remains is a position that is eligible for the optional annuity program, he or she may, within 90 days after ceasing dual employment, elect to remain in the Florida Retirement System class for which he or she is eligible or to again become a participant in the optional annuity program. Failure to elect membership in the optional annuity program within 90 days shall result in compulsory membership in the Florida Retirement System; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the position in which he or she remains is not a position that is eligible for the optional annuity program, he or she shall participate in the Florida Retirement System class for which he or she is eligible.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 86-149; s. 7, ch. 87-373; s. 10, ch. 88-382; s. 2, ch. 89-126; s. 35, ch. 89-207; s. 11, ch. 90-274; s. 19, ch. 90-365; s. 56, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 6, ch. 93-193; s. 3, ch. 93-285; s. 7, ch. 94-259; s. 1425, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 96-278; s. 6, ch. 96-368; s. 5, ch. 96-423; s. 5, ch. 97-180; s. 9, ch. 98-136; s. 6, ch. 98-138; s. 5, ch. 98-413; s. 4, ch. 99-7; s. 5, ch. 99-9; s. 34, ch. 99-255; ss. 1, 2, ch. 99-291; s. 8, ch. 99-392; s. 19, ch. 2000-169; s. 5, ch. 2001-91; s. 4, ch. 2001-235; ss. 2, 7, 11, 15, ch. 2001-262; s. 147, ch. 2001-266; ss. 3, 12, ch. 2002-177; s. 5, ch. 2002-273; s. 12, ch. 2003-1; s. 7, ch. 2003-6; s. 141, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2005-205; s. 8, ch. 2007-196; s. 6, ch. 2009-209; s. 11, ch. 2011-68; s. 2, ch. 2012-146; s. 4, ch. 2012-222.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 121.73(3) relates to allocations from the Florida Retirement System Contributions Clearing Trust Fund to provide disability coverage for members in the investment plan; s. 121.71(3) relates to employee contributions.</Text></Note></Section>