<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Credit for workers’ compensation payment periods.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the retirement system created by this chapter who has been eligible or becomes eligible to receive workers’ compensation payments for an injury or illness occurring during his or her employment while a member of any state retirement system shall, upon return to active employment with a covered employer for 1 calendar month or upon approval for disability retirement in accordance with s. 121.091(4), receive full retirement credit for the period prior to such return to active employment or disability retirement for which the workers’ compensation payments were received. However, a member may not receive retirement credit for any such period occurring after the earlier of the date of maximum medical improvement as defined in s. 440.02 or the date termination has occurred as defined in s. 121.021(39). The employer of record at the time of the workers’ compensation injury or illness shall make the required employer and employee retirement contributions based on the member’s rate of monthly compensation immediately prior to his or her receiving workers’ compensation payments for retirement credit received by the member. The employer of record at the time of the workers’ compensation injury or illness shall be assessed by the division a penalty of 1 percent of the contributions on all contributions not paid on the first payroll report after the member becomes eligible to receive credit. This delinquent assessment may not be waived.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 72-347; s. 57, ch. 79-40; s. 15, ch. 90-274; s. 9, ch. 92-122; s. 777, ch. 95-147; s. 55, ch. 99-2; s. 7, ch. 2002-194; s. 21, ch. 2011-68.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>