<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.1001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Retirement System Preservation of Benefits Plan.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 1999, the Florida Retirement System Preservation of Benefits Plan is established as a qualified governmental excess benefit arrangement pursuant to s. 415(m) of the Internal Revenue Code. The Preservation of Benefits Plan is created as a separate portion of the Florida Retirement System, for the purpose of providing benefits to a payee (retiree or beneficiary) of the Florida Retirement System whose benefits would otherwise be limited by s. 415(b) of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBILITY TO PARTICIPATE IN THE PRESERVATION OF BENEFITS PLAN.<EmDash />A payee of the Florida Retirement System shall participate in the Preservation of Benefits Plan if his or her earned benefit under the Florida Retirement System Pension Plan exceeds the benefit maximum established under s. 415(b) of the Internal Revenue Code. Participation in the Preservation of Benefits Plan shall continue for as long as the payee’s earned benefit under the pension plan is reduced by the application of the maximum benefit limit under s. 415(b) of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BENEFITS PAYABLE UNDER THE PRESERVATION OF BENEFITS PLAN.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On and after July 1, 1999, the division shall pay to each eligible payee of the Florida Retirement System who retires before, on, or after that date, a supplemental retirement benefit equal to the difference between the amount of the payee’s monthly retirement benefit which would have been payable under the Florida Retirement System Pension Plan if not for a reduction due to the application of s. 415(b) of the Internal Revenue Code and the reduced monthly retirement benefit as paid to the payee. The Preservation of Benefits Plan benefit shall be computed and payable under the same terms and conditions and to the same person as would have applied under the pension plan were it not for the federal limitation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The benefits under the Preservation of Benefits Plan shall not be subject to execution, garnishment, attachment, or any other process of any court with respect to a payee under the Preservation of Benefits Plan except for qualified domestic relations orders by a court of competent jurisdiction, income deduction orders as provided in s. 61.1301, and federal income tax levies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTRIBUTIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Preservation of Benefits Plan shall be unfunded within the meaning of the federal tax laws. No payee contributions or deferrals, direct or indirect, by election or otherwise shall be made or allowed under the Preservation of Benefits Plan. Benefits due under the Preservation of Benefits Plan as determined by the Division of Retirement shall be paid timely from the Preservation of Benefits Plan Trust Fund, if created by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Retirement System monthly retirement contributions paid to the Division of Retirement by the payee’s past covered employer shall be reduced by the employer as directed by the Division of Retirement by an amount necessary to meet the requirements for payment of restored benefits under the Preservation of Benefits Plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADMINISTRATION.<EmDash />The Division of Retirement shall compile and maintain all records necessary or appropriate for the administration of the Preservation of Benefits Plan, including, but not limited to, the making of requisite calculations and disbursements under the Preservation of Benefits Plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 99-389; s. 16, ch. 2011-68; s. 37, ch. 2012-116.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>