<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.4503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Retirement System Contributions Clearing Trust Fund.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Retirement System Contributions Clearing Trust Fund is created as a clearing fund for disbursing employer and employee contributions to the component plans of the Florida Retirement System and shall be administered by the Department of Management Services. Funds shall be credited to the trust fund as provided in this chapter and held in trust for the contributing employees and employers until such time as the assets are transferred by the department to the Florida Retirement System Trust Fund, the Florida Retirement System Investment Plan Trust Fund, or other trust funds as authorized by law, to be used for the purposes of this chapter. The trust fund is exempt from the service charges imposed by s. 215.20.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Retirement System Contributions Clearing Trust Fund is a clearing trust fund of the Department of Management Services pursuant to s. 19(f), Art. III of the State Constitution, and is not subject to termination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 2002-73; s. 28, ch. 2011-68; s. 38, ch. 2012-116.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>