<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0121.0511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation of election and alternative plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of any municipality or independent special district that has elected to participate in the Florida Retirement System may revoke its election in accordance with the following procedure:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 30 days and at least 7 days before adopting a resolution to revoke the election, in order to establish an alternative retirement plan, a public hearing must be held on the proposed revocation and proposed alternative plan. Notice of this hearing must be given in accordance with the procedures specified in s. 166.041.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 7 days, but not more than 15 days, before the hearing, notice of intent to revoke, specifying the time and place of the hearing, must be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the area affected, as provided by ss. 50.011-50.031. Proof of publication of the notice must be submitted to the Department of Management Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a municipality or independent special district seeking to revoke its election to participate in the system must, before such revocation, have an actuarial report prepared and certified by an enrolled actuary, as defined in s. 112.625, illustrating the cost to the municipality or independent special district and to its future employees of providing a new retirement plan for employees hired after January 1, 1996.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the proposed alternative plan and report must be given to each representative of each certified bargaining unit before adoption of a revocation resolution under subsection (5). A municipality or independent special district that has a collective bargaining agreement with a certified bargaining agent may not exercise the right of revocation for future members of any covered class within the unit without negotiating such revocation and proposed alternative plan, as provided in chapter 447, with each bargaining unit covering such classes of employees. If more than one bargaining unit exists, each unit must negotiate independently. The new retirement plan for special risk employees must provide benefits which meet or exceed the minimum benefits contained in chapter plans under chapter 175 or chapter 185, as appropriate. For purposes of this subsection, “chapter plans” means those plans having minimum benefits required generally under these chapters, and not local law plans having variant benefits permissible under s. 175.351 or s. 185.35.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon meeting the requirement set forth in subsections (1)-(4), and subject to the conditions set forth in subsection (6), revocation of election to participate in the system and adoption of the new retirement plan must be accomplished by resolution adopted by the municipality or independent special district. The municipality or independent special district must provide written notice of such revocation to the Division of Retirement by mailing a copy of the resolution to the division, postmarked no later than December 15, 1995. The revocation shall take effect January 1, 1996.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following the adoption of a revocation resolution under subsection (5), all employees and officers of the municipality or special district who were participants in the Florida Retirement System before January 1, 1996, remain as participants in the system for as long as they are employees or officers of the municipality or independent special district, and all rights, duties, and obligations of the municipality or special district, the system, and the employees and officers remain in effect. An employee or officer who is hired or takes office on or after January 1, 1996, may not participate in the Florida Retirement System, and the revoking municipality or independent special district has no obligation to the system with respect to such employees and officers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 95-338; s. 30, ch. 99-255.</History></Section>