<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.1122" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purchase of retirement credit for in-state public service and in-state service in accredited nonpublic schools and colleges, including charter schools and charter technical career centers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 1998, a member of the Florida Retirement System may purchase creditable service for periods of certain public or nonpublic employment performed in this state, as provided in this section.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PURCHASE OF RETIREMENT CREDIT AUTHORIZED.<EmDash />Subject to the provisions of subsections (2) and (3), a member of the Florida Retirement System may purchase up to 5 years of retirement credit for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Periods of public employment in this state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Periods of employment in charter schools or charter technical career centers or in any nonpublic school or college in this state that is accredited by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Credit for 1 year of such service may be purchased for each year of creditable service a member completes under the Florida Retirement System.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIMITATIONS AND CONDITIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member is not eligible to receive credit for in-state service under this section until he or she has completed the years of creditable service required for vesting under the Florida Retirement System, excluding service purchased under this section and out-of-state service claimed and purchased under s. 121.1115.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member may not purchase and receive credit for more than 5 years of creditable service aggregated under this section and s. 121.1115.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service credit claimed under this section shall be credited only as service in the Regular Class and is subject to s. 112.65.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service credit may not be purchased under this section if the member is eligible to receive or is receiving a pension or benefit from a retirement or pension plan based on or including the service. Eligibility for or the receipt of contributions to a retirement plan made by the employer on behalf of the employee is considered a benefit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member is eligible to receive service credit for in-state service performed after leaving the Florida Retirement System only after completing at least 1 year of creditable service in the Florida Retirement System following the in-state service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The service claimed must have been service covered by a retirement or pension plan provided by the employer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COST.<EmDash />The cost to purchase retirement credit under this section shall be calculated in the same manner as set forth in s. 121.1115(2) for purchase of credit for out-of-state service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 97-180; s. 2, ch. 98-18; s. 4, ch. 98-302; s. 8, ch. 98-413; s. 11, ch. 2000-169; ss. 42, 43, ch. 2003-399; s. 11, ch. 2009-209; s. 19, ch. 2011-68.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>