<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.77" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Deductions from member accounts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Administration may authorize the third-party administrator to deduct reasonable fees and apply appropriate charges to investment plan member accounts. In no event may administrative and educational expenses exceed the portion of employer contributions earmarked for such expenses under this part, except for reasonable administrative charges assessed against member accounts of persons for whom no employer contributions are made during the calendar quarter. Investment management fees shall be deducted from member accounts, pursuant to the terms of the contract between the provider and the board.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-177; s. 38, ch. 2011-68.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>