<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0121.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of system; appropriation; oaths; actuarial studies; public records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services has the authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of law conferring duties upon the department and to adopt rules as are necessary for the effective and efficient administration of this system. The funds to pay the expenses for administration of the system are hereby appropriated from the interest earned on investments made for the Retirement System Trust Fund and the assessments allowed under chapter 650.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services is authorized to require oaths, by affidavit or otherwise, and acknowledgments from persons in connection with the administration of its duties and responsibilities under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator shall cause an actuarial study of the system to be made at least annually and shall report the results of such study to the Legislature by December 31 prior to the next legislative session. The study shall, at a minimum, conform to the requirements of s. 112.63, with the following exceptions and additions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The valuation of plan assets shall be based on a 5-year averaging methodology such as that specified in the United States Department of Treasury Regulations, 26 C.F.R. s. 1.412(c)(2)-1 in effect on August 16, 2006, or a similar accepted approach designed to attenuate fluctuations in asset values.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The study shall include a narrative explaining the changes in the covered group over the period between actuarial valuations and the impact of those changes on actuarial results.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When substantial changes in actuarial assumptions have been made, the study shall reflect the results of an actuarial assumption as of the current date based on the assumptions utilized in the prior actuarial report.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The study shall include an analysis of the changes in actuarial valuation results by the factors generating those changes. Such analysis shall reconcile the current actuarial valuation results with those results from the prior valuation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The study shall include measures of funding status and funding progress designed to facilitate the assessment of trends over several actuarial valuations with respect to the overall solvency of the system. Such measures shall be adopted by the department and shall be used consistently in all actuarial valuations performed on the system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actuarial model used to determine the adequate level of funding for the Florida Retirement System shall include a specific rate stabilization mechanism, as prescribed herein. It is the intent of the Legislature to maintain as a reserve a specific portion of any actuarial surplus, and to use such reserve for the purpose of offsetting future unfunded liabilities caused by experience losses, thereby minimizing the risk of future increases in contribution rates. It is further the intent of the Legislature that the use of any excess above the reserve to offset retirement system normal costs shall be in a manner that will allow system employers to plan appropriately for resulting cost reductions and subsequent cost increases. The rate stabilization mechanism shall operate as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The actuarial surplus shall be the value of actuarial assets over actuarial liabilities, as is determined on the preceding June 30 or as may be estimated on the preceding December 31.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full amount of any experience loss shall be offset, to the extent possible, by any actuarial surplus.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the actuarial surplus exceeds 5 percent of actuarial liabilities, one-half of the excess may be used to offset total retirement system costs. In addition, if the actuarial surplus exceeds 10 percent of actuarial liabilities, an additional one-fourth of the excess above 10 percent may be used to offset total retirement system costs. In addition, if the actuarial surplus exceeds 15 percent of actuarial liabilities, an additional one-fourth of the excess above 15 percent may be used to offset total retirement system costs.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any surplus amounts available to offset total retirement system costs pursuant to subparagraph 3. should be amortized each year over a 10-year rolling period on a level-dollar basis.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 112.64(4) to the contrary, the net increase, if any, in unfunded liability under the system arising from significant system amendments adopted or changes in assumptions shall be amortized within 30 plan years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and addresses of retirees are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) to the extent that no state or local governmental agency may provide the names or addresses of such persons in aggregate, compiled, or list form to any person except to a public agency engaged in official business. However, a state or local government agency may provide the names and addresses of retirees from that agency to a bargaining agent as defined in s. 447.203(12) or to a retiree organization for official business use. Lists of names or addresses of retirees may be exchanged by public agencies, but such lists shall not be provided to, or open for inspection by, the public. Any person may view or copy any individual’s retirement records at the Department of Management Services, one record at a time, or may obtain information by a separate written request for a named individual for which information is desired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless prior written approval is obtained from the department or state board, any promotional materials or advertisements that, directly or indirectly, refer to the “Florida Retirement System” or the “FRS” must contain a disclaimer that the information is not approved or endorsed by the Florida Retirement System.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 70-112; s. 2, ch. 75-248; s. 6, ch. 81-295; s. 3, ch. 83-76; s. 4, ch. 84-266; ss. 64, 68, ch. 86-168; s. 6, ch. 88-382; s. 6, ch. 90-274; s. 80, ch. 91-45; s. 3, ch. 92-122; s. 54, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 26, ch. 94-249; s. 42, ch. 96-406; s. 28, ch. 99-255; s. 5, ch. 99-392; s. 19, ch. 2000-151; s. 26, ch. 2000-169; s. 39, ch. 2000-371; s. 10, ch. 2004-234; s. 3, ch. 2008-139; s. 2, ch. 2009-209.</History></Section>