<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0121.047" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Consolidation of liabilities and assets; Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences Supplemental Retirement Program; restriction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2007, the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences Supplemental Retirement Program, as established under s. 121.40, shall be consolidated under the Florida Retirement System and the system shall assume:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All liabilities related to the payment of supplemental monthly benefits to retired employees of the institute and their surviving beneficiaries; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All obligations in regard to funding and administering benefits accrued for the benefit of retired employees of the institute and their surviving beneficiaries.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator shall, as of July 1, 2007, cause to be transferred to the trust fund of the Florida Retirement System all assets of the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences Supplemental Retirement Trust Fund, including moneys, securities, and other property accumulated to date, as well as all liabilities and obligations connected therewith. Upon such transfer of assets, liabilities, and obligations, the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences Supplemental Retirement Trust Fund shall be abolished and the administrator shall become the trustee of any funds transferred to the Florida Retirement System.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in the Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences Supplemental Retirement Program does not constitute membership in the Florida Retirement System.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2007-100.</History></Section>