<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0121.355" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community College Optional Retirement Program and State University System Optional Retirement Program member transfer.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 2009, through December 31, 2009, an employee who is a former member of the Community College Optional Retirement Program or the State University System Optional Retirement Program and present mandatory member of the Florida Retirement System Pension Plan may receive service credit equal to his or her years of service under the Community College Optional Retirement Program or the State University System Optional Retirement Program under the following conditions:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cost for such credit must represent the actuarial accrued liability for the affected period of service. The cost shall be calculated using the discount rate and other relevant actuarial assumptions that were used to value the Florida Retirement System Pension Plan liabilities in the most recent actuarial valuation. The calculation must include any service already maintained under the pension plan in addition to the years under the Community College Optional Retirement Program or the State University System Optional Retirement Program. The actuarial accrued liability of any service already maintained under the pension plan shall be applied as a credit to total cost resulting from the calculation. The division shall ensure that the transfer sum is prepared using a formula and methodology certified by an enrolled actuary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee must transfer from his or her Community College Optional Retirement Program account or State University System Optional Retirement Program account, subject to the terms of the applicable optional retirement program contract, and from other employee moneys as necessary, a sum representing the actuarial accrued liability immediately following the time of such movement, determined assuming that attained service equals the sum of service in the pension plan and service in the Community College Optional Retirement Program or State University System Optional Retirement Program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employee may not receive service credit for a period of mandatory participation in the State University Optional Retirement Program or for a period for which a distribution was received from the Community College Optional Retirement Program or State University System Optional Retirement Program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2008-139; s. 25, ch. 2011-68.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 41, ch. 2011-68, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) Effective upon this act becoming a law, the State Board of Administration and the Department of Management Services shall request, as soon as practicable, a determination letter and private letter ruling from the United States Internal Revenue Service. If the United States Internal Revenue Service refuses to act upon a request for a private letter ruling, then a legal opinion from a qualified tax attorney or firm may be substituted for such private letter ruling.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) If the board or the department receives notification from the United States Internal Revenue Service that this act or any portion of this act will cause the Florida Retirement System, or a portion thereof, to be disqualified for tax purposes under the Internal Revenue Code, then the portion that will cause the disqualification does not apply. Upon receipt of such notice, the state board and the department shall notify the presiding officers of the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>