<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0121.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conduct of commission business; legal and other assistance; compensation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall conduct its business within the following guidelines:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of hearing appeals under s. 121.23, the commission may meet in panels of no fewer than three members. A quorum shall consist of three members. The concurring vote of a majority of the members present is required to reach a decision, issue orders, and conduct the business of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall elect a chair and such other officers as it deems necessary. The chair or the chair’s designee shall conduct the meetings and hearings of the commission and shall take whatever action is necessary to ensure that the business of the commission is conducted in an equitable, orderly, and expeditious manner. All parties shall abide by the decisions of the chair or the chair’s designee, unless he or she is overruled by a majority of members present.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legal counsel for the commission may be provided by the Department of Legal Affairs or by the Department of Management Services, with the concurrence of the commission, and shall be paid by the Department of Management Services from the appropriate funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall provide timely and appropriate training for newly appointed members of the commission. Such training shall be designed to acquaint new members of the commission with the duties and responsibilities of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall furnish administrative and secretarial assistance to the commission and shall provide a place where the commission may hold its meetings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Retirement Commission has the authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of law conferring duties upon the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the commission shall be paid a stipend of $100 for each day spent on the work of the commission. Additionally, each member shall receive per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061. The official headquarters of each member, for the purpose of calculating per diem and travel expenses, shall be his or her permanent home address. Members of a state-administered retirement system who are appointed to the commission shall have their work on the commission considered as part of their regular job assignments and shall not be required to take leave while engaged in the business of the commission. The receipt of such stipend shall have no effect on the retirement benefits of a retired member of the commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 75-248; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 9, ch. 83-76; ss. 15, 16, 17, ch. 86-149; s. 13, ch. 90-502; s. 1, ch. 92-63; s. 329, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 33, ch. 94-249; s. 1430, ch. 95-147; s. 49, ch. 99-255; s. 13, ch. 99-392; s. 3, ch. 2005-134; s. 16, ch. 2009-209.</History></Section>