<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0006.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lands owned or controlled by United States Department of Interior; Governor authorized to cede concurrent jurisdiction to enforce criminal laws.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service, shall desire to acquire concurrent jurisdiction to enforce criminal laws on any lands owned or controlled by the United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service, within this state and shall make application for that purpose, the Governor is authorized to cede to the United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service, such measure of jurisdiction, not exceeding that requested, as the Governor may deem proper, over all or any part of such lands as to which a cession of the concurrent jurisdiction to enforce criminal laws is requested.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application on behalf of the United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service, shall state in particular the measure of jurisdiction desired and shall be accompanied by an accurate description of the lands over which such jurisdiction is desired and by information as to which of such lands are then owned or controlled by the United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cession of jurisdiction shall become effective when it is accepted on behalf of the United States, which acceptance shall be indicated, in writing upon the instrument of cession, by an authorized official of the United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service, and by filing with the Secretary of State of the State of Florida.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state reserves jurisdiction, for itself and its political subdivisions, to enforce the laws on any lands for which concurrent jurisdiction has been ceded to the United States pursuant to this act. No person residing on such lands shall be deprived of any civil or political rights, including the right of suffrage, by reason of the cession of concurrent jurisdiction to the United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the United States tenders to the state a relinquishment of all or part of the jurisdiction theretofore acquired by it over lands within this state, the Governor is authorized to accept on behalf of the state the jurisdiction so relinquished; provided, however, that the Governor shall not accept a relinquishment of all or part of such jurisdiction over an Indian tribe recognized by the United States without the consent of its federally recognized tribal governing body.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor shall indicate his or her acceptance of such relinquished jurisdiction by a writing addressed to the head of the appropriate department or agency of the United States, and such acceptance shall be effective when said writing is deposited in the United States mail.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 86-67; s. 3, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>