<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0006.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida-Alabama boundary redefined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The middle of the Perdido River at its mouth, as defined by the Constitutions of the States of Alabama and Florida, is at latitude 30°16′53″ N. and longitude 87°31′06″ W. as the control point; the boundary line at the mouth of the Perdido River is fixed, as nearly as may be, in the axis of the mouth of said river, passing through the control point and running north and south and having as its northern terminus a point of latitude 30°17′02″ N. and longitude 87°31′06″ W., and as its southern terminus a point 1,000 feet due south of the control point; from the northern terminus of the boundary line at the mouth of the river, the boundary up the lower portion of said river be a straight line to a point at latitude 30°18′00″ N., longitude 87°27′08″ W., thence by a straight line to a point in the center line of the intracoastal canal at longitude 87°27′00″ W.; the seaward boundary between Florida and Alabama extends from the south end of the boundary line at the mouth of the Perdido River, thence south 0°01′00″ W. to the seaward limit of each respective state; and shall be deemed, taken and declared, and is hereby deemed, taken and declared to be the boundary line between the States of Florida and Alabama, at the mouth of the Perdido River and adjacent thereto, and shall be deemed and taken as such by the authorities and people of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing herein contained, nor any operations of the provisions of this section, shall prejudice the rights or claims of private individuals to any of the lands herein involved whether such rights or claims arise or exist upon the basis that the lands herein defined as being within the boundaries of the State of Alabama were previously a part of the State of Florida or included within the boundaries of the State of Florida or otherwise.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 5, ch. 28141, 1953.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Boundary.—Consent given by 68 Stat. 182, May 6, 1954.</Text></Note></Section>