<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0914.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tampering with or harassing a witness, victim, or informant; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly uses intimidation or physical force, or threatens another person, or attempts to do so, or engages in misleading conduct toward another person, or offers pecuniary benefit or gain to another person, with intent to cause or induce any person to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withhold testimony, or withhold a record, document, or other object, from an official investigation or official proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alter, destroy, mutilate, or conceal an object with intent to impair the integrity or availability of the object for use in an official investigation or official proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evade legal process summoning that person to appear as a witness, or to produce a record, document, or other object, in an official investigation or an official proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be absent from an official proceeding to which such person has been summoned by legal process;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hinder, delay, or prevent the communication to a law enforcement officer or judge of information relating to the commission or possible commission of an offense or a violation of a condition of probation, parole, or release pending a judicial proceeding; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Testify untruthfully in an official investigation or an official proceeding,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits the crime of tampering with a witness, victim, or informant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tampering with a witness, victim, or informant is a:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a misdemeanor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a third degree felony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a second degree felony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the first degree, punishable by a term of years not exceeding life or as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a first degree felony or a first degree felony punishable by a term of years not exceeding life.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a life or capital felony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the offense level of the affected official investigation or official proceeding is indeterminable or where the affected official investigation or official proceeding involves a noncriminal investigation or proceeding.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever intentionally harasses another person and thereby hinders, delays, prevents, or dissuades any person from:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attending or testifying in an official proceeding or cooperating in an official investigation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reporting to a law enforcement officer or judge the commission or possible commission of an offense or a violation of a condition of probation, parole, or release pending a judicial proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arresting or seeking the arrest of another person in connection with an offense; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Causing a criminal prosecution, or a parole or probation revocation proceeding, to be sought or instituted, or from assisting in such prosecution or proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">or attempts to do so, commits the crime of harassing a witness, victim, or informant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Harassing a witness, victim, or informant is a:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a misdemeanor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a third degree felony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a second degree felony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a first degree felony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the first degree, punishable by a term of years not exceeding life or as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the official investigation or official proceeding affected involves the investigation or prosecution of a felony of the first degree punishable by a term of years not exceeding life or a prosecution of a life or capital felony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, where the offense level of the affected official investigation or official proceeding is indeterminable or where the affected official investigation or official proceeding involves a noncriminal investigation or proceeding.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An official proceeding need not be pending or about to be instituted at the time of the offense; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The testimony or the record, document, or other object need not be admissible in evidence or free of a claim of privilege.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a prosecution for an offense under this section, no state of mind need be proved with respect to the circumstance:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the official proceeding before a judge, court, grand jury, or government agency is before a judge or court of the state, a state or local grand jury, or a state agency; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the judge is a judge of the state or that the law enforcement officer is an officer or employee of the state or a person authorized to act for or on behalf of the state or serving the state as an adviser or consultant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 72-315; s. 44, ch. 75-298; s. 14, ch. 84-363; s. 4, ch. 88-96; s. 12, ch. 91-223; s. 225, ch. 91-224; s. 1, ch. 92-281; s. 33, ch. 2004-11; s. 19, ch. 2008-238.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 918.14.</Text></Note></Section>