<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0026.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Judicial circuits; judges.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The first circuit is composed of Escambia, Okaloosa, Santa Rosa, and Walton Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The second circuit is composed of Leon, Gadsden, Jefferson, Wakulla, Liberty, and Franklin Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The third circuit is composed of Columbia, Dixie, Hamilton, Lafayette, Madison, Suwannee, and Taylor Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fourth circuit is composed of Clay, Duval, and Nassau Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fifth circuit is composed of Citrus, Hernando, Lake, Marion, and Sumter Counties. Two of the circuit judges authorized for the fifth circuit shall reside in either Citrus, Hernando, or Sumter County, and neither of such two judges shall reside in the same county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sixth circuit is composed of Pasco and Pinellas Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The seventh circuit is composed of Flagler, Putnam, St. Johns, and Volusia Counties. One judge shall reside in Flagler County; two judges shall reside in Putnam County; two judges shall reside in St. Johns County; and three judges shall reside in Volusia County. There shall be no residency requirement for any other judges in the circuit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The eighth circuit is composed of Alachua, Baker, Bradford, Gilchrist, Levy, and Union Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ninth circuit is composed of Orange and Osceola Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tenth circuit is composed of Hardee, Highlands, and Polk Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The eleventh circuit is composed of Miami-Dade County.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The twelfth circuit is composed of Manatee, Sarasota, and DeSoto Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The thirteenth circuit is composed of Hillsborough County.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fourteenth circuit is composed of Bay, Calhoun, Gulf, Holmes, Jackson, and Washington Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fifteenth circuit is composed of Palm Beach County.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sixteenth circuit is composed of Monroe County. One judge in the circuit shall reside in the middle or upper Keys. There shall be no residency requirement for any other judge in the circuit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The seventeenth circuit is composed of Broward County.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The eighteenth circuit is composed of Brevard and Seminole Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nineteenth circuit is composed of Indian River, Martin, Okeechobee, and St. Lucie Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The twentieth circuit is composed of Charlotte, Collier, Glades, Hendry, and Lee Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsections (1)-(20), the territorial jurisdiction of a circuit court may be expanded as provided for in s. 910.03(3).</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The judicial nominating commission of each circuit, in submitting nominations for any vacancy in a judgeship, and the Governor, in filling any vacancy for a judgeship, shall consider whether the existing judges within the circuit, together with potential nominees or appointees, reflect the geographic distribution of the population within the circuit, the geographic distribution of the caseload within the circuit, the racial and ethnic diversity of the population within the circuit, and the geographic distribution of the racial and ethnic minority population within the circuit.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 72-404; s. 1, ch. 80-164; s. 1, ch. 81-220; s. 1, ch. 82-238; s. 1, ch. 94-137; s. 2, ch. 94-184; s. 8, ch. 2008-4.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 26.02, 26.03, 26.04, 26.05, 26.06, 26.07, 26.08-26.16, and 26.161-26.165.</Text></Note></Section>