<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0026.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction of circuit court.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Circuit courts shall have jurisdiction of appeals from county courts except appeals of county court orders or judgments declaring invalid a state statute or a provision of the State Constitution and except orders or judgments of a county court which are certified by the county court to the district court of appeal to be of great public importance and which are accepted by the district court of appeal for review. Circuit courts shall have jurisdiction of appeals from final administrative orders of local government code enforcement boards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">They shall have exclusive original jurisdiction:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all actions at law not cognizable by the county courts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of proceedings relating to the settlement of the estates of decedents and minors, the granting of letters testamentary, guardianship, involuntary hospitalization, the determination of incompetency, and other jurisdiction usually pertaining to courts of probate;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all cases in equity including all cases relating to juveniles except traffic offenses as provided in chapters 316 and 985;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of all felonies and of all misdemeanors arising out of the same circumstances as a felony which is also charged;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all cases involving legality of any tax assessment or toll or denial of refund, except as provided in s. 72.011;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In actions of ejectment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all actions involving the title and boundaries of real property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court may issue injunctions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chief judge of a circuit may authorize a county court judge to order emergency hospitalizations pursuant to part I of chapter 394 in the absence from the county of the circuit judge; and the county court judge shall have the power to issue all temporary orders and temporary injunctions necessary or proper to the complete exercise of such jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A circuit court is a trial court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 72-404; s. 1, ch. 74-209; s. 1, ch. 77-119; s. 1, ch. 80-399; s. 1, ch. 81-178; s. 22, ch. 81-259; s. 12, ch. 82-37; s. 2, ch. 84-303; s. 5, ch. 91-112; s. 27, ch. 94-353; s. 52, ch. 95-280; s. 3, ch. 98-280; s. 1, ch. 2004-11.</History></Section>