<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0074.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Drainage districts and housing authorities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action instituted by a drainage or subdrainage district, or housing authority wherein the petitioner seeks to avail itself of the provisions of this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Action under this chapter shall not be taken unless the chair or other legally constituted head of the petitioning authority empowered to acquire the land shall be of the opinion that the ultimate award probably will be within the limits of the authority’s ability to pay.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be lawful for the petitioner to expend moneys duly appropriated for the purpose of availing itself of the provisions of this chapter in going forward with the project for which the land was taken; provided that, in the opinion of the attorney representing the taking authority, the title has been vested in the authority taking, or all persons having an interest therein have been made parties to such proceeding and will be bound by the final judgment therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No money shall be paid nor contracts made for payment for any construction or maintenance proposed by the petitioner under this chapter in excess of the amount specifically appropriated therefor by the Legislature of the state, or procured by and secured to the petitioner under contracts with private persons, firms, or corporations in accordance with the laws authorizing such taking authority to negotiate contracts with private persons, firms, or corporations, or by the issuance of bonds and other debentures pursuant to tax levies duly made, all in accordance with the law in such cases made and provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The attorney representing the petitioner is authorized to stipulate or agree in behalf of the taking authority to exclude any property, or any part thereof, or any interest therein, that may have been, or may be taken by or on behalf of the authority taking by the declaration of taking, or otherwise.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 65-369; s. 366, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>