<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0257.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of Library and Information Services authorized to accept and expend federal funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Library and Information Services of the Department of State is designated as the state library administrative agency authorized to accept, receive, administer, and expend any moneys, materials, or any other aid granted, appropriated, or made available by the United States or any of its agencies for the purpose of giving aid to libraries and providing educational library service in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to file any accounts required by federal law or regulation with reference to receiving and administering all such moneys, materials, and other aid for said purposes; provided, however, that the acceptance of such moneys, materials, and other aid shall not deprive the state from complete control and supervision of its library.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All public libraries are encouraged to adopt an Internet safety education program, including the implementation of a computer-based educational program, which has been endorsed by a government-sanctioned law enforcement agency or other reputable public safety advocacy organization and is designed for children and adults. The purpose of the Internet safety education program is to promote the use of prudent online deportment and broaden awareness of online predators. The program must be interactive and age-appropriate. Each library shall annually report to the division the annual number of program participants who complete the Internet safety education program. By April 1, 2010, the division shall adopt rules for rewarding those libraries in the program grant application process which have had 1 percent or more of their annual number of program participants, based on the total number of registered borrowers from the preceding year, complete the Internet safety education program adopted by the library. Program participants completing the program as a result of strategic partnerships or collaboration between the library and other entities shall be integrated into the library’s annual report. The division shall adopt rules to allocate 10 percent of the total points available in the library services and technology grant application evaluation process to public libraries that are in compliance with this section, beginning with the grant application cycle for the 2011-2012 fiscal year.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 26976, 1951; s. 4, ch. 63-39; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 21, ch. 69-353; s. 18, ch. 86-163; s. 4, ch. 2005-207; s. 1, ch. 2009-194.</History></Section>