<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0257.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Equalization grants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county qualifying for an operating grant is eligible to receive an equalization grant if it meets the following criteria:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county was eligible for an equalization grant in fiscal year 2007-2008.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value of 1 mill adjusted to reflect the average statewide level of assessment is below the median amount for all counties in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county operating millage subject to the 10-mill cap is equal to or above the average for all counties. If the county does not meet this millage requirement, the per capita income for the county must be equal to or below the average for all counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county has been eligible for an equalization grant each fiscal year since fiscal year 2007-2008.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a county fails to meet the eligibility criteria for an equalization grant in any one year, the county shall be notified that its equalization grant funding will be phased out over a 3-year period as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the first year, the county shall receive the grant amount for which it qualified the previous year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the second year, the county shall receive two-thirds of the grant amount it received under paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the third year, the county shall receive one-third of the grant amount it received under paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In subsequent years, the county shall not be eligible to receive an equalization grant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An equalization grant to an eligible county is calculated in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The equalization factor is computed by subtracting the value of 1 mill adjusted to reflect the average statewide level of assessment for each county from the average adjusted value of 1 mill for all counties and then dividing that amount by the average adjusted value of 1 mill for all counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An equalization grant is computed by multiplying the equalization factor times the total local funds expended for library support by that county during the second preceding year and adding that amount to the actual total local funds expended for library support by that county during the second preceding year. The result is the adjusted value for the local funds expended for library service. The amount of the equalization grant is equal to 25 cents of the adjusted value of local funds expended for library service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the adjusted mill equivalent of actual local funds expended for library support by the county during the second preceding year is above the statewide average adjusted mill equivalent of actual local funds expended by all counties receiving operating grants, the amount of the equalization grant is equal to 50 cents of the adjusted value of local funds expended for library service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county may not receive an equalization grant that is equal to more than 10 percent of the total amount required to fund equalization grants to all eligible counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Library and Information Services shall calculate equalization grants based on the amount of local funds expended for library service the second preceding year as certified by the appropriate county officials and information on the level of assessment of property in each county, the taxable value of property in each county, the county operating millage subject to the 10-mill cap, and the per capita income as reported by the agency authorized by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Equalization grants may not exceed 15 percent of the amount appropriated for operating, multicounty, and equalization grants or $8,877,057, whichever is greater. Any reductions in equalization grants necessary to meet this requirement must be applied to all equalization grants on a prorated basis. This includes grants subject to the 10-percent cap or grants in the phase-out period. If the total appropriation for operating, multicounty, and equalization grants is less than $31,999,233, s. 257.21 applies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 61-402; s. 4, ch. 72-353; s. 2, ch. 73-138; s. 5, ch. 83-24; s. 3, ch. 92-305; s. 2, ch. 2008-158.</History></Section>