<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0257.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Publications, pictures, and other documents received to constitute part of State Library; powers and duties of Division of Library and Information Services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All books, pictures, documents, publications, and manuscripts received through gifts, purchase, or exchange, or on deposit from any source for the use of the state, shall constitute a part of the State Library and shall be placed therein for the use of the public under the control of the Division of Library and Information Services of the Department of State. The division may receive gifts of money, books, or other property which may be used or held for the purpose or purposes given; and it may purchase books, periodicals, furniture, and equipment as it deems necessary to promote the efficient operation of the service it is expected to render the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may, upon request, give aid and assistance, financial, advisory, or otherwise, to all school, state institutional, academic, free, and public libraries, and to all communities in the state which may propose to establish libraries, as to the best means of establishing and administering libraries, selecting and cataloging books, and other facets of library management.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall maintain a library for state officials and employees, especially of informational material pertaining to the phases of their work, and provide for them material for general reading and study.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall maintain and provide research and information services for all state agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall make all necessary arrangements to provide library services to the blind and physically handicapped persons of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may issue printed material, such as lists and circulars of information, and in the publication thereof may cooperate with state library commissions and libraries of other states in order to secure the more economical administration of the work for which it is formed. It may conduct courses of library instruction and hold librarians’ institutes in various parts of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall perform such other services and engage in any other activity, not contrary to law, that it may think appropriate in the development of library service to state government, to the libraries and library profession of the state, and to the citizens of the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 10278, 1925; CGL 1690; s. 4, ch. 63-39; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 21, ch. 69-353; s. 3, ch. 74-228; s. 2, ch. 83-24; s. 16, ch. 86-163.</History></Section>