<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0257.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State Library Council.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a State Library Council to advise and assist the Division of Library and Information Services on its programs and activities. The council shall consist of nine members who shall be appointed by the Secretary of State. Of the nine members at least one must represent a Florida library professional association, at least one must represent a Florida archive professional association, at least one must represent a Florida records management professional association, and at least one must be a person who is not, and has never been, employed in a library or in teaching library science courses. Members shall be appointed for 4-year terms. A vacancy on the council shall be filled for the period of the unexpired term. No person may be appointed to serve more than two consecutive terms as a member of the council. The Secretary of State may remove from office any council member for malfeasance, misfeasance, neglect of duty, incompetence, permanent inability to perform official duties, or pleading guilty or nolo contendere to, or being found guilty of, a felony.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without compensation or honorarium but shall be entitled to receive reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061. The council shall meet at the call of its chair, at the request of a majority of its membership, at the request of the division, or at such times as may be prescribed by its rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of State may, in making appointments, consult Florida’s library, archival, or records management community and related statewide associations and organizations for suggestions as to persons having special knowledge and interest concerning libraries.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officers of the State Library Council shall be a chair, elected from the members thereof, and the State Librarian, who shall serve without voting rights as secretary of the council.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 10278, 1925; CGL 1688; s. 2, ch. 63-39; s. 19, ch. 63-400; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 21, ch. 69-353; s. 2, ch. 70-250; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 1, ch. 71-279; s. 2, ch. 74-228; s. 4, ch. 78-323; ss. 2, 3, 4, ch. 81-68; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 14, ch. 86-163; s. 3, ch. 87-172; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 90-21; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 150, ch. 95-148; s. 2, ch. 2005-207.</History></Section>