<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0257.172" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Multicounty library grants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrative unit of a multicounty library that serves a population of 50,000 or more and serves two or more counties, at least one of which qualifies for an equalization grant, is eligible for an annual grant from the state. The grant funds are to be used for the support and extension of library service in participating counties. The grant must be computed by the division on a state matching basis up to $1 million in local expenditures by all participating counties for operation and maintenance of a library during the second preceding year. The administrative unit of a multicounty library with:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two participating counties is eligible for a grant equal to 5 cents on each local dollar of expenditure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three participating counties is eligible for a grant equal to 10 cents on each local dollar of expenditure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four participating counties is eligible for a grant equal to 15 cents on each local dollar of expenditure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five participating counties is eligible for a grant equal to 20 cents on each local dollar of expenditure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Six or more participating counties is eligible for a grant equal to 25 cents on each local dollar of expenditure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, to support multicounty library service, the administrative unit of a multicounty library with:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two participating counties is eligible to receive a base grant of $50,000, effective July 1, 2008.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three or more participating counties is eligible to receive a base grant of a minimum of $250,000. Such amount shall be increased to $350,000 when the appropriation from state funds for operating, multicounty, and equalization grants is at least 3 percent more than the appropriation from state funds for those grants for fiscal year 2007-2008.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, s. 257.21 does not apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 83-24; s. 59, ch. 85-80; s. 2, ch. 92-305; s. 1, ch. 94-109; s. 1, ch. 2008-158.</History></Section>