<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0022.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Seat of government; emergency temporary location.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever, due to an emergency resulting from the effects of enemy attack, or the anticipated effects of a threatened enemy attack, it becomes imprudent, inexpedient, or impossible to conduct the affairs of state government at the normal location of the seat thereof in the City of Tallahassee, Leon County, the Governor shall, as often as the exigencies of the situation require, by proclamation, declare an emergency temporary location, or locations, for the seat of government at such place, or places, within or without this state as he or she may deem advisable under the circumstances, and shall take such action and issue such orders as may be necessary for an orderly transition of the affairs of state government to such emergency temporary location, or locations. Such emergency temporary location, or locations, shall remain as the seat of government until the Legislature shall by law establish a new location, or locations, or until the emergency is declared to be ended by the Governor and the seat of government is returned to its normal location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During such time as the seat of government remains at such emergency temporary location, or locations, all official acts now or hereafter required by law to be performed at the seat of government by any officer, agency, department or authority of this state, including the convening and meeting of the Legislature in regular, extraordinary or emergency session, shall be as valid and binding when performed at such emergency temporary location, or locations, as if performed at the normal location of the seat of government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall control and be supreme in the event it shall be employed notwithstanding the provisions of any other law to the contrary or in conflict herewith.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 59-498; s. 86, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>