<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0632.605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purposes and powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A society shall operate for the benefit of members and their beneficiaries by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing benefits as specified in s. 632.617; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operating for one or more social, intellectual, educational, charitable, benevolent, moral, fraternal, patriotic, or religious purposes for the benefit of its members, which may also be extended to others; provided that such purposes do not endanger the solvency of the society. Such purposes as set forth in this paragraph may be carried out directly by the society or indirectly through subsidiary corporations or affiliated organizations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No subsidiary corporation or affiliated organization shall transact insurance or engage in any other activity regulated under the Florida Insurance Code or other Florida law unless the subsidiary corporation or affiliated organization complies with all provisions of the applicable law. No society or subsidiary corporation or affiliated organization through which a society carries out its purposes shall own or operate a funeral home or undertaking establishment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every society shall have the power to adopt laws and rules for the government of the society, the admission of its members, and the management of its affairs. The society shall have the power to change, alter, add to, or amend such laws and rules and shall have such other powers as are necessary and incidental to carrying into effect the objects and purposes of the society.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 86-140; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>