<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0632.628" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports shall be filed in accordance with the provisions of this section. Every society transacting business in this state shall annually, on or before March 1, unless for cause shown such time has been extended by the office, file with the office a true statement of its financial condition, transactions, and affairs for the preceding calendar year and pay a fee for filing same, as provided in s. 624.501(4). The statement shall be in general form and context as approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners for fraternal benefits societies and as supplemented by additional information required by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of the annual statement herein required, each society shall, on or before March 1, file with the office a valuation of its certificates in force on December 31 last preceding, provided the office may, in its discretion for cause shown, extend the time for filing such valuation for not more than 2 calendar months. Such valuation shall be done in accordance with the standards specified in s. 632.627. Such valuation and underlying data shall be certified by a qualified actuary or, at the expense of the society, verified by the actuary of the insurance regulatory agency of the state of domicile of the society.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A society neglecting to file the annual statement in the form and within the time provided by this section shall be subject to an administrative fine in an amount up to $100 for each day during which such neglect continues, and, upon notice by the office to that effect, its authority to do business in this state shall cease while such default continues.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall deposit all fees received under this section to the credit of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 86-140; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1385, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>