<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0632.634" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensing and appointment of agents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agents of societies shall be licensed and appointed in accordance with the provisions of the Florida Insurance Code regulating the licensing, appointment, examination, revocation, suspension, or termination of the license of resident and nonresident life, health, and variable annuity insurance agents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No examination, license, or appointment shall be required of any regular salaried officer, employee, or member of a licensed society who devotes substantially all of her or his services to activities other than the solicitation of benefit contracts from the public and who receives no commission or other compensation directly dependent upon the amount of business obtained for the solicitation of such contracts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agent, representative, or member of a society who in any preceding calendar year has solicited and procured life insurance benefit contracts on behalf of any society in a total amount of insurance less than $50,000, or, in the case of any other kind or kinds of insurance benefit contracts which the society might write, on not more than 25 individuals, shall be exempt from the agent licensing and appointment requirements of subsection (1). Upon request by the department, every society shall register, on forms prescribed by the department and on or before March 1 of each year, the name and residence address of each agent, representative, or member exempt under the provisions of this subsection and shall, within 30 days of termination of employment, notify the department of the termination. Any agent, representative, or member for which an exemption is claimed due to employment by the society subsequent to March 1 shall be registered by the society with the department within 10 days of the date of employment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 86-140; s. 136, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 420, ch. 97-102; s. 69, ch. 2003-267; s. 60, ch. 2003-281.</History></Section>