<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0632.632" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Foreign or alien society; admission.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No foreign or alien society shall transact business in this state without a license issued by the office. Any such society desiring admission to this state shall have the qualifications required of domestic societies organized under this chapter. Any such society may be licensed to transact business in this state upon filing with the office:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A duly certified copy of its articles of incorporation;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of its bylaws, certified by its secretary or corresponding officer;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A power of attorney to the office;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of its most recent annual statement certified under oath by its president and secretary or corresponding officers in a form prescribed by the commission;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of an examination report conducted within the most recent 3-year period by the supervising insurance official of its home state or other state, territory, province, or country, satisfactory to the office;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification from the proper official of its home state, territory, province, or country that the society is legally incorporated and licensed to transact business therein;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of its certificate forms; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other information as the office may deem necessary;</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and upon a showing satisfactory to the office that its assets are invested in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 86-140; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1388, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>