<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0632.603" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">“Representative form of government” defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A society has a “representative form of government” when:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It has a supreme governing body constituted in one of the following ways:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Assembly.</Font><EmDash />The supreme governing body is an assembly composed of delegates elected directly by the members, or at intermediate assemblies or conventions of members or their representatives, together with other delegates as may be prescribed by the society’s laws. A society may provide for election of delegates by mail. The elected delegates shall constitute a majority in number and shall not have less than two-thirds of the votes and shall not have less than the number of votes required to amend the society’s laws. The assembly shall be elected and shall meet at least once every 4 years and shall elect a board of directors to conduct the business of the society between meetings of the assembly. Vacancies on the board of directors between elections may be filled in the manner prescribed by the society’s law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Direct election.</Font><EmDash />The supreme governing body is a board composed of persons elected by the members, either directly or by their representatives in intermediate assemblies, and any other persons prescribed in the society’s laws. A society may provide for election of the board by mail. Each term of a board member may not exceed 4 years. Vacancies on the board between elections may be filled in the manner prescribed by the society’s laws. Those persons elected to the board shall constitute a majority in number and not less than the number of votes required to amend the society’s laws. A person filling the unexpired term of an elected board member shall be considered to be an elected member. The board shall meet at least quarterly to conduct the business of the society. And</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officers of the society are elected either by the supreme governing body or by the board of directors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only benefit members are eligible for election to the supreme governing body, the board of directors, or any intermediate assembly; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each voting member shall have one vote; no vote may be cast by proxy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 86-140; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>