<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0632.607" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Location of office; meetings; communications to members; grievance procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principal office of any domestic society shall be located in this state. The meetings of its supreme governing body may be held in any state, district, province, or territory wherein such society has at least one subordinate lodge, and all business transacted at such meetings shall be as valid in all respects as if such meetings were held in this state. The minutes of the proceedings of the supreme governing body and of the board of directors shall be in the English language.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A society may provide in its laws for an official publication in which any notice, report, or statement required by law to be given to members, including notice of election, may be published. Such required reports, notices, and statements shall be printed conspicuously in the publication. If the records of a society show that two or more members have the same mailing address, an official publication mailed to one member is deemed to be mailed to all members at the same address unless a member requests a separate copy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not later than June 1 of each year, a synopsis of the society’s annual statement providing an explanation of the facts concerning the condition of the society thereby disclosed shall be printed and mailed to each benefit member of the society or, in lieu thereof, such synopsis may be published in the society’s official publication.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A society shall provide in its laws or rules for grievance or complaint procedures for members.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 86-140; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>