<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0632.633" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional grounds for suspension, revocation, or denial of certificate of authority; receivership; insolvency.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the grounds set forth in s. 624.418, the office may, in its discretion, suspend, revoke, or deny the certificate of authority of a society, if it finds that the society:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has exceeded its powers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to comply with any provision of this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not fulfilling its contracts in good faith;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a membership of less than 400 after an existence of 1 year or more; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is conducting business fraudulently or in a manner hazardous to its members, creditors, the public, or the business.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the grounds set forth in s. 626.9571, whenever the office has reason to believe that any society is operating in violation of this chapter or of any provision of the Florida Insurance Code applicable to societies, the provisions of ss. 626.9571, 626.9581, 626.9591, and 626.9601 shall apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any rehabilitation, liquidation, conservation, or dissolution of a society shall be conducted under the supervision of the department. The department and office shall have all the powers with respect to such rehabilitation, liquidation, conservation, or dissolution that are granted to the department and office under the laws governing the rehabilitation, liquidation, conservation, or dissolution of life insurance companies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 86-140; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1389, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>