<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0090.505" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Privilege with respect to communications to clergy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “member of the clergy” is a priest, rabbi, practitioner of Christian Science, or minister of any religious organization or denomination usually referred to as a church, or an individual reasonably believed so to be by the person consulting him or her.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A communication between a member of the clergy and a person is “confidential” if made privately for the purpose of seeking spiritual counsel and advice from the member of the clergy in the usual course of his or her practice or discipline and not intended for further disclosure except to other persons present in furtherance of the communication.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person has a privilege to refuse to disclose, and to prevent another from disclosing, a confidential communication by the person to a member of the clergy in his or her capacity as spiritual adviser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The privilege may be claimed by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guardian or conservator of a person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal representative of a deceased person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The member of the clergy, on behalf of the person. The member of the clergy’s authority to do so is presumed in the absence of evidence to the contrary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-237; s. 1, ch. 77-77; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 11, 22, ch. 78-361; ss. 1, 2, ch. 78-379; s. 477, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>