<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0090.803" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hearsay exceptions; availability of declarant immaterial.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of s. 90.802 to the contrary notwithstanding, the following are not inadmissible as evidence, even though the declarant is available as a witness:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SPONTANEOUS STATEMENT.<EmDash />A spontaneous statement describing or explaining an event or condition made while the declarant was perceiving the event or condition, or immediately thereafter, except when such statement is made under circumstances that indicate its lack of trustworthiness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXCITED UTTERANCE.<EmDash />A statement or excited utterance relating to a startling event or condition made while the declarant was under the stress of excitement caused by the event or condition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THEN-EXISTING MENTAL, EMOTIONAL, OR PHYSICAL CONDITION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the declarant’s then-existing state of mind, emotion, or physical sensation, including a statement of intent, plan, motive, design, mental feeling, pain, or bodily health, when such evidence is offered to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prove the declarant’s state of mind, emotion, or physical sensation at that time or at any other time when such state is an issue in the action.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prove or explain acts of subsequent conduct of the declarant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, this subsection does not make admissible:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An after-the-fact statement of memory or belief to prove the fact remembered or believed, unless such statement relates to the execution, revocation, identification, or terms of the declarant’s will.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement made under circumstances that indicate its lack of trustworthiness.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATEMENTS FOR PURPOSES OF MEDICAL DIAGNOSIS OR TREATMENT.<EmDash />Statements made for purposes of medical diagnosis or treatment by a person seeking the diagnosis or treatment, or made by an individual who has knowledge of the facts and is legally responsible for the person who is unable to communicate the facts, which statements describe medical history, past or present symptoms, pain, or sensations, or the inceptions or general character of the cause or external source thereof, insofar as reasonably pertinent to diagnosis or treatment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDED RECOLLECTION.<EmDash />A memorandum or record concerning a matter about which a witness once had knowledge, but now has insufficient recollection to enable the witness to testify fully and accurately, shown to have been made by the witness when the matter was fresh in the witness’s memory and to reflect that knowledge correctly. A party may read into evidence a memorandum or record when it is admitted, but no such memorandum or record is admissible as an exhibit unless offered by an adverse party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDS OF REGULARLY CONDUCTED BUSINESS ACTIVITY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A memorandum, report, record, or data compilation, in any form, of acts, events, conditions, opinion, or diagnosis, made at or near the time by, or from information transmitted by, a person with knowledge, if kept in the course of a regularly conducted business activity and if it was the regular practice of that business activity to make such memorandum, report, record, or data compilation, all as shown by the testimony of the custodian or other qualified witness, or as shown by a certification or declaration that complies with paragraph (c) and s. 90.902(11), unless the sources of information or other circumstances show lack of trustworthiness. The term “business” as used in this paragraph includes a business, institution, association, profession, occupation, and calling of every kind, whether or not conducted for profit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence in the form of an opinion or diagnosis is inadmissible under paragraph (a) unless such opinion or diagnosis would be admissible under ss. 90.701-90.705 if the person whose opinion is recorded were to testify to the opinion directly.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party intending to offer evidence under paragraph (a) by means of a certification or declaration shall serve reasonable written notice of that intention upon every other party and shall make the evidence available for inspection sufficiently in advance of its offer in evidence to provide to any other party a fair opportunity to challenge the admissibility of the evidence. If the evidence is maintained in a foreign country, the party intending to offer the evidence must provide written notice of that intention at the arraignment or as soon after the arraignment as is practicable or, in a civil case, 60 days before the trial. A motion opposing the admissibility of such evidence must be made by the opposing party and determined by the court before trial. A party’s failure to file such a motion before trial constitutes a waiver of objection to the evidence, but the court for good cause shown may grant relief from the waiver.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ABSENCE OF ENTRY IN RECORDS OF REGULARLY CONDUCTED ACTIVITY.<EmDash />Evidence that a matter is not included in the memoranda, reports, records, or data compilations, in any form, of a regularly conducted activity to prove the nonoccurrence or nonexistence of the matter, if the matter was of a kind of which a memorandum, report, record, or data compilation was regularly made and preserved, unless the sources of information or other circumstances show lack of trustworthiness.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PUBLIC RECORDS AND REPORTS.<EmDash />Records, reports, statements reduced to writing, or data compilations, in any form, of public offices or agencies, setting forth the activities of the office or agency, or matters observed pursuant to duty imposed by law as to matters which there was a duty to report, excluding in criminal cases matters observed by a police officer or other law enforcement personnel, unless the sources of information or other circumstances show their lack of trustworthiness. The criminal case exclusion shall not apply to an affidavit otherwise admissible under s. 316.1934 or s. 327.354.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDS OF VITAL STATISTICS.<EmDash />Records or data compilations, in any form, of births, fetal deaths, deaths, or marriages, if a report was made to a public office pursuant to requirements of law. However, nothing in this section shall be construed to make admissible any other marriage of any party to any cause of action except for the purpose of impeachment as set forth in s. 90.610.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ABSENCE OF PUBLIC RECORD OR ENTRY.<EmDash />Evidence, in the form of a certification in accord with s. 90.902, or in the form of testimony, that diligent search failed to disclose a record, report, statement, or data compilation or entry, when offered to prove the absence of the record, report, statement, or data compilation or the nonoccurrence or nonexistence of a matter of which a record, report, statement, or data compilation would regularly have been made and preserved by a public office and agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDS OF RELIGIOUS ORGANIZATIONS.<EmDash />Statements of births, marriages, divorces, deaths, parentage, ancestry, relationship by blood or marriage, or other similar facts of personal or family history contained in a regularly kept record of a religious organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MARRIAGE, BAPTISMAL, AND SIMILAR CERTIFICATES.<EmDash />Statements of facts contained in a certificate that the maker performed a marriage or other ceremony or administered a sacrament, when such statement was certified by a member of the clergy, public official, or other person authorized by the rules or practices of a religious organization or by law to perform the act certified, and when such certificate purports to have been issued at the time of the act or within a reasonable time thereafter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAMILY RECORDS.<EmDash />Statements of fact concerning personal or family history in family Bibles, charts, engravings in rings, inscriptions on family portraits, engravings on urns, crypts, or tombstones, or the like.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDS OF DOCUMENTS AFFECTING AN INTEREST IN PROPERTY.<EmDash />The record of a document purporting to establish or affect an interest in property, as proof of the contents of the original recorded or filed document and its execution and delivery by each person by whom it purports to have been executed, if the record is a record of a public office and an applicable statute authorized the recording or filing of the document in the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATEMENTS IN DOCUMENTS AFFECTING AN INTEREST IN PROPERTY.<EmDash />A statement contained in a document purporting to establish or affect an interest in property, if the matter stated was relevant to the purpose of the document, unless dealings with the property since the document was made have been inconsistent with the truth of the statement or the purport of the document.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATEMENTS IN ANCIENT DOCUMENTS.<EmDash />Statements in a document in existence 20 years or more, the authenticity of which is established.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MARKET REPORTS, COMMERCIAL PUBLICATIONS.<EmDash />Market quotations, tabulations, lists, directories, or other published compilations, generally used and relied upon by the public or by persons in particular occupations if, in the opinion of the court, the sources of information and method of preparation were such as to justify their admission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADMISSIONS.<EmDash />A statement that is offered against a party and is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The party’s own statement in either an individual or a representative capacity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of which the party has manifested an adoption or belief in its truth;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement by a person specifically authorized by the party to make a statement concerning the subject;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement by the party’s agent or servant concerning a matter within the scope of the agency or employment thereof, made during the existence of the relationship; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement by a person who was a coconspirator of the party during the course, and in furtherance, of the conspiracy. Upon request of counsel, the court shall instruct the jury that the conspiracy itself and each member’s participation in it must be established by independent evidence, either before the introduction of any evidence or before evidence is admitted under this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPUTATION CONCERNING PERSONAL OR FAMILY HISTORY.<EmDash />Evidence of reputation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Among members of a person’s family by blood, adoption, or marriage;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Among a person’s associates; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the community,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">concerning a person’s birth, adoption, marriage, divorce, death, relationship by blood, adoption, or marriage, ancestry, or other similar fact of personal or family history.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPUTATION CONCERNING BOUNDARIES OR GENERAL HISTORY.<EmDash />Evidence of reputation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a community, arising before the controversy about the boundaries of, or customs affecting lands in, the community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">About events of general history which are important to the community, state, or nation where located.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPUTATION AS TO CHARACTER.<EmDash />Evidence of reputation of a person’s character among associates or in the community.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FORMER TESTIMONY.<EmDash />Former testimony given by the declarant which testimony was given as a witness at another hearing of the same or a different proceeding, or in a deposition taken in compliance with law in the course of the same or another proceeding, if the party against whom the testimony is now offered, or, in a civil action or proceeding, a predecessor in interest, or a person with a similar interest, had an opportunity and similar motive to develop the testimony by direct, cross, or redirect examination; provided, however, the court finds that the testimony is not inadmissible pursuant to s. 90.402 or s. 90.403.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEARSAY EXCEPTION; STATEMENT OF CHILD VICTIM.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the source of information or the method or circumstances by which the statement is reported indicates a lack of trustworthiness, an out-of-court statement made by a child victim with a physical, mental, emotional, or developmental age of 11 or less describing any act of child abuse or neglect, any act of sexual abuse against a child, the offense of child abuse, the offense of aggravated child abuse, or any offense involving an unlawful sexual act, contact, intrusion, or penetration performed in the presence of, with, by, or on the declarant child, not otherwise admissible, is admissible in evidence in any civil or criminal proceeding if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court finds in a hearing conducted outside the presence of the jury that the time, content, and circumstances of the statement provide sufficient safeguards of reliability. In making its determination, the court may consider the mental and physical age and maturity of the child, the nature and duration of the abuse or offense, the relationship of the child to the offender, the reliability of the assertion, the reliability of the child victim, and any other factor deemed appropriate; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child either:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Testifies; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is unavailable as a witness, provided that there is other corroborative evidence of the abuse or offense. Unavailability shall include a finding by the court that the child’s participation in the trial or proceeding would result in a substantial likelihood of severe emotional or mental harm, in addition to findings pursuant to s. 90.804(1).</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a criminal action, the defendant shall be notified no later than 10 days before trial that a statement which qualifies as a hearsay exception pursuant to this subsection will be offered as evidence at trial. The notice shall include a written statement of the content of the child’s statement, the time at which the statement was made, the circumstances surrounding the statement which indicate its reliability, and such other particulars as necessary to provide full disclosure of the statement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall make specific findings of fact, on the record, as to the basis for its ruling under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEARSAY EXCEPTION; STATEMENT OF ELDERLY PERSON OR DISABLED ADULT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the source of information or the method or circumstances by which the statement is reported indicates a lack of trustworthiness, an out-of-court statement made by an elderly person or disabled adult, as defined in s. 825.101, describing any act of abuse or neglect, any act of exploitation, the offense of battery or aggravated battery or assault or aggravated assault or sexual battery, or any other violent act on the declarant elderly person or disabled adult, not otherwise admissible, is admissible in evidence in any civil or criminal proceeding if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court finds in a hearing conducted outside the presence of the jury that the time, content, and circumstances of the statement provide sufficient safeguards of reliability. In making its determination, the court may consider the mental and physical age and maturity of the elderly person or disabled adult, the nature and duration of the abuse or offense, the relationship of the victim to the offender, the reliability of the assertion, the reliability of the elderly person or disabled adult, and any other factor deemed appropriate; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The elderly person or disabled adult either:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Testifies; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is unavailable as a witness, provided that there is corroborative evidence of the abuse or offense. Unavailability shall include a finding by the court that the elderly person’s or disabled adult’s participation in the trial or proceeding would result in a substantial likelihood of severe emotional, mental, or physical harm, in addition to findings pursuant to s. 90.804(1).</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a criminal action, the defendant shall be notified no later than 10 days before the trial that a statement which qualifies as a hearsay exception pursuant to this subsection will be offered as evidence at trial. The notice shall include a written statement of the content of the elderly person’s or disabled adult’s statement, the time at which the statement was made, the circumstances surrounding the statement which indicate its reliability, and such other particulars as necessary to provide full disclosure of the statement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall make specific findings of fact, on the record, as to the basis for its ruling under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-237; s. 1, ch. 77-77; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 20, 22, ch. 78-361; ss. 1, 2, ch. 78-379; s. 4, ch. 85-53; s. 11, ch. 87-224; s. 2, ch. 90-139; s. 3, ch. 90-174; s. 12, ch. 91-255; s. 498, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 95-158; s. 2, ch. 96-330; s. 1, ch. 98-2; s. 2, ch. 2003-259.</History></Section>