<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0090.5015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Journalist’s privilege.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />For purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Professional journalist” means a person regularly engaged in collecting, photographing, recording, writing, editing, reporting, or publishing news, for gain or livelihood, who obtained the information sought while working as a salaried employee of, or independent contractor for, a newspaper, news journal, news agency, press association, wire service, radio or television station, network, or news magazine. Book authors and others who are not professional journalists, as defined in this paragraph, are not included in the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“News” means information of public concern relating to local, statewide, national, or worldwide issues or events.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRIVILEGE.<EmDash />A professional journalist has a qualified privilege not to be a witness concerning, and not to disclose the information, including the identity of any source, that the professional journalist has obtained while actively gathering news. This privilege applies only to information or eyewitness observations obtained within the normal scope of employment and does not apply to physical evidence, eyewitness observations, or visual or audio recording of crimes. A party seeking to overcome this privilege must make a clear and specific showing that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information is relevant and material to unresolved issues that have been raised in the proceeding for which the information is sought;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information cannot be obtained from alternative sources; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A compelling interest exists for requiring disclosure of the information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCLOSURE.<EmDash />A court shall order disclosure pursuant to subsection (2) only of that portion of the information for which the showing under subsection (2) has been made and shall support such order with clear and specific findings made after a hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WAIVER.<EmDash />A professional journalist does not waive the privilege by publishing or broadcasting information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSTRUCTION.<EmDash />This section must not be construed to limit any privilege or right provided to a professional journalist under law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUTHENTICATION.<EmDash />Photographs, diagrams, video recordings, audio recordings, computer records, or other business records maintained, disclosed, provided, or produced by a professional journalist, or by the employer or principal of a professional journalist, may be authenticated for admission in evidence upon a showing, by affidavit of the professional journalist, or other individual with personal knowledge, that the photograph, diagram, video recording, audio recording, computer record, or other business record is a true and accurate copy of the original, and that the copy truly and accurately reflects the observations and facts contained therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCURACY OF EVIDENCE.<EmDash />If the affidavit of authenticity and accuracy, or other relevant factual circumstance, causes the court to have clear and convincing doubts as to the authenticity or accuracy of the proffered evidence, the court may decline to admit such evidence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SEVERABILITY.<EmDash />If any provision of this section or its application to any particular person or circumstance is held invalid, that provision or its application is severable and does not affect the validity of other provisions or applications of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-48.</History></Section>