<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0090.612" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mode and order of interrogation and presentation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judge shall exercise reasonable control over the mode and order of the interrogation of witnesses and the presentation of evidence, so as to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitate, through effective interrogation and presentation, the discovery of the truth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Avoid needless consumption of time.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protect witnesses from harassment or undue embarrassment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cross-examination of a witness is limited to the subject matter of the direct examination and matters affecting the credibility of the witness. The court may, in its discretion, permit inquiry into additional matters.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leading questions should not be used on the direct examination of a witness except as may be necessary to develop the witness’s testimony. Ordinarily, leading questions should be permitted on cross-examination. When a party calls a hostile witness, an adverse party, or a witness identified with an adverse party, interrogation may be by leading questions.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The judge shall take special care to protect a witness under age 14 from questions that are in a form that cannot reasonably be understood by a person of the age and understanding of the witness, and shall take special care to restrict the unnecessary repetition of questions.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-237; s. 1, ch. 77-77; s. 22, ch. 78-361; s. 1, ch. 78-379; s. 1, ch. 95-179; s. 2, ch. 2000-316.</History></Section>