<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0090.902" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Self-authentication.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extrinsic evidence of authenticity as a condition precedent to admissibility is not required for:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A document bearing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A seal purporting to be that of the United States or any state, district, commonwealth, territory, or insular possession thereof; the Panama Canal Zone; the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands; or a court, political subdivision, department, officer, or agency of any of them; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A signature by the custodian of the document attesting to the authenticity of the seal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A document not bearing a seal but purporting to bear a signature of an officer or employee of any entity listed in subsection (1), affixed in the officer’s or employee’s official capacity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An official foreign document, record, or entry that is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Executed or attested to by a person in the person’s official capacity authorized by the laws of a foreign country to make the execution or attestation; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accompanied by a final certification, as provided herein, of the genuineness of the signature and official position of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executing person; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any foreign official whose certificate of genuineness of signature and official position relates to the execution or attestation or is in a chain of certificates of genuineness of signature and official position relating to the execution or attestation.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The final certification may be made by a secretary of an embassy or legation, consul general, consul, vice consul, or consular agent of the United States or a diplomatic or consular official of the foreign country assigned or accredited to the United States. When the parties receive reasonable opportunity to investigate the authenticity and accuracy of official foreign documents, the court may order that they be treated as presumptively authentic without final certification or permit them in evidence by an attested summary with or without final certification.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of an official public record, report, or entry, or of a document authorized by law to be recorded or filed and actually recorded or filed in a public office, including data compilations in any form, certified as correct by the custodian or other person authorized to make the certification by certificate complying with subsection (1), subsection (2), or subsection (3) or complying with any act of the Legislature or rule adopted by the Supreme Court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Books, pamphlets, or other publications purporting to be issued by a governmental authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Printed materials purporting to be newspapers or periodicals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inscriptions, signs, tags, or labels purporting to have been affixed in the course of business and indicating ownership, control, or origin.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commercial papers and signatures thereon and documents relating to them, to the extent provided in the Uniform Commercial Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any signature, document, or other matter declared by the Legislature to be presumptively or prima facie genuine or authentic.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any document properly certified under the law of the jurisdiction where the certification is made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An original or a duplicate of evidence that would be admissible under s. 90.803(6), which is maintained in a foreign country or domestic location and is accompanied by a certification or declaration from the custodian of the records or another qualified person certifying or declaring that the record:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was made at or near the time of the occurrence of the matters set forth by, or from information transmitted by, a person having knowledge of those matters;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was kept in the course of the regularly conducted activity; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was made as a regular practice in the course of the regularly conducted activity,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">provided that falsely making such a certification or declaration would subject the maker to criminal penalty under the laws of the foreign or domestic location in which the certification or declaration was signed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-237; s. 1, ch. 77-77; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 22, ch. 78-361; s. 1, ch. 78-379; s. 501, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 2003-259.</History></Section>