<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0090.202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Matters which may be judicially noticed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court may take judicial notice of the following matters, to the extent that they are not embraced within s. 90.201:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special, local, and private acts and resolutions of the Congress of the United States and of the Florida Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Decisional, constitutional, and public statutory law of every other state, territory, and jurisdiction of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contents of the Federal Register.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Laws of foreign nations and of an organization of nations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Official actions of the legislative, executive, and judicial departments of the United States and of any state, territory, or jurisdiction of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records of any court of this state or of any court of record of the United States or of any state, territory, or jurisdiction of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules of court of any court of this state or of any court of record of the United States or of any other state, territory, or jurisdiction of the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions of all municipal and county charters and charter amendments of this state, provided they are available in printed copies or as certified copies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules promulgated by governmental agencies of this state which are published in the Florida Administrative Code or in bound written copies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duly enacted ordinances and resolutions of municipalities and counties located in Florida, provided such ordinances and resolutions are available in printed copies or as certified copies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facts that are not subject to dispute because they are generally known within the territorial jurisdiction of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facts that are not subject to dispute because they are capable of accurate and ready determination by resort to sources whose accuracy cannot be questioned.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Official seals of governmental agencies and departments of the United States and of any state, territory, or jurisdiction of the United States.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 76-237; s. 1, ch. 77-77; s. 1, ch. 77-174; ss. 3, 22, ch. 78-361; ss. 1, 2, ch. 78-379.</History></Section>