<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0366.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the exercise of such jurisdiction, the commission shall have power to prescribe fair and reasonable rates and charges, classifications, standards of quality and measurements, including the ability to adopt construction standards that exceed the National Electrical Safety Code, for purposes of ensuring the reliable provision of service, and service rules and regulations to be observed by each public utility; to require repairs, improvements, additions, replacements, and extensions to the plant and equipment of any public utility when reasonably necessary to promote the convenience and welfare of the public and secure adequate service or facilities for those reasonably entitled thereto; to employ and fix the compensation for such examiners and technical, legal, and clerical employees as it deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter; and to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement and enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every public utility, as defined in s. 366.02, which in addition to the production, transmission, delivery or furnishing of heat, light, or power also sells appliances or other merchandise shall keep separate and individual accounts for the sale and profit deriving from such sales. No profit or loss shall be taken into consideration by the commission from the sale of such items in arriving at any rate to be charged for service by any public utility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall provide for the examination and testing of all meters used for measuring any product or service of a public utility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any consumer or user may have any such meter tested upon payment of the fees fixed by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall establish reasonable fees to be paid for testing such meters on the request of the consumers or users, the fee to be paid by the consumer or user at the time of his or her request, but to be paid by the public utility and repaid to the consumer or user if the meter is found defective or incorrect to the disadvantage of the consumer or user, in excess of the degree or amount of tolerance customarily allowed for such meters, or as may be provided for in rules and regulations of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may purchase materials, apparatus, and standard measuring instruments for such examination and tests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall have the power to require reports from all electric utilities to assure the development of adequate and reliable energy grids.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the commission determines that there is probable cause to believe that inadequacies exist with respect to the energy grids developed by the electric utility industry, including inadequacies in fuel diversity or fuel supply reliability, it shall have the power, after proceedings as provided by law, and after a finding that mutual benefits will accrue to the electric utilities involved, to require installation or repair of necessary facilities, including generating plants and transmission facilities, with the costs to be distributed in proportion to the benefits received, and to take all necessary steps to ensure compliance. The electric utilities involved in any action taken or orders issued pursuant to this subsection shall have full power and authority, notwithstanding any general or special laws to the contrary, to jointly plan, finance, build, operate, or lease generating and transmission facilities and shall be further authorized to exercise the powers granted to corporations in chapter 361. This subsection shall not supersede or control any provision of the Florida Electrical Power Plant Siting Act, ss. 403.501-403.518.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may require the filing of reports and other data by a public utility or its affiliated companies, including its parent company, regarding transactions, or allocations of common costs, among the utility and such affiliated companies. The commission may also require such reports or other data necessary to ensure that a utility’s ratepayers do not subsidize nonutility activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that violations of commission orders or rules, in connection with the impairment of a public utility’s operations or service, constitute irreparable harm for which there is no adequate remedy at law. The commission is authorized to seek relief in circuit court including temporary and permanent injunctions, restraining orders, or any other appropriate order. Such remedies shall be in addition to and supplementary to any other remedies available for enforcement of agency action under s. 120.69 or the provisions of this chapter. The commission shall establish procedures implementing this section by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission has the authority to assess a public utility for reasonable travel costs associated with reviewing the records of the public utility and its affiliates when such records are kept out of state. The public utility may bring the records back into the state for review.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 26545, 1951; s. 2, ch. 74-196; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 53, ch. 78-95; ss. 5, 16, ch. 80-35; s. 1, ch. 81-131; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 20, 22, ch. 89-292; s. 51, ch. 90-331; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-35; s. 552, ch. 95-148; s. 72, ch. 98-200; s. 17, ch. 2006-230.</History></Section>