<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0366.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cogeneration; small power production; commission jurisdiction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electricity produced by cogeneration and small power production is of benefit to the public when included as part of the total energy supply of the entire electric grid of the state or consumed by a cogenerator or small power producer. The electric utility in whose service area a cogenerator or small power producer is located shall purchase, in accordance with applicable law, all electricity offered for sale by such cogenerator or small power producer; or the cogenerator or small power producer may sell such electricity to any other electric utility in the state. The commission shall establish guidelines relating to the purchase of power or energy by public utilities from cogenerators or small power producers and may set rates at which a public utility must purchase power or energy from a cogenerator or small power producer. In fixing rates for power purchased by public utilities from cogenerators or small power producers, the commission shall authorize a rate equal to the purchasing utility’s full avoided costs. A utility’s “full avoided costs” are the incremental costs to the utility of the electric energy or capacity, or both, which, but for the purchase from cogenerators or small power producers, such utility would generate itself or purchase from another source. The commission may use a statewide avoided unit when setting full avoided capacity costs. If the cogenerator or small power producer provides adequate security, based on its financial stability, and no costs in excess of full avoided costs are likely to be incurred by the electric utility over the term during which electricity is to be provided, the commission shall authorize the levelization of payments and the elimination of discounts due to risk factors in determining the rates. Public utilities shall provide transmission or distribution service to enable a retail customer to transmit electrical power generated by the customer at one location to the customer’s facilities at another location, if the commission finds that the provision of this service, and the charges, terms, and other conditions associated with the provision of this service, are not likely to result in higher cost electric service to the utility’s general body of retail and wholesale customers or adversely affect the adequacy or reliability of electric service to all customers. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, power generated by the customer and provided by the utility to the customers’ facility at another location is subject to the gross receipts tax imposed under s. 203.01 and the use tax imposed under s. 212.06. Such taxes shall apply at the time the power is provided at such other location and shall be based upon the cost price of such power as provided in s. 212.06(1)(b).</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 22, ch. 89-292; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>