<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0366.825" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Clean Air Act compliance; definitions; goals; plans.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, reference to the “Clean Air Act” means 42 U.S.C. ss. 7401 et seq. as the same may hereinafter be amended and any related state or local legislation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public utility which owns or operates at least one electric generating unit affected by s. 404 or s. 405 of the Clean Air Act may submit, for commission approval, a plan to bring generating units into compliance with the Clean Air Act. A plan to implement compliance submitted by public utilities must include, at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and identity of affected generating units;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the proposed action, and alternative actions considered by the public utility, to reduce sulfur dioxide emissions to levels required by the Clean Air Act at each affected unit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the proposed action, and alternative actions considered by the public utility, to comply with nitrogen oxide emission rates required by the Clean Air Act at each affected unit;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Estimated effects of the public utility’s proposed plan on the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for construction and operation of proposed or alternative facilities;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Achievable emissions reductions and methods for monitoring emissions;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public utility’s proposed schedule for implements of compliance activities;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated cost of implementation of the public utility’s compliance plan to the utility’s customers;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public utility’s present and potential future sources of fuel; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of why the public utility’s proposed compliance plan is reasonable and in the public interest.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the proposed actions to comply with federal, state, and local requirements to implement the Clean Air Act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall review a plan to implement the Clean Air Act compliance submitted by public utilities pursuant to this section in order to determine whether such plans, the costs necessarily incurred in implementing such plans, and any effect on rates resulting from such implementation are in the public interest. The commission shall by order approve or disapprove plans to implement compliance submitted by public utilities within 8 months after the date of filing. Approval of a plan submitted by a public utility shall establish that the utility’s plan to implement compliance is prudent and the commission shall retain jurisdiction to determine in a subsequent proceeding that the actual costs of implementing the compliance plan are reasonable; provided, however, that nothing in this section shall be construed to interfere with the authority of the Department of Environmental Protection to determine whether a public utility is in compliance with ss. 403.087 and 403.0872 or the State Air Implementation Plan for the Clean Air Act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 92-132; s. 182, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>