<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0366.93" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cost recovery for the siting, design, licensing, and construction of nuclear and integrated gasification combined cycle power plants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cost” includes, but is not limited to, all capital investments, including rate of return, any applicable taxes, and all expenses, including operation and maintenance expenses, related to or resulting from the siting, licensing, design, construction, or operation of the nuclear power plant, including new, expanded, or relocated electrical transmission lines or facilities of any size that are necessary thereto, or of the integrated gasification combined cycle power plant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electric utility” or “utility” has the same meaning as that provided in s. 366.8255(1)(a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Integrated gasification combined cycle power plant” or “plant” means an electrical power plant as defined in s. 403.503(14) that uses synthesis gas produced by integrated gasification technology.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nuclear power plant” or “plant” means an electrical power plant as defined in s. 403.503(14) that uses nuclear materials for fuel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Power plant” or “plant” means a nuclear power plant or an integrated gasification combined cycle power plant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preconstruction” is that period of time after a site, including any related electrical transmission lines or facilities, has been selected through and including the date the utility completes site clearing work. Preconstruction costs shall be afforded deferred accounting treatment and shall accrue a carrying charge equal to the utility’s allowance for funds during construction (AFUDC) rate until recovered in rates.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 6 months after the enactment of this act, the commission shall establish, by rule, alternative cost recovery mechanisms for the recovery of costs incurred in the siting, design, licensing, and construction of a nuclear power plant, including new, expanded, or relocated electrical transmission lines and facilities that are necessary thereto, or of an integrated gasification combined cycle power plant. Such mechanisms shall be designed to promote utility investment in nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plants and allow for the recovery in rates of all prudently incurred costs and shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recovery through the capacity cost recovery clause of any preconstruction costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recovery through an incremental increase in the utility’s capacity cost recovery clause rates of the carrying costs on the utility’s projected construction cost balance associated with the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant. To encourage investment and provide certainty, for nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant need petitions submitted on or before December 31, 2010, associated carrying costs shall be equal to the pretax AFUDC in effect upon this act becoming law. For nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plants for which need petitions are submitted after December 31, 2010, the utility’s existing pretax AFUDC rate is presumed to be appropriate unless determined otherwise by the commission in the determination of need for the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a petition for determination of need is granted, a utility may petition the commission for cost recovery as permitted by this section and commission rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant is placed in commercial service, the utility shall be allowed to increase its base rate charges by the projected annual revenue requirements of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant based on the jurisdictional annual revenue requirements of the plant for the first 12 months of operation. The rate of return on capital investments shall be calculated using the utility’s rate of return last approved by the commission prior to the commercial inservice date of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant. If any existing generating plant is retired as a result of operation of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant, the commission shall allow for the recovery, through an increase in base rate charges, of the net book value of the retired plant over a period not to exceed 5 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The utility shall report to the commission annually the budgeted and actual costs as compared to the estimated inservice cost of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant provided by the utility pursuant to s. 403.519(4), until the commercial operation of the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant. The utility shall provide such information on an annual basis following the final order by the commission approving the determination of need for the nuclear or integrated gasification combined cycle power plant, with the understanding that some costs may be higher than estimated and other costs may be lower.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the utility elects not to complete or is precluded from completing construction of the nuclear power plant, including new, expanded, or relocated electrical transmission lines or facilities necessary thereto, or of the integrated gasification combined cycle power plant, the utility shall be allowed to recover all prudent preconstruction and construction costs incurred following the commission’s issuance of a final order granting a determination of need for the nuclear power plant and electrical transmission lines and facilities necessary thereto or for the integrated gasification combined cycle power plant. The utility shall recover such costs through the capacity cost recovery clause over a period equal to the period during which the costs were incurred or 5 years, whichever is greater. The unrecovered balance during the recovery period will accrue interest at the utility’s weighted average cost of capital as reported in the commission’s earnings surveillance reporting requirement for the prior year.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 2006-230; s. 54, ch. 2007-5; s. 1, ch. 2007-117; s. 43, ch. 2008-227.</History></Section>