<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.731" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications for general lines agent’s license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not grant or issue a license as general lines agent to any individual found by it to be untrustworthy or incompetent or who does not meet each of the following qualifications:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is a natural person at least 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is a United States citizen or legal alien who possesses work authorization from the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services and is a bona fide resident of this state. An individual who is a bona fide resident of this state shall be deemed to meet the residence requirement of this paragraph, notwithstanding the existence at the time of application for license of a license in his or her name on the records of another state as a resident licensee of such other state, if the applicant furnishes a letter of clearance satisfactory to the department that the resident licenses have been canceled or changed to a nonresident basis and that he or she is in good standing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s place of business will be located in this state and he or she will be actively engaged in the business of insurance and will maintain a place of business, the location of which is identifiable by and accessible to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license is not being sought for the purpose of writing or handling controlled business, in violation of s. 626.730.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is qualified as to knowledge, experience, or instruction in the business of insurance and meets the requirements provided in s. 626.732.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is not a service representative, a managing general agent in this state, or a special agent or similar service representative of a health insurer which also transacts property, casualty, or surety insurance; except that the president, vice president, secretary, or treasurer, including a member of the board of directors, of a corporate insurer, if otherwise qualified under and meeting the requirements of this part, may be licensed and appointed as a local resident agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has passed any required examination for license required under s. 626.221.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not grant, continue, renew, or permit to exist the license or appointment of a general lines agent unless the agent meets the requirements of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 256, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 75-303; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-116; s. 52, ch. 77-121; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 220, 241, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 29, ch. 82-386; s. 9, ch. 83-288; s. 15, ch. 88-166; ss. 67, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 240, ch. 97-102; s. 41, ch. 2003-267; s. 34, ch. 2003-281; s. 108, ch. 2004-5; s. 2, ch. 2005-195.</History></Section>