<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.922" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Evidence of the insurance; changes; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon placing a surplus lines coverage, the surplus lines agent shall promptly issue and deliver to the insured evidence of the insurance consisting either of the policy as issued by the insurer or, if such policy is not then available, a certificate, cover note, or other confirmation of insurance. Such document shall be executed or countersigned by the surplus lines agent and shall show the description and location of the subject of the insurance; coverage, conditions, and term of the insurance; the premium and rate charged and taxes collected from the insured; and the name and address of the insured and insurer. If the direct risk is assumed by more than one insurer, the document shall state the name and address and proportion of the entire direct risk assumed by each insurer. A surplus lines agent may not delegate the duty to issue any such document to producing general lines agents without prior written authority from the surplus lines insurer. A general lines agent may issue any such document only if the agent has prior written authority from the surplus lines agent. The surplus lines agent must maintain copies of the authorization from the surplus lines insurer and the delegation to the producing general lines agent. The producing agent must maintain copies of the written delegation from the surplus lines agent and copies of any evidence of coverage or certificate of insurance which the producing agent issues or delivers. Any evidence of coverage issued by a producing agent pursuant to this section must include the name and address of the authorizing surplus lines agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No surplus lines agent shall issue any such document, or purport to insure or represent that insurance will be or has been granted by any unauthorized insurer, unless he or she has prior written authority from the insurer for the insurance, or has received information from the insurer in the regular course of business that such insurance has been granted, or an insurance policy providing the insurance actually has been issued by the insurer and delivered to the insured.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If after the issuance and delivery of any such document there is any change as to the identity of the insurers, or the proportion of the direct risk assumed by the insurer as stated in the original certificate, cover note, or confirmation, or in any other material respect as to the insurance coverage evidenced by such a document, the surplus lines agent shall promptly issue and deliver to the insured a substitute certificate, cover note, or confirmation, or an endorsement for the original such document, accurately showing the current status of the coverage and the insurers responsible thereunder. No such change shall result in a coverage or insurance contract which would be in violation of this Surplus Lines Law if originally issued on such basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the policy or cover note or confirmation of insurance shall be delivered to the insured within 60 days after the effectuation of coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any surplus lines agent who knowingly or negligently issues a false certificate, cover note, or confirmation of insurance, or false endorsement therefor, or who fails promptly to notify the insured of any material change with respect to such insurance by delivery to the insured of a substitute certificate, cover note, or confirmation, or endorsement as provided in subsection (3), shall, upon conviction, be subject to the penalties provided by s. 624.15 or to any greater applicable penalty otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 361, ch. 59-205; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 318, 807, ch. 82-243; ss. 170, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 302, ch. 97-102; s. 69, ch. 98-199.</History></Section>