<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9927" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unfair trade practices; cease and desist; injunctions; civil remedy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this act is an unfair trade practice under ss. 626.9521 and 626.9541 and is subject to the penalties provided in the insurance code. Part IX of this chapter, entitled Unfair Insurance Trade Practices, applies to a licensee under this act or a transaction subject to this act as if a viatical settlement contract were an insurance policy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the penalties and other enforcement provisions of this act, if any person violates this act or any rule implementing this act, the office or department, as appropriate, may seek an injunction in the circuit court of the county where the person resides or has a principal place of business and may apply for temporary and permanent orders that the office or department determines necessary to restrain the person from committing the violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person damaged by the acts of a person in violation of this act may bring a civil action against the person committing the violation in the circuit court of the county in which the alleged violator resides or has a principal place of business or in the county wherein the alleged violation occurred. Upon an adverse adjudication, the defendant is liable for damages, together with court costs and reasonable attorney’s fees incurred by the plaintiff. When so awarded, court costs and attorney’s fees must be included in the judgment or decree rendered in the case. If it appears to the court that the suit brought by the plaintiff is frivolous or brought for purposes of harassment, the plaintiff is liable for court costs and reasonable attorney’s fees incurred by the defendant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 96-336; s. 9, ch. 99-212; s. 1057, ch. 2003-261; s. 27, ch. 2005-237.</History></Section>