<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.883" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administrator as intermediary; collections held in fiduciary capacity; establishment of account; disbursement; payments on behalf of insurer.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an insurer utilizes the services of an administrator under the terms of a written agreement, the payment to the administrator of any premiums or charges for insurance by or on behalf of the insured shall be deemed to have been received by the insurer, and return premiums or claim payments forwarded by the insurer to the administrator shall not be deemed to have been paid to the insured or claimant until such payments are received by the insured or claimant. Nothing in this part limits any right of the insurer against the administrator resulting from the failure of the administrator to make payments to the insurer, insureds, or claimants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All insurance charges or premiums collected by an administrator on behalf of or for an insurer or insurers, and return premiums received from such insurer or insurers, shall be held by the administrator in a fiduciary capacity. Such funds shall be immediately remitted to the person or persons entitled to them or shall be deposited promptly in a fiduciary account established and maintained by the administrator in a financial institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If charges or premiums deposited in a fiduciary account have been collected on behalf of or for more than one insurer, the administrator shall keep records clearly recording the deposits in and withdrawals from such account on behalf of or for each insurer. The administrator shall, upon request of an insurer, furnish such insurer with copies of records pertaining to deposits and withdrawals on behalf of or for such insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator may not pay any claim by withdrawals from a fiduciary account. Withdrawals from such account shall be made as provided in the written agreement between the administrator and the insurer for any of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remittance to an insurer entitled to such remittance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deposit in an account maintained in the name of such insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transfer to and deposit in a claims-paying account, with claims to be paid as provided by such insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment to a group policyholder for remittance to the insurer entitled to such remittance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment to the administrator of the commission, fees, or charges of the administrator.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remittance of return premium to the person or persons entitled to such return premium.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All claims paid by the administrator from funds collected on behalf of the insurer shall be paid only on drafts of, and as authorized by, such insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All payments to a health care provider by a fiscal intermediary for noncapitated providers must include an explanation of services being reimbursed which includes, at a minimum, the patient’s name, the date of service, the procedure code, the amount of reimbursement, and the identification of the plan on whose behalf the payment is being made. For capitated providers, the statement of services must include the number of patients covered by the contract, the rate per patient, the total amount of the payment, and the identification of the plan on whose behalf the payment is being made.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 83-203; s. 3, ch. 84-94; ss. 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 99-275; s. 173, ch. 99-397.</History></Section>