<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9912" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Viatical settlement provider license required; application for license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not perform the functions of a viatical settlement provider as defined in this act or enter into or solicit a viatical settlement contract without first having obtained a license from the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for a viatical settlement provider license must be made to the office by the applicant on a form prescribed by the commission, under oath and signed by the applicant. The application must be accompanied by a fee of $500. If the applicant is a corporation, the application must be under oath and signed by the president and the secretary of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the application, the applicant must provide all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s full name, age, residence address, and business address, and all occupations engaged in by the applicant during the 5 years preceding the date of the application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the applicant’s basic organizational documents, if any, including the articles of incorporation, articles of association, partnership agreement, trust agreement, or other similar documents, together with all amendments to such documents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of all bylaws, rules, regulations, or similar documents regulating the conduct of the applicant’s internal affairs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list showing the name, business and residence addresses, and official position of each individual who is responsible for conduct of the applicant’s affairs, including, but not limited to, any member of the applicant’s board of directors, board of trustees, executive committee, or other governing board or committee and any other person or entity owning or having the right to acquire 10 percent or more of the voting securities of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to each individual identified under paragraph (d):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn biographical statement on forms adopted by the commission and supplied by the office.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A set of fingerprints on forms prescribed by the commission, certified by a law enforcement officer, and accompanied by the fingerprinting fee specified in s. 624.501.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authority for release of information relating to the investigation of the individual’s background.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All applications, viatical settlement contract forms, escrow forms, and other related forms proposed to be used by the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general description of the method the viatical settlement provider will use in determining life expectancies, including a description of the applicant’s intended receipt of life expectancies, the applicant’s intended use of life expectancy providers, and the written plan or plans of policies and procedures used to determine life expectancies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other information as the commission or office deems necessary to determine that the applicant and the individuals identified under paragraph (d) are competent and trustworthy and can lawfully and successfully act as a viatical settlement provider.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may not issue a license to an entity other than a natural person if it is not satisfied that all officers, directors, employees, stockholders, partners, and any other persons who exercise or have the ability to exercise effective control of the entity or who have the ability to influence the transaction of business by the entity meet the standards of this act and have not violated any provision of this act or rules of the commission related to the business of viatical settlement contracts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a sworn application and the payment of the license fee, the office shall investigate each applicant and may issue the applicant a license if the office finds that the applicant:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has provided a detailed plan of operation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is competent and trustworthy and intends to act in good faith in the business authorized by the license applied for.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a good business reputation and has had experience, training, or education that qualifies the applicant to conduct the business authorized by the license applied for.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant is a corporation, is a corporation incorporated under the laws of this state, or is a foreign corporation authorized to transact business in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has designated the Chief Financial Officer as its agent for service of process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made the deposit required by s. 626.9913(3).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 96-336; s. 2, ch. 2000-344; s. 1045, ch. 2003-261; s. 15, ch. 2005-237; s. 140, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>