<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.593" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance agent; written contract for compensation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person licensed as an insurance agent may receive any fee or commission or any other thing of value in addition to the rates filed pursuant to chapter 627 for examining any group health insurance or any group health benefit plan for the purpose of giving or offering advice, counsel, recommendation, or information in respect to terms, conditions, benefits, coverage, or premium of any such policy or contract unless such compensation is based upon a written contract signed by the party to be charged and specifying or clearly defining the amount or extent of such compensation and informing the party to be charged that any commission received from an insurer will be rebated to the party in accordance with subsection (3). In addition, all compensation to be paid to the insurance agent must be disclosed in the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of every such contract shall be retained by the licensee for not less than 3 years after such services have been fully performed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 626.572, all commissions received by an insurance agent from an insurer in connection with the issuance of a policy, when a separate fee or other consideration has been paid to the insurance agent by an insured, shall be rebated to the insured or other party being charged within 30 days after receipt of such commission by the insurance agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is subject to the unfair insurance trade practices provisions of s. 626.9541(1)(g).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 2004-297.</History></Section>