<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examination requirement; exemptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue any license as agent, customer representative, or adjuster to any individual who has not qualified for, taken, and passed to the satisfaction of the department a written examination of the scope prescribed in s. 626.241.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, an examination is not necessary for any of the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for renewal of appointment as an agent, customer representative, or adjuster, unless the department determines that an examination is necessary to establish the competence or trustworthiness of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a limited license as agent for travel insurance, motor vehicle rental insurance, credit insurance, in-transit and storage personal property insurance, or portable electronics insurance under s. 626.321.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the discretion of the department, an applicant for reinstatement of license or appointment as an agent, customer representative, or all-lines adjuster whose license has been suspended within the 4 years before the date of application or written request for reinstatement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant who, within the 4 years before application for license and appointment as an agent, customer representative, or adjuster, was a full-time salaried employee of the department who had responsible insurance duties for at least 2 continuous years and who had been a licensee within the 4 years before employment by the department with the same class of license as that being applied for.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant who has been licensed as an all-lines adjuster and appointed as an independent adjuster or company employee adjuster if an application for licensure is filed with the department within 48 months following the date of cancellation or expiration of the prior appointment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a temporary license, except as otherwise provided in this code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a license as a life or health agent who has received the designation of chartered life underwriter (CLU) from the American College of Life Underwriters and has been engaged in the insurance business within the past 4 years, except that the applicant may be examined on pertinent provisions of this code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for license as a general lines agent, customer representative, or adjuster who has received the designation of chartered property and casualty underwriter (CPCU) from the American Institute for Property and Liability Underwriters and has been engaged in the insurance business within the past 4 years, except that the applicant may be examined on pertinent provisions of this code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for license as a customer representative who has earned the designation of Accredited Advisor in Insurance (AAI) from the Insurance Institute of America, the designation of Certified Insurance Counselor (CIC) from the Society of Certified Insurance Service Counselors, the designation of Accredited Customer Service Representative (ACSR) from the Independent Insurance Agents of America, the designation of Certified Professional Service Representative (CPSR) from the National Foundation for Certified Professional Service Representatives, the designation of Certified Insurance Service Representative (CISR) from the Society of Certified Insurance Service Representatives, or the designation of Certified Insurance Representative (CIR) from the National Association of Christian Catastrophe Insurance Adjusters. Also, an applicant for license as a customer representative who has earned an associate degree or bachelor’s degree from an accredited college or university and has completed at least 9 academic hours of property and casualty insurance curriculum, or the equivalent, or has earned the designation of Certified Customer Service Representative (CCSR) from the Florida Association of Insurance Agents, or the designation of Registered Customer Service Representative (RCSR) from a regionally accredited postsecondary institution in this state, or the designation of Professional Customer Service Representative (PCSR) from the Professional Career Institute, whose curriculum has been approved by the department and which includes comprehensive analysis of basic property and casualty lines of insurance and testing at least equal to that of standard department testing for the customer representative license. The department shall adopt rules establishing standards for the approval of curriculum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for license as a resident or nonresident all-lines adjuster who has the designation of Accredited Claims Adjuster (ACA) from a regionally accredited postsecondary institution in this state, Professional Claims Adjuster (PCA) from the Professional Career Institute, Professional Property Insurance Adjuster (PPIA) from the HurriClaim Training Academy, Certified Adjuster (CA) from ALL LINES Training, or Certified Claims Adjuster (CCA) from the Association of Property and Casualty Claims Professionals whose curriculum has been approved by the department and which includes comprehensive analysis of basic property and casualty lines of insurance and testing at least equal to that of standard department testing for the all-lines adjuster license. The department shall adopt rules establishing standards for the approval of curriculum.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant qualifying for a license transfer under s. 626.292 if the applicant:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed the prelicensing examination requirements in the applicant’s previous home state which are substantially equivalent to the examination requirements in this state, as determined by the department;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received the designation of chartered property and casualty underwriter (CPCU) from the American Institute for Property and Liability Underwriters and been engaged in the insurance business within the past 4 years if applying to transfer a general lines agent license; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received the designation of chartered life underwriter (CLU) from the American College of Life Underwriters and been engaged in the insurance business within the past 4 years if applying to transfer a life or health agent license.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a license as a nonresident agent if the applicant:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has successfully completed prelicensing examination requirements in the applicant’s home state which are substantially equivalent to the examination requirements in this state, as determined by the department, as a requirement for obtaining a resident license in his or her home state;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Held a general lines agent license, life agent license, or health agent license before a written examination was required;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received the designation of chartered property and casualty underwriter (CPCU) from the American Institute for Property and Liability Underwriters and has been engaged in the insurance business within the past 4 years, if an applicant for a nonresident license as a general lines agent; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received the designation of chartered life underwriter (CLU) from the American College of Life Underwriters and been in the insurance business within the past 4 years, if an applicant for a nonresident license as a life agent or health agent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who is already licensed as a customer representative shall not be licensed as a general lines agent without application and examination for such license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 201, ch. 59-205; s. 1, ch. 67-91; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 71-86; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 87, ch. 79-40; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 164(2nd), 217, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 17, ch. 82-386; s. 86, ch. 83-216; s. 6, ch. 88-166; ss. 21, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 218, ch. 97-102; s. 14, ch. 98-199; s. 1, ch. 2001-190; s. 1, ch. 2002-84; ss. 12, 51, ch. 2002-206; s. 918, ch. 2003-261; s. 27, ch. 2003-267; s. 20, ch. 2003-281; s. 26, ch. 2004-390; s. 10, ch. 2005-257; s. 3, ch. 2006-184; s. 2(1st), ch. 2007-199; ss. 7, 25, ch. 2008-220; s. 44, ch. 2010-175; s. 5, ch. 2012-209.</History>
</Section>