<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.874" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Catastrophe or emergency adjusters.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of a catastrophe or emergency, the department may issue a license, for the purposes and under the conditions and for the period of emergency as it shall determine, to persons who are residents or nonresidents of this state, who are at least 18 years of age, who are United States citizens or legal aliens who possess work authorization from the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services, and who are not licensed adjusters under this part but who have been designated and certified to it as qualified to act as adjusters by all-lines resident adjusters, by an authorized insurer, or by a licensed general lines agent to adjust claims, losses, or damages under policies or contracts of insurance issued by such insurers. The fee for the license is as provided in s. 624.501(12)(c).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person not a licensed adjuster who has been permitted to adjust such losses, claims, or damages under the conditions and circumstances set forth in subsection (1), engages in any of the misconduct described in or contemplated by ss. 626.611 and 626.621, the department, without notice and hearing, shall be authorized to issue its order denying such person the privileges granted under this section; and thereafter it shall be unlawful for any such person to adjust any such losses, claims, or damages in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 337, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 81-282; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 289, 293, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 148, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 93, ch. 2002-1; s. 993, ch. 2003-261; s. 62, ch. 2003-267; s. 55, ch. 2003-281; s. 120, ch. 2004-5; s. 73, ch. 2004-390; s. 44, ch. 2012-209.</History>
</Section>