<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.9894" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gifts and grants.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may accept, for purposes of anti-fraud efforts, any donation or grant of property or moneys from any governmental unit, public agency, institution, person, firm, or corporation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rights to, interest in, and title to such donated or granted property shall immediately vest in the Division of Insurance Fraud upon donation. The division may hold such property in coownership, sell its interest in the property, liquidate its interest in the property, or dispose of its interest in the property in any other reasonable manner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All donations or grants of moneys to the division shall be deposited into the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund and shall be separately accounted for and may be used by the division to carry out its duties and responsibilities, or for the subgranting of such funds to state attorneys for the purpose of funding or defraying the costs of dedicated fraud prosecutors.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moneys deposited into the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund pursuant to this section may be appropriated by the Legislature, pursuant to the provisions of chapter 216, for the purpose of enabling the division to carry out its duties and responsibilities, or for the purpose of funding or defraying the costs of dedicated fraud prosecutors.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any balance of moneys deposited into the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund pursuant to this section or s. 626.9895 remaining at the end of any fiscal year is available for carrying out the duties and responsibilities of the division. The department may request annual appropriations from the grants and donations received pursuant to this section or s. 626.9895 and cash balances in the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund for the purpose of carrying out its duties and responsibilities related to the division’s anti-fraud efforts, including the funding of dedicated prosecutors and related personnel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2011-59; s. 6, ch. 2012-197.</History>
</Section>