<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reasons for termination; confidential information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any insurer terminating the appointment of an agent; any general lines agent terminating the appointment of a customer representative or a crop hail or multiple-peril crop insurance agent; and any employer terminating the appointment of an adjuster, service representative, or managing general agent, whether such termination is by direct action of the appointing insurer, agent, or employer or by failure to renew or continue the appointment as provided, shall file with the department or office a statement of the reasons, if any, for and the facts relative to such termination. In the case of termination of the appointment of an agent, such information may be filed by the insurer or by the general agent of the insurer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of terminations by failure to renew or continue the appointment, the information required under subsection (1) shall be filed with the department or office as soon as possible, and at all events within 30 days, after the date notice of intention not to so renew or continue was filed with the department or office as required in this chapter. In all other cases, the information required under subsection (1) shall be filed with the department or office at the time, or at all events within 10 days after, notice of the termination was filed with the department or office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information, document, record, or statement furnished to the department or office under subsection (1) is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 230, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 9, ch. 71-86; s. 7, ch. 72-34; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 194(2nd), 217, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 25, ch. 82-386; s. 5, ch. 83-54; s. 10, ch. 88-166; ss. 45, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 93-80; s. 370, ch. 96-406; s. 22, ch. 98-199; s. 55, ch. 2002-206; s. 939, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>