<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.341" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional appointments; general lines, life, and health agents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time while a licensee’s license is in force, an insurer may apply to the department or person designated by the department to administer the appointment process on behalf of a licensee for an additional appointment as general lines agent or life or health agent for an additional insurer or insurers. The application for appointment shall set forth all information the department may require. Upon receipt of the appointment and payment of the applicable appointment taxes and fees, the department may issue the additional appointment without, in its discretion, further investigation concerning the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A life or health agent with an appointment in force may solicit applications for policies of insurance on behalf of an insurer with respect to which he or she is not an appointed life or health agent, unless otherwise provided by contract, if such agent simultaneously with the submission to such insurer of the application for insurance solicited by him or her requests the insurer to appoint him or her as agent. However, no commissions shall be paid by such insurer to the agent until such time as an additional appointment with respect to such insurer has been received by the department or person designated by the department to administer the appointment process pursuant to the provisions of subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 213, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 72-34; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 7, 10, ch. 80-341; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 178, 217, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 10, ch. 85-208; ss. 35, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 225, ch. 97-102; s. 34, ch. 2003-267; s. 27, ch. 2003-281.</History></Section>