<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.792" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonresident agents; licensing and restrictions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, upon written application and payment of the fees specified in s. 624.501, may issue a license as a nonresident life agent to an individual not resident of this state, upon compliance with the applicable provisions of this code, if that individual’s home state or province of Canada will accord the same privilege to a resident of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter into reciprocal agreements with the appropriate official of any other state or province of Canada waiving the written examination of any applicant resident in such other state or province if, in that other state or province, a resident of this state is privileged to procure a life insurance agent’s license upon the foregoing conditions and without discrimination as to fees or otherwise in favor of the residents of such other state or province and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written examination, substantially equivalent to the examination required by this state, is required of an applicant for a life insurance agent’s license in such other state or province.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate official of the other state or province certifies that the applicant holds a currently valid license as a life insurance agent in such other state or province and satisfies the examination requirement under s. 626.221 or is exempt under such section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the laws of another state or province of Canada require the sharing of commissions with resident agents of that state or province on applications for life insurance, or for life insurance including health insurance, written by nonresident agents, then the same provisions shall apply when resident agents of that state or province, licensed as nonresident agents of this state, write applications for insurance on residents of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue a nonresident life insurance agent’s license to any nonresident who at the time of issuance and throughout the existence of the Florida license does not hold a resident license as life agent issued by the nonresident’s state or province of Canada.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall, throughout the existence of the Florida nonresident life license and appointment, hold a license as a resident life agent in his or her state of residence. The authority of the nonresident license is limited to the specific lines of authority granted in the license issued by the agent’s state of residence and further limited to the specific lines authorized under the nonresident license issued by this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who holds a Florida nonresident agent’s license, upon becoming a resident of this state may, for a period not to exceed 90 days, continue to transact insurance in this state under the nonresident license and appointment. Such individual must make application for resident licensure and must become licensed as a resident agent within 90 days after becoming a resident of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon becoming a resident of this state, an individual who holds a Florida nonresident agent’s license is no longer eligible for licensure as a nonresident agent if such individual fails to make application for a resident license and become licensed as a resident agent within 90 days. His or her license and any appointments shall be canceled immediately. He or she may apply for a resident license pursuant to s. 626.785.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If available, the department shall verify the nonresident applicant’s licensing status through the Producer Database maintained by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, its affiliates or subsidiaries.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 296, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 63-20; s. 2, ch. 67-91; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 252, 257, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 22, ch. 88-166; ss. 100, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 265, ch. 97-102; s. 42, ch. 98-199; s. 41, ch. 99-7; s. 14, ch. 2001-142; s. 33, ch. 2002-206; s. 8, ch. 2004-374.</History></Section>