<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.2415" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual report of results of life insurance examinations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than May 1 of each year, the department or a person designated by the department shall prepare, publicly announce, and publish a report that summarizes statistical information relating to life insurance agent examinations administered during the preceding calendar year. Each report shall include the following information for all examinees combined and separately by race or ethnicity, gender, race or ethnicity within gender, education level, and native language:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total number of examinees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The percentage and number of examinees who passed the examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mean scaled scores on the examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standard deviation of scaled scores on the examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than May 1 of each year, the department or a person designated by the department shall prepare and make available upon request a report of summary statistical information relating to each life insurance test form administered during the preceding calendar year. The report shall show, for each test form, for all examinees combined and separately for African-American examinees, white examinees, American Indian examinees, Asian examinees, Hispanic examinees, and other examinees, the correct-answer rates and correlations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may provide a testing service provider, under contract with the department, demographic information received by the department on applications relating to examinations taken to qualify for an insurance agent license if the department requires the provider to review and analyze examination results in conjunction with the race or ethnicity, gender, education level, and native language of examinees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2006-184.</History></Section>