<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.7851" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirement as to knowledge, experience, or instruction.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No applicant for a license as a life agent, except for a chartered life underwriter (CLU), shall be qualified or licensed unless within the 4 years immediately preceding the date the application for a license is filed with the department he or she has:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Successfully completed 40 hours of classroom courses in insurance, 3 hours of which shall be on the subject matter of ethics, satisfactory to the department at a school or college, or extension division thereof, or other authorized course of study, approved by the department. Courses must include instruction on the subject matter of unauthorized entities engaging in the business of insurance, to include the Florida Nonprofit Multiple-Employer Welfare Arrangement Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act, 29 U.S.C. ss. 1001 et seq., as it relates to the provision of life insurance by employers to their employees and the regulation thereof;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Successfully completed a correspondence course in insurance, 3 hours of which shall be on the subject matter of ethics, satisfactory to the department and regularly offered by accredited institutions of higher learning in this state or by independent programs of study, approved by the department. Courses must include instruction on the subject matter of unauthorized entities engaging in the business of insurance, to include the Florida Nonprofit Multiple-Employer Welfare Arrangement Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act, 29 U.S.C. ss. 1001 et seq., as it relates to the provision of life insurance by employers to their employees and the regulation thereof;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Held an active license in life, or life and health, insurance in another state. This provision may not be utilized unless the other state grants reciprocal treatment to licensees formerly licensed in Florida; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Been employed by the department or office for at least 1 year, full time in life or life and health insurance regulatory matters and who was not terminated for cause, and application for examination is made within 90 days after the date of termination of his or her employment with the department or office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 244(2nd), 807, ch. 82-243; ss. 96, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 21, ch. 92-146; s. 262, ch. 97-102; s. 31, ch. 2002-206; s. 964, ch. 2003-261; s. 51, ch. 2003-267; s. 44, ch. 2003-281; s. 2(2nd), ch. 2007-199.</History></Section>