<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9914" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension, revocation, denial, or nonrenewal of viatical settlement provider license; grounds; administrative fine.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall suspend, revoke, deny, or refuse to renew the license of any viatical settlement provider if the office finds that the licensee:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made a misrepresentation in the application for the license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has engaged in fraudulent or dishonest practices, or otherwise has been shown to be untrustworthy or incompetent to act as a viatical settlement provider;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrates a pattern of unreasonable payments to viators;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been found guilty of, or has pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to, any felony, or a misdemeanor involving fraud or moral turpitude, regardless of whether a judgment of conviction has been entered by the court;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has issued viatical settlement contracts that have not been approved pursuant to this act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to honor contractual obligations related to the business of viatical settlement contracts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deals in bad faith with viators;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has violated any provision of the insurance code or of this act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employs any person who materially influences the licensee’s conduct and who fails to meet the requirements of this act;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No longer meets the requirements for initial licensure; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtains or utilizes life expectancies from life expectancy providers who are not registered with the office pursuant to this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, in lieu of or in addition to any suspension or revocation, assess an administrative fine not to exceed $2,500 for each nonwillful violation or $10,000 for each willful violation by a viatical settlement provider licensee. The office may also place a viatical settlement provider licensee on probation for a period not to exceed 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an employee of a viatical settlement provider violates any provision of this act, the office may take disciplinary action against such employee as if the employee were licensed under this act, including suspending or otherwise prohibiting the employee from performing the functions of a viatical settlement provider or viatical settlement broker as defined in this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a viatical settlement provider establishes a related provider trust as permitted by this act, the viatical settlement provider shall be liable and responsible for the performance of all obligations of the related provider trust under all viatical settlement contracts entered into by the related provider trust, and for the compliance of the related provider trust with all provisions of this act. Any violation of this act by the related provider trust shall be deemed a violation of this act by the viatical settlement provider as well as the related provider trust. If the related provider trust violates any provisions of this act, the office may exercise all remedies set forth in this act for such violations against the viatical settlement provider, as well as the related provider trust.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 96-336; s. 3, ch. 98-164; s. 1047, ch. 2003-261; s. 17, ch. 2005-237.</History></Section>