<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9272" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensing of nonresident surplus lines agents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, upon written application and the payment of the fees specified in s. 624.501, issue a nonresident surplus lines agent license to a nonresident individual licensed in his or her home state as a resident general lines and a resident surplus lines agent and otherwise qualified under the laws of this state if, under the laws of the individual’s home state, residents of this state may be licensed in a similar manner as a nonresident surplus lines agent in that state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a license unless the applicant satisfies the same licensing requirements under s. 626.927 as required of a resident surplus lines agent. The department may refuse to issue such license or appointment when it has reason to believe that any of the grounds exist for denial, suspension, or revocation of a license as set forth in ss. 626.611 and 626.621.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority of a nonresident license is limited to the specific lines of authority granted in the license issued by the agent’s home state and the lines authorized under the nonresident license by this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who holds a nonresident agent’s license, upon becoming a resident of this state, may, for a period not to exceed 90 days, operate under the nonresident license and appointment, but must become licensed as a resident agent within that time to continue transacting business in this state after the 90-day period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, nonresident surplus lines agents are subject to the requirements that apply to resident surplus lines agents in this state, including ss. 626.913-626.937.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If available, the department shall verify a nonresident applicant’s licensing status through the producer database maintained by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, its affiliates, or subsidiaries.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 2004-374.</History></Section>