<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.8696" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for adjusting firm license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application for an adjusting firm license must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each majority owner, partner, officer, and director of the adjusting firm.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resident address of each person required to be listed in the application under paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the adjusting firm and its principal business address.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of each adjusting firm office and the name under which each office conducts or will conduct business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional information that the department requires.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for an adjusting firm license must be signed by each owner of the firm. If the firm is incorporated, the application must be signed by the president and secretary of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application must be accompanied by payment of any applicable fee as prescribed in s. 624.501.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">License fees are not refundable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adjusting firm required to be licensed pursuant to s. 626.8695 must remain so licensed for a period of 3 years from the date of licensure, unless the license is suspended or revoked. The department may suspend or revoke the adjusting firm’s authority to do business for activities occurring during the time the firm is licensed, regardless of whether the licensing period has terminated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 92-146; s. 982, ch. 2003-261; s. 62, ch. 2004-390.</History></Section>