<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.84195" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidentiality of information supplied by title insurance agencies and insurers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “proprietary business information” means information that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is owned or controlled by a title insurance agency or insurer requesting confidentiality under this section;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is intended to be and is treated by the title insurance agency or insurer as private in that the disclosure of the information would cause harm to the business operations of the title insurance agency or insurer;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not been publicly disclosed unless disclosed pursuant to a statutory provision, an order of a court or administrative body, or a private agreement, providing that the information may be released to the public; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Concerns:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business plans;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Internal auditing controls and reports of internal auditors;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports of external auditors for privately held companies;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trade secrets, as defined in s. 688.002; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial information, including, but not limited to, revenue data, loss expense data, gross receipts, taxes paid, capital investment, customer identification, and employee wages.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proprietary business information provided to the office by a title insurance agency or insurer is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution until such information is otherwise publicly available or is no longer treated by the title insurance agency or insurer as proprietary business information. However, information provided by multiple title insurance agencies and insurers may be aggregated on an industrywide basis and disclosed to the public as long as the specific identities of the agencies or insurers are not revealed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15 and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2017, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2012-207.</History>
</Section>