<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.785" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications for license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not grant or issue a license as life agent to any individual found by it to be untrustworthy or incompetent, or who does not meet the following qualifications:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be a natural person of at least 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be a United States citizen or legal alien who possesses work authorization from the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services and a bona fide resident of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must not be an employee of the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or state service office, as referred to in s. 626.788.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must not be a funeral director or direct disposer, or an employee or representative thereof, or have an office in, or in connection with, a funeral establishment, except that a funeral establishment may contract with a life insurance agent to sell a preneed contract as defined in s. 497.005. Notwithstanding other provisions of this chapter, such insurance agent may sell limited policies of insurance covering the expense of final disposition or burial of an insured in the amount of $12,500, plus an annual percentage increase based on the Annual Consumer Price Index compiled by the United States Department of Labor, beginning with the Annual Consumer Price Index announced by the United States Department of Labor for the year 2003.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must take and pass any examination for license required under s. 626.221.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be qualified as to knowledge, experience, or instruction in the business of insurance and meet the requirements relative thereto provided in s. 626.7851.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who is a bona fide resident of this state shall be deemed to meet the residence requirement of paragraph (1)(b), notwithstanding the existence at the time of application for license of a license in his or her name on the records of another state as a resident licensee of such other state, if the applicant furnishes a letter of clearance satisfactory to the department that the resident licenses have been canceled or changed to a nonresident basis and that he or she is in good standing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, a funeral director, a direct disposer, or an employee of a funeral establishment that holds a certificate of authority pursuant to s. 497.452 may obtain an agent’s license to sell only policies of life insurance covering the expense of a prearrangement for funeral services or merchandise so as to provide funds at the time the services and merchandise are needed. The face amount of insurance covered by any such policy shall not exceed $12,500, plus an annual percentage increase based on the Annual Consumer Price Index compiled by the United States Department of Labor, beginning with the Annual Consumer Price Index announced by the United States Department of Labor for 2003.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 289, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-116; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 245(1st), 257, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 1, ch. 84-196; s. 4, ch. 85-67; s. 1, ch. 86-246; s. 20, ch. 88-166; ss. 95, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 30, ch. 93-268; s. 115, ch. 93-399; s. 261, ch. 97-102; s. 30, ch. 2002-206; s. 50, ch. 2003-267; s. 43, ch. 2003-281; s. 113, ch. 2004-5; s. 147, ch. 2004-301; s. 52, ch. 2005-155.</History></Section>