<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.207" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disqualification of applicants and licensees; penalties against licensees; rulemaking authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “financial services business” means any financial activity regulated by the Department of Financial Services, the Office of Insurance Regulation, or the Office of Financial Regulation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the terms “felony of the first degree” and “capital felony” include all felonies designated as such by the Florida Statutes, as well as any felony so designated in the jurisdiction in which the plea is entered or judgment is rendered.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant who commits a felony of the first degree; a capital felony; a felony involving money laundering, fraud, or embezzlement; or a felony directly related to the financial services business is permanently barred from applying for a license under this part. This bar applies to convictions, guilty pleas, or nolo contendere pleas, regardless of adjudication, by any applicant, officer, director, majority owner, partner, manager, or other person who manages or controls any applicant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all other crimes not included in subsection (3), the department shall adopt rules establishing the process and application of disqualifying periods that include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 15-year disqualifying period for all felonies involving moral turpitude that are not specifically included in the permanent bar contained in subsection (3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 7-year disqualifying period for all felonies to which neither the permanent bar in subsection (3) nor the 15-year disqualifying period in paragraph (a) applies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 7-year disqualifying period for all misdemeanors directly related to the financial services business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules providing for additional disqualifying periods due to the commitment of multiple crimes and other factors reasonably related to the applicant’s criminal history. The rules shall provide for mitigating and aggravating factors. However, mitigation may not result in a period of disqualification of less than 7 years and may not mitigate the disqualifying periods in paragraphs (4)(b) and (c).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the disqualifying periods begin upon the applicant’s final release from supervision or upon completion of the applicant’s criminal sentence, including payment of fines, restitution, and court costs for the crime for which the disqualifying period applies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the disqualifying period has been met, the burden is on the applicant to demonstrate that the applicant has been rehabilitated, does not pose a risk to the insurance-buying public, is fit and trustworthy to engage in the business of insurance pursuant to s. 626.611(7), and is otherwise qualified for licensure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing specific penalties against licensees in accordance with ss. 626.641 and 626.651 for violations of s. 626.611, s. 626.621, s. 626.8437, s. 626.844, s. 626.935, s. 634.181, s. 634.191, s. 634.320, s. 634.321, s. 634.422, s. 634.423, s. 642.041, or s. 642.043. The purpose of the revocation or suspension is to provide a sufficient penalty to deter future violations of the Florida Insurance Code. The imposition of a revocation or the length of suspension shall be based on the type of conduct and the probability that the propensity to commit further illegal conduct has been overcome at the time of eligibility for relicensure. The length of suspension may be adjusted based on aggravating or mitigating factors, established by rule and consistent with this purpose.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 112.011 does not apply to any applicants for licensure under the Florida Insurance Code, including, but not limited to, agents, agencies, adjusters, adjusting firms, customer representatives, or managing general agents.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2002-206; s. 9, ch. 2005-237; s. 6, ch. 2011-174.</History>
</Section>