<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.611" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for compulsory refusal, suspension, or revocation of agent’s, title agency’s, adjuster’s, customer representative’s, service representative’s, or managing general agent’s license or appointment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deny an application for, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew or continue the license or appointment of any applicant, agent, title agency, adjuster, customer representative, service representative, or managing general agent, and it shall suspend or revoke the eligibility to hold a license or appointment of any such person, if it finds that as to the applicant, licensee, or appointee any one or more of the following applicable grounds exist:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lack of one or more of the qualifications for the license or appointment as specified in this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material misstatement, misrepresentation, or fraud in obtaining the license or appointment or in attempting to obtain the license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to pass to the satisfaction of the department any examination required under this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the license or appointment is willfully used, or to be used, to circumvent any of the requirements or prohibitions of this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful misrepresentation of any insurance policy or annuity contract or willful deception with regard to any such policy or contract, done either in person or by any form of dissemination of information or advertising.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, as an adjuster, or agent licensed and appointed to adjust claims under this code, he or she has materially misrepresented to an insured or other interested party the terms and coverage of an insurance contract with intent and for the purpose of effecting settlement of claim for loss or damage or benefit under such contract on less favorable terms than those provided in and contemplated by the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated lack of fitness or trustworthiness to engage in the business of insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated lack of reasonably adequate knowledge and technical competence to engage in the transactions authorized by the license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent or dishonest practices in the conduct of business under the license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misappropriation, conversion, or unlawful withholding of moneys belonging to insurers or insureds or beneficiaries or to others and received in conduct of business under the license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unlawfully rebating, attempting to unlawfully rebate, or unlawfully dividing or offering to divide his or her commission with another.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having obtained or attempted to obtain, or having used or using, a license or appointment as agent or customer representative for the purpose of soliciting or handling “controlled business” as defined in s. 626.730 with respect to general lines agents, s. 626.784 with respect to life agents, and s. 626.830 with respect to health agents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful failure to comply with, or willful violation of, any proper order or rule of the department or willful violation of any provision of this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been found guilty of or having pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or a crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of the United States of America or of any state thereof or under the law of any other country which involves moral turpitude, without regard to whether a judgment of conviction has been entered by the court having jurisdiction of such cases.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent or dishonest practice in submitting or aiding or abetting any person in the submission of an application for workers’ compensation coverage under chapter 440 containing false or misleading information as to employee payroll or classification for the purpose of avoiding or reducing the amount of premium due for such coverage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sale of an unregistered security that was required to be registered, pursuant to chapter 517.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In transactions related to viatical settlement contracts as defined in s. 626.9911:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commission of a fraudulent or dishonest act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No longer meeting the requirements for initial licensure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having received a fee, commission, or other valuable consideration for his or her services with respect to viatical settlements that involved unlicensed viatical settlement providers or persons who offered or attempted to negotiate on behalf of another person a viatical settlement contract as defined in s. 626.9911 and who were not licensed life agents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dealing in bad faith with viators.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 240, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 12, ch. 71-86; s. 160, ch. 73-333; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 78-95; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 204, 217, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 28, ch. 82-386; s. 13, ch. 88-166; s. 49, ch. 90-201; ss. 55, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 47, ch. 91-1; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 14, ch. 92-146; s. 10, ch. 92-318; s. 236, ch. 97-102; s. 28, ch. 98-199; s. 12, ch. 2001-142; s. 59, ch. 2002-206; s. 947, ch. 2003-261; s. 45, ch. 2004-390; s. 11, ch. 2005-237.</History></Section>