<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9915" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of suspension or revocation of viatical settlement provider license; duration of suspension; reinstatement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When its license is suspended or revoked, the provider must proceed, immediately following the effective date of the suspension or revocation, to conclude the affairs it is transacting under its license. The provider may not solicit, negotiate, advertise, or effectuate new contracts. The office retains jurisdiction over the provider until all contracts have been fulfilled or canceled or have expired. A provider whose license is suspended or revoked may continue to maintain and service viaticated policies subject to the approval of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The suspension of the license of a viatical settlement provider licensee may be for such period, not to exceed 2 years, as determined by the office. The office may shorten, rescind, or modify the suspension.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the period of suspension, the licensee shall file its annual statement and pay license fees as if the license had continued in full force.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, upon expiration of the suspension order, the license has not otherwise been terminated, the office must reinstate the license only upon written request by the suspended licensee unless the office finds that the grounds giving rise to the suspension have not been removed or that the licensee is otherwise not in compliance with the requirements of this act. The office shall give the licensee notice of its findings no later than 90 days after receipt of the request or upon expiration of the suspension order, whichever occurs later. If a license is not reinstated pursuant to the procedures set forth in this subsection, it expires at the end of the suspension or on the date it otherwise would have expired, whichever is sooner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 96-336; s. 14, ch. 2000-344; s. 1048, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>