<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9271" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary license; death, disability, absence of surplus lines agent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, in its discretion, issue a temporary license and appointment as a surplus lines agent to a licensed surplus lines agent’s employee, family member, business associate, or personal representative for the purpose of continuing or winding up the business affairs of the surplus lines agent or agency, subject to the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surplus lines agent being replaced must have died or become unable to perform his or her duties as agent because of military service or illness or other physical or mental disability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There must be no other person connected with the surplus lines agent’s business who is licensed as a surplus lines agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed temporary licensee must be qualified for a regular surplus lines agent’s license under this code except as to residence, examination, education, or experience.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for the temporary license and appointment must be made by the applicant upon statements and affidavit filed with the department on forms as prescribed and furnished by it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The temporary license and appointment shall be issued and be valid for a period of not over 4 months, and may not be renewed to the holder of the temporary license or to any other person for or on behalf of the surplus lines agent or agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant for a temporary license and appointment shall pay to the department, prior to the issuance thereof, the applicable license and appointment fees specified in s. 624.501.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holder of a temporary license may be granted a regular surplus lines agent’s license upon passing an examination as required by s. 626.927.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as in this section expressly provided, the holder of a temporary license shall be subject to the same requirements and responsibilities as apply under this code to agents regularly licensed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 308, 807, ch. 82-243; ss. 174, 205, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 305, ch. 97-102; s. 72, ch. 98-199.</History></Section>