<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.8437" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for denial, suspension, revocation, or refusal to renew license or appointment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deny, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew or continue the license or appointment of any title insurance agent or agency, and it shall suspend or revoke the eligibility to hold a license or appointment of such person, if it finds that as to the applicant, licensee, appointee, or any principal thereof, any one or more of the following grounds exist:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lack of one or more of the qualifications for the license or appointment as specified in ss. 626.8417, 626.8418, and 626.8419.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material misstatement, misrepresentation, or fraud in obtaining, or attempting to obtain, the license or appointment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful misrepresentation of any title insurance policy, guarantee of title, binder, or commitment, or willful deception with regard to any such policy, guarantee, binder, or commitment, done either in person or by any form of dissemination of information or advertising.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated lack of fitness or trustworthiness to represent a title insurer in the issuance of its commitments, binders, policies of title insurance, or guarantees of title.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated lack of reasonably adequate knowledge and technical competence to engage in the transactions authorized by the license or appointment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent or dishonest practices in the conduct of business under the license or appointment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misappropriation, conversion, or unlawful withholding of moneys belonging to title insurers or insureds or others and received in conduct of business under the license or appointment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unlawful rebating, or attempting to unlawfully rebate, or unlawfully dividing, or offering to unlawfully divide, title insurance premiums, fees, or charges with another, as prohibited by s. 626.9541(1)(h)3.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful failure to comply with, or willful violation of, any proper order or rule of the department or willful violation of any provision of this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee if an individual, or the partners if a partnership, or owner if a sole proprietorship, or the officers if a corporation, having been found guilty of or having pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or a crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of the United States or of any state or under the law of any other country which involves moral turpitude, without regard to whether a judgment of conviction has been entered by the court having jurisdiction of such cases.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to timely submit data as required by s. 627.782.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 85-185; s. 1, ch. 86-286; s. 5, ch. 89-305; s. 125, ch. 90-363; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 48, ch. 98-199; s. 2, ch. 2012-206.</History>
</Section>