<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for license as an agent, customer representative, adjuster, service representative, managing general agent, or reinsurance intermediary.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a license as agent, customer representative, adjuster, service representative, managing general agent, or reinsurance intermediary to any person except upon written application filed with the department, meeting the qualifications for the license applied for as determined by the department, and payment in advance of all applicable fees. The application must be made under the oath of the applicant and be signed by the applicant. An applicant may permit a third party to complete, submit, and sign an application on the applicant’s behalf, but is responsible for ensuring that the information on the application is true and correct and is accountable for any misstatements or misrepresentations. The department shall accept the uniform application for nonresident agent licensing. The department may adopt revised versions of the uniform application by rule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the application, the applicant shall set forth:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Reference Number="1" />
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">His or her full name, age, social security number, residence address, business address, mailing address, contact telephone numbers, including a business telephone number, and e-mail address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement indicating the method the applicant used or is using to meet any required prelicensing education, knowledge, experience, or instructional requirements for the type of license applied for.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether he or she has been refused or has voluntarily surrendered or has had suspended or revoked a license to solicit insurance by the department or by the supervising officials of any state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether any insurer or any managing general agent claims the applicant is indebted under any agency contract or otherwise and, if so, the name of the claimant, the nature of the claim, and the applicant’s defense thereto, if any.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that the applicant meets the requirements for the type of license for which he or she is applying.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s gender (male or female).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s native language.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The highest level of education achieved by the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s race or ethnicity (African American, white, American Indian, Asian, Hispanic, or other).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other or additional information as the department may deem proper to enable it to determine the character, experience, ability, and other qualifications of the applicant to hold himself or herself out to the public as an insurance representative.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, the application must contain a statement that an applicant is not required to disclose his or her race or ethnicity, gender, or native language, that he or she will not be penalized for not doing so, and that the department will use this information exclusively for research and statistical purposes and to improve the quality and fairness of the examinations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application shall be accompanied by payment of any applicable fee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a license as an agent, customer representative, adjuster, service representative, managing general agent, or reinsurance intermediary must submit a set of the individual applicant’s fingerprints, or, if the applicant is not an individual, a set of the fingerprints of the sole proprietor, majority owner, partners, officers, and directors, to the department and must pay the fingerprint processing fee set forth in s. 624.501. Fingerprints shall be used to investigate the applicant’s qualifications pursuant to s. 626.201. The fingerprints shall be taken by a law enforcement agency, designated examination center, or other department-approved entity. The department shall require all designated examination centers to have fingerprinting equipment and to take fingerprints from any applicant or prospective applicant who pays the applicable fee. The department may not approve an application for licensure as an agent, customer service representative, adjuster, service representative, managing general agent, or reinsurance intermediary if fingerprints have not been submitted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application for license filing fee prescribed in s. 624.501 is not subject to refund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, each party is required to provide his or her social security number in accordance with this section. Disclosure of social security numbers obtained through this requirement shall be limited to the purpose of administration of the Title IV-D program for child support enforcement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 196, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 71-86; s. 1, ch. 72-34; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 158(2nd), 217, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; s. 3, ch. 85-208; ss. 16, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 42, ch. 92-146; s. 212, ch. 97-102; s. 66, ch. 97-170; s. 10, ch. 98-199; s. 4, ch. 2001-142; ss. 9, 50, ch. 2002-206; s. 912, ch. 2003-261; s. 23, ch. 2003-267; s. 16, ch. 2003-281; s. 22, ch. 2004-390; s. 8, ch. 2005-257; s. 1, ch. 2006-184; s. 138, ch. 2007-5; s. 2, ch. 2008-237; s. 3, ch. 2012-209.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 12, ch. 2008-237, provides in part that “[e]ffective [June 30, 2008,] the Department of Financial Services may adopt rules to implement this act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>