<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.99287" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contestability of viaticated policies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as hereinafter provided, if a viatical settlement contract is entered into within the 2-year period commencing with the date of issuance of the insurance policy or certificate to be acquired, the viatical settlement contract is void and unenforceable by either party. Notwithstanding this limitation, such a viatical settlement contract is not void and unenforceable if:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The policy was issued upon the owner’s exercise of conversion rights arising out of a group or term policy;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of the policy is a charitable organization exempt from taxation under 26 U.S.C. s. 501(c)(3);</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of the policy is not a natural person;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viatical settlement contract was entered into before July 1, 2000;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viator certifies by producing independent evidence to the viatical settlement provider that one or more of the following conditions have been met within the 2-year period:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viator or insured is diagnosed with an illness or condition that is either:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Catastrophic or life threatening; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requires a course of treatment for a period of at least 3 years of long-term care or home health care; and</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The condition was not known to the insured at the time the life insurance contract was entered into.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viator’s spouse dies;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viator divorces his or her spouse;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viator retires from full-time employment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viator becomes physically or mentally disabled and a physician determines that the disability prevents the viator from maintaining full-time employment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner of the policy was the insured’s employer at the time the policy or certificate was issued and the employment relationship terminated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A final order, judgment, or decree is entered by a court of competent jurisdiction, on the application of a creditor of the viator, adjudicating the viator bankrupt or insolvent, or approving a petition seeking reorganization of the viator or appointing a receiver, trustee, or liquidator to all or a substantial part of the viator’s assets; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The viator experiences a significant decrease in income which is unexpected by the viator and which impairs his or her reasonable ability to pay the policy premium.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the viatical settlement provider submits to the insurer a copy of the viator’s or owner’s certification described above, then the provider submits a request to the insurer to effect the transfer of the policy or certificate to the viatical settlement provider, the viatical settlement agreement shall not be void or unenforceable by operation of this section. The insurer shall timely respond to such request. Nothing in this section shall prohibit an insurer from exercising its right during the contestability period to contest the validity of any policy on grounds of fraud.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2000-344.</History></Section>