<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.99278" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Viatical provider anti-fraud plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every licensed viatical settlement provider and registered life expectancy provider must adopt an anti-fraud plan and file it with the Division of Insurance Fraud of the department. Each anti-fraud plan shall include:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the procedures for detecting and investigating possible fraudulent acts and procedures for resolving material inconsistencies between medical records and insurance applications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the procedures for the mandatory reporting of possible fraudulent insurance acts and prohibited practices set forth in s. 626.99275 to the Division of Insurance Fraud of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the plan for anti-fraud education and training of its underwriters or other personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written description or chart outlining the organizational arrangement of the anti-fraud personnel who are responsible for the investigation and reporting of possible fraudulent insurance acts and for the investigation of unresolved material inconsistencies between medical records and insurance applications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For viatical settlement providers, a description of the procedures used to perform initial and continuing review of the accuracy of life expectancies used in connection with a viatical settlement contract or viatical settlement investment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 2000-344; s. 29, ch. 2005-237.</History></Section>