<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.907" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service of process; judgment by default.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service of process upon an insurer or person representing or aiding such insurer pursuant to s. 626.906 shall be made by delivering to and leaving with the Chief Financial Officer or some person in apparent charge of his or her office two copies thereof. The Chief Financial Officer shall forthwith mail by registered mail one of the copies of such process to the defendant at the defendant’s last known principal place of business and shall keep a record of all process so served upon him or her. The service of process is sufficient, provided notice of such service and a copy of the process are sent within 10 days thereafter by registered mail by plaintiff or plaintiff’s attorney to the defendant at the defendant’s last known principal place of business, and the defendant’s receipt, or receipt issued by the post office with which the letter is registered, showing the name of the sender of the letter and the name and address of the person to whom the letter is addressed, and the affidavit of the plaintiff or plaintiff’s attorney showing a compliance herewith are filed with the clerk of the court in which the action is pending on or before the date the defendant is required to appear, or within such further time as the court may allow.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service of process in any such action, suit, or proceeding shall, in addition to the manner provided in subsection (1), be valid if served upon any person within this state who, in this state on behalf of the unauthorized insurer or person representing or aiding such insurer, is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soliciting insurance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making, issuing, or delivering any contract of insurance; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collecting or receiving any premium, membership fee, assessment, or other consideration for insurance;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and a copy of such process is sent within 10 days thereafter by registered mail by the plaintiff or plaintiff’s attorney to the defendant at the last known principal place of business of the defendant, and the defendant’s receipt, or the receipt issued by the post office with which the letter is registered, showing the name of the sender of the letter and the name and address of the person to whom the letter is addressed, and the affidavit of the plaintiff or plaintiff’s attorney showing a compliance herewith are filed with the clerk of the court in which such action is pending on or before the date the defendant is required to appear, or within such further time as the court may allow.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No plaintiff shall be entitled to a judgment by default or a decree pro confesso under this section until the expiration of 30 days from date of the filing of the affidavit of compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall limit or abridge the right to serve any process, notice, or demand upon any insurer or person representing or aiding such insurer in any other manner now or hereafter permitted by law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 348, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 318, 807, ch. 82-243; ss. 156, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 296, ch. 97-102; s. 1011, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>