<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.8685" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Portable electronics insurance claims; exemption; licensure restriction.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not apply to any individual who collects claims information from, or furnishes claims information to, insureds or claimants, and who conducts data entry, including entering data into an automated claims adjudication system, provided that the individual is an employee of a business entity licensed under this chapter, or its affiliate, and no more than 25 such persons are under the supervision of one licensed independent adjuster or licensed agent who is exempt from licensure pursuant to s. 626.862. For purposes of this subsection, the term “automated claims adjudication system” means a preprogrammed computer system designed for the collection, data entry, calculation, and final resolution of portable electronics insurance claims that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May be used only by a licensed independent adjuster, licensed agent, or supervised individual operating pursuant to this subsection;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must comply with all claims payment requirements of the insurance code; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be certified as compliant with this subsection by a licensed independent adjuster that is an officer of a licensed business entity under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a resident of Canada may not be licensed as a nonresident independent adjuster for purposes of adjusting portable electronics insurance claims unless the person has successfully obtained an adjuster’s license in another state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2012-151.</History>
</Section>