<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.561" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reporting and accounting for funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All premiums, return premiums, or other funds belonging to insurers or others received by an agent, insurance agency, customer representative, or adjuster in transactions under the license are trust funds received by the licensee in a fiduciary capacity. An agent or insurance agency shall keep the funds belonging to each insurer for which an agent is not appointed, other than a surplus lines insurer, in a separate account so as to allow the department or office to properly audit such funds. The licensee in the applicable regular course of business shall account for and pay the same to the insurer, insured, or other person entitled thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall keep and make available to the department or office books, accounts, and records as will enable the department or office to determine whether such licensee is complying with the provisions of this code. Every licensee shall preserve books, accounts, and records pertaining to a premium payment for at least 3 years after payment; provided, however, the preservation of records by computer or photographic reproductions or records in photographic form shall constitute compliance with this requirement. All other records shall be maintained in accordance with s. 626.748. The 3-year requirement shall not apply to insurance binders when no policy is ultimately issued and no premium is collected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any agent, insurance agency, customer representative, or adjuster who, not being lawfully entitled thereto, either temporarily or permanently diverts or misappropriates such funds or any portion thereof or deprives the other person of a benefit therefrom commits the offense specified below:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the funds diverted or misappropriated are $300 or less, a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the funds diverted or misappropriated are more than $300, but less than $20,000, a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the funds diverted or misappropriated are $20,000 or more, but less than $100,000, a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the funds diverted or misappropriated are $100,000 or more, a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 235, ch. 59-205; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 202, 217, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 50, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 95-340; s. 232, ch. 97-102; s. 25, ch. 98-199; s. 57, ch. 2002-206; s. 943, ch. 2003-261; s. 18, ch. 2005-257.</History></Section>