<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.016" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of department, commission, and office.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers and duties of the Chief Financial Officer and the department specified in this part apply only with respect to insurance agents, insurance agencies, managing general agents, insurance adjusters, reinsurance intermediaries, viatical settlement brokers, customer representatives, service representatives, and agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers and duties of the commission and office specified in this part apply only with respect to service companies, administrators, and viatical settlement providers and contracts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has jurisdiction to enforce provisions of parts VIII and IX of this chapter with respect to persons who engage in actions for which a license issued by the department is legally required. The office has jurisdiction to enforce provisions of parts VIII and IX of this chapter with respect to persons who engage in actions for which a license or certificate of authority issued by the office is legally required. For persons who violate a provision of this chapter for whom a license or certificate of authority issued by either the department or office is not required, either the department or office may take administrative action against such person as authorized by this chapter, pursuant to agreement between the office and department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section is intended to limit the authority of the department and the Division of Insurance Fraud, as specified in s. 626.989.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 908, ch. 2003-261; s. 19, ch. 2004-390; s. 5, ch. 2005-257.</History></Section>