<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.7454" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Managing general agents; duties of insurers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer shall have on file for each managing general agent with which it has done business an independent financial examination in a form acceptable to the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a managing general agent establishes total loss reserves, including IBNR if any, the insurer shall annually obtain the opinion of an actuary attesting to the adequacy of loss reserves established for losses incurred and outstanding on business produced by the managing general agent. This subsection is in addition to any other requirement of loss reserve certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer shall, at least annually, conduct an onsite review of the underwriting and claims processing operations of the managing general agent; however, the insurer shall conduct an onsite review of the underwriting and claims processing operations of a newly engaged managing general agent within 6 months after he or she is engaged.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Binding authority for all reinsurance contracts or participation in insurance or reinsurance syndicates shall rest with an officer of the insurer, who shall not be affiliated with the managing general agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after entering into or terminating a contract with a managing general agent, the insurer shall provide written notification of the appointment or termination to the department and office. Notices of appointment of a managing general agent shall include a statement of duties which the applicant is expected to perform on behalf of the insurer, the lines of insurance for which the applicant is to be authorized to act, and any other information the department or office may request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An insurer shall review its books and records on a quarterly basis to determine if any producer has become a managing general agent as defined in s. 626.015. If the insurer determines that a producer has become a managing general agent, the insurer shall promptly notify the producer and the department and office of such determination and the insurer and producer must fully comply with the provisions of this section and ss. 626.7451, 626.7452, and 626.7453 within 30 days after such determination.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Subsections (1), (3), and (4) do not apply to a managing general agent that is a controlled or controlling person.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 87, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 2, ch. 91-296; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 253, ch. 97-102; s. 26, ch. 2002-206; s. 959, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>