<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9372" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disclosure statement of certain information required; liability claims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each insurer that provides or may provide liability insurance coverage to pay all or a portion of any claim that might be made under surplus lines policies issued on or after October 1, 2009, shall provide, within 60 days after the written request of the claimant, a statement of a corporate officer or the insurer’s claims manager or superintendent setting forth the following information with regard to each known policy of insurance, including excess or umbrella insurance:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the insurer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each insured.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limits of the liability coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of any policy or coverage defense that such insurer reasonably believes is available to such insurer at the time of filing such statement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the policy.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">In addition, the insured, or her or his insurance agent, upon written request of the claimant or the claimant’s attorney, shall disclose the name and coverage of each known insurer to the claimant and forward such request for information as required by this subsection to all affected insurers. The insurer shall supply the information required in this subsection to the claimant within 60 days after receipt of such request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statement required by subsection (1) must be amended within 60 days after the date of discovery of facts necessitating an amendment to such statement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2009-166.</History></Section>