<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.9325" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service fee.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The premiums charged for surplus lines insurance are subject to a service fee as provided in s. 626.921(3)(f). The surplus lines agent shall collect from the insured the amount of the fee at the time of the delivery of the policy, or other initial confirmation of insurance, in addition to the full amount of the gross premium charged by the insurer for the insurance. The surplus lines agent is prohibited from absorbing such fee or, as an inducement for insurance or for any other reason, rebating all or any part of such fee or of his or her commission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surplus lines agent shall pay on or before the 45th day following each calendar quarter to the Florida Surplus Lines Service Office the fees related to all policies reported during the previous calendar quarter in accordance with the plan of operation of the Florida Surplus Lines Service Office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent shall pay interest on the amount of any delinquent fees due, at the rate of 9 percent per year, compounded annually, beginning the day the amount becomes delinquent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a surplus lines policy covers risks or exposures only partially in this state and the state is the home state as defined in the federal Nonadmitted and Reinsurance Reform Act of 2010 (NRRA), the fee payable shall be computed on the gross premium.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply as to insurance of risks of the state government or its agencies, or of any county or municipality or of any agency thereof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association shall use the fees to fund the cost of operations of the Florida Surplus Lines Service Office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “premium” means the consideration for insurance by whatever name called and includes any assessment, or any membership, policy, survey, inspection, service, or similar fee or charge in consideration for an insurance contract, which items are deemed to be a part of the premium. The per-policy fee authorized by s. 626.916(4) is specifically included within the meaning of the term “premium.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 97-196; s. 42, ch. 99-7; s. 3, ch. 2011-46.</History>
</Section>