<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.99275" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited practices; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To knowingly enter into, broker, or otherwise deal in a viatical settlement contract the subject of which is a life insurance policy, knowing that the policy was obtained by presenting materially false information concerning any fact material to the policy or by concealing, for the purpose of misleading another, information concerning any fact material to the policy, where the viator or the viator’s agent intended to defraud the policy’s issuer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To knowingly or with the intent to defraud, for the purpose of depriving another of property or for pecuniary gain, issue or use a pattern of false, misleading, or deceptive life expectancies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To knowingly engage in any transaction, practice, or course of business intending thereby to avoid the notice requirements of s. 626.9924(7).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To knowingly or intentionally facilitate the change of state of residency of a viator to avoid the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates any provision of this section commits:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the insurance policy involved is valued at any amount less than $20,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the insurance policy involved is valued at $20,000 or more, but less than $100,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the insurance policy involved is valued at $100,000 or more.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 99-212; s. 9, ch. 2000-344; s. 53, ch. 2001-63; s. 28, ch. 2005-237.</History></Section>