<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary licensing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a nonrenewable temporary license for a period not to exceed 6 months authorizing appointment of a general lines insurance agent or a life agent, or an industrial fire or burglary agent, subject to the conditions described in this section. The fees paid for a temporary license and appointment shall be as specified in s. 624.501. Fees paid shall not be refunded after a temporary license has been issued.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a temporary license must be:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A natural person at least 18 years of age.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A United States citizen or legal alien who possesses work authorization from the United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a general lines agent, the department may issue a temporary license to an employee, a family member, a business associate, or a personal representative of a licensed general lines agent for the purpose of continuing or winding up the business affairs of the agent or agency in the event the licensed agent has died or become unable to perform his or her duties because of military service or illness or other physical or mental disability, subject to the following conditions:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No other individual connected with the agent’s business may be licensed as a general lines agent.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed temporary licensee shall be qualified for a regular general lines agent license under this code except as to residence, examination, education, or experience.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for the temporary license shall have been made by the applicant upon statements and affidavit filed with the department on forms prescribed and furnished by the department.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under a temporary license and appointment, the licensee shall not represent any insurer not last represented by the agent being replaced and shall not be licensed or appointed as to any additional kind, line, or class of insurance other than those covered by the last existing agency appointments of the replaced agent. If an insurer withdraws from the agency during the temporary license period, the temporary licensee may be appointed by another similar insurer but only for the period remaining under the temporary license.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A regular general lines agent license may be issued to a temporary licensee upon meeting the qualifications for a general lines agent license under s. 626.731.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a life agent, the department may issue a temporary license:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the executor or administrator of the estate of a deceased individual licensed and appointed as a life agent at the time of death;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a surviving next of kin of the deceased individual, if no administrator or executor has been appointed and qualified; however, any license and appointment under this subparagraph shall be canceled upon issuance of a license to an executor or administrator under subparagraph 1.; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To an individual otherwise qualified to be licensed as an agent who has completed the educational or training requirements prescribed in s. 626.7851 and has successfully sat for the required examination prior to termination of such 6-month period. The department may issue this temporary license only in the case of a life agent to represent an insurer of the industrial or ordinary-combination class.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a limited license authorizing appointment as an industrial fire or burglary agent, the department may issue a temporary license to an individual otherwise qualified to be licensed as an agent who has completed the educational or training requirements prescribed in s. 626.732 and has successfully sat for the required examination prior to termination of the 6-month period.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an absent or disabled agent being replaced under a temporary license returns or becomes able to resume the active conduct of the agency, or if the disposition of the affairs of the agency of a deceased or mentally incompetent agent is completed, or the temporary licensee has qualified for a regular license, before expiration otherwise of the temporary license, the temporary license shall terminate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the 6-month temporary license and appointment period, the applicant passes the licensing examination, the temporary license shall terminate and a license shall be issued by the department after payment of a modification fee as prescribed in s. 624.501.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a temporary license shall be made by the applicant upon statements and affidavit filed with the department on forms prescribed and furnished by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this section, the holder of a temporary license shall be subject to the Florida Insurance Code to the same extent as regularly licensed and appointed agents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may limit the authority of any temporary licensee in any way deemed necessary to protect insureds and the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue to an applicant only one temporary license for each kind, line, or class of insurance or a single temporary license covering multiple lines.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 2002-206; s. 24, ch. 2003-267; s. 17, ch. 2003-281; s. 106, ch. 2004-5.</History></Section>