<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.872" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary license.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a temporary license as an all-lines adjuster, subject to the following conditions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must be an employee of an adjuster currently licensed by the department, an authorized insurer, or an established adjusting firm or corporation who is supervised by a currently licensed all-lines adjuster.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must be a natural person of at least 18 years of age, a bona fide resident of this state, trustworthy, and have a business reputation that would reasonably ensure that the applicant will conduct his or her business as an adjuster fairly and in good faith and without detriment to the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s employer is responsible for the adjustment acts of the temporary licensee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicable license fee must be paid before issuance of the temporary license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The temporary license is effective for 1 year, but is subject to earlier termination at the request of the employer, if the licensee fails to take an examination as an all-lines adjuster within 6 months after issuance of the temporary license, or if the temporary license is suspended or revoked by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If during the 1-year temporary license period the applicant passes the examination as for a regular license, the temporary license shall continue in effect as a regular license, but subject to expiration, renewal, or continuation, if the licensee remains continuously employed as referred to in paragraph (1)(a), under the supervision of a licensed adjuster or as an employee of an authorized insurer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adjuster licensed under this section may not adjust losses in this state after expiration of the temporary license without having been issued a regular adjuster’s license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the temporary license, the licensee shall have the authority to handle only such classes of business as his or her supervising adjuster is licensed to handle, except that the temporary licensee shall not be permitted by his or her employer to negotiate settlements with the insured or claimant for amounts in excess of $20,000.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a temporary license as an all-lines adjuster to an individual who has held such license in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 335, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 81-282; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 287, 293, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 146, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 291, ch. 97-102; s. 64, ch. 98-199; s. 18, ch. 2001-142; s. 987, ch. 2003-261; s. 67, ch. 2004-390; s. 39, ch. 2012-209.</History>
</Section>