<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.8419" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment of title insurance agency.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The title insurer engaging or employing the title insurance agency must file with the department, on forms furnished by the department, an application certifying that the proposed title insurance agency meets all of the following requirements:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency must have obtained a fidelity bond in an amount, not less than $50,000, acceptable to the insurer appointing the agency. If a fidelity bond is unavailable generally, the department must adopt rules for alternative methods to comply with this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency must have obtained errors and omissions insurance in an amount acceptable to the insurer appointing the agency. The amount of the coverage may not be less than $250,000 per claim and an aggregate limit with a deductible no greater than $10,000. If errors and omissions insurance is unavailable generally, the department must adopt rules for alternative methods to comply with this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 626.8418(2), the agency must have obtained a surety bond in an amount not less than $35,000 made payable to the title insurer or title insurers appointing the agency. The surety bond must be for the benefit of any appointing title insurer damaged by a violation by the title insurance agency of its contract with the appointing title insurer. If the surety bond is payable to multiple title insurers, the surety bond must provide that each title insurer is to be notified in the event a claim is made upon the surety bond or the bond is terminated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surety bond must remain in effect and unimpaired as long as the agency is appointed by a title insurer. The agency must provide written proof to the appointing title insurer or insurers on an annual basis evidencing that the surety bond is still in effect and unimpaired.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A title insurer may not provide the surety bond directly or indirectly on behalf of the agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not exempt title insurance agents from the appointment requirements of part I.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 92-318; s. 25, ch. 2012-209.</History>
</Section>