<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.8796" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public adjuster contracts; fraud statement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All contracts for public adjuster services must be in writing and prominently display the following statement on the contract: “Pursuant to s. 817.234, Florida Statutes, any person who, with the intent to injure, defraud, or deceive an insurer or insured, prepares, presents, or causes to be presented a proof of loss or estimate of cost or repair of damaged property in support of a claim under an insurance policy knowing that the proof of loss or estimate of claim or repairs contains false, incomplete, or misleading information concerning any fact or thing material to the claim commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, Florida Statutes.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public adjuster contract relating to a property and casualty claim must contain the full name, permanent business address, and license number of the public adjuster; the full name of the public adjusting firm; and the insured’s full name and street address, together with a brief description of the loss. The contract must state the percentage of compensation for the public adjuster’s services; the type of claim, including an emergency claim, nonemergency claim, or supplemental claim; the signatures of the public adjuster and all named insureds; and the signature date. If all of the named insureds’ signatures are not available, the public adjuster must submit an affidavit signed by the available named insureds attesting that they have authority to enter into the contract and settle all claim issues on behalf of the named insureds. An unaltered copy of the executed contract must be remitted to the insurer within 30 days after execution. A public adjusting firm that adjusts claims primarily for commercial entities with operations in more than one state and that does not directly or indirectly perform adjusting services for insurers or individual homeowners is deemed to comply with the requirements of this subsection if, at the time a proof of loss is submitted, the public adjusting firm remits to the insurer an affidavit signed by the public adjuster or public adjuster apprentice that identifies:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name, permanent business address, and license number of the public adjuster or public adjuster apprentice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name of the public adjusting firm.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insured’s full name and street address, together with a brief description of the loss.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An attestation that the compensation for public adjusting services will not exceed the limitations provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of claim, including an emergency claim, nonemergency claim, or supplemental claim.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2008-220; s. 80, ch. 2009-21; s. 9, ch. 2011-39; s. 47, ch. 2012-209.</History>
</Section>