<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.8467" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Testimony compelled; immunity from prosecution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person asks to be excused from attending or testifying or from producing any books, papers, records, contracts, documents, or other evidence in connection with any examination, hearing, or investigation being conducted under s. 624.5015, ss. 626.8417-626.847, or s. 627.791 by the department or office or its examiner on the ground that the testimony or evidence required of the person may tend to incriminate him or her or subject him or her to a penalty or forfeiture and notwithstanding is directed to give such testimony or produce such evidence, the person must, if so directed by the Department of Financial Services and the Department of Legal Affairs or by the office and the Department of Legal Affairs, nonetheless comply with such direction, but he or she shall not thereafter be prosecuted or subjected to any penalty or forfeiture for or on account of any transaction, matter, or thing concerning which he or she may have so testified or produced evidence, and no testimony so given or evidence produced shall be received against the person upon any criminal action, investigation, or proceeding. However, a person so testifying shall not be exempt from prosecution or punishment for any perjury committed by him or her in such testimony, and the testimony or evidence so given or produced shall be admissible against him or her upon any criminal action, investigation, or proceeding concerning such perjury; and such person shall not be exempt from the refusal, suspension, or revocation of any license or appointment, permission, or authority conferred or to be conferred pursuant to s. 624.5015, ss. 626.8417-626.847, or s. 627.791.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such person may execute, acknowledge, and file with the Department of Financial Services or the office, as appropriate, a statement expressly waiving such immunity or privilege with respect to any transaction, matter, or thing specified in the statement, and thereupon the testimony of such person or such evidence in relation to such transaction, matter, or thing may be received or produced before any judge or justice, court, tribunal, or grand jury or otherwise and, if so received or produced, such person shall not be entitled to any immunity or privilege on account of any testimony he or she may so give or evidence so produced.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 85-185; s. 1, ch. 86-286; s. 133, ch. 90-363; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 281, ch. 97-102; s. 969, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>