<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.7354" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Customer representative’s powers; agent’s or agency’s responsibility.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A customer representative’s license shall not cover life insurance or any kind of insurance for which the agent or agency by which he or she is appointed is not then licensed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A customer representative may engage in transacting insurance with customers who have been solicited by any agent or customer representative in the same agency, and may engage in transacting insurance with customers who have not been so solicited to the extent and under conditions that are otherwise consistent with this part and with the insurer’s contract with the agent appointing him or her.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A customer representative shall be a salaried employee of the agent or agency. His or her compensation shall not include commissions and shall not be primarily based on the production of applications, insurance, or premiums.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A customer representative shall not engage in transacting insurance outside of the office of his or her agent or agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All business transacted by a customer representative under his or her license shall be in the name of the agent or agency by which he or she is appointed, and the agent or agency shall be responsible and accountable for all acts of the customer representative within the scope of such appointment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 74, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 246, ch. 97-102; s. 83, ch. 2003-1; s. 46, ch. 2003-267; s. 39, ch. 2003-281.</History></Section>