<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.99175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Life expectancy providers; registration required; denial, suspension, revocation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After July 1, 2006, a person may not perform the functions of a life expectancy provider without first having registered as a life expectancy provider, except as provided in subsection (6).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for registration as a life expectancy provider must be made to the office by the applicant on a form prescribed by the office, under oath and signed by the applicant. The application must be accompanied by a fee of $500.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A completed application shall be evidenced on a form and in a manner prescribed by the office and shall require the registered life expectancy provider to update such information and renew such registration as required by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the application, the applicant must provide all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name, age, residence address, and business address, and all occupations engaged in by the applicant during the 5 years preceding the date of the application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the applicant’s basic organizational documents, if any, including the articles of incorporation, articles of association, partnership agreement, trust agreement, or other similar documents, together with all amendments to such documents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of all bylaws, rules, regulations, or similar documents regulating the conduct of the applicant’s internal affairs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list showing the name, business and residence addresses, and official position of each individual who is responsible for conduct of the applicant’s affairs, including, but not limited to, any member of the board of directors, board of trustees, executive committee, or other governing board or committee and any other person or entity owning or having the right to acquire 10 percent or more of the voting securities of the applicant, and any person performing life expectancies by the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn biographical statement on forms supplied by the office with respect to each individual identified under paragraph (d), including whether such individual has been associated with any other life expectancy provider or has performed any services for a person in the business of viatical settlements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement of any criminal and civil actions pending or final against the registrant or any individual identified under paragraph (d).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A general description of the following policies and procedures covering all life expectancy determination criteria and protocols:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan or plans of policies and procedures used to determine life expectancies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the training, including continuing training, of the individuals who determine life expectancies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of how the life expectancy provider updates its manuals, underwriting guides, mortality tables, and other reference works and ensures that the provider bases its determination of life expectancies on current data.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plan for assuring confidentiality of personal, medical, and financial information in accordance with federal and state laws.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An anti-fraud plan as required pursuant to s. 626.99278.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of any agreements, contracts, or any other arrangement to provide life expectancies to a viatical settlement provider, viatical settlement broker, or any other person in the business of viatical settlements in connection with any viatical settlement contract or viatical settlement investment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of the application, and on or before March 1 of every 3 years thereafter, a registered life expectancy provider shall file with the office an audit of all life expectancies by the life expectancy provider for the 5 calendar years immediately preceding such audit, which audit shall be conducted and certified by a nationally recognized actuarial firm and shall include only the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mortality table.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number, percentage, and an actual-to-expected ratio of life expectancies in the following categories: life expectancies of less than 24 months, life expectancies of 25 months to 48 months, life expectancies of 49 months to 72 months, life expectancies of 73 months to 108 months, life expectancies of 109 months to 144 months, life expectancies of 145 months to 180 months, and life expectancies of more than 180 months.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No viatical settlement broker, viatical settlement provider, or insurance agent in the business of viatical settlements in this state shall directly or indirectly own or be an officer, director, or employee of a life expectancy provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each registered life expectancy provider shall provide the office, as applicable, at least 30 days’ advance notice of any change in the registrant’s name, residence address, principal business address, or mailing address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person required to be registered by this section shall for 5 years retain copies of all life expectancies and supporting documents and medical records unless those personal medical records are subject to different retention or destruction requirements of a federal or state personal health information law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for life expectancy provider registration shall be approved or denied by the commissioner within 60 calendar days following receipt of a completed application by the commissioner. The office shall notify the applicant that the application is complete. A completed application that is not approved or denied in 60 calendar days following its receipt shall be deemed approved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, in its discretion, deny the application for a life expectancy provider registration or suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew or continue the registration of a life expectancy provider if the office finds:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any cause for which registration could have been refused had it then existed and been known to the office;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of any provision of this code or of any other law applicable to the applicant or registrant;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of any lawful order or rule of the department, commission, or office; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the applicant or registrant:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been found guilty of or pled guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or a crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of the United States of America or of any state thereof or under the law of any other country;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has knowingly and willfully aided, assisted, procured, advised, or abetted any person in the violation of a provision of the insurance code or any order or rule of the department, commission, or office;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has knowingly and with intent to defraud, provided a life expectancy that does not conform to an applicant’s or registrant’s general practice;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have a good business reputation or does not have experience, training, or education that qualifies the applicant or registrant to conduct the business of a life expectancy provider; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has demonstrated a lack of fitness or trustworthiness to engage in the business of issuing life expectancies.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, in lieu of or in addition to any suspension or revocation, assess an administrative fine not to exceed $2,500 for each nonwillful violation or $10,000 for each willful violation by a registered life expectancy provider. The office may also place a registered life expectancy provider on probation for a period not to exceed 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a violation of this section for a person to represent, orally or in writing, that a life expectancy provider’s registration pursuant to this act is in any way a recommendation or approval of the entity or means that the qualifications or abilities have in any way been approved of.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Financial Services Commission may, by rule, require that all or part of the statements or filings required under this section be submitted by electronic means and in a computer-readable format specified by the commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 2005-237; s. 2, ch. 2006-64.</History></Section>