<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0626.8734" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonresident all-lines adjuster license qualifications.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license to an applicant for a nonresident all-lines adjuster license upon determining that the applicant has paid the applicable license fees required under s. 624.501 and:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a natural person at least 18 years of age.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed to the satisfaction of the department a written Florida all-lines adjuster examination of the scope prescribed in s. 626.241(6); however, the requirement for the examination does not apply to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant who is licensed as an all-lines adjuster in his or her home state if that state has entered into a reciprocal agreement with the department; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant who is licensed as a nonresident all-lines adjuster in a state other than his or her home state and a reciprocal agreement with the appropriate official of the state of licensure has been entered into with the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is licensed as an all-lines adjuster and is self appointed, or appointed and employed by an independent adjusting firm or other independent adjuster, or is an employee of an insurer admitted to do business in this state, a wholly owned subsidiary of an insurer admitted to <Reference Number="1"/>do business in this state, or other insurers under the common control or ownership of such insurers. Applicants licensed as nonresident all-lines adjusters under this section must be appointed as an independent adjuster or company employee adjuster in accordance with ss. 626.112 and 626.451. Appointment fees as specified in s. 624.501 must be paid to the department in advance. The appointment of a nonresident independent adjuster continues in force until suspended, revoked, or otherwise terminated, but is subject to biennial renewal or continuation by the licensee in accordance with s. 626.381 for licensees in general.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is trustworthy and has such business reputation as would reasonably ensure that he or she will conduct his or her business as a nonresident all-lines adjuster fairly and in good faith and without detriment to the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has had sufficient experience, training, or instruction concerning the adjusting of damages or losses under insurance contracts, other than life and annuity contracts; is sufficiently informed as to the terms and effects of those types of insurance contracts; and possesses adequate knowledge of the laws of this state relating to such contracts as to enable and qualify him or her to engage in the business of insurance adjuster fairly and without injury to the public or any member thereof with whom he or she may have business as an all-lines adjuster.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must furnish the following with his or her application:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A complete set of his or her fingerprints. The applicant’s fingerprints must be certified by an authorized law enforcement officer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If currently licensed as an all-lines adjuster in the applicant’s home state, a certificate or letter of authorization from the licensing authority of the applicant’s home state stating that the applicant holds a current license to act as an all-lines adjuster. The certificate or letter of authorization must be signed by the insurance commissioner, or his or her deputy or the appropriate licensing official, and must disclose whether the adjuster has ever had a license or eligibility to hold any license declined, denied, suspended, revoked, or placed on probation or whether an administrative fine or penalty has been levied against the adjuster and, if so, the reason for the action. Such certificate or letter is not required if the nonresident applicant’s licensing status can be verified through the Producer Database maintained by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, its affiliates, or subsidiaries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant’s home state does not require licensure as an all-lines adjuster and the applicant has been licensed as a resident insurance adjuster, agent, broker, or other insurance representative in his or her home state or any other state within the past 3 years, a certificate or letter of authorization from the licensing authority stating that the applicant holds or has held a license to act as an insurance adjuster, agent, or other insurance representative. The certificate or letter of authorization must be signed by the insurance commissioner, or his or her deputy or the appropriate licensing official, and must disclose whether the adjuster, agent, or other insurance representative has ever had a license or eligibility to hold any license declined, denied, suspended, revoked, or placed on probation or whether an administrative fine or penalty has been levied against the adjuster and, if so, the reason for the action. Such certificate or letter is not required if the nonresident applicant’s licensing status can be verified through the Producer Database maintained by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, its affiliates, or subsidiaries.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The usual and customary records pertaining to transactions under the license of a nonresident all-lines adjuster must be retained for at least 3 years after completion of the adjustment and be made available in this state to the department upon request. The failure of a nonresident all-lines adjuster to properly maintain records and make them available to the department upon request constitutes grounds for the immediate suspension of the license issued under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition of doing business in this state as a nonresident independent adjuster, the appointee must submit an affidavit to the department certifying that the licensee is familiar with and understands the insurance laws and administrative rules of this state and the provisions of the contracts negotiated or to be negotiated. Compliance with this filing requirement is a condition precedent to the issuance, continuation, reinstatement, or renewal of a nonresident independent adjuster’s appointment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 58, ch. 98-199; s. 50, ch. 2001-63; s. 990, ch. 2003-261; s. 70, ch. 2004-390; s. 42, ch. 2012-209.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “do” was inserted by the editors.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>