<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.8427" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Number of applications for licensure required; exemption; effect of expiration of license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a license as a title insurance agent has been issued to a title insurance agent, the agent is not required to file another license application for a similar license, irrespective of the number of insurers to be represented by the agent, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent is specifically ordered by the department to complete a new application; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During any period of 48 months since the filing of the original license application, the agent was not appointed, unless in the case of individuals the failure to be so appointed was due to military service, in which event the period within which a new application is not required may, in the discretion of the department, be extended for 12 months following the date of discharge from military service if the military service does not exceed 3 years, but in no event shall the period be extended under this clause for a period of more than 6 years from the date of filing the original application.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not charge a fee for filing an application for license with respect to any applicant for license who is exempted under this section from filing an application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the expiration or termination of a title insurance agent’s appointment, the title insurance agent is without authority conferred by the license and shall not engage or attempt to engage in any activity requiring a title insurance agent’s license and appointment. The agent shall not again be granted an appointment until he or she fully qualifies therefor as provided in this chapter. An application shall be required in all cases for qualification of a new title insurance agent’s license when application is made after the expiration of 4 years from the date of the expiration or termination of the last appointment held by a licensee.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 85-185; s. 1, ch. 86-286; s. 122, ch. 90-363; s. 114, ch. 92-318; s. 278, ch. 97-102; s. 16, ch. 2001-142; s. 967, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>