<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.742" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonresident agents; service of process.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed nonresident agent shall appoint the Chief Financial Officer as his or her attorney to receive service of legal process issued against the agent in this state, upon causes of action arising within this state out of transactions under the agent’s license and appointment. Service upon the Chief Financial Officer as attorney shall constitute effective legal service upon the agent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appointment of the Chief Financial Officer for service of process shall be irrevocable for as long as there could be any cause of action against the agent arising out of his or her insurance transactions in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duplicate copies of such legal process against such agent shall be served upon the Chief Financial Officer by a person competent to serve a summons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receiving such service, the Chief Financial Officer shall forthwith send one of the copies of the process, by registered mail with return receipt requested, to the defendant agent at his or her last address of record with the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall keep a record of the day and hour of service upon him or her of all such legal process.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 266, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 230, 241, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 81, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 251, ch. 97-102; s. 957, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>