<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.451" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment of agent or other representative.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each appointing entity or person designated by the department to administer the appointment process appointing an agent, adjuster, service representative, customer representative, or managing general agent in this state shall file the appointment with the department or office and, at the same time, pay the applicable appointment fee and taxes. Every appointment shall be subject to the prior issuance of the appropriate agent’s, adjuster’s, service representative’s, customer representative’s, or managing general agent’s license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By authorizing the effectuation of an appointment for a licensee, the appointing entity is thereby certifying to the department that an investigation of the licensee has been made and that in the appointing entity’s opinion and to the best of its knowledge and belief, the licensee is of good moral character and reputation, and is fit to engage in the insurance business. The appointing entity shall provide to the department any other information the department or office may reasonably require relative to the proposed appointee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By authorizing the effectuation of the appointment of an agent, adjuster, service representative, customer representative, or managing general agent the appointing entity is thereby certifying to the department that it is willing to be bound by the acts of the agent, adjuster, service representative, customer representative, or managing general agent, within the scope of the licensee’s employment or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each appointing entity shall advise the department or office in writing within 15 days after it or its general agent, officer, or other official becomes aware that an appointee has pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to or has been found guilty of a felony after being appointed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement agency or state attorney’s office that is aware that an agent, adjuster, service representative, customer representative, or managing general agent has pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to or has been found guilty of a felony shall notify the department or office of such fact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of an information or indictment against an agent, adjuster, service representative, customer representative, or managing general agent, the state attorney shall immediately furnish the department or office a certified copy of the information or indictment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee shall advise the department in writing within 30 days after having been found guilty of or having pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or a crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the laws of the United States, any state of the United States, or any other country, without regard to whether a judgment of conviction has been entered by the court having jurisdiction of such cases.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 224, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 191, 217, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 42, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 228, ch. 97-102; s. 21, ch. 98-199; s. 54, ch. 2002-206; s. 936, ch. 2003-261; s. 37, ch. 2003-267; s. 30, ch. 2003-281; s. 16, ch. 2005-257.</History></Section>