<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.837" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Excess or rejected business.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed health agent may place excess or rejected risks within the class of business for which he or she is licensed and appointed, and which the insurer appointing the agent is authorized to transact, with any other authorized insurer without being required to secure an appointment as to such other insurer, but subject to the agent’s agreement with the insurer appointing him or her.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Excess business” is that portion of a risk above the limits of that which the agent’s own insurer will accept.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rejected business” is a risk that the agent’s own insurer is authorized to write but rejects for underwriting reasons, or is willing to accept only on a substandard basis; but which business will be accepted and issued by another authorized insurer at a lower rate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be construed to permit an agent properly licensed and appointed by the department to broker business with another licensed and appointed agent in this state when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Both agents are licensed and appointed for the class of business involved;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agent to whom the risk is brokered is appointed by the issuing insurer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The brokerage arrangement is desired; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The brokerage arrangement is in the best interest of the insured.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 days after the last day of each month, any insurer accepting business under this section shall report to the department the name, address, telephone number, and social security number of each agent from which the insurer received more than 24 risks during the calendar year. Once the insurer has reported pursuant to this subsection an agent’s name to the department, additional reports on the same agent shall not be required. However, the fee set forth in s. 624.501 shall be paid for the agent by the insurer for each year until the insurer notifies the department that the insurer is no longer accepting business from the agent pursuant to this section. The insurer may require that the agent reimburse the insurer for the fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a managing general agent handles or an insurer accepts business under this section, relative to that business:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer shall be liable to the insured for coverage arising hereunder and for the acts of the agent in producing their business; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing general agent or insurer shall be responsible and accountable for any violation of this code by the producing agent, and the violation shall be deemed to be a violation of the code by the managing general agent or insurer if the managing general agent or insurer knew of or encouraged, aided, or abetted in the agent’s violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 312, ch. 59-205; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 3, ch. 81-282; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 268, 271, 807, 810, ch. 82-243; ss. 114, 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 23, ch. 92-146; s. 274, ch. 97-102; s. 44, ch. 98-199.</History></Section>