<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0626.9641" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Policyholders, bill of rights.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The principles expressed in the following statements shall serve as standards to be followed by the department, commission, and office in exercising their powers and duties, in exercising administrative discretion, in dispensing administrative interpretations of the law, and in adopting rules:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have the right to competitive pricing practices and marketing methods that enable them to determine the best value among comparable policies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have the right to obtain comprehensive coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have the right to insurance advertising and other selling approaches that provide accurate and balanced information on the benefits and limitations of a policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have a right to an insurance company that is financially stable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have the right to be serviced by a competent, honest insurance agent or broker.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have the right to a readable policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have the right to an insurance company that provides an economic delivery of coverage and that tries to prevent losses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policyholders shall have the right to a balanced and positive regulation by the department, commission, and office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not be construed as creating a civil cause of action by any individual policyholder against any individual insurer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 76-260; s. 807, ch. 82-243; ss. 206, 207, ch. 90-363; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1039, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>