<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0696.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Photographic recording by clerk of circuit court.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In every county in this state, the clerk of the circuit court may record any and all instruments filed for record by photographic process, this phrase being used in its most general sense and including miniature photographic, microfilming or microphotographic processes or any other photographic, mechanical or other process heretofore or hereafter devised, however designated, such as may be recommended by the clerk from time to time and approved by the board of county commissioners. The board of county commissioners shall provide out of the general revenue fund adequate equipment and supplies for making and preserving such records in accordance with the process so recommended and approved, and shall also provide adequate equipment for reproduction, and for viewing where said recording process is miniature photographic, microfilming or microphotographic, it being the intent hereof that such records shall be readily available for public inspection and copying. The clerk of the circuit court may note on the index to the photographic record of a mortgage or lien a note of assignment or a note of satisfaction of the mortgage or lien.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All instruments heretofore recorded and all action of the boards of county commissioners and clerks of the circuit courts heretofore performed in the purchase of photographic equipment and its use in accordance with the provisions of this act are hereby validated and shall be held good and valid. All service charges shall be as provided in s. 28.24.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 10300, 1925; CGL 1936 Supp. 5722(1); ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 22051, 1943; s. 8, ch. 29749, 1955; s. 1, ch. 59-429; s. 1, ch. 61-186; s. 28, ch. 70-134.</History></Section>