<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.0311" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment of relatives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Corrections.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Relative” means an individual who is related to another as father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister, uncle, aunt, first cousin, nephew, niece, husband, wife, father-in-law, mother-in-law, daughter-in-law, brother-in-law, sister-in-law, stepfather, stepmother, stepson, stepdaughter, stepbrother, stepsister, half brother, or half sister.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Organizational unit” includes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit of a state correctional institution such as security, medical, dental, classification, maintenance, personnel, or business. A work camp, boot camp, or other annex of a state correctional institution is considered part of the institution and not a separate unit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area of a regional office such as personnel, medical, administrative services, probation and parole, or community facilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A correctional work center, road prison, or work release center.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A probation and parole circuit office or a suboffice within a circuit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bureau of the Office of the Secretary or of any of the assistant secretaries.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Line of authority” means any position having supervisory authority within the direct chain of command or supervisory path that organizationally links any position in the department to the secretary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct supervision” means being an employee’s immediate supervisor, or the rater or reviewer of the employee’s performance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the interest of security and effective management, the department may adopt rules prohibiting the employment of relatives in the same organizational unit or in positions in which one employee would be in the line of authority over the other or under the direct supervision of the other.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 95-283.</History></Section>