<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Jurisdiction of department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall have supervisory and protective care, custody, and control of the inmates, buildings, grounds, property, and all other matters pertaining to the following facilities and programs for the imprisonment, correction, and rehabilitation of adult offenders:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department of Corrections adult correctional institutions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department of Corrections youthful offender institutions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department of Corrections Mental Health Treatment Facility;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department of Corrections Probation and Restitution Center;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department of Corrections community correctional centers; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Department of Corrections vocational centers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In establishing, operating, and utilizing these facilities, the department shall attempt, whenever possible, to avoid the placement of nondangerous offenders who have potential for rehabilitation with repeat offenders or dangerous offenders. Medical, mental, and psychological problems shall be diagnosed and treated whenever possible. The Department of Children and Family Services and the Agency for Persons with Disabilities shall cooperate to ensure the delivery of services to persons under the custody or supervision of the department. When it is the intent of the department to transfer a mentally ill or retarded prisoner to the Department of Children and Family Services or the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, an involuntary commitment hearing shall be held according to the provisions of chapter 393 or chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be other correctional facilities, including detention facilities of varying levels of security, work-release facilities, and community correctional facilities, halfway houses, and other approved community residential and nonresidential facilities and programs; however, no adult correctional facility may be established by changing the use and purpose of any mental health facility or mental health institution under the jurisdiction of any state agency or department without authorization in the General Appropriation Act or other approval by the Legislature. Any community residential facility may be deemed a part of the state correctional system for purposes of maintaining custody of offenders, and for this purpose the department may contract for and purchase the services of such facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in chapter 287 shall be construed as requiring competitive bids for health services involving examination, diagnosis, or treatment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 57-317; s. 1, ch. 67-99; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-441; s. 26, ch. 74-112; s. 14, ch. 75-49; s. 1, ch. 76-232; s. 69, ch. 77-120; s. 475, ch. 77-147; s. 6, ch. 77-312; s. 78, ch. 79-3; s. 8, ch. 80-374; s. 1, ch. 83-46; s. 2, ch. 83-346; s. 6, ch. 87-87; s. 76, ch. 87-226; s. 313, ch. 99-8; s. 65, ch. 2006-227.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 965.01(1).</Text></Note></Section>