<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0945.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; ss. 945.40-945.49.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 945.40-945.49, the following terms shall have the meanings ascribed to them, unless the context shall clearly indicate otherwise:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court” means the circuit court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Crisis stabilization care” means a level of care that is less restrictive and intense than care provided in a mental health treatment facility, that includes a broad range of evaluation and treatment services provided within a highly structured setting or locked residential setting, and that is intended for inmates who are experiencing acute emotional distress and who cannot be adequately evaluated and treated in a transitional care unit or infirmary isolation management room. Such treatment is also more intense than treatment provided in a transitional care unit and is devoted principally toward rapid stabilization of acute symptoms and conditions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Corrections.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the Director for Mental Health Services of the Department of Corrections or his or her designee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“In immediate need of care and treatment” means that an inmate is apparently mentally ill and is not able to be appropriately cared for in the institution where he or she is confined and that, but for being isolated in a more restrictive and secure housing environment, because of the apparent mental illness:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate is demonstrating a refusal to care for himself or herself and without immediate treatment intervention is likely to continue to refuse to care for himself or herself, and such refusal poses an immediate, real, and present threat of substantial harm to his or her well-being; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is an immediate, real, and present threat that the inmate will inflict serious bodily harm on himself or herself or another person, as evidenced by recent behavior involving causing, attempting, or threatening such harm;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate is unable to determine for himself or herself whether placement is necessary; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All available less restrictive treatment alternatives that would offer an opportunity for improvement of the inmate’s condition have been clinically determined to be inappropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“In need of care and treatment” means that an inmate has a mental illness for which inpatient services in a mental health treatment facility are necessary and that, but for being isolated in a more restrictive and secure housing environment, because of the mental illness:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate is demonstrating a refusal to care for himself or herself and without treatment is likely to continue to refuse to care for himself or herself, and such refusal poses a real and present threat of substantial harm to his or her well-being; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a substantial likelihood that in the near future the inmate will inflict serious bodily harm on himself or herself or another person, as evidenced by recent behavior causing, attempting, or threatening such harm;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate is unable to determine for himself or herself whether placement is necessary; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All available less restrictive treatment alternatives that would offer an opportunity for improvement of the inmate’s condition have been clinically determined to be inappropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Inmate” means any person committed to the custody of the Department of Corrections.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mental health treatment facility” means any extended treatment or hospitalization-level unit within the corrections system which the Assistant Secretary for Health Services of the department specifically designates by rule to provide acute psychiatric care and which may include involuntary treatment and therapeutic intervention in contrast to less intensive levels of care such as outpatient mental health care, transitional mental health care, or crisis stabilization care.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mentally ill” means an impairment of the mental or emotional processes, of the ability to exercise conscious control of one’s actions, or of the ability to perceive or understand reality, which impairment substantially interferes with a person’s ability to meet the ordinary demands of living, regardless of etiology, except that, for the purposes of transfer of an inmate to a mental health treatment facility, the term does not include retardation or developmental disability as defined in chapter 393, simple intoxication, or conditions manifested only by antisocial behavior or substance abuse addiction. However, an individual who is mentally retarded or developmentally disabled may also have a mental illness.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Psychiatrist” means a medical practitioner licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459 who has primarily diagnosed and treated nervous and mental disorders for a period of not less than 3 years inclusive of psychiatric residency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Psychological professional” means a behavioral practitioner who has an approved doctoral degree in psychology as defined in s. 490.003(3)(b) and is employed by the department or who is licensed as a psychologist pursuant to chapter 490.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secretary” means the Secretary of Corrections.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transitional mental health care” means a level of care that is more intensive than outpatient care, but less intensive than crisis stabilization care, and is characterized by the provision of traditional mental health treatments such as group and individual therapy, activity therapy, recreational therapy, and psychotropic medications in the context of a structured residential setting. Transitional mental health care is indicated for a person with chronic or residual symptomatology who does not require crisis stabilization care or acute psychiatric care, but whose impairment in functioning nevertheless renders him or her incapable of adjusting satisfactorily within the general inmate population.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Warden” means the warden of a state corrections facility or his or her designee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 82-224; s. 29, ch. 84-361; s. 26, ch. 91-225; s. 3, ch. 96-422; s. 1859, ch. 97-102; s. 19, ch. 2000-161; s. 11, ch. 2008-250; s. 13, ch. 2010-64.</History>
</Section>