<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.6035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dispute resolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority and the Assistant Secretary for Health Services shall attempt to expeditiously resolve any disputes arising between the authority and the department regarding the physical and mental health care of inmates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the authority and the Assistant Secretary for Health Services are unable to resolve a dispute regarding inmate physical or mental health care, the authority may submit a written notice to the Assistant Secretary for Health Services, setting forth each issue in controversy and the position of the authority. The Assistant Secretary for Health Services shall respond to the authority within 30 days after receipt of such written notice. The authority shall place the assistant secretary’s response on the agenda of the next regularly scheduled meeting of the authority. If the dispute remains unresolved, the authority may submit a written report to the secretary detailing the authority’s objections. The Assistant Secretary for Health Services shall submit a written report setting forth his or her position to the secretary on the issue or issues raised by the authority within 5 working days after receipt of the submission by the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secretary shall review any disputes between the authority and the Assistant Secretary for Health Services, and shall provide written notice to the authority of his or her decision regarding such disputes within 40 days after the date when the authority provides written notice of the dispute to the secretary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, at the end of the 40-day period, no resolution has been reached, the authority is authorized to appeal to the Administration Commission for a review and resolution of the dispute between the department and the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority, within 30 days after receiving written notice of the action of the secretary or, if no response is received, within 30 days after the secretary’s response is due pursuant to subsection (3), may file an appeal by petition to the Administration Commission, filed with the Secretary of the Administration Commission. The petition shall set forth the issues in controversy between the authority and the department, in the form and manner prescribed by the Administration Commission, and shall contain the reasons for the appeal. The department has 5 days after delivery of a copy of any such petition to file its reply with the Secretary of the Administration Commission, and the department shall also deliver a copy of its reply to the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issues which may be raised by the authority on appeal to the Administration Commission are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adoption or implementation by the department of a health care standard which does not conform to the standard of care generally accepted in the professional health community at large.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the department to comply with an adopted health care standard.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to timely file a corrective action plan regarding all deficiencies which are determined by the authority to exist at an institution, as required pursuant to s. 945.6031.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to implement a corrective action plan filed pursuant to s. 945.6031.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after receipt of a petition from the authority, the Secretary of the Administration Commission, or his or her designee, shall conduct an informal hearing to consider the matters presented in the petition and the reply, and after the informal hearing shall promptly submit a report of the findings and recommendations to the Administration Commission. Within 30 days after the informal hearing, the Administration Commission shall approve either the position of the authority or that of the department. If the position of the authority is approved, the Administration Commission shall set forth whatever remedial measures it deems appropriate and the department shall implement such remedial measures. The decision of the Administration Commission is final and binding on the authority and the department and shall not be subject to appeal pursuant to s. 120.68.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 86-183; s. 1, ch. 87-50; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 92-47; s. 1664, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>