<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.603" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the authority is to assist in the delivery of health care services for inmates in the Department of Corrections by advising the Secretary of Corrections on the professional conduct of primary, convalescent, dental, and mental health care and the management of costs consistent with quality care, by advising the Governor and the Legislature on the status of the Department of Corrections’ health care delivery system, and by assuring that adequate standards of physical and mental health care for inmates are maintained at all Department of Corrections institutions. For this purpose, the authority has the authority to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and advise the Secretary of Corrections on cost containment measures the Department of Corrections could implement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and make recommendations regarding health care for the delivery of health care services including, but not limited to, acute hospital-based services and facilities, primary and tertiary care services, ancillary and clinical services, dental services, mental health services, intake and screening services, medical transportation services, and the use of nurse practitioner and physician assistant personnel to act as physician extenders as these relate to inmates in the Department of Corrections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and recommend to the Governor and the Legislature an annual budget for all or part of the operation of the State of Florida prison health care system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and advise the Secretary of Corrections on contracts between the Department of Corrections and third parties for quality management programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and advise the Secretary of Corrections on minimum standards needed to ensure that an adequate physical and mental health care delivery system is maintained by the Department of Corrections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and advise the Secretary of Corrections on the sufficiency, adequacy, and effectiveness of the Department of Corrections’ Office of Health Services’ quality management program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and advise the Secretary of Corrections on the projected medical needs of the inmate population and the types of programs and resources required to meet such needs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and advise the Secretary of Corrections on the adequacy of preservice, inservice, and continuing medical education programs for all health care personnel and, if necessary, recommend changes to such programs within the Department of Corrections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify and recommend to the Secretary of Corrections the professional incentives required to attract and retain qualified professional health care staff within the prison health care system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate the development of prospective payment arrangements as described in s. 408.50 when appropriate for the acquisition of inmate health care services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review the Department of Corrections’ health services plan and advise the Secretary of Corrections on its implementation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue and be sued in its own name and plead and be impleaded.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make and execute agreements of lease, contracts, deeds, mortgages, notes, and other instruments necessary or convenient in the exercise of its powers and functions under this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ or contract with health care providers, medical personnel, management consultants, consulting engineers, architects, surveyors, attorneys, accountants, financial experts, and such other employees, entities, or agents as may be necessary in its judgment to carry out the mandates of the Correctional Medical Authority and fix their compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the Legislature such performance and financial audits of the Office of Health Services in the Department of Corrections as the authority considers advisable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 86-183; s. 1, ch. 87-50; s. 86, ch. 88-122; s. 14, ch. 89-531; s. 2, ch. 90-83; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 105, ch. 92-33; s. 2, ch. 92-47; s. 17, ch. 96-312; s. 117, ch. 97-237.</History></Section>