<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.36" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemption from health testing regulations for law enforcement personnel conducting drug tests on inmates and releasees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer, state or county probation officer, or employee of the Department of Corrections, who is certified by the Department of Corrections pursuant to subsection (2), is exempt from part I of chapter 483, for the limited purpose of administering a urine screen drug test to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons during incarceration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons released as a condition of probation for either a felony or misdemeanor;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons released as a condition of community control;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons released as a condition of conditional release;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons released as a condition of parole;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons released as a condition of provisional release;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons released as a condition of pretrial release; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons released as a condition of control release.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall develop a procedure for certification of any law enforcement officer, state or county probation officer, or employee of the Department of Corrections to perform a urine screen drug test on the persons specified in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-205; s. 79, ch. 95-211.</History></Section>