<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.6036" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department fails to substantially comply with the dispute resolution decision of the Administration Commission or fails to implement required remedial action within 45 days after such decision or within the time period set by the Administration Commission, whichever period is longer, the authority is authorized to petition the Circuit Court in Leon County for an order requiring the department to comply. For the purposes of this section, “substantial compliance” means a firm effort to comply fully with the decision without omitting any essential part, and that any omission consists solely of an unimportant defect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the authority fails to initiate a circuit court proceeding pursuant to this section, an inmate has the right to file a verified petition with the authority requesting that such a proceeding be initiated. The petition shall set forth with particularity the manner in which the department has failed to implement the decision of the Administration Commission, including any required remedial actions. The authority has 45 days after receipt of a verified petition to either initiate an action in circuit court pursuant to this section or advise the inmate in writing of the reason such an action will not be initiated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after service of the written decision of the authority setting forth its reason why an action will not be initiated by the authority pursuant to this section, an inmate may initiate an appropriate proceeding in the Circuit Court in Leon County to require the department to substantially comply with the decision of the Administration Commission.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 92-47.</History></Section>