<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inmate welfare and employee benefit trust funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INMATE PURCHASES; DEPARTMENT OF CORRECTIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From the net proceeds from operating inmate canteens, vending machines used primarily by inmates and visitors, hobby shops, and other such facilities must be deposited in the General Revenue Fund; however, funds necessary to purchase items for resale at inmate canteens and vending machines must be deposited into local bank accounts designated by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All proceeds from contracted telephone commissions must be deposited in the General Revenue Fund. The department shall develop and update, as necessary, administrative procedures to verify that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracted telephone companies accurately record and report all telephone calls made by inmates incarcerated in correctional facilities under the department’s jurisdiction;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons who accept collect calls from inmates are charged the contracted rate; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department receives the contracted telephone commissions.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any funds that may be assigned by inmates or donated to the department by the general public or an inmate service organization must be deposited in the General Revenue Fund; however, the department shall not accept any donation from, or on behalf of, any individual inmate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All proceeds from the following sources must be deposited in the General Revenue Fund:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The confiscation and liquidation of any contraband found upon, or in the possession of, any inmate;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary fines imposed against inmates;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forfeitures of inmate earnings; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unexpended balances in individual inmate trust fund accounts of less than $1.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Items for resale at inmate canteens and vending machines maintained at the correctional facilities shall be priced comparatively with like items for retail sale at fair market prices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, inmates with sufficient balances in their individual inmate bank trust fund accounts, after all debts against the account are satisfied, shall be allowed to request a weekly draw of up to an amount set by the Secretary of Corrections, not to exceed $100, to be expended for personal use on canteen and vending machine items.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRIVATELY OPERATED INSTITUTIONS INMATE WELFARE TRUST FUND; PRIVATE CORRECTIONAL FACILITIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, privately operated institutions or private correctional facilities are those correctional facilities under contract with the department pursuant to chapter 944 or the Department of Management Services pursuant to chapter 957.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The net proceeds derived from inmate canteens, vending machines used primarily by inmates, telephone commissions, and similar sources at private correctional facilities shall be deposited in the Privately Operated Institutions Inmate Welfare Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds in the Privately Operated Institutions Inmate Welfare Trust Fund shall be expended only pursuant to legislative appropriation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services shall annually compile a report that documents Privately Operated Institutions Inmate Welfare Trust Fund receipts and expenditures at each private correctional facility. This report must specifically identify receipt sources and expenditures. The Department of Management Services shall compile this report for the prior fiscal year and shall submit the report by September 1 of each year to the chairs of the appropriate substantive and fiscal committees of the Senate and House of Representatives and to the Executive Office of the Governor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EMPLOYEE BENEFIT TRUST FUND; DEPARTMENT OF CORRECTIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may establish an Employee Benefit Trust Fund. Trust fund sources may be derived from any of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proceeds of vending machines, staff canteens, or other such services not intended for use by inmates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net proceeds of the recycling program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Donations, except for donations made by, or on behalf of, an individual inmate, and except for donations made by a person who provides, or seeks to provide, goods or services to the department under a contract or an agreement, individually or through a corporation or organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additional trust funds and grants which may become available.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds from the Employee Benefit Trust Fund may be used for employee appreciation programs and activities and to construct, operate, and maintain training and recreation facilities at correctional facilities for the exclusive use of department employees. Such facilities are the property of the department and must provide the maximum benefit to all interested employees, regardless of gender.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Employee Benefit Trust Fund shall be established as a separate and distinct set of accounts, which shall be maintained centrally by the department, overseen by the secretary, and subject to an annual audit by the department’s inspector general.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall maintain sufficient data to provide an annual report, upon request, to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Executive Office of the Governor on December 1 which lists the types of services provided using moneys in the trust fund and the allocations of funds spent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to administer this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-78; s. 10, ch. 85-288; s. 1, ch. 87-233; s. 5, ch. 94-273; s. 14, ch. 96-312; s. 1858, ch. 97-102; s. 3, ch. 98-388; s. 14, ch. 99-271; s. 4, ch. 2000-328; s. 1, ch. 2001-379; s. 1, ch. 2002-268; s. 10, ch. 2003-179; s. 9, ch. 2004-248; s. 3, ch. 2007-210.</History></Section>