<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.601" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Correctional Medical Authority; ss. 945.601-945.6035, definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Authority” means the State of Florida Correctional Medical Authority created in this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care provider” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A regional research hospital or research center which is authorized by law to provide hospital services in accordance with chapter 395, which has a contractual or operating arrangement with a regional school of medicine, and which is located at that regional school of medicine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity which has agreed to provide hospital services to inmates in the Department of Corrections; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity licensed to provide hospital services in accordance with chapter 395.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Project” means any structure, facility, machinery, equipment, or other property suitable for use by a health facility in connection with its operations or proposed operations, including, without limitation, real property therefor; a clinic, computer facility, dining hall, firefighting facility, fire prevention facility, long-term care facility, hospital, interns’ residence, laboratory, laundry, maintenance facility, nurses’ residence, office, parking area, pharmacy, recreational facility, research facility, storage facility, utility, or X-ray facility, or any combination of the foregoing; and other structure or facility related thereto or required or useful for health care purposes, the conducting of research, or the operation of a health facility, including a facility or structure essential or convenient for the orderly conduct of the health facility and other similar items necessary or convenient for the operation of a particular facility or structure in the manner for which its use is intended. “Project” does not include such items as fuel, supplies, or other items which are customarily deemed to result in a current operating charge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Quality management program” means to monitor and evaluate inmate health care and includes the following objectives:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assuring that all inmates receive appropriate and timely services in a safe environment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assuring systematic monitoring of the treatment environment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting in the reduction of professional and general liability risks.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enhancing efficient utilization of resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting in credential review and privilege delineation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enhancing the identification of continuing educational needs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitating the identification of strengths, weaknesses, and opportunities for improvement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilitating the coordination and integration of information systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assuring the resolution of identified problems.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Real property” includes all lands, including buildings, structures, improvements, and fixtures thereon; any property of any nature appurtenant thereto or used in connection therewith; and every estate, interest, and right, legal or equitable, therein, including any such interest for a term of years.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 86-183; s. 1, ch. 87-50; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 15, ch. 96-312.</History></Section>