<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0945.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidential information.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law or in this section, the following records and information held by the Department of Corrections are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mental health, medical, or substance abuse records of an inmate or an offender.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preplea, pretrial intervention, and presentence or postsentence investigative records, except as provided in s. 960.001(1)(g).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information regarding a person in the federal witness protection program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parole Commission records which are confidential or exempt from public disclosure by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information which if released would jeopardize a person’s safety.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning a victim’s statement and identity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information which identifies an executioner, or any person prescribing, preparing, compounding, dispensing, or administering a lethal injection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records that are otherwise confidential or exempt from public disclosure by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The records and information specified in paragraphs (1)(a)-(h) may be released as follows unless expressly prohibited by federal law:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specified in paragraphs (1)(b), (d), and (f) to the Office of the Governor, the Legislature, the Parole Commission, the Department of Children and Family Services, a private correctional facility or program that operates under a contract, the Department of Legal Affairs, a state attorney, the court, or a law enforcement agency. A request for records or information pursuant to this paragraph need not be in writing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specified in paragraphs (1)(c), (e), and (h) to the Office of the Governor, the Legislature, the Parole Commission, the Department of Children and Family Services, a private correctional facility or program that operates under contract, the Department of Legal Affairs, a state attorney, the court, or a law enforcement agency. A request for records or information pursuant to this paragraph must be in writing and a statement provided demonstrating a need for the records or information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specified in paragraph (1)(b) to an attorney representing an inmate under sentence of death, except those portions of the records containing a victim’s statement or address, or the statement or address of a relative of the victim. A request for records of information pursuant to this paragraph must be in writing and a statement provided demonstrating a need for the records or information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specified in paragraph (1)(b) to a public defender representing a defendant, except those portions of the records containing a victim’s statement or address, or the statement or address of a relative of the victim. A request for records or information pursuant to this paragraph need not be in writing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specified in paragraph (1)(b) to state or local governmental agencies. A request for records or information pursuant to this paragraph must be in writing and a statement provided demonstrating a need for the records or information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specified in paragraph (1)(b) to a person conducting legitimate research. A request for records and information pursuant to this paragraph must be in writing, the person requesting the records or information must sign a confidentiality agreement, and the department must approve the request in writing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information specified in paragraph (1)(a) to the Department of Health and the county health department where an inmate plans to reside if he or she has tested positive for the presence of the antibody or antigen to human immunodeficiency virus infection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Records and information released under this subsection remain confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution when held by the receiving person or entity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Due to substantial concerns regarding institutional security and unreasonable and excessive demands on personnel and resources if an inmate or an offender has unlimited or routine access to records of the Department of Corrections, an inmate or an offender who is under the jurisdiction of the department may not have unrestricted access to the department’s records or to information contained in the department’s records. However, except as to another inmate’s or offender’s records, the department may permit limited access to its records if an inmate or an offender makes a written request and demonstrates an exceptional need for information contained in the department’s records and the information is otherwise unavailable. Exceptional circumstances include, but are not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate or offender requests documentation to resolve a conflict between the inmate’s court documentation and the commitment papers or court orders received by the department regarding the inmate or offender.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate’s or offender’s release is forthcoming and a prospective employer requests, in writing, documentation of the inmate’s or offender’s work performance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate or offender needs information concerning the amount of victim restitution paid during the inmate’s or offender’s incarceration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requested records contain information required to process an application or claim by the inmate or offender with the Internal Revenue Service, the Social Security Administration, the Department of Economic Opportunity, or any other similar application or claim with a state agency or federal agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate or offender wishes to obtain the current address of a relative whose address is in the department’s records and the relative has not indicated a desire not to be contacted by the inmate or offender.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other similar circumstances that do not present a threat to the security, order, or rehabilitative objectives of the correctional system or to any person’s safety.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall adopt rules to prevent disclosure of confidential records or information to unauthorized persons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections and the Parole Commission shall mutually cooperate with respect to maintaining the confidentiality of records that are exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 57-213; s. 18, ch. 61-530; s. 1, ch. 65-453; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 24, ch. 74-112; s. 255, ch. 77-104; s. 87, ch. 79-3; s. 1, ch. 88-118; s. 56, ch. 88-122; s. 1, ch. 94-83; s. 448, ch. 96-406; s. 2, ch. 98-4; s. 314, ch. 99-8; s. 1, ch. 99-263; s. 2, ch. 2000-1; s. 3, ch. 2002-292; s. 3, ch. 2003-272; s. 43, ch. 2010-117; s. 446, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>