<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of employment, appointment, or separation; response by the correctional officer; duty of department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “commission” refers to the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to s. 943.139, the department shall immediately notify the commission in writing, on a form adopted by the commission, of the employment or appointment, or separation from employment or appointment, of any correctional officer. The department must maintain the form and submit, or electronically transmit, a copy of the form to the commission. “Separation from employment or appointment” includes any firing, termination, resignation, retirement, or voluntary or involuntary extended leave of absence of any correctional officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a case of separation from employment or appointment, the department shall execute and maintain an affidavit-of-separation form adopted by the commission, setting forth in detail the facts and reasons for such separation. A copy of the affidavit-of-separation form must be submitted, or electronically transmitted, to the commission. If the correctional officer is separated for failure to comply with s. 943.13, the notice must so specify. The affidavit must be executed under oath and constitutes an official statement within the purview of s. 837.06. The affidavit must include conspicuous language that intentional false execution of the affidavit constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree. Any correctional officer who has separated from employment or appointment must be permitted to respond to the separation, in writing, to the commission, setting forth the facts and reasons for the separation as the officer understands them.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before employing or appointing any correctional officer, the department must contact the commission to inquire as to the facts and reasons an officer became separated from any previous employing agency. The commission shall, upon request and without prejudice, provide to the department all information that is required under subsections (2) and (3) and that is in its possession.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An administrator of the department who discloses information pursuant to this section is immune from civil liability in accordance with the provisions of s. 768.095.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 96-312.</History></Section>