<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0945.73" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inmate training program operation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, subject to specific legislative appropriation, develop and implement training programs for eligible inmates which include, but are not limited to, marching drills, calisthenics, a rigid dress code, work assignments, physical training, training in decisionmaking and personal development, drug counseling, education, and rehabilitation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing criteria for placement in the training program and providing the requirements for successful completion of the program. Only inmates eligible for control release pursuant to s. 947.146 shall be permitted to participate in the training program. The rules shall further define the structured disciplinary program and allow for restrictions on general inmate population privileges.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inmate training program shall provide a short incarceration period of rigorous training to inmates who require a greater degree of supervision than is provided for those on community control or probation. The inmate training program is not intended to divert offenders away from probation or community control, but to divert them from long periods of incarceration when a short “shock” incarceration could produce the same deterrent effect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon an inmate’s completion of the inmate training program, the department shall submit a report to the releasing authority that describes the inmate’s performance. If the performance has been satisfactory, the releasing authority shall establish a release date which is within 30 days following program completion. As a condition of release, the inmate shall be placed on community supervision as provided in chapter 947, and shall be subject to the conditions established therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an inmate in the training program becomes unmanageable, the department may place the inmate in the general inmate population to complete the remainder of his or her sentence. Any period of time in which the inmate is unable to participate in the inmate training program activities may be excluded from the specified time requirements in the inmate training program. The portion of the sentence served prior to placement in the inmate training program shall not be counted toward program completion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall work cooperatively with the Control Release Authority, the Florida Parole Commission, or such other authority as may exist or be established in the future which is empowered by law to effect the release of an inmate who has successfully completed the requirements established by ss. 945.71-945.74.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide a special training program for staff selected to operate the inmate training program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 92-310; s. 1665, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>