<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0719.3026" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contracts for products and services; in writing; bids; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Associations with less than 100 units may opt out of the provisions of this section if two-thirds of the unit owners vote to do so, which opt-out may be accomplished by a proxy specifically setting forth the exception from this section.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All contracts as further described herein or any contract that is not to be fully performed within 1 year after the making thereof, for the purchase, lease, or renting of materials or equipment to be used by the association in accomplishing its purposes under this chapter, and all contracts for the provision of services, shall be in writing. If a contract for the purchase, lease, or renting of materials or equipment, or for the provision of services, requires payment by the association in an amount which in the aggregate exceeds 5 percent of the association’s budget, including reserves, the association shall obtain competitive bids for the materials, equipment, or services. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to require the association to accept the lowest bid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the foregoing, contracts with employees of the association, and contracts for attorney, accountant, architect, community association manager, timeshare management firm, engineering, and landscape architect services shall not be subject to the provisions of this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contract executed before January 1, 1992, and any renewal thereof, is not subject to the competitive bid requirements of this section. If a contract was awarded under the competitive bid procedures of this section, any renewal of that contract is not subject to such competitive bid requirements if the contract contains a provision that allows the board to cancel the contract on 30 days’ notice. Materials, equipment, or services provided to a cooperative pursuant to a local government franchise agreement by a franchise holder are not subject to the competitive bid requirement. A contract with a manager, if made by a competitive bid, may be made for up to 3 years. A condominium whose declaration or bylaws provides for competitive bidding for services may operate under the provisions of that declaration or bylaws in lieu of this section if those provisions are not less stringent than the requirements of this section.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not limit the ability of an association to obtain needed products and services in an emergency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply if the business entity with which the association desires to enter into a contract is the only source of supply within the county serving the association.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 92-49; s. 4, ch. 2000-302.</History></Section>