<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0719.303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obligations of owners.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each unit owner, each tenant and other invitee, and each association shall be governed by, and shall comply with the provisions of, this chapter, the cooperative documents, the documents creating the association, and the association bylaws, and the provisions thereof shall be deemed expressly incorporated into any lease of a unit. Actions for damages or for injunctive relief, or both, for failure to comply with these provisions may be brought by the association or by a unit owner against:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit owner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directors designated by the developer, for actions taken by them prior to the time control of the association is assumed by unit owners other than the developer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any director who willfully and knowingly fails to comply with these provisions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any tenant leasing a unit, and any other invitee occupying a unit.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The prevailing party in any such action or in any action in which the purchaser claims a right of voidability based upon contractual provisions as required in s. 719.503(1)(a) is entitled to recover reasonable attorney’s fees. A unit owner prevailing in an action between the association and the unit owner under this section, in addition to recovering his or her reasonable attorney’s fees, may recover additional amounts as determined by the court to be necessary to reimburse the unit owner for his or her share of assessments levied by the association to fund its expenses of the litigation. This relief does not exclude other remedies provided by law. Actions arising under this subsection shall not be deemed to be actions for specific performance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provision of this chapter may not be waived if the waiver would adversely affect the rights of a unit owner or the purpose of the provision, except that unit owners or members of a board of administration may waive notice of specific meetings in writing if provided by the bylaws. Any instrument given in writing by the unit owner or purchaser to an escrow agent may be relied upon by an escrow agent, whether or not such instruction and the payment of funds thereunder might constitute a waiver of any provision of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association may levy reasonable fines for failure of the unit owner or the unit’s occupant, licensee, or invitee to comply with any provision of the cooperative documents or reasonable rules of the association. A fine may not become a lien against a unit. A fine may be levied on the basis of each day of a continuing violation, with a single notice and opportunity for hearing. However, the fine may not exceed $100 per violation, or $1,000 in the aggregate.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An association may suspend, for a reasonable period of time, the right of a unit owner, or a unit owner’s tenant, guest, or invitee, to use the common elements, common facilities, or any other association property for failure to comply with any provision of the cooperative documents or reasonable rules of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fine or suspension may not be imposed except after giving reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing to the unit owner and, if applicable, the unit’s licensee or invitee. The hearing must be held before a committee of other unit owners. If the committee does not agree with the fine or suspension, it may not be imposed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a unit owner is more than 90 days delinquent in paying a monetary obligation due to the association, the association may suspend the right of the unit owner or the unit’s occupant, licensee, or invitee to use common elements, common facilities, or any other association property until the monetary obligation is paid in full. This subsection does not apply to limited common elements intended to be used only by that unit, common elements needed to access the unit, utility services provided to the unit, parking spaces, or elevators. The notice and hearing requirements under subsection (3) do not apply to suspensions imposed under this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An association may suspend the voting rights of a unit or member due to nonpayment of any monetary obligation due to the association which is more than 90 days delinquent. A voting interest or consent right allocated to a unit or member which has been suspended by the association may not be counted towards the total number of voting interests for any purpose, including, but not limited to, the number of voting interests necessary to constitute a quorum, the number of voting interests required to conduct an election, or the number of voting interests required to approve an action under this chapter or pursuant to the cooperative documents, articles of incorporation, or bylaws. The suspension ends upon full payment of all obligations currently due or overdue the association. The notice and hearing requirements under subsection (3) do not apply to a suspension imposed under this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All suspensions imposed pursuant to subsection (4) or subsection (5) must be approved at a properly noticed board meeting. Upon approval, the association must notify the unit owner and, if applicable, the unit’s occupant, licensee, or invitee by mail or hand delivery.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 76-222; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 28, ch. 86-175; s. 6, ch. 87-117; s. 27, ch. 92-49; s. 882, ch. 97-102; s. 15, ch. 2003-14; s. 15, ch. 2011-196.</History></Section>