<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0719.105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperative parcels; appurtenances; possession and enjoyment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each cooperative parcel has, as appurtenances thereto:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of membership, ownership of shares, or other interest in the association with the full voting rights appertaining thereto. Such evidence must include a legal description of each dwelling unit and must be recorded in the office of the clerk of the circuit court as required by s. 201.02(3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An undivided share in the assets of the association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exclusive right to use that portion of the common areas as may be provided by the cooperative documents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An undivided share in the common surplus attributable to the unit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other appurtenances provided for in the cooperative documents.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each unit owner is entitled to the exclusive possession of his or her unit. The unit owner is entitled to use the common areas in accordance with the purposes for which they are intended, but no use may hinder or encroach upon the rights of other unit owners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a unit is leased, the tenant has all use rights in the association property available for use generally by the unit owner and the unit owner does not have such rights except as a guest. This subsection does not interfere with the access rights of the unit owner as a landlord pursuant to chapter 83. The association may adopt rules to prohibit dual usage by a unit owner and a tenant of cooperative property.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 76-222; s. 13, ch. 86-175; s. 11, ch. 92-32; s. 19, ch. 92-49; s. 876, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>