<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0719.114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Separate taxation of cooperative parcels; survival of contractual provisions after tax sale.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ad valorem taxes and special assessments by taxing authorities shall be assessed against the cooperative parcels and not upon the cooperative property as a whole. No ad valorem tax or special assessment may be separately assessed against common areas if the common areas are owned by the cooperative association or are jointly owned by the owners of the cooperative parcels. Each cooperative parcel shall be separately assessed for ad valorem taxes and special assessments as a single parcel. The property appraiser must be provided the necessary documents, as evidenced in the official records of the clerk of the circuit court of the county, to make a determination as to the ownership of a cooperative parcel for assessment and homestead tax exemption purposes. The taxes and special assessments levied against each cooperative parcel shall constitute a lien only upon the cooperative parcel assessed and upon no other portion of the cooperative property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All contractual provisions relating to a cooperative parcel which has been sold for taxes or special assessments survive and are enforceable after issuance of a tax deed or master’s deed, upon foreclosure of an assessment, a certificate or lien, a tax deed, tax certificate, or tax lien, to the same extent that they would be enforceable against a voluntary grantee of the title immediately prior to the delivery of the tax deed, master’s deed, or clerk’s certificate of title as provided in s. 197.573.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperative property divided into timeshare estates shall be assessed for purposes of ad valorem taxes and special assessments as provided in s. 192.037.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 86-175; s. 12, ch. 92-32; s. 3, ch. 2000-302.</History></Section>