<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0719.608" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of intended conversion; time of delivery; content.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to or simultaneous with the first offering of individual units to any person, each developer shall deliver a notice of intended conversion to all tenants of the existing improvements being converted to residential cooperative. All such notices shall be given within a 72-hour period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each notice of intended conversion shall be dated and in writing. The notice shall contain the following statement, with the phrases of the following statement which appear in upper case printed in conspicuous type:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">These apartments are being converted to cooperative by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of developer)</Directions>, the developer.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">YOU MAY REMAIN AS A RESIDENT UNTIL THE EXPIRATION OF YOUR RENTAL AGREEMENT. FURTHER, YOU MAY EXTEND YOUR RENTAL AGREEMENT AS FOLLOWS:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If you have continuously been a resident of these apartments during the last 180 days and your rental agreement expires during the next 270 days, you may extend your rental agreement for up to 270 days after the date of this notice.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If you have not been a continuous resident of these apartments for the last 180 days and your rental agreement expires during the next 180 days, you may extend your rental agreement for up to 180 days after the date of this notice.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IN ORDER FOR YOU TO EXTEND YOUR RENTAL AGREEMENT, YOU MUST GIVE THE DEVELOPER WRITTEN NOTICE WITHIN 45 DAYS AFTER THE DATE OF THIS NOTICE.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IF YOUR RENTAL AGREEMENT EXPIRES IN THE NEXT 45 DAYS, you may extend your rental agreement for up to 45 days after the date of this notice while you decide whether to extend your rental agreement as explained above. To do so, you must notify the developer in writing. You will then have the full 45 days to decide whether to extend your rental agreement as explained above.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the extension of your rental agreement you will be charged the same rent that you are now paying.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">YOU MAY CANCEL YOUR RENTAL AGREEMENT AND ANY EXTENSION OF THE RENTAL AGREEMENT AS FOLLOWS:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If your rental agreement began or was extended or renewed after May 1, 1980, and your rental agreement, including extensions and renewals, has an unexpired term of 180 days or less, you may cancel your rental agreement upon 30 days’ written notice and move. Also, upon 30 days’ written notice, you may cancel any extension of the rental agreement.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If your rental agreement was not begun or was not extended or renewed after May 1, 1980, you may not cancel the rental agreement without the consent of the developer. If your rental agreement, including extensions and renewals, has an unexpired term of 180 days or less, you may, however, upon 30 days’ written notice cancel any extension of the rental agreement.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All notices must be given in writing and sent by mail, return receipt requested, or delivered in person to the developer at this address: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name and address of developer)</Directions>.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If you have continuously been a resident of these apartments during the last 180 days:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">You have the right to purchase your apartment and will have 45 days to decide whether to purchase. If you do not buy the unit at that price and the unit is later offered at a lower price, you will have the opportunity to buy the unit at the lower price. However, in all events your right to purchase the unit ends when the rental agreement or any extension of the rental agreement ends or when you waive this right in writing.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days you will be provided purchase information relating to your apartment, including the price of your unit and the condition of the building. If you do not receive this information within 90 days, your rental agreement and any extension will be extended 1 day for each day over 90 days until you are given the purchase information. If you do not want this rental agreement extension, you must notify the developer in writing.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro" SpaceBelow="true">If you have any questions regarding this conversion or the Cooperative Act, you may contact the developer or the state agency which regulates cooperatives: The Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Tallahassee address and telephone number of division)</Directions>.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a developer offers tenants an optional tenant relocation payment pursuant to s. 719.606(4), the notice of intended conversion shall contain a statement substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">If you have been a continuous resident of these apartments for the last 180 days and your lease expires during the next 180 days, you may extend your rental agreement for up to 270 days, or you may extend your rental agreement for up to 180 days and receive a cash payment at least equal to 1 month’s rent. You must make your decision and inform the developer in writing within 45 days after the date of this notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro" SpaceBelow="true">When the rental agreement extension provisions of s. 719.606(6) are applicable to a conversion, subparagraphs 1.a. and b. of the notice of intended conversion shall read as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">YOU MAY REMAIN AS A RESIDENT UNTIL THE EXPIRATION OF YOUR RENTAL AGREEMENT. FURTHER, YOU MAY EXTEND YOUR RENTAL AGREEMENT AS FOLLOWS:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If you have continuously been a resident of these apartments during the last 180 days and your rental agreement expires during the next 360 days, you may extend your rental agreement for up to 360 days after the date of this notice.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro" SpaceBelow="true">If you have not been a continuous resident of these apartments for the last 180 days and your rental agreement expires during the next 270 days, you may extend your rental agreement for up to 270 days after the date of this notice.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of intended conversion may not be waived by a tenant unless the tenant’s lease conspicuously states that the building is to be converted and the other tenants residing in the building have previously received a notice of intended conversion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the request of a developer and payment of a fee prescribed by the rules of the division not to exceed $50, the division may verify to a developer that a notice complies with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to delivering a notice of intended conversion to tenants of existing improvements being converted to a residential cooperative, each developer shall file with the division a copy of the notice of intended conversion. Upon filing, each developer shall pay to the division a filing fee of $100.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 80-3; s. 15, ch. 85-60; s. 38, ch. 86-175; s. 32, ch. 92-49; s. 61, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>