<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0287.0595" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pollution response action contracts; department rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection shall establish, by adopting administrative rules as provided in chapter 120:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for determining the qualifications of responsible potential vendors prior to advertisement for and receipt of bids, proposals, or replies for pollution response action contracts, including procedures for the rejection of unqualified vendors. Response actions are those activities described in s. 376.301(39).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for awarding such contracts to the lowest responsible and responsive vendor as well as procedures to be followed in cases in which the department declares a valid emergency to exist which would necessitate the waiver of the rules governing the awarding of such contracts to the lowest responsible and responsive vendor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures governing payment of contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures to govern negotiations for contracts, modifications to contract documents, and terms and conditions of contracts.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In adopting rules under this section, the Department of Environmental Protection shall follow the criteria applicable to the department’s contracting to the maximum extent possible, consistent with the goals and purposes of ss. 376.307 and 376.3071.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bid submitted under this section shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until a selection is made and a contract signed or until bids are no longer under active consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to contracts which must be negotiated under s. 287.055.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-337; s. 9, ch. 87-374; s. 8, ch. 89-188; s. 2, ch. 89-377; s. 3, ch. 90-54; s. 103, ch. 90-360; s. 253, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 1, ch. 94-355; s. 114, ch. 94-356; s. 86, ch. 95-143; s. 18, ch. 96-263; s. 14, ch. 96-277; s. 14, ch. 96-321; s. 133, ch. 96-406; s. 15, ch. 98-189; s. 55, ch. 99-13; s. 19, ch. 2002-207; s. 3, ch. 2005-50.</History></Section>