<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0287.087" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preference to businesses with drug-free workplace programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever two or more bids, proposals, or replies that are equal with respect to price, quality, and service are received by the state or by any political subdivision for the procurement of commodities or contractual services, a bid, proposal, or reply received from a business that certifies that it has implemented a drug-free workplace program shall be given preference in the award process. In order to have a drug-free workplace program, a business shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publish a statement notifying employees that the unlawful manufacture, distribution, dispensing, possession, or use of a controlled substance is prohibited in the workplace and specifying the actions that will be taken against employees for violations of such prohibition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform employees about the dangers of drug abuse in the workplace, the business’s policy of maintaining a drug-free workplace, any available drug counseling, rehabilitation, and employee assistance programs, and the penalties that may be imposed upon employees for drug abuse violations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give each employee engaged in providing the commodities or contractual services that are under bid a copy of the statement specified in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the statement specified in subsection (1), notify the employees that, as a condition of working on the commodities or contractual services that are under bid, the employee will abide by the terms of the statement and will notify the employer of any conviction of, or plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, any violation of chapter 893 or of any controlled substance law of the United States or any state, for a violation occurring in the workplace no later than 5 days after such conviction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose a sanction on, or require the satisfactory participation in a drug abuse assistance or rehabilitation program if such is available in the employee’s community by, any employee who is so convicted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make a good faith effort to continue to maintain a drug-free workplace through implementation of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 90-268; s. 24, ch. 2002-207.</History></Section>