<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0287.0585" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Late payments by contractors to subcontractors and suppliers; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a contractor receives from a state agency any payment for contractual services, commodities, supplies, or construction contracts, except those construction contracts subject to the provisions of chapter 339, the contractor shall pay such moneys received to each subcontractor and supplier in proportion to the percentage of work completed by each subcontractor and supplier at the time of receipt of the payment. If the contractor receives less than full payment, then the contractor shall be required to disburse only the funds received on a pro rata basis with the contractor, subcontractors, and suppliers, each receiving a prorated portion based on the amount due on the payment. If the contractor without reasonable cause fails to make payments required by this section to subcontractors and suppliers within 7 working days after the receipt by the contractor of full or partial payment, the contractor shall pay to the subcontractors and suppliers a penalty in the amount of one-half of 1 percent of the amount due, per day, from the expiration of the period allowed herein for payment. Such penalty shall be in addition to actual payments owed and shall not exceed 15 percent of the outstanding balance due. In addition to other fines or penalties, a person found not in compliance with any provision of this subsection may be ordered by the court to make restitution for attorney’s fees and all related costs to the aggrieved party or the Department of Legal Affairs when it provides legal assistance pursuant to this section. The Department of Legal Affairs may provide legal assistance to subcontractors or vendors in proceedings brought against contractors under the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply when the contract between the contractor and subcontractors or subvendors provides otherwise, or when payments under the contract are otherwise governed by ss. 255.0705-255.078.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 85-104; s. 2, ch. 89-200; s. 9, ch. 91-162; s. 14, ch. 2005-230.</History></Section>