<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0287.083" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purchase of commodities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the policy of the state for the Department of Management Services to consider the life-cycle cost of commodities purchased by the state, when applicable and feasible as determined by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Definitions.<EmDash />For the purpose of this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Major energy-consuming product” means any article so designated by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Energy-efficiency standard” means a performance standard which prescribes the relationship of the energy use of a product to its useful output of services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to establish by rule energy-efficiency standards for major energy-consuming products.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When federal energy-efficiency standards exist, the department shall, when feasible, adopt standards at least as stringent as the federal standards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When energy-efficiency standards are established, life-cycle costs shall be used by the department in contracting for major energy-consuming products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the life-cycle cost, the department may consider the acquisition cost of the product; the energy consumption and the projected cost of energy over the useful life of the product; and the anticipated trade-in, resale, or salvage value of the product.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 77-316; s. 25, ch. 81-169; s. 85, ch. 98-279.</History></Section>