<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0287.0822" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Beef and pork; prohibition on purchase; bid specifications; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fresh or frozen beef or pork that has not been inspected by the United States Department of Agriculture or by another state’s inspection program which has been approved by the United States Department of Agriculture shall not be purchased, or caused to be purchased, by any agency of the state or of any municipality, political subdivision, school district, or special district for consumption in this state or for distribution for consumption in this state. Solicitations issued by any agency of the state or of any municipality, political subdivision, school district, or special district for the purchase of fresh or frozen beef or pork must specify that only beef or pork inspected and passed by either the United States Department of Agriculture or by another state’s inspection program which has been approved by the United States Department of Agriculture will be accepted. The supplier or vendor shall certify on the invoice that the fresh or frozen beef or pork or imported beef or pork supplied is either domestic or complies with this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All solicitations for purchase of fresh or frozen meats of any kind by any agency of the state or of any municipality, political subdivision, school district, or special district using state or local funds shall include the words: “ ‘All American’ and ‘Genuine Florida’ meats or meat products shall be granted preference as allowed by Section 287.082, Florida Statutes.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly violates or causes to be violated the provisions of this section shall be personally liable to the affected public agency for any funds spent in violation of the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-61; s. 1, ch. 78-71; s. 2, ch. 87-400; s. 62, ch. 90-321; s. 46, ch. 94-180; s. 3, ch. 95-168; s. 29, ch. 2000-308; s. 22, ch. 2002-207.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 585.3401; s. 585.89.</Text></Note></Section>