<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0287.155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Motor vehicles; purchase by Department of Children and Family Services, Agency for Persons with Disabilities, Department of Health, Department of Juvenile Justice, and Department of Corrections.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, the Department of Health, the Department of Juvenile Justice, and the Department of Corrections may, subject to the approval of the Department of Management Services, purchase automobiles, trucks, tractors, and other automotive equipment for the use of institutions or developmental disabilities centers under the management of the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, the Department of Health, and the Department of Corrections, and for the use of residential facilities managed or contracted by the Department of Juvenile Justice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall, prior to purchasing motor vehicles, seek to procure the motor vehicles from those vehicles renovated pursuant to correctional work programs of the Department of Corrections, and for the use of residential facilities managed or contracted by the Department of Juvenile Justice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health is authorized, subject to the approval of the Department of Management Services, to purchase automobiles, trucks, and other automotive equipment for use by county health departments.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12A, ch. 20980, 1941; s. 7, ch. 22071, 1943; s. 6, ch. 22827, 1945; s. 6, ch. 23915, 1947; s. 5, ch. 25370, 1949; s. 6, ch. 26859, s. 2, ch. 26971, 1951; s. 2, ch. 63-204; ss. 2, 3, ch. 67-371; ss. 15, 19, 22, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 77-120; s. 1, ch. 77-300; s. 6, ch. 79-3; s. 262, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 4, ch. 95-430; s. 15, ch. 96-398; s. 12, ch. 96-420; s. 51, ch. 99-8; s. 6, ch. 99-397; s. 5, ch. 2006-227; s. 36, ch. 2007-217; s. 1, ch. 2008-244.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 116.161.</Text></Note></Section>