<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0211.3103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Levy of tax on severance of phosphate rock; rate, basis, and distribution of tax.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby levied an excise tax upon each person engaging in the business of severing phosphate rock from the soils or waters of this state for commercial use. The tax shall be collected, administered, and enforced by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax rate shall be $1.61 per ton severed, except for the time period beginning January 1, 2015, until December 31, 2022, when the tax rate shall be $1.80 per ton severed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The excise tax levied by this section applies to the total production of the producer during the taxable year, measured on the basis of bone-dry tons produced at the point of severance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The excise tax levied on the severance of phosphate rock is in addition to any ad valorem taxes levied upon the separately assessed mineral interest in the real property upon which the site of severance is located, or any other tax, permit, or license fee imposed by the state or its political subdivisions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax levied by this section shall be collected in the manner prescribed in s. 211.33.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1 of the 2011-2012 fiscal year, the proceeds of all taxes, interest, and penalties imposed under this section are exempt from the general revenue service charge provided in s. 215.20, and such proceeds shall be paid into the State Treasury as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund, 25.5 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the General Revenue Fund of the state, 35.7 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For payment to counties in proportion to the number of tons of phosphate rock produced from a phosphate rock matrix located within such political boundary, 12.8 percent. The department shall distribute this portion of the proceeds annually based on production information reported by the producers on the annual returns for the taxable year. Any such proceeds received by a county shall be used only for phosphate-related expenses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For payment to counties that have been designated as a rural area of critical economic concern pursuant to s. 288.0656 in proportion to the number of tons of phosphate rock produced from a phosphate rock matrix located within such political boundary, 10.0 percent. The department shall distribute this portion of the proceeds annually based on production information reported by the producers on the annual returns for the taxable year. Payments under this subparagraph shall be made to the counties unless the Legislature by special act creates a local authority to promote and direct the economic development of the county. If such authority exists, payments shall be made to that authority.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Trust Fund, 6.2 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Phosphate Research Trust Fund in the Division of Universities of the Department of Education, 6.2 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Minerals Trust Fund, 3.6 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), from January 1, 2015, until December 31, 2022, the proceeds of all taxes, interest, and penalties imposed under this section are exempt from the general revenue service charge provided in s. 215.20, and such proceeds shall be paid to the State Treasury as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Conservation and Recreation Lands Trust Fund, 22.8 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the General Revenue Fund of the state, 31.9 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For payment to counties pursuant to subparagraph (a)3., 11.5 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For payment to counties pursuant to subparagraph (a)4., 8.9 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Nonmandatory Land Reclamation Trust Fund, 16.1 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Phosphate Research Trust Fund in the Division of Universities of the Department of Education, 5.6 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the credit of the Minerals Trust Fund, 3.2 percent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, “phosphate-related expenses” means those expenses that provide for infrastructure or services in support of the phosphate industry, reclamation or restoration of phosphate lands, community infrastructure on such reclaimed lands, and similar expenses directly related to support of the industry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 81-35; s. 1, ch. 82-184; s. 9, ch. 84-330; s. 6, ch. 87-96; s. 4, ch. 91-305; s. 3, ch. 91-420; s. 3, ch. 94-197; s. 10, ch. 96-321; s. 24, ch. 2000-170; s. 2, ch. 2000-176; s. 22, ch. 2000-317; s. 11, ch. 2002-218; s. 1, ch. 2003-423; s. 18, ch. 2007-106; s. 20, ch. 2007-217; s. 2, ch. 2008-150; s. 3, ch. 2010-166; s. 5, ch. 2012-32.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 25, ch. 2012-32, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The executive director of the Department of Revenue is authorized, and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules under ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54(4), Florida Statutes, for the purpose of implementing this act.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) Notwithstanding any provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the date adopted and may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>