<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0211.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of law; books and records; powers of the department; refunds; enforcement provisions; confidentiality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall administer and enforce the provisions of this part and may prescribe the form and content of returns and reports and may adopt such rules as it deems necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state, county, or municipal agencies, boards, bureaus, departments, or districts shall cooperate with the department and shall furnish any information the department deems necessary, without cost to the department, for the purposes of administering, collecting, or enforcing any tax imposed under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person subject to the provisions of this part shall keep suitable books and records relating to the severance or production of taxable products in this state to enable the department to determine the amount of tax due under this part. Such books and records shall be preserved until the time within which the department may make an assessment with respect thereto has expired, as provided in s. 213.35.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the power to inspect or examine the books, records, or papers of any operator, producer, purchaser, royalty interest owner, taxpayer, or transporter of taxable products which are reasonably required for the purposes of this part and may require such person to testify under oath or affirmation or to answer competent questions touching upon such person’s business or production of taxable products in the state.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue subpoenas to compel third parties to testify or to produce records or other evidence held by them.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any duly authorized representative of the department may administer an oath or affirmation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person fails to comply with a request of the department for the inspection of records, fails to give testimony or respond to competent questions, or fails to comply with a subpoena, a circuit court having jurisdiction over such person may, upon application by the department, issue orders necessary to secure compliance.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All books and records required to be kept under this subsection shall be available for inspection by the department, upon written request, during normal business hours.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may audit or examine the books and records of persons subject to this part to determine whether returns have been properly filed and tax properly paid. An audit may be commenced for any month for which the power of the department to make an assessment of amounts due under this part is available. An audit shall be commenced by service of a written notice of intent to audit upon the taxpayer, either in person or by certified mail. The date of personal contact or the date of the notice shall govern the period subject to audit. If there is jeopardy to the revenue and jeopardy is asserted in or with an assessment, the department shall proceed in the manner specified for jeopardy assessment in s. 213.732.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may assess, with or without an audit, any deficiency resulting from nonpayment or underpayment of the tax, interest, or penalties imposed by this part. The department shall inform the taxpayer, by written notice, of the amount of any deficiency or overpayment revealed by an audit, including the tax, interest, or penalties due, and shall explain the basis for the determination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the power to make an assessment under this part based upon the best information available to it. The department may make an assessment based upon an estimate of amounts due under this part if the taxpayer fails to file a return, files a grossly incorrect or fraudulent return, or refuses to permit inspection of records. An assessment of the amounts due under this part shall be considered prima facie correct, and the taxpayer shall have the burden of showing any error in it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of a deficiency, the department shall issue its written notice to the taxpayer for the tax, penalties, or interest due. Full payment of the total amount assessed shall be made in the manner prescribed by the department in its notice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may credit or refund any overpayments of amounts due under this part which are revealed by an audit or for which a timely claim for refund has been properly filed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim for refund may be filed within the period specified in s. 215.26(2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claim for refund must be signed by the taxpayer or the taxpayer’s duly authorized representative, successor, or assigns and must include information the department requires to determine the correctness of the claim.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amounts due under this part shall remain a lien upon the property, assets, and effects of the taxpayer until paid or until collection thereof is barred under s. 95.091, and may be recovered by the department, on behalf of the state, by an action in any county where the property, assets, or effects of the taxpayer are located.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any tax imposed by this part becomes delinquent or is otherwise in jeopardy, the department may issue a warrant for the full amount due or estimated to be due, including the tax, penalties, interest, and costs of collection. The warrant shall be directed to each sheriff and may be recorded with the clerk of the circuit court in any county where the taxpayer’s property is located. Upon recording, the clerk of the circuit court shall execute the warrant in the same manner prescribed by law for executions upon judgments and shall be entitled to the same fees for this service. Upon payment of the warrant, the department shall satisfy the lien of record within 30 days. Thereafter, any interested person may compel the department to satisfy the lien of record.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the department deems it necessary, an alias tax execution may be issued. Each alias tax execution shall be so designated on its face and shall have the same force and effect as the original.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tax executions may be levied upon any third party who is in possession or control of any assets of a delinquent taxpayer or who is indebted to a delinquent taxpayer. Such tax executions shall have the force and effect of a writ of garnishment. The third party shall pay the debt or deliver the assets of the delinquent taxpayer to the department, and receipt by the department shall discharge the third party completely to the extent of the debt paid or assets surrendered to the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any tax execution becomes void, the department may cancel it of record and shall do so upon the request of any interested person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any employee of the department may be designated by the executive director to make and sign assessments, tax warrants, and satisfactions of tax warrants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any suit brought by the department against any person for violating this part shall be brought in circuit court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All returns and information filed with the department under this part are confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1), and such returns or information shall be protected from unauthorized disclosure as provided in s. 213.053 and shall be exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 86-178; s. 53, ch. 87-6; ss. 9, 28, ch. 88-119; s. 45, ch. 90-360; s. 11, ch. 92-315; s. 48, ch. 94-353; s. 59, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>