<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0211.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assessment upon escaped oil; claims against same.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any regular monthly report required from taxpayers by this chapter does not disclose the actual source of any oil taxable under this chapter, but does show such oil to have escaped from a well or wells and to have been recovered from streams, lakes, ravines, or other natural depression; it shall be the duty of the department to collect, in addition to the excise tax herein imposed, an additional amount equal to 12.5 percent of the gross value of such escaped oil. The department shall hold such additional collection in a special escrow account for a period of 12 months from the date of the collections, during which time any person or persons, who claim to be the rightful owner or owners of any royalty interest in the escaped oil, may present proper and satisfactory proof of such ownership to the department. If the department shall be satisfied as to the ownership of such escaped oil, then it shall pay to such claimant or claimants a proportionate part of such additional collection held in escrow, according to their proper interest or interests. No payment to any claimant shall be made, however, before it is approved by the Department of Legal Affairs or before it is ordered by any court having proper jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the lapse of 12 months from the date of any additional collection, if no claim or claims have been made to it, or to the balance remaining of it after the payment by the department of any claim or claims, the department shall distribute the additional collection or any balance of it in the same manner as is herein provided for the distribution of the tax imposed by this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 22784, 1945; s. 4, ch. 23883, 1947; ss. 11, 21, 35, ch. 69-106.</History></Section>