<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0856.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Open house parties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Definitions.<EmDash />As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alcoholic beverage” means distilled spirits and any beverage containing 0.5 percent or more alcohol by volume. The percentage of alcohol by volume shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of s. 561.01(4)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Control” means the authority or ability to regulate, direct, or dominate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Drug” means a controlled substance, as that term is defined in ss. 893.02(4) and 893.03.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Minor” means an individual not legally permitted by reason of age to possess alcoholic beverages pursuant to chapter 562.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Open house party” means a social gathering at a residence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual 18 years of age or older.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residence” means a home, apartment, condominium, or other dwelling unit.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person having control of any residence may not allow an open house party to take place at the residence if any alcoholic beverage or drug is possessed or consumed at the residence by any minor where the person knows that an alcoholic beverage or drug is in the possession of or being consumed by a minor at the residence and where the person fails to take reasonable steps to prevent the possession or consumption of the alcoholic beverage or drug.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not apply to the use of alcoholic beverages at legally protected religious observances or activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (2) commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. A person who violates subsection (2) a second or subsequent time commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a violation of subsection (2) causes or contributes to causing serious bodily injury, as defined in s. 316.1933, or death to the minor, or if the minor causes or contributes to causing serious bodily injury or death to another as a result of the minor’s consumption of alcohol or drugs at the open house party, the violation is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 5, 6, 7, ch. 88-196; ss. 64, 65, 66, 67, ch. 88-381; s. 45, ch. 91-110; s. 217, ch. 91-224; s. 103, ch. 97-264; s. 9, ch. 99-186; s. 19, ch. 2000-320; s. 1, ch. 2002-60; s. 9, ch. 2002-78; s. 1, ch. 2011-161.</History></Section>