<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0095.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitations other than for the recovery of real property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions other than for recovery of real property shall be commenced as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WITHIN TWENTY YEARS.<EmDash />An action on a judgment or decree of a court of record in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WITHIN FIVE YEARS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action on a judgment or decree of any court, not of record, of this state or any court of the United States, any other state or territory in the United States, or a foreign country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legal or equitable action on a contract, obligation, or liability founded on a written instrument, except for an action to enforce a claim against a payment bond, which shall be governed by the applicable provisions of paragraph (5)(e), s. 255.05(10), s. 337.18(1), or s. 713.23(1)(e).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action to foreclose a mortgage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action alleging a willful violation of s. 448.110.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (b), an action for breach of a property insurance contract, with the period running from the date of loss.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WITHIN FOUR YEARS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action founded on negligence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action relating to the determination of paternity, with the time running from the date the child reaches the age of majority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action founded on the design, planning, or construction of an improvement to real property, with the time running from the date of actual possession by the owner, the date of the issuance of a certificate of occupancy, the date of abandonment of construction if not completed, or the date of completion or termination of the contract between the professional engineer, registered architect, or licensed contractor and his or her employer, whichever date is latest; except that, when the action involves a latent defect, the time runs from the time the defect is discovered or should have been discovered with the exercise of due diligence. In any event, the action must be commenced within 10 years after the date of actual possession by the owner, the date of the issuance of a certificate of occupancy, the date of abandonment of construction if not completed, or the date of completion or termination of the contract between the professional engineer, registered architect, or licensed contractor and his or her employer, whichever date is latest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action to recover public money or property held by a public officer or employee, or former public officer or employee, and obtained during, or as a result of, his or her public office or employment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for injury to a person founded on the design, manufacture, distribution, or sale of personal property that is not permanently incorporated in an improvement to real property, including fixtures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action founded on a statutory liability.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for trespass on real property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for taking, detaining, or injuring personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action to recover specific personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legal or equitable action founded on fraud.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A legal or equitable action on a contract, obligation, or liability not founded on a written instrument, including an action for the sale and delivery of goods, wares, and merchandise, and on store accounts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action to rescind a contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for money paid to any governmental authority by mistake or inadvertence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for a statutory penalty or forfeiture.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for assault, battery, false arrest, malicious prosecution, malicious interference, false imprisonment, or any other intentional tort, except as provided in subsections (4), (5), and (7).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action not specifically provided for in these statutes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action alleging a violation, other than a willful violation, of s. 448.110.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WITHIN TWO YEARS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for professional malpractice, other than medical malpractice, whether founded on contract or tort; provided that the period of limitations shall run from the time the cause of action is discovered or should have been discovered with the exercise of due diligence. However, the limitation of actions herein for professional malpractice shall be limited to persons in privity with the professional.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for medical malpractice shall be commenced within 2 years from the time the incident giving rise to the action occurred or within 2 years from the time the incident is discovered, or should have been discovered with the exercise of due diligence; however, in no event shall the action be commenced later than 4 years from the date of the incident or occurrence out of which the cause of action accrued, except that this 4-year period shall not bar an action brought on behalf of a minor on or before the child’s eighth birthday. An “action for medical malpractice” is defined as a claim in tort or in contract for damages because of the death, injury, or monetary loss to any person arising out of any medical, dental, or surgical diagnosis, treatment, or care by any provider of health care. The limitation of actions within this subsection shall be limited to the health care provider and persons in privity with the provider of health care. In those actions covered by this paragraph in which it can be shown that fraud, concealment, or intentional misrepresentation of fact prevented the discovery of the injury the period of limitations is extended forward 2 years from the time that the injury is discovered or should have been discovered with the exercise of due diligence, but in no event to exceed 7 years from the date the incident giving rise to the injury occurred, except that this 7-year period shall not bar an action brought on behalf of a minor on or before the child’s eighth birthday. This paragraph shall not apply to actions for which ss. 766.301-766.316 provide the exclusive remedy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action to recover wages or overtime or damages or penalties concerning payment of wages and overtime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for wrongful death.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action founded upon a violation of any provision of chapter 517, with the period running from the time the facts giving rise to the cause of action were discovered or should have been discovered with the exercise of due diligence, but not more than 5 years from the date such violation occurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for personal injury caused by contact with or exposure to phenoxy herbicides while serving either as a civilian or as a member of the Armed Forces of the United States during the period January 1, 1962, through May 7, 1975; the period of limitations shall run from the time the cause of action is discovered or should have been discovered with the exercise of due diligence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for libel or slander.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WITHIN ONE YEAR.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action for specific performance of a contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action to enforce an equitable lien arising from the furnishing of labor, services, or material for the improvement of real property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action to enforce rights under the Uniform Commercial Code<EmDash />Letters of Credit, chapter 675.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action against any guaranty association and its insured, with the period running from the date of the deadline for filing claims in the order of liquidation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for actions governed by s. 255.05(10), s. 337.18(1), or s. 713.23(1)(e), an action to enforce any claim against a payment bond on which the principal is a contractor, subcontractor, or sub-subcontractor as defined in s. 713.01, for private work as well as public work, from the last furnishing of labor, services, or materials or from the last furnishing of labor, services, or materials by the contractor if the contractor is the principal on a bond on the same construction project, whichever is later.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for actions described in subsection (8), a petition for extraordinary writ, other than a petition challenging a criminal conviction, filed by or on behalf of a prisoner as defined in s. 57.085.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for actions described in subsection (8), an action brought by or on behalf of a prisoner, as defined in s. 57.085, relating to the conditions of the prisoner’s confinement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LACHES.<EmDash />Laches shall bar any action unless it is commenced within the time provided for legal actions concerning the same subject matter regardless of lack of knowledge by the person sought to be held liable that the person alleging liability would assert his or her rights and whether the person sought to be held liable is injured or prejudiced by the delay. This subsection shall not affect application of laches at an earlier time in accordance with law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOR INTENTIONAL TORTS BASED ON ABUSE.<EmDash />An action founded on alleged abuse, as defined in s. 39.01, s. 415.102, or s. 984.03, or incest, as defined in s. 826.04, may be commenced at any time within 7 years after the age of majority, or within 4 years after the injured person leaves the dependency of the abuser, or within 4 years from the time of discovery by the injured party of both the injury and the causal relationship between the injury and the abuse, whichever occurs later.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">WITHIN 30 DAYS FOR ACTIONS CHALLENGING CORRECTIONAL DISCIPLINARY PROCEEDINGS.<EmDash />Any court action challenging prisoner disciplinary proceedings conducted by the Department of Corrections pursuant to s. 944.28(2) must be commenced within 30 days after final disposition of the prisoner disciplinary proceedings through the administrative grievance process under chapter 33, Florida Administrative Code. Any action challenging prisoner disciplinary proceedings shall be barred by the court unless it is commenced within the time period provided by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SEXUAL BATTERY OFFENSES ON VICTIMS UNDER AGE 16.<EmDash />An action related to an act constituting a violation of s. 794.011 involving a victim who was under the age of 16 at the time of the act may be commenced at any time. This subsection applies to any such action other than one which would have been time barred on or before July 1, 2010.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FOR INTENTIONAL TORTS RESULTING IN DEATH FROM ACTS DESCRIBED IN S. 782.04 OR S. 782.07.<EmDash />Notwithstanding paragraph (4)(d), an action for wrongful death seeking damages authorized under s. 768.21 brought against a natural person for an intentional tort resulting in death from acts described in s. 782.04 or s. 782.07 may be commenced at any time. This subsection shall not be construed to require an arrest, the filing of formal criminal charges, or a conviction for a violation of s. 782.04 or s. 782.07 as a condition for filing a civil action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COURT COSTS AND FINES.<EmDash />Notwithstanding subsection (1), an action to collect court costs, fees, or fines owed to the state may be commenced at any time.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 1869, 1872; s. 1, ch. 3900, 1889; RS 1294; GS 1725; s. 10, ch. 7838, 1919; RGS 2939; CGL 4663; s. 1, ch. 21892, 1943; s. 7, ch. 24337, 1947; s. 24, ch. 57-1; s. 1, ch. 59-188; s. 1, ch. 67-284; s. 1, ch. 71-254; s. 30, ch. 73-333; s. 7, ch. 74-382; s. 7, ch. 75-9; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 11, ch. 78-435; s. 1, ch. 80-322; s. 34, ch. 83-38; s. 1, ch. 84-13; s. 1, ch. 85-63; s. 139, ch. 86-220; s. 1, ch. 86-231; s. 1, ch. 86-272; s. 1, ch. 88-397; s. 20, ch. 90-109; s. 1, ch. 92-102; s. 520, ch. 95-147; s. 2, ch. 95-283; s. 4, ch. 96-106; s. 1, ch. 96-167; s. 15, ch. 98-280; s. 2, ch. 99-5; s. 12, ch. 99-137; s. 2, ch. 2001-211; s. 15, ch. 2005-230; s. 1, ch. 2005-353; s. 1, ch. 2006-145; s. 2, ch. 2010-45; s. 1, ch. 2010-54; s. 1, ch. 2011-39; s. 13, ch. 2012-100; s. 1, ch. 2012-211.</History></Section>