<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0095.192" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitation upon acting against tax deeds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a tax deed has been issued to any person under s. 197.552 for 4 years, no action shall be brought by the former owner of the property or any claimant under the former owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a tax deed is issued conveying or attempting to convey real property before a patent has been issued thereon by the United States, or before a conveyance by the state, and thereafter a patent by the United States or a conveyance by the state is issued to the person to whom the property was assessed or a claimant under him or her, and the tax deed grantee or a claimant under the tax deed grantee has paid the taxes for 4 successive years at any time after the issuance of the patent or conveyance, the patentee, or grantee, and any claimant under the patentee or grantee shall be presumed to have abandoned the property and any right, title, and interest in it. Upon such abandonment, the tax deed grantee and any claimant under the tax deed grantee is the legal owner of the property described by the tax deed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This statute applies whether the tax deed grantee or any claimant under the tax deed grantee has been in actual possession of the property described in the tax deed or not. If a tax deed has been issued to property in the actual possession of the legal owner and the legal owner or any claimant under him or her continues in actual possession 1 year after issuance of the tax deed and before an action to eject him or her is begun, subsections (1) and (2) shall not apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 73-332; s. 201, ch. 85-342; s. 524, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>