<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0913.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for challenge to individual jurors for cause.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A challenge for cause to an individual juror may be made only on the following grounds:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror does not have the qualifications required by law;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror is of unsound mind or has a bodily defect that renders him or her incapable of performing the duties of a juror, except that, in a civil action, deafness or hearing impairment shall not be the sole basis of a challenge for cause of an individual juror;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror has conscientious beliefs that would preclude him or her from finding the defendant guilty;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror served on the grand jury that found the indictment or on a coroner’s jury that inquired into the death of a person whose death is the subject of the indictment or information;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror served on a jury formerly sworn to try the defendant for the same offense;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror served on a jury that tried another person for the offense charged in the indictment, information, or affidavit;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror served as a juror in a civil action brought against the defendant for the act charged as an offense;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror is an adverse party to the defendant in a civil action, or has complained against or been accused by the defendant in a criminal prosecution;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror is related by blood or marriage within the third degree to the defendant, the attorneys of either party, the person alleged to be injured by the offense charged, or the person on whose complaint the prosecution was instituted;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror has a state of mind regarding the defendant, the case, the person alleged to have been injured by the offense charged, or the person on whose complaint the prosecution was instituted that will prevent the juror from acting with impartiality, but the formation of an opinion or impression regarding the guilt or innocence of the defendant shall not be a sufficient ground for challenge to a juror if he or she declares and the court determines that he or she can render an impartial verdict according to the evidence;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror was a witness for the state or the defendant at the preliminary hearing or before the grand jury or is to be a witness for either party at the trial;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The juror is a surety on defendant’s bail bond in the case.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 184, ch. 19554, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 8663(191); s. 85, ch. 70-339; s. 5, ch. 93-125; s. 1520, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>