<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0369.320" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Wastewater facility plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local governments within the Wekiva Study Area shall develop a wastewater facility plan for joint planning areas and utility service areas where central wastewater systems are not readily available. The facility plan shall include: the delineation of areas within the utility service area that are to be served by central facilities within 5 years; a financially feasible schedule of improvements; an infrastructure work plan to build the facilities needed to implement the facility plan, including those needed to meet enhanced treatment standards adopted by the Department of Environmental Protection; and a phase-out of existing onsite septic tank systems where central facilities are available. The term available shall be interpreted consistent with the definition of s. 381.0065(2)(a). The facility plan shall also include a long-range component addressing service of the joint planning area or utility service area. In addition, local governments shall establish a water reuse program that allows for reuse of reclaimed water on a site-by-site basis for development over a size threshold to be determined by the local government or on a jurisdiction-wide basis to minimize pumpage of groundwater for nonpotable usage.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local governments shall update their wastewater facility plans required in subsection (1) where the Total Maximum Daily Loads Program requires reductions in point source pollutants for a basin or as required by legislation for enhanced treatment standards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those local governments located partially within the Wekiva Study Area, this section applies only to that portion located within the Wekiva Study Area.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-384; s. 3, ch. 2005-106.</History></Section>