<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0369.307" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Developments of regional impact in the Wekiva River Protection Area; land acquisition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 380.06(15), the counties shall consider and issue the development permits applicable to a proposed development of regional impact which is located partially or wholly within the Wekiva River Protection Area at the same time as the development order approving, approving with conditions, or denying a development of regional impact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 380.0651 or any other provisions of chapter 380, the numerical standards and guidelines provided in chapter 28-24, Florida Administrative Code, shall be reduced by 50 percent as applied to proposed developments entirely or partially located within the Wekiva River Protection Area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Wekiva River Protection Area is hereby declared to be a natural resource of state and regional importance. The East Central Florida Regional Planning Council shall adopt policies as part of its strategic regional policy plan and regional issues list which will protect the water quantity, water quality, hydrology, wetlands, aquatic and wetland-dependent wildlife species, habitat of species designated pursuant to rules 39-27.003, 39-27.004, and 39-27.005, Florida Administrative Code, and native vegetation in the Wekiva River Protection Area. The council shall also cooperate with the department in the department’s implementation of the provisions of s. 369.305.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 369.305 of this act shall be inapplicable to developments of regional impact in the Wekiva River Protection Area if an application for development approval was filed prior to June 1, 1988, and in the event that a development order is issued pursuant to such application on or before April 1, 1989.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Environmental Protection is directed to proceed to negotiate for acquisition of conservation and recreation lands projects within the Wekiva River Protection Area provided that such projects have been deemed qualified under statutory and rule criteria for purchase and have been placed on the priority list for acquisition by the advisory council created in s. 259.035 or its successor.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-121; s. 26, ch. 88-393; s. 14, ch. 89-116; s. 191, ch. 94-356; s. 10, ch. 95-149; s. 31, ch. 99-247.</History></Section>