<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0369.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Aquatic plants; definitions; permits; powers of department; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Aquatic plant” means any plant, including a floating, emersed, submersed, or ditch bank species, growing in, or closely associated with, an aquatic environment and includes any part or seed of such plant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonnursery cultivation” means the tending of aquatic plant species for harvest in the natural environment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Noxious aquatic plant” means any part, including, but not limited to, seeds or reproductive parts, of an aquatic plant which has the potential to hinder the growth of beneficial plants, interfere with irrigation or navigation, or adversely affect the public welfare or the natural resources of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” includes a natural person, a public or private corporation, a governmental entity, or any other kind of entity.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall engage in any business involving the importation, transportation, cultivation, collection, sale, or possession of any aquatic plant species without a permit issued by the department. No person shall import, transport, cultivate, collect, sell, or possess any noxious aquatic plant listed on the prohibited aquatic plant list established by the department without a permit issued by the department. No permit shall be issued until the department determines that the proposed activity poses no threat or danger to the waters, wildlife, natural resources, or environment of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has the following powers:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make such rules governing the importation, transportation, nonnursery cultivation, collection, and possession of aquatic plants as may be necessary for the eradication, control, or prevention of the dissemination of noxious aquatic plants that are not inconsistent with rules of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish by rule lists of aquatic plant species regulated under this section, including those exempted from such regulation, provided the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission approves such lists prior to the lists becoming effective.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To evaluate an aquatic plant species through research or other means to determine whether such species poses a threat or danger to the waters, wildlife, natural resources, or environment of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To declare a quarantine against aquatic plants, including the vats, pools, or other containers or bodies of water in which such plants are growing, to prevent the dissemination of any noxious aquatic plant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make rules governing the application for, issuance of, suspension of, and revocation of permits under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter into cooperative agreements with any person as necessary or desirable to carry out and enforce the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To purchase all necessary supplies, material, facilities, and equipment and accept all grants and donations useful in the implementation and enforcement of the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enter upon and inspect any facility or place where aquatic plants are cultivated, held, packaged, shipped, stored, or sold, or any vehicle of conveyance of aquatic plants, to ascertain whether the provisions of this section and department regulations are being complied with, and to seize and destroy, without compensation, any aquatic plants imported, transported, cultivated, collected, or otherwise possessed in violation of this section or department regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt rules requiring the revegetation of a site on sovereignty lands where excessive collection has occurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enforce this section and s. 369.251 in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in s. 581.211.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules that limit the sanctions available for violations under this act to quarantine and confiscation:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the prohibited activity apparently results from natural dispersion; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a small amount of noxious aquatic plant material incidentally adheres to a boat or boat trailer operated by a person who is not involved in any phase of the aquatic plant business and if that person is not knowingly violating this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All law enforcement officers of the state and its agencies with power to make arrests for violations of state law shall enforce the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-158; ss. 14, 26, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 70-203; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 350, ch. 71-136; s. 2, ch. 71-137; s. 140, ch. 77-104; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 23, ch. 78-95; s. 1, ch. 84-120; s. 1, ch. 92-147; s. 189, ch. 94-356; s. 93, ch. 99-245; s. 1, ch. 2000-146; s. 1, ch. 2001-258; s. 8, ch. 2008-150; s. 32, ch. 2009-86.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 403.271.</Text></Note></Section>