<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0369.251" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Invasive nonnative plants; prohibitions; study; removal; rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not sell, transport, collect, cultivate, or possess any plant, including any part or seed, of the species <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Melaleuca quinquenervia</Font>, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Schinus terebinthifolius</Font>, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Casuarina equisetifolia</Font>, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Casuarina glauca</Font>, or <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Mimosa pigra</Font> without a permit from the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. Any person who violates this section commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable by fine only, as provided in s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in coordination with the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, shall study methods of control of plants of the species <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Melaleuca quinquenervia</Font>, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Schinus terebinthifolius</Font>, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Casuarina equisetifolia</Font>, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Casuarina glauca</Font>, and <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Mimosa pigra</Font>. The South Florida Water Management District shall undertake programs to remove such plants from conservation area I, conservation area II, and conservation area III of the district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this section. Possession or transportation resulting from natural dispersion, mulching operations, control and disposal, or use in herbaria or other educational or research institutions, or for other reasons determined by the department to be consistent with this section and where there is neither the danger of, nor intent to, further disperse any plant species prohibited by this section, is not subject to the permit or penalty provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-313; s. 190, ch. 94-356; s. 77, ch. 98-200; s. 9, ch. 2008-150.</History></Section>