<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0593.116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalty for violation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who, except in compliance with ss. 593.101-593.117 or rules of the department, moves any regulated article within the state or into this state from any other state against which the department has declared a quarantine pursuant to ss. 593.101-593.117 is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, or, upon a second or subsequent conviction thereof, is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commercial cotton grower who fails to pay any assessment levied under ss. 593.101-593.117 or fails to destroy cotton stalks by February 1 of each year in which the boll weevil eradication program is in effect is subject to a penalty of not more than $25 per acre, such amount to be established by the department upon the recommendation of the board of directors of the cotton growers’ organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any commercial cotton grower who fails to pay all assessments, including penalties, within 30 days after the date of the notice is required to destroy all cotton plants growing on his or her property subject to assessment. Any cotton plant not destroyed is deemed a public nuisance. The department may apply to any court of competent jurisdiction, and the court is authorized, in its discretion, to issue judgment and order condemnation and destruction of the nuisance. The grower is liable for all court costs, fees, and other expenses incurred in such action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 87-55; s. 1, ch. 88-303; s. 1, ch. 89-11; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 965, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>