<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0949.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Compact for the supervision of adult offenders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that this section is necessary for the immediate preservation of the public peace, health, and safety.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor is authorized and directed to enter into a compact on behalf of the state with any state of the United States legally joining therein in a form substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE I</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">PURPOSE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) The compacting states to this interstate compact recognize that each state is responsible for the supervision of adult offenders in the community who are authorized pursuant to the by-laws and rules of this compact to travel across state lines both to and from each compacting state, in such a manner as to track the location of offenders, transfer supervision authority in an orderly and efficient manner, and, when necessary, return offenders to the originating jurisdictions. The compacting states also recognize that Congress, by enacting the “Crime Control Act,” 4 U.S.C. s. 112, has authorized and encouraged compacts for cooperative efforts and mutual assistance in the prevention of crime.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) It is the purpose of this compact and the Interstate Commission created hereunder, through means of joint and cooperative action among the compacting states, to provide the framework for the promotion of public safety and protect the rights of victims through the control and regulation of the interstate movement of offenders in the community; to provide for the effective tracking, supervision, and rehabilitation of these offenders by the sending and receiving states; and to equitably distribute the costs, benefits, and obligations of the compact among the compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) In addition, this compact:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Creates an Interstate Commission that will establish uniform procedures and rules for managing the movement between states of adults placed under community supervision and released to the community under the jurisdiction of courts, paroling authorities, corrections agencies, or other criminal justice agencies;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Ensures an opportunity for input and timely notice to victims and to jurisdictions where defined offenders are authorized to travel or to relocate across state lines;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) Establishes a system of uniform data collection, access to information on active cases by authorized criminal justice officials, and regular reporting of compact activities to heads of state councils; state executive, judicial, and legislative branches; and criminal justice administrators;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) Provides for monitoring compliance with rules governing interstate movement of offenders and initiating interventions to address and correct noncompliance; and</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) Provides for coordinating training and education regarding regulations of interstate movement of offenders for officials involved in such activity.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) The compacting states recognize that offenders have no right to live in another state and that duly accredited officers of a sending state may at all times enter a receiving state and apprehend and retake any offender under supervision subject to the provisions of this compact and by-laws and rules adopted under this compact. It is the policy of the compacting states that the purpose of the Interstate Commission is the formation of public policies and that the commission’s activities therefore constitute public business.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE II</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">DEFINITIONS</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) As used in this compact, the term:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) “Adult” refers to individuals legally classified as adults and to juveniles treated as adults by court order, statute, or operation of law.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) “By-laws” means those by-laws established by the Interstate Commission for its governance or for directing or controlling the Interstate Commission’s actions or conduct.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) “Compact administrator” means the individual in each compacting state appointed pursuant to the terms of this compact who is responsible for the administration and management of the state’s supervision and transfer of offenders subject to the terms of this compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission, and policies adopted by the state council under this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) “Compacting state” means any state that has enacted the enabling legislation for this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) “Commissioner” means the voting representative of each compacting state appointed pursuant to article III of this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(f) “Interstate Commission” means the Interstate Commission for Adult Offender Supervision established by this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(g) “Member” means the commissioner of a compacting state or designee, who must be a person officially connected with the commissioner.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(h) “Noncompacting state” means any state that has not enacted the enabling legislation for this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(i) “Offender” means an adult placed under, or subject to, supervision as the result of the commission of a criminal offense and released to the community under the jurisdiction of courts, paroling authorities, corrections agencies, or other criminal justice agencies.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(j) “Person” means any individual, corporation, business enterprise, or other legal entity, either public or private.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(k) “Rules” means acts of the Interstate Commission, duly adopted pursuant to article VIII of this compact, substantially affecting interested parties in addition to the Interstate Commission, which shall have the force and effect of law in the compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(l) “State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any other territorial possessions of the United States.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(m) “State council” means the resident members of the State Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision created by each state under article IV of this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE III</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">THE COMPACT COMMISSION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) The compacting states hereby create the Interstate Commission for Adult Offender Supervision. The Interstate Commission shall be a body corporate and a joint agency of the compacting states. The Interstate Commission shall have all the responsibilities, powers, and duties set forth in this compact, including the power to sue and be sued, and such additional powers as are conferred upon it by subsequent action of the respective legislatures of the compacting states in accordance with the terms of this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) The Interstate Commission shall consist of commissioners selected and appointed by resident members of a state council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision for each state. In addition to the commissioners who are the voting representatives of each state, the Interstate Commission shall include individuals who are not commissioners but who are members of interested organizations. Such noncommissioner members shall include a member of the national organizations of governors, legislators, state chief justices, attorneys general, and crime victims. All noncommissioner members of the Interstate Commission shall be ex officio, nonvoting members. The Interstate Commission may provide in its by-laws for such additional, ex officio, nonvoting members as it deems necessary.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) Each compacting state represented at any meeting of the Interstate Commission is entitled to one vote. A majority of the compacting states shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless a larger quorum is required by the by-laws of the Interstate Commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) The Interstate Commission shall meet at least once each calendar year. The chairperson may call additional meetings and, upon the request of 27 or more compacting states, shall call additional meetings. Public notice shall be given of all meetings, and meetings shall be open to the public.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) The Interstate Commission shall establish an executive committee that shall include commission officers, members, and others as determined by the by-laws. The executive committee shall have the power to act on behalf of the Interstate Commission during periods when the Interstate Commission is not in session, with the exception of rulemaking and amendments to the compact. The executive committee oversees the day-to-day activities managed by the executive director and Interstate Commission staff; administers enforcement and compliance with the provisions of the compact and its by-laws and as directed by the Interstate Commission; and performs other duties as directed by the Interstate Commission or set forth in the by-laws.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE IV</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">THE STATE COUNCIL</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) Each member state shall create a State Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision, which shall appoint the commissioner who shall serve on the Interstate Commission from that state. Each state council shall appoint as its commissioner the compact administrator from that state to serve on the Interstate Commission in such capacity under or pursuant to applicable law of the member state. While each member state may determine the membership of its own state council, its membership must include at least one representative each from victims groups and compact administrators.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) The State Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision in this state shall consist of seven members. These members shall include the compact administrator, a representative from a victims assistance organization, and one at-large member.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The Secretary of Corrections, or the secretary’s designee, shall serve as compact administrator and chairperson of the State Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision. If the Secretary of Corrections elects to appoint a designee, the designee shall be:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. The Deputy Secretary of Corrections;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. The Director of the Office of Community Corrections; or</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. The bureau chief in the Office of Community Corrections that has operational authority over the Interstate Compact Bureau.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The Governor shall appoint the remaining members of the State Council.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The term of office of a member is 4 years.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) The State Council shall meet at least twice a year.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) The State Council may advise the Compact Administrator on participation in the Interstate Commission activities and administration of the compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) Members of the council are entitled to reimbursement for travel and expenses related to the Interstate Commission as provided by state law.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) The State Council shall exercise oversight and advocacy concerning its participation in Interstate Commission activities and other duties as determined by each member state, including, but not limited to, development of policy concerning operations and procedures of the compact within that state.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE V</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">POWERS AND DUTIES OF<NewLine />THE INTERSTATE COMMISSION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) The Interstate Commission may:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Adopt a seal and suitable by-laws governing the management and operation of the Interstate Commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Adopt rules that shall have the force and effect of statutory law and shall be binding in the compacting states to the extent and in the manner provided in this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) Oversee, supervise, and coordinate the interstate movement of offenders subject to the terms of this compact and any by-laws and rules adopted by the Interstate Commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) Enforce compliance with compact provisions, Interstate Commission rules, and by-laws using all necessary and proper means, including, but not limited to, the use of the judicial process.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) Establish and maintain offices.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(f) Purchase and maintain insurance and bonds.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(g) Borrow, accept, or contract for services of personnel, including, but not limited to, members and their staffs.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(h) Establish and appoint committees and hire staff that it deems necessary for the carrying out of its functions, including, but not limited to, an executive committee as required by article III, which shall have the power to act on behalf of the Interstate Commission in carrying out its powers and duties under this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(i) Elect or appoint such officers, attorneys, employees, agents, or consultants as the commission considers necessary, and fix their compensation, define their duties, and determine their qualifications, and establish the commission’s personnel policies and programs relating to, among other things, conflicts of interest, rates of compensation, and qualifications of personnel.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(j) Accept any and all donations and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services, and receive, use, and dispose of the same.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(k) Lease, purchase, accept contributions or donations of, or otherwise own, hold, improve, or use, any property, real, personal, or mixed.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(l) Sell, convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, abandon, or otherwise dispose of any property, real, personal, or mixed.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(m) Establish a budget and make expenditures and levy dues as provided in article X of this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(n) Sue and be sued.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(o) Provide for dispute resolution among compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(p) Perform functions necessary or appropriate to achieve the purposes of this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(q) Report annually to the legislatures, governors, judiciary, and state councils of the compacting states concerning the activities of the commission during the preceding year. Such reports must also include any recommendations that may have been adopted by the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(r) Coordinate education, training, and public awareness regarding the interstate movement of offenders for officials involved in such activity.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(s) Establish uniform standards for reporting, collecting, and exchanging data.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VI</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">ORGANIZATION AND OPERATION<NewLine />OF THE INTERSTATE COMMISSION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) BY-LAWS.—The Interstate Commission, by a majority of the members, within 1 year after the first commission meeting, shall adopt by-laws to govern its conduct as necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the compact, including, but not limited to:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Establishing the fiscal year of the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Establishing an executive committee and other committees as necessary and providing reasonable standards and procedures:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. For the establishment of committees; and</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. Governing any general or specific delegation of any authority or function of the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) Providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the commission and for ensuring reasonable notice of each meeting.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) Establishing the titles and responsibilities of the officers of the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) Providing reasonable standards and procedures for the establishment of the personnel policies and programs of the commission. Notwithstanding any civil service or other similar laws of any compacting state, the by-laws shall exclusively govern the personnel policies and programs of the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(f) Providing a mechanism for concluding the operations of the commission and the equitable return of any surplus funds that may exist upon the termination of the compact after the payment or reserving of all of its debts and obligations.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(g) Providing transition rules for the implementation of the compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(h) Establishing standards and procedures for compliance and technical assistance in carrying out the compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) OFFICERS AND STAFF.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The Interstate Commission, by a majority of the members, shall elect from among its members a chairperson and a vice chairperson, each of whom shall have the authorities and duties specified in the by-laws. The chairperson or, in his or her absence or disability, the vice chairperson, shall preside at all meetings of the commission. The officers so elected shall serve without compensation or remuneration from the commission. However, subject to the availability of budgeted funds, the officers shall be reimbursed for any actual and necessary costs and expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties and responsibilities as officers of the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The commission, through its executive committee, shall appoint or retain an executive director for such period, upon such terms and conditions, and for such compensation as the commission deems appropriate. The executive director shall serve as secretary to the commission and hire and supervise other staff as authorized by the commission, but may not be a member.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) CORPORATE RECORDS OF THE INTERSTATE COMMISSION.—The Interstate Commission shall maintain its corporate books and records in accordance with the by-laws.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) QUALIFIED IMMUNITY, DEFENSE, AND INDEMNIFICATION.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The members, officers, executive director, and employees of the Interstate Commission shall be immune from suit and liability, either personally or in their official capacity, for any claim for damage to or loss of property or personal injury or other civil liability caused or arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of commission employment, duties, or responsibilities. However, this paragraph does not protect any such person from suit or liability for any damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of any such person.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The Interstate Commission shall defend the commissioner of a compacting state, or his or her representatives or employees, or the commission’s representatives or employees in any civil action seeking to impose liability arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities or that the defendant had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, if the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from intentional wrongdoing on the part of such person.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The Interstate Commission shall indemnify and hold the commissioner of a compacting state, his or her appointed designee or employees, or the Interstate Commission’s representatives harmless in the amount of any settlement or judgment obtained against such persons arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities or that such persons had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, if the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from gross negligence or intentional wrongdoing on the part of such person.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">ACTIVITIES OF THE<NewLine />INTERSTATE COMMISSION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) The Interstate Commission shall meet and take such actions as are consistent with this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) Except as otherwise provided in this compact and unless a greater percentage is required by the by-laws, in order to constitute an act of the Interstate Commission, such act must be taken at a meeting of the commission and must receive an affirmative vote of a majority of the members present.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) Each member of the commission may cast a vote to which that compacting state is entitled and may participate in the business and affairs of the commission. A member shall vote in person on behalf of the state and may not delegate a vote to another member state. However, a state council shall appoint another authorized representative, in the absence of the commissioner from that state, to cast a vote on behalf of the member state at a specified meeting. The by-laws may provide for members’ participation in meetings by telephone or other means of telecommunication or electronic communication. Any voting conducted by telephone or other means of telecommunication or electronic communication is subject to the same quorum requirements as meetings where members are present in person.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) The Interstate Commission shall meet at least once during each calendar year. The chairperson of the commission may call additional meetings at any time and, upon the request of a majority of the members, shall call additional meetings.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) The Interstate Commission’s by-laws shall establish conditions and procedures under which the commission shall make its information and official records available to the public for inspection or copying. The commission may exempt from disclosure any information or official records to the extent that they would adversely affect personal privacy rights or proprietary interests. In adopting such rules, the Interstate Commission may make available to law enforcement agencies records and information otherwise exempt from disclosure and may enter into agreements with law enforcement agencies to receive or exchange information or records subject to nondisclosure and confidentiality provisions.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) Public notice shall be given of all meetings and all meetings shall be open to the public, except as set forth in the rules or as otherwise provided in the compact. The Interstate Commission shall adopt rules consistent with the principles contained in the “Government in Sunshine Act,” 5 U.S.C. s. 552(b), as amended.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The Interstate Commission shall keep minutes that fully and clearly describe all matters discussed in any meeting and provide a full and accurate summary of any actions taken and the reasons therefor, including a description of each of the views expressed on any item and the record of any roll call vote, reflecting the vote of each member on the question. All documents considered in connection with any action must be identified in the minutes.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The Interstate Commission shall collect standardized data concerning the interstate movement of offenders as directed through its by-laws and rules, which shall specify the data to be collected, the means of collection, and data exchange and reporting requirements.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VIII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">RULEMAKING FUNCTIONS OF<NewLine />THE INTERSTATE COMMISSION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) The Interstate Commission shall adopt rules in order to effectively and efficiently achieve the purposes of the compact, including transition rules governing administration of the compact during the period in which it is being considered and enacted by the states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) Rulemaking shall occur pursuant to the criteria set forth in this article and the by-laws and rules adopted pursuant thereto. Such rulemaking shall substantially conform to the principles of the federal “Administrative Procedure Act,” 5 U.S.C.S. s. 551 et seq., and the federal “Advisory Committee Act,” 5 U.S.C.S. App. 2, s. 1 et seq., as amended. All rules and amendments take effect on the date specified in each rule or amendment.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) If a majority of the legislatures of the compacting states rejects a rule by enactment of a statute or resolution in the same manner used to adopt the compact, such rule shall have no further force and effect in any compacting state.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) When adopting a rule, the Interstate Commission shall:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Publish the proposed rule stating with particularity the text of the rule that is proposed and the reason for the proposed rule;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Allow persons to submit written data, facts, opinions, and arguments, which information must be publicly available;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) Provide an opportunity for an informal hearing; and</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) Adopt a final rule and its effective date, if appropriate, based on the rulemaking record. Not later than 60 days after a rule is adopted, any interested person may file a petition in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the federal district court where the Interstate Commission’s principal office is located for judicial review of such rule. If the court finds that the Interstate Commission’s action is not supported by substantial evidence, as defined in the federal Administrative Procedure Act, in the rulemaking record, the court shall hold the rule unlawful and set it aside. Subjects to be addressed within 12 months after the first meeting must, at a minimum, include:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. Notice to victims and opportunity to be heard;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. Offender registration and compliance;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. Violations and returns;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">4. Transfer procedures and forms;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">5. Eligibility for transfer;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">6. Collection of restitution and fees from offenders;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">7. Data collection and reporting;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">8. The level of supervision to be provided by the receiving state;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">9. Transition rules governing the operation of the compact and the Interstate Commission during all or part of the period between the effective date of the compact and the date on which the last eligible state adopts the compact; and</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">10. Mediation, arbitration, and dispute resolution.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) The existing rules governing the operation of the previous compact superseded by this act shall be null and void 12 months after the first meeting of the Interstate Commission created under this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) Upon determination by the Interstate Commission that an emergency exists, it may adopt an emergency rule that takes effect immediately upon adoption. However, the usual rulemaking procedures provided under this compact must be retroactively applied to the rule as soon as reasonably possible, but not later than 90 days after the effective date of the rule.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE IX</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">OVERSIGHT, ENFORCEMENT, AND<NewLine />DISPUTE RESOLUTION BY THE<NewLine />INTERSTATE COMMISSION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) OVERSIGHT.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The Interstate Commission shall oversee the interstate movement of adult offenders in the compacting states and shall monitor activities being administered in noncompacting states which may significantly affect compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The courts and executive agencies in each compacting state shall enforce this compact and shall take all actions necessary and appropriate to effectuate the compact’s purposes and intent. In any judicial or administrative proceeding in a compacting state pertaining to the subject matter of this compact which may affect the powers, responsibilities, or actions of the Interstate Commission, the commission is entitled to receive all service of process in any such proceeding and has standing to intervene in the proceeding for all purposes.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) DISPUTE RESOLUTION.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The compacting states shall report to the Interstate Commission on issues or activities of concern to them and cooperate with and support the commission in the discharge of its duties and responsibilities.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The Interstate Commission shall attempt to resolve any disputes or other issues that are subject to the compact and that arise among compacting states and noncompacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The Interstate Commission shall enact a by-law or adopt a rule providing for both mediation and binding dispute resolution for disputes among the compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) ENFORCEMENT.—The Interstate Commission, in the reasonable exercise of its discretion, shall enforce the provisions of this compact using any or all means set forth in article XII(2) of this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE X</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">FINANCE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) The Interstate Commission shall pay or provide for the payment of the reasonable expenses of its establishment, organization, and ongoing activities.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) The Interstate Commission shall levy on and collect an annual assessment from each compacting state to cover the cost of the internal operations and activities of the Interstate Commission and its staff, which must be in a total amount sufficient to cover the Interstate Commission’s annual budget as approved each year. The aggregate annual assessment amount shall be allocated based upon a formula to be determined by the Interstate Commission, taking into consideration the population of the state and the volume of interstate movement of offenders in each compacting state. The Interstate Commission shall adopt a rule that is binding upon all compacting states and that governs the assessment.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) The Interstate Commission may not incur any obligations of any kind prior to securing the funds adequate to meet the obligations, and the Interstate Commission may not pledge the credit of any of the compacting states except by and with the authority of the compacting state.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) The Interstate Commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and disbursements. The receipts and disbursements of the commission are subject to the audit and accounting procedures established under its by-laws. However, all receipts and disbursements of funds handled by the commission shall be audited yearly by a certified or licensed public accountant, and the report of the audit must be included in and become part of the annual report of the commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE XI</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">COMPACTING STATES, EFFECTIVE<NewLine />DATE, AND AMENDMENT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) Any state, as defined in article II of this compact, is eligible to become a compacting state.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) The compact shall become effective and binding upon legislative enactment of the compact into law by not less than 35 of the states. The initial effective date shall be the later of July 1, 2001, or upon enactment into law by the 35th jurisdiction. Thereafter, the compact shall become effective and binding as to any other compacting state upon enactment of the compact into law by that state. The governors of nonmember states or their designees will be invited to participate in Interstate Commission activities on a nonvoting basis prior to adoption of the compact by all states and territories of the United States.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) Amendments to the compact may be proposed by the Interstate Commission for enactment by the compacting states. An amendment does not become effective and binding upon the Interstate Commission or the compacting states unless and until it is enacted into law by unanimous consent of the compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE XII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">WITHDRAWAL, DEFAULT, TERMINATION,<NewLine />AND JUDICIAL ENFORCEMENT</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) WITHDRAWAL.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Once effective, the compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each and every compacting state. However, a compacting state may withdraw from the compact by enacting a law specifically repealing the statute that enacted the compact into law.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The effective date of withdrawal is the effective date of the repeal.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The withdrawing state shall immediately notify the chairperson of the Interstate Commission in writing upon the introduction of legislation repealing this compact in the withdrawing state. The Interstate Commission shall notify the other compacting states of the withdrawing state’s intent to withdraw within 60 days after its receipt of the notice.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) The withdrawing state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred by it through the effective date of withdrawal, including any obligations the performance of which extend beyond the effective date of withdrawal.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) Reinstatement following withdrawal of any compacting state shall occur upon the withdrawing state reenacting the compact or upon such later date as determined by the Interstate Commission.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) DEFAULT.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) If the Interstate Commission determines that any compacting state has at any time defaulted in the performance of any of its obligations or responsibilities under this compact, the by-laws, or any adopted rules, the commission may impose any or all of the following penalties:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. Fines, fees, or costs in amounts deemed to be reasonable, as fixed by the Interstate Commission;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. Remedial training and technical assistance, as directed by the Interstate Commission;</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. Suspension and termination of membership in the compact. Suspension shall be imposed only after all other reasonable means of securing compliance under the by-laws and rules have been exhausted. Immediate notice of suspension shall be given by the Interstate Commission to the Governor, the Chief Justice or chief judicial officer of the state, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature, and the state council.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The grounds for default include, but are not limited to, failure of a compacting state to perform the obligations or responsibilities imposed upon it by this compact or by Interstate Commission by-laws or rules. The Interstate Commission shall immediately notify the defaulting state in writing of the penalty imposed by the commission on the defaulting state pending a cure of the default. The commission shall stipulate the conditions and the time period within which the defaulting state must cure its default. If the defaulting state fails to cure the default within the time specified by the commission, in addition to any other penalties imposed the defaulting state may be terminated from the compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the compacting states and all rights, privileges, and benefits conferred by this compact shall be terminated from the effective date of suspension. Within 60 days after the effective date of termination of a defaulting state, the Interstate Commission must notify the Governor, the Chief Justice or chief judicial officer, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature, and the state council of such termination.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The defaulting state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination, including any obligations the performance of which extends beyond the effective date of termination.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) The Interstate Commission may not bear any costs relating to the defaulting state unless otherwise mutually agreed upon between the Interstate Commission and the defaulting state. Reinstatement following termination of any compacting state requires a reenactment of the compact by the defaulting state and the approval of the Interstate Commission pursuant to the rules.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) JUDICIAL ENFORCEMENT.—The Interstate Commission, by majority vote of the members, may initiate legal action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or, at the discretion of the Interstate Commission, in the federal district where the Interstate Commission has its offices to enforce compliance with the provisions of the compact for the commission’s adopted rules and by-laws against any compacting state in default. If judicial enforcement is necessary, the prevailing party shall be awarded all costs of such litigation, including reasonable attorney’s fees.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) DISSOLUTION OF COMPACT.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The compact dissolves on the date of the withdrawal or default of the compacting state which reduces membership in the compact to one compacting state.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Upon the dissolution of this compact, the compact becomes null and void and shall have no further force or effect, and the business and affairs of the Interstate Commission shall be concluded and any surplus funds shall be distributed in accordance with the by-laws.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE XIII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">SEVERABILITY AND CONSTRUCTION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) The provisions of this compact are severable, and if any phrase, clause, sentence, or provision is deemed unenforceable, the remaining provisions of the compact are enforceable.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) The provisions of this compact shall be liberally construed to carry out its purposes.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE XIV</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter">BINDING EFFECT OF<NewLine />COMPACT AND OTHER LAWS</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter"></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">(1) OTHER LAWS.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Nothing in this compact prevents the enforcement of any other law of a compacting state which is not inconsistent with this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Any law of a compacting state which conflicts with this compact is superseded to the extent of the conflict.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) BINDING EFFECT OF THE COMPACT.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) All lawful actions of the Interstate Commission, including all rules and by-laws adopted by the Interstate Commission, are binding upon the compacting states.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) All agreements between the Interstate Commission and the compacting states are binding in accordance with the terms of the agreements.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) Upon the request of a party to a conflict over meaning or interpretation of Interstate Commission actions, and upon a majority vote of the compacting states, the Interstate Commission may issue advisory opinions regarding such meaning or interpretation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) If any provision of this compact exceeds the constitutional limits imposed on the legislature of any compacting state, the obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction sought to be conferred by such provision upon the Interstate Commission shall be ineffective, and such obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction shall remain in the compacting state and shall be exercised by the agency thereof to which such obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction are delegated by law in effect at the time this compact becomes effective.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 20455, 1941; s. 1691, ch. 97-102; s. 8, ch. 2001-209.</History></Section>