<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0493.6105" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Initial application for license.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each individual, partner, or principal officer in a corporation, shall file with the department a complete application accompanied by an application fee not to exceed $60, except that the applicant for a Class “D” or Class “G” license is not required to submit an application fee. The application fee is not refundable.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application submitted by any individual, partner, or corporate officer must be approved by the department before the individual, partner, or corporate officer assumes his or her duties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals who invest in the ownership of a licensed agency but do not participate in, direct, or control the operations of the agency are not required to file an application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application must be signed and verified by the individual under oath as provided in s. 92.525.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application must contain the following information concerning the individual signing the application:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Name and any aliases.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Age and date of birth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place of birth.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social security number or alien registration number, whichever is applicable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Current residence address and mailing address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of all criminal convictions, findings of guilt, and pleas of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of adjudication of guilt. An applicant for a Class “G” or Class “K” license who is younger than 24 years of age shall also include a statement regarding any finding of having committed a delinquent act in any state, territory, or country which would be a felony if committed by an adult and which is punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One passport-type color photograph taken within the 6 months immediately preceding submission of the application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement whether he or she has ever been adjudicated incompetent under chapter 744.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement whether he or she has ever been committed to a mental institution under chapter 394.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A full set of fingerprints on a card provided by the department and a fingerprint fee to be established by rule of the department based upon costs determined by state and federal agency charges and department processing costs. An applicant who has, within the immediately preceding 6 months, submitted a fingerprint card and fee for licensing purposes under this chapter is not required to submit another fingerprint card or fee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A personal inquiry waiver that allows the department to conduct necessary investigations to satisfy the requirements of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such further facts as may be required by the department to show that the individual signing the application is of good moral character and qualified by experience and training to satisfy the requirements of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the application requirements outlined under subsection (3), the applicant for a Class “C,” Class “E,” Class “M,” Class “MA,” Class “MB,” or Class “MR” license must include a statement on a form provided by the department of the experience that he or she believes will qualify him or her for such license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements outlined in subsection (3), an applicant for a Class “G” license must satisfy minimum training criteria for firearms established by rule of the department, which training criteria includes, but is not limited to, 28 hours of range and classroom training taught and administered by a Class “K” licensee; however, no more than 8 hours of such training shall consist of range training. The department may waive the foregoing firearms training requirement if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant provides proof that he or she is currently certified as a law enforcement officer or correctional officer pursuant to the requirements of the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission or has successfully completed the training required for certification within the last 12 months.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant provides proof that he or she is currently certified as a federal law enforcement officer and has received law enforcement firearms training administered by a federal law enforcement agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant submits a valid firearm certificate among those specified in paragraph (6)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements under subsection (3), an applicant for a Class “K” license must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit one of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission Instructor Certificate and written confirmation by the commission that the applicant possesses an active firearms certification.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The National Rifle Association Private Security Firearm Instructor Certificate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A firearms instructor certificate issued by a federal law enforcement agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay the fee for and pass an examination administered by the department which shall be based upon, but is not necessarily limited to, a firearms instruction manual provided by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the application requirements for individuals, partners, or officers outlined under subsection (3), the application for an agency license must contain the following information:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed name under which the agency intends to operate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address, mailing address, and telephone numbers of the principal location at which business is to be conducted in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address, mailing address, and telephone numbers of all branch offices within this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and titles of all partners or, in the case of a corporation, the names and titles of its principal officers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon submission of a complete application, a Class “CC,” Class “C,” Class “D,” Class “EE,” Class “E,” Class “M,” Class “MA,” Class “MB,” or Class “MR” applicant may commence employment or appropriate duties for a licensed agency or branch office. However, the Class “C” or Class “E” applicant must work under the direction and control of a sponsoring licensee while his or her application is being processed. If the department denies application for licensure, the employment of the applicant must be terminated immediately, unless he or she performs only unregulated duties.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 1, ch. 91-248; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 93-49; s. 527, ch. 97-103; s. 3, ch. 97-248; s. 2, ch. 2011-205; s. 14, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>