<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6406" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recovery agent school or training facility.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any school, training facility, or instructor who offers the training outlined in s. 493.6403(2) for Class “E” or Class “EE” applicants shall, before licensure of such school, training facility, or instructor, file with the department an application accompanied by an application fee in an amount to be determined by rule, not to exceed $60. The fee shall not be refundable. This training may be offered as face-to-face training, Internet-based training, or correspondence training.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application must be signed and verified by the applicant under oath as provided in s. 92.525 and shall contain, at a minimum, the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the school or training facility and, if the applicant is an individual, his or her name, address, and social security or alien registration number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of the place at which the training is to be conducted or the street address of the Class “RS” school offering Internet-based or correspondence training.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the training curriculum and final examination to be administered.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules establishing the criteria for approval of schools, training facilities, and instructors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 540, ch. 97-103; s. 3, ch. 2007-232; s. 18, ch. 2011-205.</History></Section>