<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Classes of licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, company, partnership, or corporation which engages in business as a private investigative agency shall have a Class “A” license. A Class “A” license is valid for only one location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each branch office of a Class “A” agency shall have a Class “AA” license. Where a person, firm, company, partnership, or corporation holds both a Class “A” and Class “B” license, each additional or branch office shall have a Class “AB” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs the services of a manager for a:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class “A” private investigative agency or Class “AA” branch office shall have a Class “MA” license. A Class “C” or Class “M” licensee may be designated as the manager, in which case the Class “MA” license is not required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class “A” and “B” agency or a Class “AB” branch office shall have a Class “M” license.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class “C” or Class “CC” licensees shall own or be an employee of a Class “A” agency, a Class “A” and Class “B” agency, or a branch office. This does not include those who are exempt under s. 493.6102, but who possess a Class “C” license solely for the purpose of holding a Class “G” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs the services of a private investigator shall have a Class “C” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs private investigative work as an intern under the direction and control of a designated, sponsoring Class “C” licensee or a designated, sponsoring Class “MA” or Class “M” licensee must have a Class “CC” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only Class “M,” Class “MA,” Class “C,” or Class “CC” licensees are permitted to bear a firearm, and any such licensee who bears a firearm shall also have a Class “G” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Class “C” or Class “CC” licensee may perform bodyguard services without obtaining a Class “D” license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 11, ch. 94-172; s. 70, ch. 95-144; s. 8, ch. 97-248.</History></Section>