<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License requirements; posting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each individual licensed by the department must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be of good moral character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not have been adjudicated incapacitated under s. 744.331 or a similar statute in another state, unless her or his capacity has been judicially restored; not have been involuntarily placed in a treatment facility for the mentally ill under chapter 394 or a similar statute in any other state, unless her or his competency has been judicially restored; and not have been diagnosed as having an incapacitating mental illness, unless a psychologist or psychiatrist licensed in this state certifies that she or he does not currently suffer from the mental illness.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not be a chronic and habitual user of alcoholic beverages to the extent that her or his normal faculties are impaired; not have been committed under chapter 397, former chapter 396, or a similar law in any other state; not have been found to be a habitual offender under s. 856.011(3) or a similar law in any other state; and not have had two or more convictions under s. 316.193 or a similar law in any other state within the 3-year period immediately preceding the date the application was filed, unless the individual establishes that she or he is not currently impaired and has successfully completed a rehabilitation course.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not have been committed for controlled substance abuse or have been found guilty of a crime under chapter 893 or a similar law relating to controlled substances in any other state within a 3-year period immediately preceding the date the application was filed, unless the individual establishes that she or he is not currently abusing any controlled substance and has successfully completed a rehabilitation course.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a citizen or permanent legal resident alien of the United States or have appropriate authorization issued by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services of the United States Department of Homeland Security.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a Class “C,” Class “CC,” Class “D,” Class “DI,” Class “E,” Class “EE,” Class “M,” Class “MA,” Class “MB,” Class “MR,” or Class “RI” license who is not a United States citizen must submit proof of current employment authorization issued by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services or proof that she or he is deemed a permanent legal resident alien by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a Class “G” or Class “K” license who is not a United States citizen must submit proof that she or he is deemed a permanent legal resident alien by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services, together with additional documentation establishing that she or he has resided in the state of residence shown on the application for at least 90 consecutive days before the date that the application is submitted.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for an agency or school license who is not a United States citizen or permanent legal resident alien must submit documentation issued by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services stating that she or he is lawfully in the United States and is authorized to own and operate the type of agency or school for which she or he is applying. An employment authorization card issued by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services is not sufficient documentation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not be prohibited from purchasing or possessing a firearm by state or federal law if the individual is applying for a Class “G” license or a Class “K” license.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency shall have a minimum of one physical location within this state from which the normal business of the agency is conducted, and this location shall be considered the primary office for that agency in this state.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an agency or branch office desires to change the physical location of the business, as it appears on the license, the department must be notified within 10 days after the change, and, except upon renewal, the fee prescribed in s. 493.6107 must be submitted for each license requiring revision. Each license requiring revision must be returned with such notification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Class “A,” Class “B,” or Class “R” license and any branch office or school license shall at all times be posted in a conspicuous place at the licensed physical location in this state where the business is conducted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Class “A,” Class “B,” Class “R,” branch office, or school licensee shall display, in a place that is in clear and unobstructed public view, a notice on a form prescribed by the department stating that the business operating at this location is licensed and regulated by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and that any questions or complaints should be directed to the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minimum of one properly licensed manager shall be designated for each agency and branch office location.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Class “C,” Class “CC,” Class “D,” Class “DI,” Class “E,” Class “EE,” Class “G,” Class “K,” Class “M,” Class “MA,” Class “MB,” Class “MR,” or Class “RI” licensee shall notify the division in writing within 10 days of a change in her or his residence or mailing address.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 2, ch. 91-248; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 93-49; s. 4, ch. 94-172; s. 528, ch. 97-103; s. 83, ch. 2004-5; s. 1, ch. 2006-165; s. 3, ch. 2011-205.</History></Section>