<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the license requirements set forth elsewhere in this chapter, each individual or agency must comply with the following additional requirements:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency or branch office shall designate a minimum of one appropriately licensed individual to act as manager, directing the activities of the Class “D” employees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a Class “MB” license shall have 2 years of lawfully gained, verifiable, full-time experience, or training in:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Security work or related fields of work that provided equivalent experience or training;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Experience described in paragraph (a) for 1 year and experience described in paragraph (c) for 1 year;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 1 year using:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Either college coursework related to criminal justice, criminology, or law enforcement administration; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Successfully completed law enforcement-related training received from any federal, state, county, or municipal agency; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Experience described in paragraph (a) for 1 year and work in a managerial or supervisory capacity for 1 year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a Class “M” license shall qualify for licensure as a Class “MA” manager as outlined under s. 493.6203(2) and as a Class “MB” manager as outlined under subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 2012, an applicant for a Class “D” license must submit proof of successful completion of a minimum of 40 hours of professional training at a school or training facility licensed by the department. The training must be provided in two parts, one 24-hour course and one 16-hour course. The department shall by rule establish the general content and number of hours of each subject area to be taught.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who submits an application for a Class “D” license on or after January 1, 2007, through December 31, 2011, who has not completed the 16-hour course must submit proof of successful completion of the course within 180 days after the date the application is submitted. If documentation of completion of the required training is not submitted by that date, the individual’s license shall be automatically suspended until proof of the required training is submitted to the department. A person licensed before January 1, 2007, is not required to complete additional training hours in order to renew an active license beyond the total required hours, and the timeframe for completion in effect at the time he or she was licensed applies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual whose license is suspended or revoked pursuant to paragraph (b), or is expired for at least 1 year, is considered, upon reapplication for a license, an initial applicant and must submit proof of successful completion of 40 hours of professional training at a school or training facility licensed by the department as provided in paragraph (a) before a license is issued.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for a Class “G” license shall satisfy the firearms training outlined in s. 493.6115.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 11, ch. 91-248; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 15, ch. 94-172; s. 3, ch. 2006-165; s. 14, ch. 2011-205.</History></Section>