<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6123" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Publication to industry.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the authority to periodically, through the publication of a newsletter, advise its licensees of information that the department or the advisory council determines is of interest to the industry. Additionally, this newsletter shall contain the name and locality of any licensed or unlicensed person or agency against which the department has filed a final order relative to an administrative complaint and shall contain the final disposition. This newsletter shall be published not less than two or more than four times annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop and make available to each Class “C,” Class “D,” and Class “E” licensee and all interns a pamphlet detailing in plain language the legal authority, rights, and obligations of his or her class of licensure. Within the pamphlet, the department should endeavor to present situations that the licensee may be expected to commonly encounter in the course of doing business pursuant to his or her specific license, and provide to the licensee information on his or her legal options, authority, limits to authority, and obligations. The department shall supplement this with citations to statutes and legal decisions, as well as a selected bibliography that would direct the licensee to materials the study of which would enhance his or her professionalism. The department shall provide a single copy of the appropriate pamphlet without charge to each individual to whom a license is issued, but may charge for additional copies to recover its publication costs. The pamphlet shall be updated every 2 years as necessary to reflect rule or statutory changes, or court decisions. Intervening changes to the regulatory situation shall be noticed in the industry newsletter issued pursuant to subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 537, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>