<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Classes of licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, company, partnership, or corporation which engages in business as a security agency shall have a Class “B” license. A Class “B” license is valid for only one location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each branch office of a Class “B” agency shall have a Class “BB” license. Where a person, firm, company, partnership, or corporation holds both a Class “A” and Class “B” license, each branch office shall have a Class “AB” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs the services of a manager for a:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class “B” security agency or Class “BB” branch office shall have a Class “MB” license. A Class “M” licensee, or a Class “D” licensee who has been so licensed for a minimum of 2 years, may be designated as the manager, in which case the Class “MB” license is not required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class “A” and Class “B” agency or a Class “AB” branch office shall have a Class “M” license.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Class “D” licensee shall own or be an employee of a Class “B” security agency or branch office. This does not include those individuals who are exempt under s. 493.6102(4) but who possess a Class “D” license solely for the purpose of holding a Class “G” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs the services of a security officer shall have a Class “D” license. However, a Class “C” licensee or a Class “CC” licensee may perform bodyguard services without a Class “D” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only Class “M,” Class “MB,” or Class “D” licensees are permitted to bear a firearm, and any such licensee who bears a firearm shall also have a Class “G” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who operates a security officer school or training facility must have a Class “DS” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who teaches or instructs at a Class “DS” security officer school or training facility must have a Class “DI” license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 10, ch. 91-248; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 13, ch. 94-172; s. 71, ch. 95-144; s. 7, ch. 96-407; s. 9, ch. 97-248.</History></Section>