<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any individual, firm, company, agency, organization, partnership, or corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means any person licensed under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal pronoun “he” or the personal pronoun “she” implies the impersonal pronoun “it.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Principal officer” means an individual who holds the office of president, vice president, secretary, or treasurer in a corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Advertising” means the submission of bids, contracting, or making known by any public notice or solicitation of business, directly or indirectly, that services regulated under this chapter are available for consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Good moral character” means a personal history of honesty, fairness, and respect for the rights and property of others and for the laws of this state and nation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Conviction” means an adjudication of guilt by a federal or state court resulting from plea or trial, regardless of whether imposition of sentence was suspended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unarmed” means that no firearm shall be carried by the licensee while providing services regulated by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Branch office” means each additional location of an agency where business is actively conducted which advertises as performing or is engaged in the business authorized by the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sponsor” means any Class “C,” Class “MA,” or Class “M” licensee who supervises and maintains under his or her direction and control a Class “CC” intern; or any Class “E” or Class “MR” licensee who supervises and maintains under his or her direction and control a Class “EE” intern.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intern” means an individual who studies as a trainee or apprentice under the direction and control of a designated sponsoring licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manager” means any licensee who directs the activities of licensees at any agency or branch office. The manager shall be assigned to and shall primarily operate from the agency or branch office location for which he or she has been designated as manager.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Firearm instructor” means any Class “K” licensee who provides classroom or range instruction to applicants for a Class “G” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private investigative agency” means any person who, for consideration, advertises as providing or is engaged in the business of furnishing private investigations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private investigator” means any individual who, for consideration, advertises as providing or performs private investigation. This does not include an informant who, on a one-time or limited basis, as a result of a unique expertise, ability, vocation, or special access and who, under the direction and control of a Class “C” licensee or a Class “MA” licensee, provides information or services that would otherwise be included in the definition of private investigation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private investigation” means the investigation by a person or persons for the purpose of obtaining information with reference to any of the following matters:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crime or wrongs done or threatened against the United States or any state or territory of the United States, when operating under express written authority of the governmental official responsible for authorizing such investigation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity, habits, conduct, movements, whereabouts, affiliations, associations, transactions, reputation, or character of any society, person, or group of persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The credibility of witnesses or other persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The whereabouts of missing persons, owners of unclaimed property or escheated property, or heirs to estates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location or recovery of lost or stolen property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The causes and origin of, or responsibility for, fires, libels, slanders, losses, accidents, damage, or injuries to real or personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business of securing evidence to be used before investigating committees or boards of award or arbitration or in the trial of civil or criminal cases and the preparation therefor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Security agency” means any person who, for consideration, advertises as providing or is engaged in the business of furnishing security services, armored car services, or transporting prisoners. This includes any person who utilizes dogs and individuals to provide security services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Security officer” means any individual who, for consideration, advertises as providing or performs bodyguard services or otherwise guards persons or property; attempts to prevent theft or unlawful taking of goods, wares, and merchandise; or attempts to prevent the misappropriation or concealment of goods, wares or merchandise, money, bonds, stocks, choses in action, notes, or other documents, papers, and articles of value or procurement of the return thereof. The term also includes armored car personnel and those personnel engaged in the transportation of prisoners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recovery agency” means any person who, for consideration, advertises as providing or is engaged in the business of performing repossessions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recovery agent” means any individual who, for consideration, advertises as providing or performs repossessions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Repossession” means the recovery of a motor vehicle as defined under s. 320.01(1), a mobile home as defined in s. 320.01(2), a motorboat as defined under s. 327.02, an aircraft as defined in s. 330.27(1), a personal watercraft as defined in s. 327.02, an all-terrain vehicle as defined in s. 316.2074, farm equipment as defined under s. 686.402, or industrial equipment, by an individual who is authorized by the legal owner, lienholder, or lessor to recover, or to collect money payment in lieu of recovery of, that which has been sold or leased under a security agreement that contains a repossession clause. As used in this subsection, the term “industrial equipment” includes, but is not limited to, tractors, road rollers, cranes, forklifts, backhoes, and bulldozers. The term “industrial equipment” also includes other vehicles that are propelled by power other than muscular power and that are used in the manufacture of goods or used in the provision of services. A repossession is complete when a licensed recovery agent is in control, custody, and possession of such repossessed property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Felony” means a criminal offense that is punishable under the laws of this state, or that would be punishable if committed in this state, by death or imprisonment in the state penitentiary; a crime in any other state or a crime against the United States which is designated as a felony; or an offense in any other state, territory, or country punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 10, ch. 94-241; s. 5, ch. 96-407; s. 1137, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 97-248; s. 34, ch. 2001-36; s. 4, ch. 2002-295; s. 1, ch. 2005-143.</History></Section>