<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Classes of licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm, company, partnership, or corporation which engages in business as a recovery agency shall have a Class “R” license. A Class “R” license is valid for only one location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each branch office of a Class “R” agency shall have a Class “RR” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs the services of a manager for a Class “R” recovery agency or a Class “RR” branch office must have a Class “MR” license. A Class “E” licensee may be designated as the manager, in which case the Class “MR” license is not required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs the services of a recovery agent must have a Class “E” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who performs repossession as an intern under the direction and control of a designated, sponsoring Class “E” licensee or a designated, sponsoring Class “MR” licensee shall have a Class “EE” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class “E” or Class “EE” licensees shall own or be an employee of a Class “R” agency or branch office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who operates a recovery agent school or training facility or who conducts an Internet-based training course or a correspondence training course must have a Class “RS” license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who teaches or instructs at a Class “RS” recovery agent school or training facility shall have a Class “RI” license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 14, ch. 91-248; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 7, ch. 93-49; s. 2, ch. 2007-232; s. 16, ch. 2011-205.</History></Section>