<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0493.6116" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sponsorship of interns.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only licensees may sponsor interns. A Class “C,” Class “M,” or Class “MA” licensee may sponsor a Class “CC” private investigator intern; a Class “E” or Class “MR” licensee may sponsor a Class “EE” recovery agent intern.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An internship may not commence until the sponsor has submitted to the department the notice of intent to sponsor. Such notice shall be on a form provided by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Internship is intended to serve as a learning process. Sponsors shall assume a training status by providing direction and control of interns. Sponsors shall only sponsor interns whose place of business is within a 50-mile distance of the sponsor’s place of business and shall not allow interns to operate independently of such direction and control, or require interns to perform activities which do not enhance the intern’s qualification for licensure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No sponsor may sponsor more than six interns at the same time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sponsor shall certify a biannual progress report on each intern and shall certify completion or termination of an internship to the department within 15 days after such completion or termination. The report must be made on a form provided by the department and must include at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The inclusive dates of the internship.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A narrative part explaining the primary duties, types of experiences gained, and the scope of training received.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An evaluation of the performance of the intern and a recommendation regarding future licensure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 11, ch. 90-364; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 8, ch. 94-172; s. 68, ch. 95-144.</History></Section>