<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0642.0331" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for suspension or revocation of certificate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate of authority of an insurer, whether issued pursuant to this chapter or the insurance code, may be revoked or suspended, or the office may refuse to renew a certificate of authority, if the office determines that the insurer:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has violated any lawful rule or order of the commission or office or any provision of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in an unsound financial condition which would render its further transaction of business in this state hazardous or injurious to its policyholders, its certificateholders, or the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is using such methods or practices in the conduct of its business so as to render its further transaction of business in this state hazardous or injurious to its policyholders, its certificateholders, or the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has refused to be examined or to produce its accounts, records, or files for examination, or if any of its officers have refused to give information with respect to its affairs or have refused to perform any other legal obligation as to such examination, when required by the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to pay any final judgment rendered against it in this state within 60 days after the judgment became final.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without just cause has refused to pay proper claims or perform services arising under its policies or contracts; without just cause has compelled policyholders or certificateholders to accept less than the amount due them; or has employed attorneys, or has brought suit against the association, to secure full payment or settlement of such claims.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is affiliated with, and under the same general management or interlocking directorate or ownership as, another insurer which transacts business in this state without having a certificate of authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, pursuant to s. 120.60, in its discretion and without advance notice or hearing thereon, immediately suspend the certificate of any insurer, whether such certificate was issued pursuant to this chapter or the insurance code, if it finds that one or more of the following circumstances exist:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The insurer is insolvent or impaired.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The deposit required by s. 642.023 is not being maintained.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proceedings for receivership, conservatorship, or rehabilitation or other delinquency proceedings regarding the insurer have been commenced in any state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial condition or business practices of the insurer otherwise pose an imminent threat to the public health, safety, or welfare of the residents of this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 9, 21, ch. 83-278; ss. 6, 7, ch. 93-147; s. 1643, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>