<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.1504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Amended certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation authorized to conduct its affairs in this state shall make application to the Department of State to obtain an amended certificate of authority if it changes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its corporate name;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The period of its duration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose or purposes which it intends to pursue in this state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of its incorporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such application shall be made within 90 days after the occurrence of any change mentioned in subsection (1), shall be made on forms prescribed by the department, shall be executed and filed in the same manner as an original application for authority, and shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the foreign corporation as it appears on the department’s records;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of its incorporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date it was authorized to conduct its affairs in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the name of the foreign corporation has changed, the name relinquished, the new name, a statement that the change of name has been effected under the laws of the jurisdiction of its incorporation, and the date the change was effected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the period of duration has changed, a statement of such change and the date the change was effected;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the jurisdiction of incorporation has changed, a statement of such change and the date the change was effected; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the purposes that the corporation intends to pursue in this state have changed, a statement of such new purposes, and a further statement that the corporation is authorized to pursue such purposes in the jurisdiction of its incorporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of s. 617.1503 for obtaining an original certificate of authority apply to obtaining an amended certificate under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 94, ch. 90-179; s. 64, ch. 93-281; s. 46, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>