<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.1531" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Procedure for and effect of revocation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Department of State determines that one or more grounds exist under s. 617.1530 for revocation of a certificate of authority, the Department of State shall serve the foreign corporation with notice of its intent to revoke the foreign corporation’s certificate of authority. If the foreign corporation has provided the department with an electronic mail address, such notice shall be by electronic transmission. Revocation for failure to file an annual report shall occur on the fourth Friday in September of each year. The Department of State shall issue a certificate of revocation to each revoked corporation. Issuance of the certificate of revocation may be by electronic transmission to any foreign corporation that has provided the department with an electronic mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the foreign corporation does not correct each ground for revocation under s. 617.1530(2)-(7) or demonstrate to the reasonable satisfaction of the Department of State that each ground determined by the Department of State does not exist within 60 days after issuance of notice, the Department of State shall revoke the foreign corporation’s certificate of authority by issuing a certificate of revocation that recites the ground or grounds for revocation and its effective date. Issuance of the certificate of revocation may be by electronic transmission to any foreign corporation that has provided the department with an electronic mail address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority of a foreign corporation to conduct its affairs in this state ceases on the date shown on the certificate revoking its certificate of authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation of a foreign corporation’s certificate of authority does not terminate the authority of the registered agent of the corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 103, ch. 90-179; s. 20, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>