<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.1401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Voluntary dissolution of corporation prior to conducting its affairs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time after the filing of the articles of incorporation, a corporation which has not commenced to conduct its affairs may be voluntarily dissolved in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there are no directors of the corporation, by the incorporator or, if there is more than one incorporator, by a majority of the incorporators; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there are directors of the corporation, by a majority of the directors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Articles of dissolution must be executed in accordance with s. 617.01201 and must set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date of filing of its articles of incorporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the corporation has not commenced to conduct its affairs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That no debts of the corporation remain unpaid; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the incorporator or a majority of the incorporators or a majority of the directors, as the case may be, authorized the dissolution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of dissolution must be filed and shall become effective in accordance with s. 617.1403, may be revoked in accordance with s. 617.1404, and shall have the effect prescribed in s. 617.1405.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 80, ch. 90-179; s. 61, ch. 93-281.</History></Section>