<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0835" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited activities by private foundations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, section references, unless otherwise indicated, refer to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, Title 26 of the United States Code, including corresponding provisions of any subsequent federal tax laws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation, during the period it is a “private foundation” as defined in s. 509(a), may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage in any act of “self-dealing,” as defined in s. 4941(d), which would give rise to any liability for the tax imposed by s. 4941(a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retain any “excess business holdings,” as defined in s. 4943(c), which would give rise to any liability for the tax imposed by s. 4943(a);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any investment which would jeopardize the carrying out of any of its exempt purposes, within the meaning of s. 4944, so as to give rise to any liability for the tax imposed by s. 4944(a); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any “taxable expenditures,” as defined in s. 4945(d), which would give rise to any liability for the tax imposed by s. 4945(a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporation, during the period it is a “private foundation” as defined in s. 509, shall distribute, for the purposes specified in its articles of incorporation or organization, for each taxable year, amounts at least sufficient to avoid liability for the tax imposed by s. 4942(a).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsections (2) and (3) do not apply to any corporation to the extent that a court of competent jurisdiction determines that such application would be contrary to the terms of the articles of incorporation or organization or other instrument governing such corporation or governing the administration of charitable funds held by it and that the same may not properly be changed to conform to such subsections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not impair the rights and powers of the courts or of the Department of Legal Affairs with respect to any corporation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 90-179.</History></Section>