<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0809" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board vacancy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 617.0808(1)(f), any vacancy occurring on the board of directors may be filled by the affirmative vote of the majority of the remaining directors, even though the remaining directors constitute less than a quorum, or by the sole remaining director or, if the vacancy is not so filled or if no director remains, by the members or, on the application of any person, by the circuit court of the county where the registered office of the corporation is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a vacancy occurs with respect to a director elected by a class, chapter, unit, or group, the vacancy may be filled only by members of that class, chapter, unit, or group, or by a majority of the directors then in office elected by such class, chapter, unit, or group.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of a director elected or appointed to fill a vacancy expires at the next annual meeting at which directors are elected. Any directorship to be filled by reason of an increase in the number of directors may be filled by the board of directors, but only for a term of office continuing until the next election of directors by the members or, if the corporation has no members or no members having the right to vote thereon, for such term of office as is provided in the articles of incorporation or the bylaws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vacancy that will occur at a specific later date, by reason of a resignation effective at a later date under s. 617.0807 or otherwise, may be filled before the vacancy occurs. However, the new director may not take office until the vacancy occurs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 90-179; s. 86, ch. 97-102; s. 29, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>