<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0701" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Meetings of members, generally; failure to hold annual meeting; special meeting; consent to corporate actions without meetings; waiver of notice of meetings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The frequency of all meetings of members, the time and manner of notice of such meetings, the conduct and adjournment of such meetings, the determination of members entitled to notice or to vote at such meetings, and the number or voting power of members necessary to constitute a quorum, shall be determined by or in accordance with the articles of incorporation or the bylaws. The place and time of all meetings may be determined by the board of directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to hold an annual meeting does not cause a forfeiture or give cause for dissolution of the corporation, nor does such failure affect otherwise valid corporate acts, except as provided in s. 617.1430 in the case of a deadlock among the directors or the members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in the articles of incorporation or bylaws, special meetings of the members may be called by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair of the board of directors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other officers or persons as are provided for in the articles of incorporation or the bylaws;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The holders of at least 5 percent of the voting power of a corporation when one or more written demands for the meeting, which describe the purpose for which the meeting is to be held, are signed, dated, and delivered to a corporate officer; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who signs a demand for a special meeting pursuant to paragraph (e) if notice for a special meeting is not given within 30 days after receipt of the demand. The person signing the demand may set the time and place of the meeting and give notice under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation, action required or permitted by this chapter to be taken at an annual or special meeting of members may be taken without a meeting, without prior notice, and without a vote if the action is taken by the members entitled to vote on such action and having not less than the minimum number of votes necessary to authorize such action at a meeting at which all members entitled to vote on such action were present and voted.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be effective, the action must be evidenced by one or more written consents describing the action taken, dated and signed by approving members having the requisite number of votes and entitled to vote on such action, and delivered to the corporation to its principal office in this state, its principal place of business, the corporate secretary, or another officer or agent of the corporation having custody of the book in which proceedings of meetings of members are recorded. Written consent to take the corporate action referred to in the consent is not effective unless the consent is signed by members having the requisite number of votes necessary to authorize the action within 90 days after the date of the earliest dated consent and is delivered in the manner required by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any written consent may be revoked prior to the date that the corporation receives the required number of consents to authorize the proposed action. A revocation is not effective unless in writing and until received by the corporation at its principal office in this state or its principal place of business, or received by the corporate secretary or other officer or agent of the corporation having custody of the book in which proceedings of meetings of members are recorded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after obtaining authorization by written consent, notice must be given to those members who are entitled to vote on the action but who have not consented in writing. The notice must fairly summarize the material features of the authorized action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A consent signed under this section has the effect of a meeting vote and may be described as such in any document.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the action to which the members consent is such as would have required the filing of articles or a certificate under any other section of this chapter if such action had been voted on by members at a meeting, the articles or certificate filed under such other section must state that written consent has been given in accordance with this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever action is taken pursuant to this section, the written consent of the members consenting to such action or the written reports of inspectors appointed to tabulate such consents must be filed with the minutes of member proceedings.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of a meeting of members need not be given to any member who signs a waiver of notice, in person or by proxy, either before or after the meeting. Unless required by the bylaws, neither the affairs transacted nor the purpose of the meeting need be specified in the waiver.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attendance of a member at a meeting, either in person or by proxy, constitutes waiver of notice and waiver of any and all objections to the place of the meeting, the time of the meeting, or the manner in which it has been called or convened, unless the member attends a meeting solely for the purpose of stating, at the beginning of the meeting, any such objection or objections to the transaction of affairs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1) and (3) do not apply to any corporation that is an association as defined in s. 720.301; a corporation regulated by chapter 718, chapter 719, chapter 720, chapter 721, or chapter 723; or a corporation where membership in such corporation is required pursuant to a document recorded in the county property records.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 90-179; s. 49, ch. 95-274; s. 81, ch. 97-102; s. 53, ch. 2000-258; s. 21, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>