<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0802" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications of directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directors must be natural persons who are 18 years of age or older but need not be residents of this state or members of the corporation unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws so require. For a corporation organized according to the provisions of s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, but not for a corporation regulated by chapter 718, chapter 719, chapter 720, chapter 721, or chapter 723 or a corporation for which membership in such corporation is required pursuant to a document recorded in the county property records, one director may be 15 years of age or older if so permitted in the articles of incorporation or bylaws or by resolution of the board of directors. The articles of incorporation or the bylaws may prescribe additional qualifications for directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that the eligibility to serve as a member of the board of directors of a condominium association, cooperative association, homeowners’ association, or mobile home owners’ association is restricted to membership in such association and membership is appurtenant to ownership of a unit, parcel, or mobile home, a grantor of a trust described in s. 733.707(3), or a beneficiary as defined in former s. 737.303(4)(b) of a trust which owns a unit, parcel, or mobile home shall be deemed a member of the association and eligible to serve as a director of the condominium association, cooperative association, homeowners’ association, or mobile home owners’ association, provided that said beneficiary occupies the unit, parcel, or mobile home.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 39, ch. 90-179; s. 3, ch. 99-382; s. 143, ch. 2008-4; s. 18, ch. 2008-5; s. 26, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>