<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.1007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restated articles of incorporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation’s board of directors may restate its articles of incorporation at any time with or without a vote of the members.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The restatement may include one or more amendments to the articles of incorporation. If the restatement includes an amendment requiring member approval, it must be adopted as provided in s. 617.1002.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation restating its articles of incorporation shall deliver to the department for filing articles of restatement, executed in accordance with s. 617.01201, setting forth the name of the corporation and the text of the restated articles of incorporation together with a certificate setting forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the restatement contains an amendment to the articles of incorporation requiring member approval and, if it does not, that the board of directors adopted the restatement; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the restatement contains an amendment to the articles of incorporation requiring member approval, the information required by s. 617.1006.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duly adopted restated articles of incorporation supersede the original articles of incorporation and all amendments to them.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may certify restated articles of incorporation, as the articles of incorporation currently in effect, without including the certificate information required by subsection (3).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 66, ch. 90-179; s. 60, ch. 93-281; s. 34, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>