<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0617.1809" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited agricultural association; conversion to a domestic corporation not for profit.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “limited agricultural association” or “association” means a limited agricultural association formed under ss. 604.09-604.14.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited agricultural association may convert to a domestic corporation not for profit by filing the following documents with the department in accordance with s. 617.01201:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of conversion, which must be executed by a person authorized in s. 617.01201(6) and such other persons that may be required in the association’s articles of association or bylaws.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Articles of incorporation, which must comply with s. 617.0202 and be executed by a person authorized in s. 617.01201(6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate of conversion must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date upon which the association was initially formed under ss. 604.09-604.14.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the association immediately before filing the certificate of conversion.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the domestic corporation as set forth in its articles of incorporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective date of the conversion. If the conversion does not take effect upon filing the certificate of conversion and articles of incorporation, the delayed effective date for the conversion, subject to the limitation in s. 617.0123(2), must be a date certain and the same as the effective date of the articles of incorporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the certificate of conversion and articles of incorporation are filed with the department, or upon the delayed effective date, the association is converted to the domestic corporation, and the corporation becomes subject to this chapter. However, notwithstanding s. 617.0123, the existence of the corporation is deemed to have commenced when the association was initially formed under ss. 604.09-604.14.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conversion of a limited agricultural association to a domestic corporation does not affect any obligation or liability of the association that was incurred before the conversion.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a conversion takes effect under this section, all rights, privileges, and powers of the converting association, all property, real, personal, and mixed, and all debts due to the association, as well as all other assets and causes of action belonging to the association, are vested in the domestic corporation to which the association is converted and are the property of the corporation as they were of the association. The title to any real property that is vested by deed or otherwise in the converting association does not revert and is not impaired by the operation of this chapter, but all rights of creditors and all liens upon any property of the association are preserved unimpaired, and all debts, liabilities, and duties of the association attach to the domestic corporation and are enforceable against it to the same extent as if the debts, liabilities, and duties had been incurred or contracted by the corporation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited agricultural association is not required to wind up its affairs or pay its liabilities and distribute its assets. Conversion does not constitute a dissolution of the association but is a continuation of the association’s existence in the form of the domestic corporation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before a limited agricultural association may file a certificate of conversion with the department, unless otherwise specified in the association’s articles of association or bylaws, the conversion must be approved by a majority vote of the association’s members, and the articles of incorporation must be approved by the same authorization required for approval of the conversion. As part of the approval, the converting association may provide a plan or other record of conversion which describes the manner and basis of converting the membership interests in the association into membership interests in the domestic corporation. The plan or other record may also contain other provisions relating to the conversion, including, but not limited to, the right of the converting association to abandon the proposed conversion or an effective date for the conversion that is consistent with paragraph (3)(d).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2012-71.</History>
</Section>