<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.1520" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Withdrawal of foreign corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation authorized to conduct its affairs in this state may not withdraw from this state until it obtains a certificate of withdrawal from the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign corporation authorized to conduct its affairs in this state may apply for a certificate of withdrawal by delivering an application to the Department of State for filing. The application shall be made on forms prescribed and furnished by the Department of State and shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the foreign corporation and the jurisdiction under the law of which it is incorporated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it is not conducting its affairs in this state and that it surrenders its authority to conduct its affairs in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That it revokes the authority of its registered agent to accept service on its behalf and appoints the Department of State as its agent for service of process based on a cause of action arising during the time it was authorized to conduct its affairs in this state;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mailing address to which the Department of State may mail a copy of any process served on it under paragraph (c); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commitment to notify the Department of State in the future of any change in its mailing address.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the withdrawal of the corporation is effective, service of process on the Department of State under this section is service on the foreign corporation. Upon receipt of the process, the Department of State shall mail a copy of the process to the foreign corporation at the mailing address set forth under subsection (2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 101, ch. 90-179.</History></Section>