<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.2006" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Incorporation of labor unions or bodies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any group or combination of groups of workers or wage earners, bearing the name labor, organized labor, federation of labor, brotherhood of labor, union labor, union labor committee, trade union, trades union, union labor council, building trades council, building trades union, allied trades union, central labor body, central labor union, federated trades council, local union, state union, national union, international union, district labor council, district labor union, American Federation of Labor, Florida Federation of Labor, or any component parts or significant words of such terms, whether the same be used in juxtaposition or with interspace, may be incorporated under this act.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of ss. 617.02011 and 617.0202, the articles of incorporation for a labor union or body shall set forth the necessity for the incorporation, shall be subscribed to by not less than five persons, and shall be acknowledged by all of the subscribers, who shall also make and subscribe to an oath, to be endorsed on the articles of incorporation, that it is intended in good faith to carry out the purposes and objects set forth in the articles of incorporation. The articles of incorporation shall be filed in the office of the clerk of the circuit court of the county in which the labor union or body is organized, and the approval of the judge of the circuit court shall be obtained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The subscribers of the articles of incorporation shall give notice of their intention to obtain approval thereof by the circuit judge. Such notice shall state the name of the judge, the date the articles of incorporation will be presented, and the general nature and necessity of the articles of incorporation. Notice shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the county in which the labor union or body is organized at least once, or posted at the courthouse door in counties having no newspapers, at least 10 days prior to the date the articles of incorporation will be presented to the judge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When presented to the judge, the articles of incorporation shall be accompanied by a petition, signed and sworn to by the subscribers, stating fully the aims and purposes of such organization and the necessity therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of the articles of incorporation and the petition, and the giving of such notice, the circuit judge to whom such petition may be addressed shall, upon the date stated in such notice, take testimony and inquire into the admissions and purposes of such organization and the necessity therefor, and upon such hearing, if the circuit judge shall be satisfied that the allegations set forth in the petition and articles of incorporation have been substantiated, and shall find that such organization will not be harmful to the community in which it proposes to operate, or to the state, and that it is intended in good faith to carry out the purposes and objects set forth in the articles of incorporation, and that there is a necessity therefor, the judge shall approve the articles of incorporation and endorse his or her approval thereon. Upon the filing of the articles of incorporation with its endorsements thereupon with the Department of State and payment of the filing fees specified in s. 617.0122, the subscribers and their associates and successors shall be a corporation by the name given.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may intervene by filing an answer to the petition stating his or her reasons, if any, and be heard thereon, why the circuit judge shall not approve the articles of incorporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existence, amendment of the articles of incorporation, and dissolution of any such corporation shall be in accordance with this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 121, ch. 90-179; s. 106, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>