<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.1101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Plan of merger.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any two or more domestic corporations may merge into one domestic corporation pursuant to a plan of merger approved in the manner provided in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each corporation must adopt a plan of merger setting forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of the corporations proposing to merge and the name of the surviving corporation into which each other corporation plans to merge, which is designated as the surviving corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and conditions of the proposed merger;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of any changes in the articles of incorporation of the surviving corporation to be effected by such merger; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manner and basis, if any, of converting the memberships of each merging corporation into memberships, obligations, or securities of the surviving corporation or any other corporation or, in whole or in part, into cash or other property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan of merger may set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amendments to, or a restatement of, the articles of incorporation of the surviving corporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effective date of the merger, which may be on or after the date of filing the articles of incorporation or merger; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other provisions relating to the merger.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 69, ch. 90-179; s. 35, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>