<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.1433" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Judgment of dissolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If after a hearing the court determines that one or more grounds for judicial dissolution described in s. 617.1430 exist, it may enter a judgment dissolving the corporation and specifying the effective date of the dissolution, and the clerk of the court shall deliver a certified copy of the judgment to the Department of State, which shall file it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After entering the judgment of dissolution, the court shall direct the winding up and liquidation of the corporation’s affairs in accordance with ss. 617.1405 and 617.1406, subject to the provisions of subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding for judicial dissolution, the court may require all creditors of the corporation to file with the clerk of the court or with the receiver, in such form as the court may prescribe, proofs under oath of their respective claims. If the court requires the filing of claims, it shall fix a date, which shall be not less than 4 months after the date of the order, as the last day for filing of claims. The court shall prescribe the deadline for filing claims that shall be given to creditors and claimants. Prior to the date so fixed, the court may extend the time for the filing of claims by court order. Creditors and claimants failing to file proofs of claim on or before the date so fixed may be barred, by order of court, from participating in the distribution of the assets of the corporation. Nothing in this section affects the enforceability of any recorded mortgage or lien or the perfected security interest or rights of a person in possession of real or personal property.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 89, ch. 90-179; s. 62, ch. 93-281.</History></Section>