<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filing duties of Department of State.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a document delivered to the Department of State for filing satisfies the requirements of s. 617.01201, the Department of State shall file it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State files a document by stamping or otherwise endorsing “filed,” together with the Secretary of State’s official title and the date and time of receipt. After filing a document, the Department of State shall deliver the acknowledgment of filing or a certified copy to the domestic or foreign corporation or its representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Department of State refuses to file a document, it shall return it to the domestic or foreign corporation or its representative within 15 days after the document was received for filing, together with a brief, written explanation of the reason for refusal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State’s duty to file documents under this section is ministerial. The filing or refusing to file a document does not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affect the validity or invalidity of the document in whole or part;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relate to the correctness or incorrectness of information contained in the document; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create a presumption that the document is valid or invalid or that information contained in the document is correct or incorrect.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If not otherwise provided by law and the provisions of this act, the Department of State shall determine, by rule, the appropriate format for, number of copies of, manner of execution of, method of electronic transmission of, and amount of and method of payment of fees for, any document placed under its jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 90-179.</History></Section>