<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0830" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General standards for directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director shall discharge his or her duties as a director, including his or her duties as a member of a committee:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In good faith;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the care an ordinarily prudent person in a like position would exercise under similar circumstances; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a manner he or she reasonably believes to be in the best interests of the corporation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In discharging his or her duties, a director may rely on information, opinions, reports, or statements, including financial statements and other financial data, if prepared or presented by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more officers or employees of the corporation whom the director reasonably believes to be reliable and competent in the matters presented;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legal counsel, public accountants, or other persons as to matters the director reasonably believes are within the persons’ professional or expert competence; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A committee of the board of directors of which he or she is not a member if the director reasonably believes the committee merits confidence.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director is not acting in good faith if he or she has knowledge concerning the matter in question that makes reliance otherwise permitted by subsection (2) unwarranted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A director is not liable for any action taken as a director, or any failure to take any action, if he or she performed the duties of his or her office in compliance with this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 52, ch. 90-179; s. 90, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>