<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice under this act must be in writing, unless oral notice is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expressly authorized by the articles of incorporation or the bylaws; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reasonable under the circumstances.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice may be communicated in person; by telephone (where oral notice is permitted), telegraph, teletype, or other form of electronic transmission; or by mail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written notice by a domestic or foreign corporation authorized to conduct its affairs in this state to its member, if in a comprehensible form, is effective:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When mailed, if mailed postpaid and correctly addressed to the member’s address shown in the corporation’s current record of members;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When actually transmitted by facsimile telecommunication, if correctly directed to a number at which the member has consented to receive notice;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When actually transmitted by electronic mail, if correctly directed to an electronic mail address at which the member has consented to receive notice;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When posted on an electronic network that the member has consented to consult, upon the later of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such correct posting; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The giving of a separate notice to the member of the fact of such specific posting; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When correctly transmitted to the member, if by any other form of electronic transmission consented to by the member to whom notice is given.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent by a member to receive notice by electronic transmission shall be revocable by the member by written notice to the corporation. Any such consent shall be deemed revoked if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation is unable to deliver by electronic transmission two consecutive notices given by the corporation in accordance with such consent; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such inability becomes known to the secretary or an assistant secretary of the corporation, or other authorized person responsible for the giving of notice. However, the inadvertent failure to treat such inability as a revocation does not invalidate any meeting or other action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written notice to a domestic or foreign corporation authorized to conduct its affairs in this state may be addressed to its registered agent at its registered office or to the corporation or its secretary at its principal office shown in its most recent annual report or, in the case of a corporation that has not yet delivered an annual report, in a domestic corporation’s articles of incorporation or in a foreign corporation’s application for certificate of authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (3) or elsewhere in this act, written notice, if in a comprehensible form, is effective at the earliest date of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When received;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five days after its deposit in the United States mail, as evidenced by the postmark, if mailed postpaid and correctly addressed; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On the date shown on the return receipt, if sent by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, and the receipt is signed by or on behalf of the addressee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Oral notice is effective when communicated if communicated directly to the person to be notified in a comprehensible manner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affidavit of the secretary, an assistant secretary, the transfer agent, or other authorized agent of the corporation that the notice has been given by a form of electronic transmission is, in the absence of fraud, prima facie evidence of the facts stated in the notice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If this act prescribes notice requirements for particular circumstances, those requirements govern. If articles of incorporation or bylaws prescribe notice requirements not less stringent than the requirements of this section or other provisions of this act, those requirements govern.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 90-179; s. 2, ch. 2003-14.</History></Section>