<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0834" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Officers and directors of certain corporations and associations not for profit; immunity from civil liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer or director of a nonprofit organization recognized under s. 501(c)(3) or s. 501(c)(4) or s. 501(c)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, or of an agricultural or a horticultural organization recognized under s. 501(c)(5), of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, is not personally liable for monetary damages to any person for any statement, vote, decision, or failure to take an action, regarding organizational management or policy by an officer or director, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officer or director breached or failed to perform his or her duties as an officer or director; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officer’s or director’s breach of, or failure to perform, his or her duties constitutes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the criminal law, unless the officer or director had reasonable cause to believe his or her conduct was lawful or had no reasonable cause to believe his or her conduct was unlawful. A judgment or other final adjudication against an officer or director in any criminal proceeding for violation of the criminal law estops that officer or director from contesting the fact that his or her breach, or failure to perform, constitutes a violation of the criminal law, but does not estop the officer or director from establishing that he or she had reasonable cause to believe that his or her conduct was lawful or had no reasonable cause to believe that his or her conduct was unlawful;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transaction from which the officer or director derived an improper personal benefit, directly or indirectly; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recklessness or an act or omission that was committed in bad faith or with malicious purpose or in a manner exhibiting wanton and willful disregard of human rights, safety, or property.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Recklessness” means the acting, or omission to act, in conscious disregard of a risk:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Known, or so obvious that it should have been known, to the officer or director; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Known to the officer or director, or so obvious that it should have been known, to be so great as to make it highly probable that harm would follow from such action or omission.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means a person who serves as a director, trustee, or member of the governing board of an organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Officer” means a person who serves as an officer without compensation except reimbursement for actual expenses incurred or to be incurred.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 54, ch. 90-179; s. 92, ch. 97-102; s. 33, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>