<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corporate name.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporate name:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must contain the word “corporation” or “incorporated” or the abbreviation “corp.” or “inc.” or words or abbreviations of like import in language, as will clearly indicate that it is a corporation instead of a natural person, unincorporated association, or partnership. The name of the corporation may not contain the word “company” or its abbreviation “co.”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May contain the word “cooperative” or “co-op” only if the resulting name is distinguishable from the name of any corporation, agricultural cooperative marketing association, or nonprofit cooperative association existing or doing business in this state under chapter 607, chapter 618, or chapter 619;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not contain language stating or implying that the corporation is organized for a purpose other than that permitted in this act and its articles of incorporation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not contain language stating or implying that the corporation is connected with a state or federal government agency or a corporation chartered under the laws of the United States; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be distinguishable from the names of all other entities or filings, except fictitious name registrations pursuant to s. 865.09, organized, registered, or reserved under the laws of this state, that are on file with the Division of Corporations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any corporation eligible to reincorporate under s. 617.0901, may do so and retain its corporate name, subject to the requirements of paragraphs (1)(a) and (b).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 90-179; s. 51, ch. 93-281.</History></Section>