<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0617.0505" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Distributions; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as authorized in s. 617.1302, a corporation may not make distributions to its members, directors, or officers.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mutual benefit corporation, such as a private club that is established for social, pleasure, or recreational purposes and that is organized as a corporation of which the equity interests are held by the members, may, subject to s. 617.1302, purchase the equity membership interest of any member, and the payment for such interest is not a distribution for purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation may pay compensation in a reasonable amount to its members, directors, or officers for services rendered, may confer benefits upon its members in conformity with its purposes, and, upon dissolution or final liquidation, may make distributions to its members as permitted by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If expressly permitted by its articles of incorporation, a corporation may make distributions upon partial liquidation to its members, as permitted by this section. Any such payment, benefit, or distribution does not constitute a dividend or a distribution of income or profit for purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation that is a utility exempt from regulation under s. 367.022(7), whose articles of incorporation state that it is exempt from taxation under s. 501(c)(12) of the Internal Revenue Code, may make refunds to its members, prior to a dissolution or liquidation, as its managing board deems necessary to establish or preserve its tax-exempt status. Any such refund does not constitute a dividend or a distribution of income or profit for purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corporation that is regulated by chapter 718, chapter 719, chapter 720, chapter 721, or chapter 723, or a corporation where membership in such corporation is required pursuant to a document recorded in the county property records, may make refunds to its members, giving credits to its members, disbursing insurance proceeds to its members, or disbursing or paying settlements to its members without violating this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 90-179; s. 2, ch. 96-343; s. 15, ch. 2005-267; s. 15, ch. 2009-205.</History></Section>