<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0507.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Estimates and contracts for service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before providing any moving or accessorial services, a contract and estimate must be provided to a prospective shipper in writing, must be signed and dated by the shipper and the mover, and must include:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, telephone number, and physical address where the mover’s employees are available during normal business hours.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date the contract or estimate is prepared and any proposed date of the move.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the shipper, the addresses where the articles are to be picked up and delivered, and a telephone number where the shipper may be reached.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, telephone number, and physical address of any location where the goods will be held pending further transportation, including situations where the mover retains possession of goods pending resolution of a fee dispute with the shipper.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An itemized breakdown and description and total of all costs and services for loading, transportation or shipment, unloading, and accessorial services to be provided during a household move or storage of household goods.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acceptable forms of payment. A mover shall accept a minimum of two of the three following forms of payment:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash, cashier’s check, money order, or traveler’s check;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Valid personal check, showing upon its face the name and address of the shipper or authorized representative; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Valid credit card, which shall include, but not be limited to, Visa or MasterCard.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A mover must clearly and conspicuously disclose to the shipper in the estimate and contract for services the forms of payments the mover will accept, including the forms of payment described in paragraphs (a)-(c).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-53; s. 64, ch. 2003-1; s. 7, ch. 2006-4.</History></Section>