<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0069.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State named party; lien foreclosure, suit to quiet title.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under the conditions prescribed in this section for the protection of the state, the state may be named a party to a civil action in any court of this state, or in any district court of the United States, having jurisdiction of the subject matter, either:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To quiet title to real property wherein the state has or claims any adverse interest in the title to real estate; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the foreclosure of a mortgage or other lien on real or personal property on which the state has or claims a mortgage or other lien.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The complaint shall set forth with particularity the nature of the interest claimed by the state in such real property with respect to quiet title proceedings. In the case of mortgage or lien foreclosure, the complaint shall set forth with particularity the nature of the lien claimed by the state in such real property.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A judicial sale in a mortgage foreclosure action shall have the same effect respecting the discharge of the property from liens and encumbrances held by the state as is provided about such matters by the law of this state. A sale to satisfy a lien inferior to one of the state shall be made subject to and without disturbing the lien of the state, unless the state consents that the property may be sold free of its liens and the proceeds divided as the parties may be entitled.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue has the right to participate in the disbursement of funds remaining in the registry of the court after distribution pursuant to s. 45.031(7). The department shall participate in accordance with applicable procedures in any mortgage foreclosure action in which the department has a duly filed tax warrant, or interests under a lien arising from a judgment, order, or decree for support, as defined in s. 409.2554, or interest in a reemployment assistance tax lien under contract with the Department of Economic Opportunity through an interagency agreement pursuant to s. 443.1316, against the subject property and with the same priority, regardless of whether a default against the department, the Department of Economic Opportunity, or the former Agency for Workforce Innovation has been entered for failure to file an answer or other responsive pleading.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a duly filed tax warrant, paragraph (a) applies only to mortgage foreclosure actions initiated on or after July 1, 1994, and to those mortgage foreclosure actions initiated before July 1, 1994, in which no default has been entered against the Department of Revenue before July 1, 1994. With respect to mortgage foreclosure actions initiated based upon interests under a lien arising from a judgment, order, or decree for support, paragraph (a) applies only to mortgage foreclosure actions initiated on or after July 1, 1998, and to those mortgage foreclosure actions initiated before July 1, 1998, in which no default has been entered against the Department of Revenue before July 1, 1998.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 29724, 1955; s. 23, ch. 67-254; s. 1, ch. 70-326; s. 2, ch. 94-314; s. 2, ch. 94-353; s. 12, ch. 98-397; s. 17, ch. 2001-158; s. 3, ch. 2002-218; s. 2, ch. 2003-36; s. 44, ch. 2011-142; s. 4, ch. 2011-213; s. 39, ch. 2012-30.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 69.17-69.19.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>