<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0106.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Campaign fund raisers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No campaign fund raiser may be held unless the person for whom such funds are to be so used is a candidate for public office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All money and contributions received with respect to such a campaign fund raiser shall be deemed to be campaign contributions, and shall be accounted for, and subject to the same restrictions, as other campaign contributions. All expenditures made with respect to such a campaign fund raiser which are made or reimbursed by a check drawn on the campaign depository of the candidate for whom the funds are to be used and shall be deemed to be campaign expenditures to be accounted for, and subject to the same restrictions, as other campaign expenditures.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any tickets or advertising for such a campaign fund raiser is exempt from the requirements of s. 106.143.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or candidate who holds a campaign fund raiser, or consents to a campaign fund raiser being held, in violation of the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to any campaign fund raiser held on behalf of a political party by the state or county executive committee or an affiliated party committee of such party, provided that the proceeds of such campaign fund raiser are reported pursuant to s. 106.29.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 40, ch. 77-175; s. 51, ch. 81-259; s. 24, ch. 81-304; s. 27, ch. 83-217; s. 4, ch. 89-256; ss. 7, 30, ch. 2011-6; s. 56, ch. 2011-40; HJR 7105, 2011 Regular Session.</History>
</Section>