<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0106.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petty cash funds allowed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each campaign treasurer designated pursuant to s. 106.021(1) for a candidate or political committee is authorized to withdraw from the primary campaign account, until the close of the last day for qualifying for office, the amount of $500 per calendar quarter reporting period for the purpose of providing a petty cash fund for the candidate or political committee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following the close of the last day for qualifying and until the last election in a given election period in which the political committee participates, the campaign treasurer of each political committee is authorized to withdraw the following amount each week from the primary depository campaign account for the purpose of providing a petty cash fund for the political committee, and, following the close of the last day for qualifying and until the election at which such candidate is eliminated or elected to office, or the time at which the candidate becomes unopposed, the campaign treasurer of each candidate is authorized to withdraw the following amount each week from the primary depository campaign account for the purpose of providing a petty cash fund for the candidate:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all candidates for nomination or election on a statewide basis, $500 per week.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all other candidates and all political committees, $100 per week.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petty cash fund so provided shall be spent only in amounts less than $100 and only for office supplies, transportation expenses, and other necessities. Petty cash shall not be used for the purchase of time, space, or services from communications media as defined in s. 106.011(13).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 73-128; s. 48, ch. 77-175; s. 9, ch. 85-226; s. 5, ch. 2002-197.</History></Section>