<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0106.125" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Credit cards; conditions on use.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any candidate for statewide office or any political committee created to support or oppose any candidate for statewide office or to support or oppose any statewide issue may obtain, and use in making travel-related campaign expenditures, credit cards. The obtention and use of credit cards by any such candidate or political committee shall be subject to the following conditions:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit cards may be obtained only from the same bank which has been designated as the candidate’s or political committee’s primary campaign depository.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Credit cards shall be in the name of the candidate or political committee and shall reflect that the account is a campaign account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before a credit card may be used, a copy of the agreement or contract between the candidate and the bank, or the political committee and the bank, and a list of all persons who have been authorized to use the card shall be filed with the Secretary of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All credit cards issued to candidates or political committees shall expire no later than midnight of the last day of the month of the general election.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each statement rendered by the issuer of a credit card shall be paid upon receipt.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Campaign travel-related expenditures shall include transportation, lodging, meals, and other expenses incurred in connection with traveling for campaign purposes.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This section shall not be deemed to preclude the use of advance payments by a check drawn on the primary depository account for travel-related expenses. The treasurer shall require an accounting of actual expenses and reconcile any overpayment or underpayment to the original payee.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 79-365; s. 2, ch. 86-134.</History></Section>