<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0106.1475" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Telephone solicitation; registered agent requirements; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or organization that conducts any business in this state which consists of making paid telephone calls supporting or opposing any candidate or elected public official must, prior to conducting such business, have and continuously maintain, for at least 180 days following the cessation of such business activities in the state, a registered agent for the purpose of any service of process, notice, or demand required or authorized by law and must file with the division a notice of such registered agent. Such registered agent must be an individual who is a resident of this state, a domestic corporation, or a foreign corporation authorized to do business in this state. However, this subsection does not apply to any person or organization already lawfully registered to conduct business in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, conducting business in this state as specified in subsection (1) includes both placing telephone calls from a location in this state and placing telephone calls from a location outside this state to individuals located in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall create and maintain forms for the notice required by subsection (1), which, at a minimum, must elicit all of the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number of the registered agent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number of the person or organization conducting business in this state as specified in subsection (1).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person or organization conducting business in this state as specified in subsection (1) must immediately notify the division of any changes in the information required in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or organization that violates this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 97-13.</History></Section>