<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0106.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Treasurer to keep records; inspections.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The campaign treasurer of each candidate and the campaign treasurer of each political committee shall keep detailed accounts, current within not more than 2 days after the date of receiving a contribution or making an expenditure, of all contributions received and all expenditures made by or on behalf of the candidate or political committee that are required to be set forth in a statement filed under this chapter. The campaign treasurer shall also keep detailed accounts of all deposits made in any separate interest-bearing account or certificate of deposit and of all withdrawals made therefrom to the primary depository and of all interest earned thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accounts, including separate interest-bearing accounts and certificates of deposit, kept by the campaign treasurer of a candidate or political committee may be inspected under reasonable circumstances before, during, or after the election to which the accounts refer by any authorized representative of the Division of Elections or the Florida Elections Commission. The right of inspection may be enforced by appropriate writ issued by any court of competent jurisdiction. The campaign treasurer of a political committee supporting a candidate may be joined with the campaign treasurer of the candidate as respondent in such a proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accounts kept by a campaign treasurer of a candidate shall be preserved by the campaign treasurer for a number of years equal to the term of office of the office to which the candidate seeks election. Accounts kept by a campaign treasurer of a political committee shall be preserved by such treasurer for at least 2 years after the date of the election to which the accounts refer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 73-128; s. 45, ch. 77-175; s. 3, ch. 79-378; s. 8, ch. 89-256; s. 30, ch. 90-315.</History></Section>