<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0106.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determinations by commission; legal disposition.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criminal proceedings for violations of this chapter or chapter 104 may be brought in the appropriate court of competent jurisdiction. Any such action brought under this chapter or chapter 104 shall be advanced on the docket of the court in which filed and put ahead of all other actions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Civil actions may be brought by the commission for relief, including permanent or temporary injunctions, restraining orders, or any other appropriate order for the imposition of civil penalties provided by this chapter. Such civil actions shall be brought by the commission in the appropriate court of competent jurisdiction, and the venue shall be in the county in which the alleged violation occurred or in which the alleged violator or violators are found, reside, or transact business. Upon a proper showing that such person, political committee, committee of continuous existence, affiliated party committee, or political party has engaged, or is about to engage, in prohibited acts or practices, a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order shall be granted without bond by such court, and the civil fines provided by this chapter may be imposed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Civil actions may be brought to enjoin temporarily the issuance of certificates of election to successful candidates who are alleged to have violated the provisions of this chapter or chapter 104. Such injunctions shall issue upon a showing of probable cause that such violation has occurred. Such actions shall be brought in the circuit court for the circuit in which is located the officer before whom the candidate qualified for office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 73-128; s. 13, ch. 74-200; s. 62, ch. 77-175; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; ss. 8, 14, 15, ch. 90-338; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 37, ch. 98-129; ss. 25, 30, ch. 2011-6; HJR 7105, 2011 Regular Session.</History>
</Section>