<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0106.088" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Independent expenditures; contribution limits; restrictions on affiliated party committees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition of receiving a rebate of party assessments under s. 103.121(1)(b), the leader or treasurer of an affiliated party committee as defined in s. 103.092 shall take and subscribe to an oath or affirmation in writing. During the qualifying period for state candidates and prior to distribution of such funds, a printed copy of the oath or affirmation shall be filed with the Secretary of State and shall be substantially in the following form:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">State of Florida</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">County of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Before me, an officer authorized to administer oaths, personally appeared <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name)</Directions>, to me well known, who, being sworn, says that he or she is the <Directions xml:space="preserve">(title)</Directions> of the <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of party)</Directions><Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of chamber)</Directions> affiliated party committee; that the affiliated party committee has not made, either directly or indirectly, an independent expenditure in support of or opposition to a candidate or elected public official in the prior 6 months; that the affiliated party committee will not make, either directly or indirectly, an independent expenditure in support of or opposition to a candidate or elected public official, through and including the upcoming general election; and that the affiliated party committee will not violate the contribution limits applicable to candidates under s. 106.08(2), Florida Statutes.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of committee officer)</Directions></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Address)</Directions></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Sworn to and subscribed before me this<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule>, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, at <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"></HorizontalRule> County, Florida.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature and title of officer administering oath)</Directions></Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any affiliated party committee found to have violated the provisions of the oath or affirmation prior to receiving funds shall be ineligible to receive the rebate for that general election year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any affiliated party committee found to have violated the provisions of the oath or affirmation after receiving funds shall be ineligible to receive the rebate from candidates qualifying for the following general election cycle.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any funds not distributed to the affiliated party committee pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 30, ch. 2011-6; HJR 7105, 2011 Regular Session.</History>
</Section>