<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0106.1435" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Usage and removal of political campaign advertisements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each candidate, whether for a federal, state, county, or district office, shall make a good faith effort to remove all of his or her political campaign advertisements within 30 days after:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withdrawal of his or her candidacy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been eliminated as a candidate; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being elected to office.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, a candidate is not expected to remove those political campaign advertisements which are in the form of signs used by an outdoor advertising business as provided in chapter 479. The provisions herein do not apply to political campaign advertisements placed on motor vehicles or to campaign messages designed to be worn by persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If political campaign advertisements are not removed within the specified period, the political subdivision or governmental entity has the authority to remove such advertisements and may charge the candidate the actual cost for such removal. Funds collected for removing such advertisements shall be deposited to the general revenue of the political subdivision.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to chapter 479, no political campaign advertisements shall be erected, posted, painted, tacked, nailed, or otherwise displayed, placed, or located on or above any state or county road right-of-way.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officer before whom a candidate qualifies for office shall notify the candidate, in writing, of the provisions in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This provision does not preclude municipalities from imposing additional or more stringent requirements on the usage and removal of political campaign advertisements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-221; s. 20, ch. 84-302; s. 14, ch. 87-224; s. 647, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>