<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0350.042" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Ex parte communications.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commissioner should accord to every person who is legally interested in a proceeding, or the person’s lawyer, full right to be heard according to law, and, except as authorized by law, shall neither initiate nor consider ex parte communications concerning the merits, threat, or offer of reward in any proceeding other than a proceeding under s. 120.54 or s. 120.565, workshops, or internal affairs meetings. No individual shall discuss ex parte with a commissioner the merits of any issue that he or she knows will be filed with the commission within 90 days. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to commission staff.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not prohibit an individual residential ratepayer from communicating with a commissioner, provided that the ratepayer is representing only himself or herself, without compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to oral communications or discussions in scheduled and noticed open public meetings of educational programs or of a conference or other meeting of an association of regulatory agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a commissioner knowingly receives an ex parte communication relative to a proceeding other than as set forth in subsection (1), to which he or she is assigned, he or she must place on the record of the proceeding copies of all written communications received, all written responses to the communications, and a memorandum stating the substance of all oral communications received and all oral responses made, and shall give written notice to all parties to the communication that such matters have been placed on the record. Any party who desires to respond to an ex parte communication may do so. The response must be received by the commission within 10 days after receiving notice that the ex parte communication has been placed on the record. The commissioner may, if he or she deems it necessary to eliminate the effect of an ex parte communication received by him or her, withdraw from the proceeding, in which case the chair shall substitute another commissioner for the proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any individual who makes an ex parte communication shall submit to the commission a written statement describing the nature of such communication, to include the name of the person making the communication, the name of the commissioner or commissioners receiving the communication, copies of all written communications made, all written responses to such communications, and a memorandum stating the substance of all oral communications received and all oral responses made. The commission shall place on the record of a proceeding all such communications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any commissioner who knowingly fails to place on the record any such communications, in violation of the section, within 15 days of the date of such communication is subject to removal and may be assessed a civil penalty not to exceed $5,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the Commission on Ethics to receive and investigate sworn complaints of violations of this section pursuant to the procedures contained in ss. 112.322-112.3241.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Commission on Ethics finds that there has been a violation of this section by a public service commissioner, it shall provide the Governor and the Florida Public Service Commission Nominating Council with a report of its findings and recommendations. The Governor is authorized to enforce the findings and recommendations of the Commission on Ethics, pursuant to part III of chapter 112.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a commissioner fails or refuses to pay the Commission on Ethics any civil penalties assessed pursuant to the provisions of this section, the Commission on Ethics may bring an action in any circuit court to enforce such penalty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, during the course of an investigation by the Commission on Ethics into an alleged violation of this section, allegations are made as to the identity of the person who participated in the ex parte communication, that person must be given notice and an opportunity to participate in the investigation and relevant proceedings to present a defense. If the Commission on Ethics determines that the person participated in the ex parte communication, the person may not appear before the commission or otherwise represent anyone before the commission for a period of 2 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 90-272; s. 532, ch. 95-148; s. 5, ch. 2005-132.</History></Section>