<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0350.0611" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public Counsel; duties and powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the Public Counsel to provide legal representation for the people of the state in proceedings before the commission and in proceedings before counties pursuant to s. 367.171(8). The Public Counsel shall have such powers as are necessary to carry out the duties of his or her office, including, but not limited to, the following specific powers:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To recommend to the commission or the counties, by petition, the commencement of any proceeding or action or to appear, in the name of the state or its citizens, in any proceeding or action before the commission or the counties and urge therein any position which he or she deems to be in the public interest, whether consistent or inconsistent with positions previously adopted by the commission or the counties, and utilize therein all forms of discovery available to attorneys in civil actions generally, subject to protective orders of the commission or the counties which shall be reviewable by summary procedure in the circuit courts of this state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have access to and use of all files, records, and data of the commission or the counties available to any other attorney representing parties in a proceeding before the commission or the counties;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any proceeding in which he or she has participated as a party, to seek review of any determination, finding, or order of the commission or the counties, or of any hearing examiner designated by the commission or the counties, in the name of the state or its citizens;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prepare and issue reports, recommendations, and proposed orders to the commission, the Governor, and the Legislature on any matter or subject within the jurisdiction of the commission, and to make such recommendations as he or she deems appropriate for legislation relative to commission procedures, rules, jurisdiction, personnel, and functions; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To appear before other state agencies, federal agencies, and state and federal courts in connection with matters under the jurisdiction of the commission, in the name of the state or its citizens.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-195; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 6, ch. 87-50; s. 536, ch. 95-148; s. 12, ch. 2000-350; s. 2, ch. 2001-145.</History></Section>