<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1013.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following terms shall be defined as follows for the purpose of this chapter:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ancillary plant” is comprised of the building, site, and site improvements necessary to provide such facilities as vehicle maintenance, warehouses, maintenance, or administrative buildings necessary to provide support services to an educational program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Auxiliary facility” means the spaces located at educational plants which are not designed for student occupant stations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board,” unless otherwise specified, means a district school board, a Florida College System institution board of trustees, a university board of trustees, and the Board of Trustees for the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind. The term “board” does not include the State Board of Education or the Board of Governors.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Capital project,” for the purpose of s. 9(a)(2), Art. XII of the State Constitution, as amended, means sums of money appropriated from the Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund to the state system of public education and other educational agencies as authorized by the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Core facilities” means the media center, cafeteria, toilet facilities, and circulation space of an educational plant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Educational facilities” means the buildings and equipment, structures, and special educational use areas that are built, installed, or established to serve primarily the educational purposes and secondarily the social and recreational purposes of the community and which may lawfully be used as authorized by the Florida Statutes and approved by boards.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Educational plant” comprises the educational facilities, site, and site improvements necessary to accommodate students, faculty, administrators, staff, and the activities of the educational program of each plant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Educational plant survey” means a systematic study of present educational and ancillary plants and the determination of future needs to provide an appropriate educational program and services for each student based on projected capital outlay FTE’s approved by the Department of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Feasibility study” means the examination and analysis of information related to projected educational facilities to determine whether they are reasonable and possible.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Long-range planning” means devising a systematic method based on educational information and needs, carefully analyzed, to provide the facilities to meet the goals and objectives of the educational agency for a period of 5 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Low-energy usage features” means engineering features or devices that supplant or minimize the consumption of fossil fuels by heating equipment and cooling equipment. Such features may include, but are not limited to, high efficiency chillers and boilers, thermal storage tanks, solar energy systems, waste heat recovery systems, and facility load management systems.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Maintenance and repair” means the upkeep of educational and ancillary plants, including, but not limited to, roof or roofing replacement short of complete replacement of membrane or structure; repainting of interior or exterior surfaces; resurfacing of floors; repair or replacement of glass; repair of hardware, furniture, equipment, electrical fixtures, and plumbing fixtures; and repair or resurfacing of parking lots, roads, and walkways. The term “maintenance and repair” does not include custodial or groundskeeping functions, or renovation except for the replacement of equipment with new equipment of equal systems meeting current code requirements, provided that the replacement item neither places increased demand upon utilities services or structural supports nor adversely affects the function of safety to life systems.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Need determination” means the identification of types and amounts of educational facilities necessary to accommodate the educational programs, student population, faculty, administrators, staff, and auxiliary and ancillary services of an educational agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“New construction” means any construction of a building or unit of a building in which the entire work is new or an entirely new addition connected to an existing building or which adds additional square footage to the space inventory.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Passive design elements” means architectural features that minimize heat gain, heat loss, and the use of heating and cooling equipment when ambient conditions are extreme and that permit use of the facility without heating or air-conditioning when ambient conditions are moderate. Such features may include, but are not limited to, building orientation, landscaping, earth bermings, insulation, thermal windows and doors, overhangs, skylights, thermal chimneys, and other design arrangements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public education capital outlay (PECO) funded projects” means site acquisition, renovation, remodeling, construction projects, and site improvements necessary to accommodate buildings, equipment, other structures, and special educational use areas that are built, installed, or established to serve primarily the educational instructional program of the district school board, Florida College System institution board of trustees, or university board of trustees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Remodeling” means the changing of existing facilities by rearrangement of spaces and their use and includes, but is not limited to, the conversion of two classrooms to a science laboratory or the conversion of a closed plan arrangement to an open plan configuration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Renovation” means the rejuvenating or upgrading of existing facilities by installation or replacement of materials and equipment and includes, but is not limited to, interior or exterior reconditioning of facilities and spaces; air-conditioning, heating, or ventilating equipment; fire alarm systems; emergency lighting; electrical systems; and complete roofing or roof replacement, including replacement of membrane or structure. As used in this subsection, the term “materials” does not include instructional materials.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Satisfactory educational facility” means a facility that has been recommended for continued use by an educational plant survey or that has been classified as satisfactory in the state inventory of educational facilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Site” means a space of ground occupied or to be occupied by an educational facility or program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Site development” means work that must be performed on an unimproved site in order to make it usable for the desired purpose or work incidental to new construction or to make an addition usable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Site improvement” means work that must be performed on an existing site to improve its utilization, correct health and safety deficiencies, meet special program needs, or provide additional service areas.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Site improvement incident to construction” means the work that must be performed on a site as an accompaniment to the construction of an educational facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Satellite facility” means the buildings and equipment, structures, and special educational use areas that are built, installed, or established by private business or industry in accordance with chapter 6A-2, Florida Administrative Code, to be used exclusively for educational purposes to serve primarily the students of its employees and that are staffed professionally by the district school board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 797, ch. 2002-387; s. 166, ch. 2007-217; s. 199, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>