<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1013.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">School district educational facilities plan performance and productivity standards; development; measurement; application.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Educational Facilities shall develop and adopt measures for evaluating the performance and productivity of school district educational facilities plans. The measures may be both quantitative and qualitative and must, to the maximum extent practical, assess those factors that are within the districts’ control. The measures must, at a minimum, assess performance in the following areas:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Frugal production of high-quality projects.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Efficient finance and administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Optimal school and classroom size and utilization rate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Safety.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Core facility space needs and cost-effective capacity improvements that consider demographic projections.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Level of district local effort.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall establish annual performance objectives and standards that can be used to evaluate district performance and productivity.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall conduct ongoing evaluations of district educational facilities program performance and productivity, using the measures adopted under this section. If, using these measures, the office finds that a district failed to perform satisfactorily, the office must recommend to the district school board actions to be taken to improve the district’s performance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 2002-296; s. 800, ch. 2002-387; s. 13, ch. 2010-70.</History>
</Section>