<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1013.40" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Planning and construction of Florida College System institution facilities; property acquisition.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The need for Florida College System institution facilities shall be established by a survey conducted pursuant to this chapter. The facilities recommended by such survey must be approved by the State Board of Education, and the projects must be constructed according to the provisions of this chapter and State Board of Education rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No Florida College System institution may expend public funds for the acquisition of additional property without the specific approval of the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No facility may be acquired or constructed by a Florida College System institution or its direct-support organization if such facility requires general revenue funds for operation or maintenance upon project completion or in subsequent years of operation, unless prior approval is received from the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The campus of a Florida College System institution within a municipality designated as an area of critical state concern, as defined in s. 380.05, and having a comprehensive plan and land development regulations containing a building permit allocation system that limits annual growth, may construct dormitories for up to 100 beds for Florida College System institution students. Such dormitories shall be exempt from the building permit allocation system and may be constructed up to 45 feet in height provided that they are otherwise consistent with the comprehensive plan, the Florida College System institution has a hurricane evacuation plan that requires all dormitory occupants to be evacuated 48 hours in advance of tropical force winds, and that transportation is provided for dormitory occupants during an evacuation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 839, ch. 2002-387; s. 4, ch. 2008-213; s. 214, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>