<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1013.737" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Class Size Reduction and Educational Facilities Lottery Revenue Bond Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established the Class Size Reduction and Educational Facilities Lottery Revenue Bond Program.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuance of revenue bonds is authorized to finance or refinance the construction, acquisition, reconstruction, or renovation of educational facilities. Such bonds shall be issued pursuant to and in compliance with the provisions of s. 11(d), Art. VII of the State Constitution, the provisions of the State Bond Act, ss. 215.57-215.83, as amended, and the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bonds are payable from, and secured by a first lien on, the first lottery revenues transferred to the Educational Enhancement Trust Fund each fiscal year, as provided by s. 24.121(2), and do not constitute a general obligation of, or a pledge of the full faith and credit of, the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state hereby covenants with the holders of such revenue bonds that it will not take any action that will materially and adversely affect the rights of such holders so long as bonds authorized by this section are outstanding. The state does hereby additionally authorize the establishment of a covenant in connection with the bonds which provides that any additional funds received by the state from new or enhanced lottery programs; video gaming; banking card games, including baccarat, chemin de fer, or blackjack; electronic or electromechanical facsimiles of any game of chance; casino games; slot machines; or other similar activities will first be available for payments relating to bonds pledging revenues available pursuant to s. 24.121(2), prior to use for any other purpose.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bonds shall be issued by the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration on behalf of the Department of Education in such amount as shall be requested by resolution of the State Board of Education. However, the total principal amount of bonds, excluding refunding bonds, issued pursuant to this section shall not exceed amounts specifically authorized in the General Appropriations Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proceeds available from the sale of the bonds shall be deposited in the Lottery Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund within the Department of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facilities to be financed with the proceeds of such bonds are designated as state fixed capital outlay projects for purposes of s. 11(d), Art. VII of the State Constitution, and the specific facilities to be financed shall be determined in accordance with state law and appropriations from the Educational Enhancement Trust Fund. Projects shall be funded from the Lottery Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund. Each educational facility to be financed with the proceeds of the bonds issued pursuant to this section is hereby approved as required by s. 11(f), Art. VII of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any complaint for validation of such bonds is required to be filed only in the circuit court of the county where the seat of state government is situated. The notice required to be published by s. 75.06 is required to be published only in the county where the complaint is filed, and the complaint and order of the circuit court need be served only on the state attorney of the circuit in which the action is pending.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education shall provide for timely encumbrances of funds for duly authorized projects. Encumbrances may include proceeds to be received under a resolution approved by the State Board of Education authorizing issuance of class size reduction lottery bonds or educational facilities bonds pursuant to s. 11(d), Art. VII of the State Constitution, this section, and other applicable law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2003-391; s. 3, ch. 2009-170; s. 39, ch. 2011-55; s. 46, ch. 2011-63.</History>
</Section>