<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1013.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reduction of relocatable facilities in use.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a goal of the Legislature that all school districts shall provide a quality educational environment for their students such that, by July 1, 2003, student stations in relocatable facilities exceeding 20 years of age and in use by a district during the 1998-1999 fiscal year shall be removed and the number of all other relocatable student stations at over-capacity schools during that fiscal year shall be decreased by half. The Legislature finds, however, that necessary maintenance of existing facilities and public school enrollment growth impair the ability of some districts to achieve the goal of this section within 5 years. Therefore, the Legislature is increasing its commitment to school funding in this act, in part to help districts reduce the number of temporary, relocatable student stations at over-capacity schools. The Legislature intends that local school districts also increase their investment toward meeting this goal. Each district’s progress toward meeting this goal shall be measured annually by comparing district facilities work programs for replacing relocatables with the state capital outlay projections for education prepared by the Office of Educational Facilities. District facilities work programs shall be monitored by the Office of Educational Facilities to measure the commitment of local school districts toward this goal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, an “over-capacity school” means a school the capital outlay FTE enrollment of which exceeds 100 percent of the space and occupant design capacity of its nonrelocatable facilities. However, if a school’s initial design incorporated relocatable or modular instructional space, an “over-capacity school” shall mean a school the capital outlay FTE enrollment of which exceeds 100 percent of the space and occupant design capacity of its core facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with the legislative goal described in subsection (1), any relocatables purchased with money appropriated pursuant to chapter 97-384, Laws of Florida, shall be counted at actual student capacity for purposes of s. 1013.31 for the life cycle of the relocatable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 815, ch. 2002-387; s. 14, ch. 2010-70.</History>
</Section>