<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1013.356" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Local funding for educational facilities benefit districts or community development districts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon confirmation by a district school board of the commitment of revenues by an educational facilities benefit district or community development district necessary to construct and maintain an educational facility contained within an individual district facilities work program or proposed by an approved charter school or a charter school applicant, the following funds shall be provided to the educational facilities benefit district or community development district annually, beginning with the next fiscal year after confirmation until the district’s financial obligations are completed:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All educational facilities impact fee revenue collected for new development within the educational facilities benefit district or community development district. Funds provided under this subsection shall be used to fund the construction and capital maintenance costs of educational facilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For construction and capital maintenance costs not covered by the funds provided under subsection (1), an annual amount contributed by the district school board equal to one-half of the remaining costs of construction and capital maintenance of the educational facility. Any construction costs above the cost-per-student criteria established for the SIT Program in s. 1013.72(2) shall be funded exclusively by the educational facilities benefit district or the community development district. Funds contributed by a district school board shall not be used to fund operational costs.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Educational facilities funded pursuant to this act may be constructed on land that is owned by any person after the district school board has acquired from the owner of the land a long-term lease for the use of this land for a period of not less than 40 years or the life expectancy of the permanent facilities constructed thereon, whichever is longer. All interlocal agreements entered into pursuant to this act shall provide for ownership of educational facilities funded pursuant to this act to revert to the district school board if such facilities cease to be used for public educational purposes prior to 40 years after construction or prior to the end of the life expectancy of the educational facilities, whichever is longer.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 2002-296; s. 131, ch. 2003-1.</History></Section>