<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1013.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative capital outlay budget request.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education shall develop a procedure deemed appropriate in arriving at the amounts required to fund projects as reflected in the integrated, comprehensive budget request required by this section. The official estimates for funds accruing to the Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund made by the Revenue Estimating Conference shall be used in determining the budget request pursuant to this section. The commissioner, in consultation with the appropriations committees of the Legislature, shall provide annually an estimate of funds that shall be utilized by Florida College System institutions and universities in developing their required 3-year priority lists pursuant to s. 1013.64.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioner shall submit to the Governor and to the Legislature an integrated, comprehensive budget request for educational facilities construction and fixed capital outlay needs for school districts, Florida College System institutions, and universities, pursuant to the provisions of s. 1013.64 and applicable provisions of chapter 216. Each Florida College System institution board of trustees and each university board of trustees shall submit to the commissioner a 3-year plan and data required in the development of the annual capital outlay budget. The information that is approved by the Board of Governors must be submitted to the Commissioner of Education for inclusion in the comprehensive budget request for educational facilities. No further disbursements shall be made from the Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund to a board of trustees that fails to timely submit the required data until such board of trustees submits the data.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioner shall submit an integrated, comprehensive budget request to the Executive Office of the Governor and to the Legislature each fiscal year by the submission date specified in s. 216.023(1). Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 216.043, the integrated, comprehensive budget request shall include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for the priority of expenditure of funds in the state system of public education, with reasons for the recommended priorities, and other recommendations which relate to the effectiveness of the educational facilities construction program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All items in s. 1013.64.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 857, ch. 2002-387; s. 182, ch. 2007-217; s. 218, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>