<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1013.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proposed purchase of real property by a board; confidentiality of records; procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case in which a board, pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, seeks to acquire by purchase any real property for educational purposes, every appraisal, offer, or counteroffer must be in writing and is exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until an option contract is executed or, if no option contract is executed, until 30 days before a contract or agreement for purchase is considered for approval by the board. If a contract or agreement for purchase is not submitted to the board for approval, the exemption from s. 119.07(1) shall expire 30 days after the termination of negotiations. The board shall maintain complete and accurate records of every such appraisal, offer, and counteroffer. For the purposes of this section, the term “option contract” means an agreement by the board to purchase a piece of property, subject to the approval of the board at a public meeting after 30 days’ public notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to acquisition of the property, the board shall obtain at least one appraisal by an appraiser approved pursuant to s. 253.025(6)(b) for each purchase in an amount greater than $100,000 and not more than $500,000. For each purchase in an amount in excess of $500,000, the board shall obtain at least two appraisals by appraisers approved pursuant to s. 253.025(6)(b). If the agreed to purchase price exceeds the average appraised value, the board is required to approve the purchase by an extraordinary vote.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be interpreted as providing an exemption from, or an exception to, s. 286.011.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 807, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>