<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1013.735" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Classrooms for Kids Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ALLOCATION.<EmDash />The department shall allocate funds appropriated for the Classrooms for Kids Program. It is the intent of the Legislature that this program be administered as nearly as practicable in the same manner as the capital outlay program authorized under s. 9(a), Art. XII of the State Constitution. Each district school board’s share of the annual appropriation for the Classrooms for Kids Program must be calculated according to the following formula:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent of the appropriation shall be prorated to the districts based on each district’s percentage of K-12 base capital outlay full-time equivalent membership, and 65 percent shall be based on each district’s percentage of K-12 growth capital outlay full-time equivalent membership as specified for the allocation of funds from the Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund by s. 1013.64(3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ten percent of the appropriation must be allocated among district school boards according to the allocation formula in s. 1013.64(1)(a), excluding adult vocational technical facilities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISTRICT PARTICIPATION.<EmDash />In order to participate in the Classrooms for Kids Program, a district school board shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into an interlocal agreement pursuant to s. 1013.33.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certify that the district’s inventory of facilities listed in the Florida Inventory of School Houses is accurate and up-to-date pursuant to s. 1013.31.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OF FUNDS.<EmDash />In order to increase capacity to reduce class size, a district school board shall expend the funds received pursuant to this section only to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construct, renovate, remodel, or repair educational facilities that are in excess of projects identified in the district’s 5-year work program adopted prior to March 15, 2003; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase or lease-purchase relocatable facilities that are in excess of relocatables identified in the district’s 5-year work program adopted prior to March 15, 2003.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2003-391; s. 4, ch. 2004-42.</History></Section>