<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1013.37" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State uniform building code for public educational facilities construction.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNIFORM BUILDING CODE.<EmDash />A uniform statewide building code for the planning and construction of public educational and ancillary plants by district school boards and Florida College System institution district boards of trustees shall be adopted by the Florida Building Commission within the Florida Building Code, pursuant to s. 553.73. Included in this code must be flood plain management criteria in compliance with the rules and regulations in 44 C.F.R. parts 59 and 60, and subsequent revisions thereto which are adopted by the Federal Emergency Management Agency. It is also the responsibility of the department to develop, as a part of the uniform building code, standards relating to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prefabricated facilities or factory-built facilities that are designed to be portable, relocatable, demountable, or reconstructible; are used primarily as classrooms; and do not fall under the provisions of ss. 320.822-320.862. Such standards must permit boards to contract with the Department of Business and Professional Regulation for factory inspections by certified building code inspectors to certify conformance with applicable law and rules. The standards must comply with the requirements of s. 1013.20 for relocatable facilities intended for long-term use as classroom space, and the relocatable facilities shall be designed subject to missile impact criteria of s. 423(24)(d)(1) of the Florida Building Code when located in the windborne debris region.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sanitation of educational and ancillary plants and the health of occupants of educational and ancillary plants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The safety of occupants of educational and ancillary plants as provided in s. 1013.12, except that the firesafety criteria shall be established by the State Fire Marshal in cooperation with the Florida Building Commission and the department and such firesafety requirements must be incorporated into the Florida Fire Prevention Code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accessibility for children, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 553.512.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance of life-cycle cost analyses on alternative architectural and engineering designs to evaluate their energy efficiencies.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The life-cycle cost analysis must consist of the sum of:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonably expected fuel costs over the life of the building which are required to maintain illumination, water heating, temperature, humidity, ventilation, and all other energy-consuming equipment in a facility; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonable costs of probable maintenance, including labor and materials, and operation of the building.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For computation of the life-cycle costs, the department shall develop standards that must include, but need not be limited to:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The orientation and integration of the facility with respect to its physical site.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and type of glass employed in the facility and the directions of exposure.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The effect of insulation incorporated into the facility design and the effect on solar utilization of the properties of external surfaces.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The variable occupancy and operating conditions of the facility and subportions of the facility.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An energy-consumption analysis of the major equipment of the facility’s heating, ventilating, and cooling system; lighting system; and hot water system and all other major energy-consuming equipment and systems as appropriate.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life-cycle cost criteria published by the Department of Education for use in evaluating projects.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standards for construction materials and systems based on life-cycle costs that consider initial costs, maintenance costs, custodial costs, operating costs, and life expectancy. The standards may include multiple acceptable materials. It is the intent of the Legislature to require district school boards to comply with these standards when expending funds from the Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund or the School District and Community College District Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund and to prohibit district school boards from expending local capital outlay revenues for any project that includes materials or systems that do not comply with these standards, unless the district school board submits evidence that alternative materials or systems meet or exceed standards developed by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">It is not a purpose of the Florida Building Code to inhibit the use of new materials or innovative techniques; nor may it specify or prohibit materials by brand names. The code must be flexible enough to cover all phases of construction so as to afford reasonable protection for the public safety, health, and general welfare. The department may secure the service of other state agencies or such other assistance as it finds desirable in recommending to the Florida Building Commission revisions to the code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPROVAL.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before a contract has been let for the construction, the department, the district school board, the Florida College System institution board, or its authorized review agent must approve the phase III construction documents. A district school board or a Florida College System institution board may reuse prototype plans on another site, provided the facilities list and phase III construction documents have been updated for the new site and for compliance with the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code and any laws relating to firesafety, health and sanitation, casualty safety, and requirements for the physically handicapped which are in effect at the time a construction contract is to be awarded.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In reviewing plans for approval, the department, the district school board, the Florida College System institution board, or its review agent as authorized in s. 1013.38, shall take into consideration:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The need for the new facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The educational and ancillary plant planning.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The architectural and engineering planning.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location on the site.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plans for future expansion.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The type of construction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sanitary provisions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conformity to Florida Building Code standards.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The structural design and strength of materials proposed to be used.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mechanical design of any heating, air-conditioning, plumbing, or ventilating system. Typical heating, ventilating, and air-conditioning systems preapproved by the department for specific applications may be used in the design of educational facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The electrical design of educational plants.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The energy efficiency and conservation of the design.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life-cycle cost considerations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The design to accommodate physically handicapped persons.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ratio of net to gross square footage.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="16">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed construction cost per gross square foot.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="17">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conformity with the Florida Fire Prevention Code.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board or the Florida College System institution board may not occupy a facility until the project has been inspected to verify compliance with statutes, rules, and codes affecting the health and safety of the occupants. Verification of compliance with rules, statutes, and codes for nonoccupancy projects such as roofing, paving, site improvements, or replacement of equipment may be certified by the architect or engineer of record, and verification of compliance for other projects may be made by an inspector certified by the department or certified pursuant to chapter 468 who is not the architect or engineer of record. The board shall maintain a record of the project’s completion and permanent archive of phase III construction documents, including any addenda and change orders to the project. The boards shall provide project data to the department, as requested, for purposes and reports needed by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REVIEW PROCEDURE.<EmDash />The Commissioner of Education shall cooperate with the Florida Building Commission in addressing all questions, disputes, or interpretations involving the provisions of the Florida Building Code which govern the construction of public educational and ancillary facilities, and any objections to decisions made by the inspectors or the department must be submitted in writing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BIENNIAL REVIEW AND UPDATE; DISSEMINATION.<EmDash />The department shall biennially review and recommend to the Florida Building Commission updates and revisions to the provisions of the Florida Building Code which govern the construction of public educational and ancillary facilities. The department shall publish and make available to each board at no cost copies of the State Requirements for Educational Facilities and each amendment and revision thereto. The department shall make additional copies available to all interested persons at a price sufficient to recover costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LOCAL LEGISLATION PROHIBITED.<EmDash />After June 30, 1985, pursuant to s. 11(a)(21), Art. III of the State Constitution, there shall not be enacted any special act or general law of local application which proposes to amend, alter, or contravene any provisions of the State Building Code adopted under the authority of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 834, ch. 2002-387; s. 38, ch. 2009-59; s. 18, ch. 2011-3; s. 212, ch. 2011-5; s. 472, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>