<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0506.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Filing and recording of marks and brands on field boxes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to avail herself or himself of the benefits of ss. 506.19-506.28, may make application to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services and shall file with such department a true copy and description of such identifying mark or brand, which, if entitled thereto under the provisions of ss. 506.19-506.28, shall be filed and recorded by such department in a book to be provided and kept by it for that purpose, and the name of the owner of such brand or mark shall be likewise entered into such record, and such department shall then assign or designate a permanent registered number to the owner of such brand or mark, said number to be assigned progressively as marks and brands are received and recorded, and the registered number so assigned shall then become a part of the registered brand or mark and shall plainly and distinctly be made to appear on such field boxes, pallets, crates, receptacles and containers, together with the identifying mark or brand referred to in s. 506.19 hereof. The department shall determine if such brand or mark so applied for is not a duplication of any brand or mark previously recorded by or with it, or does not so closely resemble the same as to be misleading or deceiving. If the brand or mark applied for does so resemble or is such a duplication of previously recorded brands or marks as to be misleading or deceiving, the application shall be denied and the applicant may file some other brand or mark in the manner described above. The books and records previously kept by the Secretary of State shall be transferred to the Commissioner of Agriculture upon the effective date of this act.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 16018, 1933; s. 2, ch. 16859, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 7087(2), (14); s. 1, ch. 67-18; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-47; s. 655, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>