<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0948.001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrative probation” means a form of noncontact supervision in which an offender who presents a low risk of harm to the community may, upon satisfactory completion of half the term of probation, be transferred by the Department of Corrections to nonreporting status until expiration of the term of supervision.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child care facility” has the same meaning as provided in s. 402.302.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community control” means a form of intensive, supervised custody in the community, including surveillance on weekends and holidays, administered by officers with restricted caseloads. Community control is an individualized program in which the freedom of an offender is restricted within the community, home, or noninstitutional residential placement and specific sanctions are imposed and enforced.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community residential drug punishment center” means a residential drug punishment center designated by the Department of Corrections. The Department of Corrections shall adopt rules as necessary to define and operate such a center.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Drug offender probation” means a form of intensive supervision that emphasizes treatment of drug offenders in accordance with individualized treatment plans administered by officers with restricted caseloads. Caseloads should be restricted to a maximum of 50 cases per officer in order to ensure an adequate level of staffing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Park” has the same meaning as provided in s. 775.215.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Playground” has the same meaning as provided in s. 775.215.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Probation” means a form of community supervision requiring specified contacts with parole and probation officers and other terms and conditions as provided in s. 948.03.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified practitioner” means a social worker, mental health counselor, or a marriage and family therapist licensed under chapter 491 who, as determined by rule of the respective board, has the coursework, training, qualifications, and experience to evaluate and treat sexual offenders; a psychiatrist licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459; or a psychologist licensed under chapter 490.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Risk assessment” means an assessment completed by a qualified practitioner to evaluate the level of risk associated when a sex offender has contact with a child.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Safety plan” means a written document prepared by the qualified practitioner, in collaboration with the sex offender, the child’s parent or legal guardian, and, when appropriate, the child which establishes clear roles and responsibilities for each individual involved in any contact between the child and the sex offender.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“School” has the same meaning as provided in s. 775.215.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sex offender probation” or “sex offender community control” means a form of intensive supervision, with or without electronic monitoring, which emphasizes treatment and supervision of a sex offender in accordance with an individualized treatment plan administered by an officer who has a restricted caseload and specialized training. An officer who supervises an offender placed on sex offender probation or sex offender community control must meet as necessary with a treatment provider and polygraph examiner to develop and implement the supervision and treatment plan, if a treatment provider and polygraph examiner specially trained in the treatment and monitoring of sex offenders are reasonably available.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-131; s. 13, ch. 91-225; s. 32, ch. 92-310; s. 3, ch. 93-59; s. 13, ch. 93-227; s. 80, ch. 95-211; s. 2, ch. 97-308; s. 1, ch. 2004-373; s. 3, ch. 2005-67; s. 8, ch. 2007-200; s. 9, ch. 2007-209; s. 17, ch. 2010-64; s. 11, ch. 2010-92; s. 9, ch. 2010-113.</History>
</Section>