<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0948.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Drug offender probation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it appears to the court upon a hearing that the defendant is a chronic substance abuser whose criminal conduct is a violation of s. 893.13(2)(a) or (6)(a), or other nonviolent felony if such nonviolent felony is committed on or after July 1, 2009, and notwithstanding s. 921.0024 the defendant’s Criminal Punishment Code scoresheet total sentence points are 60 points or fewer, the court may either adjudge the defendant guilty or stay and withhold the adjudication of guilt. In either case, the court may also stay and withhold the imposition of sentence and place the defendant on drug offender probation or into a postadjudicatory treatment-based drug court program if the defendant otherwise qualifies. As used in this section, the term “nonviolent felony” means a third degree felony violation under chapter 810 or any other felony offense that is not a forcible felony as defined in s. 776.08.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections shall develop and administer a drug offender probation program which emphasizes a combination of treatment and intensive community supervision approaches and which includes provision for supervision of offenders in accordance with a specific treatment plan. The program may include the use of graduated sanctions consistent with the conditions imposed by the court. Drug offender probation status shall include surveillance and random drug testing, and may include those measures normally associated with community control, except that specific treatment conditions and other treatment approaches necessary to monitor this population may be ordered.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offenders placed on drug offender probation are subject to revocation of probation as provided in s. 948.06.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 91-225; s. 6, ch. 97-239; s. 4, ch. 2001-55; s. 10, ch. 2004-373; s. 7, ch. 2009-64; s. 5, ch. 2011-33.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve">Former s. 948.01(13).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>