<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0948.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Electronic monitoring devices.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections may, at its discretion, electronically monitor an offender sentenced to community control.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any offender placed on community control who violates the terms and conditions of community control and is restored to community control may be supervised by means of an electronic monitoring device or system.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For those offenders being electronically monitored, the Department of Corrections shall develop procedures to determine, investigate, and report the offender’s noncompliance with the terms and conditions of sentence 24 hours per day. All reports of noncompliance shall be immediately investigated by a community control officer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Corrections may contract with local law enforcement agencies to assist in the location and apprehension of offenders who are in noncompliance as reported by the electronic monitoring system. This contract is intended to provide the department a means for providing immediate investigation of noncompliance reports, especially after normal office hours.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person being electronically monitored by the department as a result of being placed on supervision shall pay the department for the electronic monitoring services as provided in s. 948.09(2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For probationers, community controllees, or conditional releasees who have current or prior convictions for violent or sexual offenses, the department, in carrying out a court or commission order to electronically monitor an offender, must use a system that actively monitors and identifies the offender’s location and timely reports or records the offender’s presence near or within a crime scene or in a prohibited area or the offender’s departure from specified geographic limitations. Procurement of electronic monitoring services under this subsection shall be by competitive procurement in accordance with s. 287.057.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who intentionally alters, tampers with, damages, or destroys any electronic monitoring equipment pursuant to court or commission order, unless such person is the owner of the equipment, or an agent of the owner, performing ordinary maintenance and repairs, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 87-211; s. 37, ch. 89-526; ss. 4, 9, ch. 91-280; s. 15, ch. 93-227; s. 16, ch. 2004-373; s. 18, ch. 2005-28; s. 12, ch. 2009-63; s. 21, ch. 2010-64; s. 14, ch. 2010-113.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1)-(4) former s. 948.03(3).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>