<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0948.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Identifying, assessing, and monitoring high-risk sex offenders on community supervision; providing cumulative criminal and supervision histories on the Internet.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By December 1, 2005, the department shall develop a graduated risk assessment that identifies, assesses, and closely monitors a high-risk sex offender who is placed on probation or in community control and who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has previously been placed on probation or in community control and has a history of committing multiple violations of community supervision in this state or in any other jurisdiction or has previously been incarcerated in this state or in any other jurisdiction; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has experienced more than one of the following risk factors that could potentially make the offender more likely to pose a danger to others:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Previous conviction for domestic violence;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">History of substance abuse;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unemployment or substantial financial difficulties;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Previous conviction for violence or sex acts against children, particularly involving strangers; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other risk factor identified by the department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To facilitate the information available to the court at first appearance hearings and at all subsequent hearings for these high-risk sex offenders, the department shall, no later than March 1, 2006, post on FDLE’s Criminal Justice Intranet a cumulative chronology of the sex offender’s prior terms of state probation and community control, including all substantive or technical violations of state probation or community control. The county jail in the county where the arrested person is booked shall ensure that state and national criminal history information and all criminal justice information available in the Florida Crime Information Center and the National Crime Information Center, is provided to the court at the time of the first appearance. The courts shall assist the department’s dissemination of critical information by creating and maintaining an automated system to provide the information as specified in this subsection and by providing the necessary technology in the courtroom to deliver the information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In monitoring the location of high-risk sex offenders, the department shall, no later than October 1, 2006, have fingerprint-reading equipment and capability that will immediately identify the probationer or community controllee when he or she reports to his or her designated probation officer and alert department probation officials when probationers and community controllees are subsequently rearrested.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2005-28; s. 117, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>