<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0948.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional terms and conditions of probation or community control for certain sex offenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conditions imposed pursuant to this section do not require oral pronouncement at the time of sentencing and shall be considered standard conditions of probation or community control for offenders specified in this section.</Text>
<Subsection Id="1">
	<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective for probationers or community controllees whose crime was committed on or after October 1, 1995, and who are placed under supervision for violation of chapter 794, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145, the court must impose the following conditions in addition to all other standard and special conditions imposed:</Text>
	<Paragraph Id="a">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mandatory curfew from 10 p.m. to 6 a.m. The court may designate another 8-hour period if the offender’s employment precludes the above specified time, and the alternative is recommended by the Department of Corrections. If the court determines that imposing a curfew would endanger the victim, the court may consider alternative sanctions.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="b">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the victim was under the age of 18, a prohibition on living within 1,000 feet of a school, child care facility, park, playground, or other place where children regularly congregate, as prescribed by the court. The 1,000-foot distance shall be measured in a straight line from the offender’s place of residence to the nearest boundary line of the school, child care facility, park, playground, or other place where children congregate. The distance may not be measured by a pedestrian route or automobile route. A probationer or community controllee who is subject to this paragraph may not be forced to relocate and does not violate his or her probation or community control if he or she is living in a residence that meets the requirements of this paragraph and a school, child care facility, park, playground, or other place where children regularly congregate is subsequently established within 1,000 feet of his or her residence.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="c">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Active participation in and successful completion of a sex offender treatment program with qualified practitioners specifically trained to treat sex offenders, at the probationer’s or community controllee’s own expense. If a qualified practitioner is not available within a 50-mile radius of the probationer’s or community controllee’s residence, the offender shall participate in other appropriate therapy.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="d">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prohibition on any contact with the victim, directly or indirectly, including through a third person, unless approved by the victim, a qualified practitioner in the sexual offender treatment program, and the sentencing court.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="e">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the victim was under the age of 18, a prohibition on contact with a child under the age of 18 except as provided in this paragraph. The court may approve supervised contact with a child under the age of 18 if the approval is based upon a recommendation for contact issued by a qualified practitioner who is basing the recommendation on a risk assessment. Further, the sex offender must be currently enrolled in or have successfully completed a sex offender therapy program. The court may not grant supervised contact with a child if the contact is not recommended by a qualified practitioner and may deny supervised contact with a child at any time. When considering whether to approve supervised contact with a child, the court must review and consider the following:</Text>
		<SubParagraph Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A risk assessment completed by a qualified practitioner. The qualified practitioner must prepare a written report that must include the findings of the assessment and address each of the following components:</Text>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s current legal status;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s history of adult charges with apparent sexual motivation;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s history of adult charges without apparent sexual motivation;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s history of juvenile charges, whenever available;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s offender treatment history, including consultations with the sex offender’s treating, or most recent treating, therapist;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s current mental status;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s mental health and substance abuse treatment history as provided by the Department of Corrections;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sex offender’s personal, social, educational, and work history;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The results of current psychological testing of the sex offender if determined necessary by the qualified practitioner;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the proposed contact, including the location, frequency, duration, and supervisory arrangement;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child’s preference and relative comfort level with the proposed contact, when age appropriate;</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent’s or legal guardian’s preference regarding the proposed contact; and</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<SubSubParagraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The qualified practitioner’s opinion, along with the basis for that opinion, as to whether the proposed contact would likely pose significant risk of emotional or physical harm to the child.</Text>
			</SubSubParagraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The written report of the assessment must be given to the court;</Text>
		</SubParagraph>
		<SubParagraph Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recommendation made as a part of the risk assessment report as to whether supervised contact with the child should be approved;</Text>
		</SubParagraph>
		<SubParagraph Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written consent signed by the child’s parent or legal guardian, if the parent or legal guardian is not the sex offender, agreeing to the sex offender having supervised contact with the child after receiving full disclosure of the sex offender’s present legal status, past criminal history, and the results of the risk assessment. The court may not approve contact with the child if the parent or legal guardian refuses to give written consent for supervised contact;</Text>
		</SubParagraph>
		<SubParagraph Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A safety plan prepared by the qualified practitioner, who provides treatment to the offender, in collaboration with the sex offender, the child’s parent or legal guardian, if the parent or legal guardian is not the sex offender, and the child, when age appropriate, which details the acceptable conditions of contact between the sex offender and the child. The safety plan must be reviewed and approved by the court; and</Text>
		</SubParagraph>
		<SubParagraph Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence that the child’s parent or legal guardian understands the need for and agrees to the safety plan and has agreed to provide, or to designate another adult to provide, constant supervision any time the child is in contact with the offender.</Text>
		</SubParagraph>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The court may not appoint a person to conduct a risk assessment and may not accept a risk assessment from a person who has not demonstrated to the court that he or she has met the requirements of a qualified practitioner as defined in this section.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="f">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the victim was under age 18, a prohibition on working for pay or as a volunteer at any place where children regularly congregate, including, but not limited to, schools, child care facilities, parks, playgrounds, pet stores, libraries, zoos, theme parks, and malls.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="g">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise indicated in the treatment plan provided by a qualified practitioner in the sexual offender treatment program, a prohibition on viewing, accessing, owning, or possessing any obscene, pornographic, or sexually stimulating visual or auditory material, including telephone, electronic media, computer programs, or computer services that are relevant to the offender’s deviant behavior pattern.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="h">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective for probationers and community controllees whose crime is committed on or after July 1, 2005, a prohibition on accessing the Internet or other computer services until a qualified practitioner in the offender’s sex offender treatment program, after a risk assessment is completed, approves and implements a safety plan for the offender’s accessing or using the Internet or other computer services.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="i">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A requirement that the probationer or community controllee must submit a specimen of blood or other approved biological specimen to the Department of Law Enforcement to be registered with the DNA data bank.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="j">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A requirement that the probationer or community controllee make restitution to the victim, as ordered by the court under s. 775.089, for all necessary medical and related professional services relating to physical, psychiatric, and psychological care.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="k">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission to a warrantless search by the community control or probation officer of the probationer’s or community controllee’s person, residence, or vehicle.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective for a probationer or community controllee whose crime was committed on or after October 1, 1997, and who is placed on community control or sex offender probation for a violation of chapter 794, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145, in addition to any other provision of this section, the court must impose the following conditions of probation or community control:</Text>
	<Paragraph Id="a">
	<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of a treatment program, participation at least annually in polygraph examinations to obtain information necessary for risk management and treatment and to reduce the sex offender’s denial mechanisms. A polygraph examination must be conducted by a polygrapher who is a member of a national or state polygraph association and who is certified as a postconviction sex offender polygrapher, where available, and shall be paid for by the probationer or community controllee. The results of the polygraph examination shall be provided to the probationer’s or community controllee’s probation officer and qualified practitioner and shall not be used as evidence in court to prove that a violation of community supervision has occurred.</Text>
</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of a driving log and a prohibition against driving a motor vehicle alone without the prior approval of the supervising officer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prohibition against obtaining or using a post office box without the prior approval of the supervising officer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there was sexual contact, a submission to, at the probationer’s or community controllee’s expense, an HIV test with the results to be released to the victim or the victim’s parent or guardian.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electronic monitoring when deemed necessary by the community control or probation officer and his or her supervisor, and ordered by the court at the recommendation of the Department of Corrections.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective for a probationer or community controllee whose crime was committed on or after September 1, 2005, and who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is placed on probation or community control for a violation of chapter 794, s. 800.04(4), (5), or (6), s. 827.071, or s. 847.0145 and the unlawful sexual activity involved a victim 15 years of age or younger and the offender is 18 years of age or older;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is designated a sexual predator pursuant to s. 775.21; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has previously been convicted of a violation of chapter 794, s. 800.04(4), (5), or (6), s. 827.071, or s. 847.0145 and the unlawful sexual activity involved a victim 15 years of age or younger and the offender is 18 years of age or older,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the court must order, in addition to any other provision of this section, mandatory electronic monitoring as a condition of the probation or community control supervision.</Text>
		</Subsection><Subsection Id="4">
	<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to all other conditions imposed, for a probationer or community controllee who is subject to supervision for a crime that was committed on or after May 26, 2010, and who has been convicted at any time of committing, or attempting, soliciting, or conspiring to commit, any of the criminal offenses listed in s. 943.0435(1)(a)1.a.(I), or a similar offense in another jurisdiction, against a victim who was under the age of 18 at the time of the offense; if the offender has not received a pardon for any felony or similar law of another jurisdiction necessary for the operation of this subsection, if a conviction of a felony or similar law of another jurisdiction necessary for the operation of this subsection has not been set aside in any postconviction proceeding, or if the offender has not been removed from the requirement to register as a sexual offender or sexual predator pursuant to s. 943.04354, the court must impose the following conditions:</Text>
	<Paragraph Id="a">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prohibition on visiting schools, child care facilities, parks, and playgrounds, without prior approval from the offender’s supervising officer. The court may also designate additional locations to protect a victim. The prohibition ordered under this paragraph does not prohibit the offender from visiting a school, child care facility, park, or playground for the sole purpose of attending a religious service as defined in s. 775.0861 or picking up or dropping off the offender’s children or grandchildren at a child care facility or school.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
	<Paragraph Id="b">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A prohibition on distributing candy or other items to children on Halloween; wearing a Santa Claus costume, or other costume to appeal to children, on or preceding Christmas; wearing an Easter Bunny costume, or other costume to appeal to children, on or preceding Easter; entertaining at children’s parties; or wearing a clown costume; without prior approval from the court.</Text>
	</Paragraph>
</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 59, ch. 95-283; s. 6, ch. 96-409; s. 3, ch. 97-308; s. 14, ch. 98-81; s. 13, ch. 99-201; s. 3, ch. 2000-246; s. 1, ch. 2003-18; s. 1, ch. 2003-63; s. 18, ch. 2004-373; s. 151, ch. 2005-2; s. 20, ch. 2005-28; s. 4, ch. 2005-67; s. 31, ch. 2008-172; ss. 12, 18, ch. 2010-92.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 948.03(5).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>