<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0948.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Residential treatment as a condition of probation or community control.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court imposes a period of residential treatment or incarceration as a condition of probation or community control, the residential treatment or incarceration shall be restricted to the following facilities:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Department of Corrections probation and restitution center;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A probation program drug punishment treatment community;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A community residential facility which is owned and operated by any public or private entity, excluding a community correctional center as defined in s. 944.026; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county-owned facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that a county jail be used as the last available alternative for placement of an offender as a condition of probation. However, this shall not create a right of placement for the probationer, nor shall it restrict judicial discretion in ordering such treatment or incarceration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to admission to such a facility or treatment community, the court shall obtain an individual assessment and recommendation on the appropriate treatment needs pursuant to the Community Control Implementation Manual which shall be considered by the court in ordering such placements. Placement in such a facility or center, or in the phase I secure residential phase of a probation program drug punishment treatment community, shall not exceed 364 days. Early completion of an offender’s placement shall be recommended to the court, when appropriate, by the facility or center supervisor, by the supervising probation officer, or by the program manager. The Department of Corrections is authorized to contract with appropriate agencies for provision of services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 85-288; s. 37, ch. 89-526; s. 10, ch. 90-287; s. 11, ch. 91-225; s. 4, ch. 91-280; s. 20, ch. 2004-373.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 948.03(7).</Text></Note></Section>