<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0948.062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reviewing and reporting serious offenses committed by offenders placed on probation or community control.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall review the circumstances related to an offender placed on probation or community control who has been arrested while on supervision for the following offenses:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any murder as provided in s. 782.04;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any sexual battery as provided in s. 794.011 or s. 794.023;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any sexual performance by a child as provided in s. 827.071;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any kidnapping, false imprisonment, or luring of a child as provided in s. 787.01, s. 787.02, or s. 787.025;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lewd and lascivious battery or lewd and lascivious molestation as provided in s. 800.04(4) or (5);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any aggravated child abuse as provided in s. 827.03(2)(a);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any robbery with a firearm or other deadly weapon, home invasion robbery, or carjacking as provided in s. 812.13(2)(a), s. 812.135, or s. 812.133;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any aggravated stalking as provided in s. 784.048(3), (4), or (5);</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any forcible felony as provided in s. 776.08, committed by a person on probation or community control who is designated as a sexual predator; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any DUI manslaughter as provided in s. 316.193(3)(c), or vehicular or vessel homicide as provided in s. 782.071 or s. 782.072, committed by a person who is on probation or community control for an offense involving death or injury resulting from a driving incident.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide a statistical data summary from these reviews to the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability. The Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall analyze this data and provide a written report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by March 1, 2006. The report must include, at a minimum, any identified systemic deficiencies in managing high-risk offenders on community supervision, any patterns of noncompliance by correctional probation officers, and recommendations for improving the community supervision program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 2005-28; s. 118, ch. 2006-1; s. 14, ch. 2012-155.</History>
</Section>