<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0948.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Misdemeanor pretrial substance abuse education and treatment intervention program; misdemeanor pretrial veterans’ treatment intervention program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is charged with a nonviolent, nontraffic-related misdemeanor and identified as having a substance abuse problem or who is charged with a misdemeanor for possession of a controlled substance or drug paraphernalia under chapter 893, prostitution under s. 796.07, possession of alcohol while under 21 years of age under s. 562.111, or possession of a controlled substance without a valid prescription under s. 499.03, and who has not previously been convicted of a felony, is eligible for voluntary admission into a misdemeanor pretrial substance abuse education and treatment intervention program, including a treatment-based drug court program established pursuant to s. 397.334, approved by the chief judge of the circuit, for a period based on the program requirements and the treatment plan for the offender, upon motion of either party or the court’s own motion, except, if the state attorney believes the facts and circumstances of the case suggest the defendant is involved in dealing and selling controlled substances, the court shall hold a preadmission hearing. If the state attorney establishes, by a preponderance of the evidence at such hearing, that the defendant was involved in dealing or selling controlled substances, the court shall deny the defendant’s admission into the pretrial intervention program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While enrolled in a pretrial intervention program authorized by this section, the participant is subject to a coordinated strategy developed by a drug court team under s. 397.334(4). The coordinated strategy may include a protocol of sanctions that may be imposed upon the participant for noncompliance with program rules. The protocol of sanctions may include, but is not limited to, placement in a substance abuse treatment program offered by a licensed service provider as defined in s. 397.311 or in a jail-based treatment program or serving a period of incarceration within the time limits established for contempt of court. The coordinated strategy must be provided in writing to the participant before the participant agrees to enter into a pretrial treatment-based drug court program or other pretrial intervention program. Any person whose charges are dismissed after successful completion of the treatment-based drug court program, if otherwise eligible, may have his or her arrest record and plea of nolo contendere to the dismissed charges expunged under s. 943.0585.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A veteran, as defined in s. 1.01, or servicemember, as defined in s. 250.01, who suffers from a military service-related mental illness, traumatic brain injury, substance abuse disorder, or psychological problem, and who is charged with a misdemeanor is eligible for voluntary admission into a misdemeanor pretrial veterans’ treatment intervention program approved by the chief judge of the circuit, for a period based on the program’s requirements and the treatment plan for the offender, upon motion of either party or the court’s own motion. However, the court may deny the defendant admission into a misdemeanor pretrial veterans’ treatment intervention program if the defendant has previously entered a court-ordered veterans’ treatment program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While enrolled in a pretrial intervention program authorized by this section, the participant shall be subject to a coordinated strategy developed by a veterans’ treatment intervention team. The coordinated strategy should be modeled after the therapeutic jurisprudence principles and key components in s. 397.334(4), with treatment specific to the needs of veterans and servicemembers. The coordinated strategy may include a protocol of sanctions that may be imposed upon the participant for noncompliance with program rules. The protocol of sanctions may include, but need not be limited to, placement in a treatment program offered by a licensed service provider or in a jail-based treatment program or serving a period of incarceration within the time limits established for contempt of court. The coordinated strategy must be provided in writing to the participant before the participant agrees to enter into a misdemeanor pretrial veterans’ treatment intervention program or other pretrial intervention program. Any person whose charges are dismissed after successful completion of the misdemeanor pretrial veterans’ treatment intervention program, if otherwise eligible, may have his or her arrest record <Reference Number="1"/>of the dismissed charges expunged under s. 943.0585.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the end of the pretrial intervention period, the court shall consider the recommendation of the treatment program and the recommendation of the state attorney as to disposition of the pending charges. The court shall determine, by written finding, whether the defendant successfully completed the pretrial intervention program. Notwithstanding the coordinated strategy developed by a drug court team pursuant to s. 397.334(4) or by the veterans’ treatment intervention team, if the court finds that the defendant has not successfully completed the pretrial intervention program, the court may order the person to continue in education and treatment or return the charges to the criminal docket for prosecution. The court shall dismiss the charges upon finding that the defendant has successfully completed the pretrial intervention program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any public or private entity providing a pretrial substance abuse education and treatment program under this section shall contract with the county or appropriate governmental entity. The terms of the contract shall include, but not be limited to, the requirements established for private entities under s. 948.15(3). This requirement does not apply to services provided by the Department of Veterans’ Affairs or the United States Department of Veterans Affairs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2001-48; s. 9, ch. 2006-97; s. 6, ch. 2009-64; s. 1, ch. 2012-35; s. 19, ch. 2012-159.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “of” was substituted for the word “to” by the editors to conform to context.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>