<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0948.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Terms and conditions of probation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall determine the terms and conditions of probation. Conditions specified in this section do not require oral pronouncement at the time of sentencing and may be considered standard conditions of probation. These conditions may include among them the following, that the probationer or offender in community control shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report to the probation and parole supervisors as directed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permit such supervisors to visit him or her at his or her home or elsewhere.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work faithfully at suitable employment insofar as may be possible.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remain within a specified place.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Live without violating any law. A conviction in a court of law is not necessary for such a violation of law to constitute a violation of probation, community control, or any other form of court-ordered supervision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make reparation or restitution to the aggrieved party for the damage or loss caused by his or her offense in an amount to be determined by the court. The court shall make such reparation or restitution a condition of probation, unless it determines that clear and compelling reasons exist to the contrary. If the court does not order restitution, or orders restitution of only a portion of the damages, as provided in s. 775.089, it shall state on the record in detail the reasons therefor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 1994, and applicable for offenses committed on or after that date, make payment of the debt due and owing to a county or municipal detention facility under s. 951.032 for medical care, treatment, hospitalization, or transportation received by the felony probationer while in that detention facility. The court, in determining whether to order such repayment and the amount of the repayment, shall consider the amount of the debt, whether there was any fault of the institution for the medical expenses incurred, the financial resources of the felony probationer, the present and potential future financial needs and earning ability of the probationer, and dependents, and other appropriate factors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Support his or her legal dependents to the best of his or her ability.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make payment of the debt due and owing to the state under s. 960.17, subject to modification based on change of circumstances.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay any application fee assessed under s. 27.52(1)(b) and attorney’s fees and costs assessed under s. 938.29, subject to modification based on change of circumstances.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not associate with persons engaged in criminal activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to random testing as directed by the correctional probation officer or the professional staff of the treatment center where he or she is receiving treatment to determine the presence or use of alcohol or controlled substances.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the offense was a controlled substance violation and the period of probation immediately follows a period of incarceration in the state correction system, the conditions shall include a requirement that the offender submit to random substance abuse testing intermittently throughout the term of supervision, upon the direction of the correctional probation officer as defined in s. 943.10(3).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be prohibited from possessing, carrying, or owning any:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Firearm.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weapon without first procuring the consent of the correctional probation officer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be prohibited from using intoxicants to excess or possessing any drugs or narcotics unless prescribed by a physician. The probationer or community controllee shall not knowingly visit places where intoxicants, drugs, or other dangerous substances are unlawfully sold, dispensed, or used.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to the drawing of blood or other biological specimens as prescribed in ss. 943.325 and 948.014, and reimburse the appropriate agency for the costs of drawing and transmitting the blood or other biological specimens to the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to the taking of a digitized photograph by the department as a part of the offender’s records. This photograph may be displayed on the department’s public website while the offender is under court-ordered supervision. However, the department may not display the photograph on the website if the offender is only on pretrial intervention supervision or if the offender’s identity is exempt from disclosure due to an exemption from the requirements of s. 119.07.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enumeration of specific kinds of terms and conditions shall not prevent the court from adding thereto such other or others as it considers proper. However, the sentencing court may only impose a condition of supervision allowing an offender convicted of s. 794.011, s. 800.04, s. 827.071, s. 847.0135(5), or s. 847.0145, to reside in another state, if the order stipulates that it is contingent upon the approval of the receiving state interstate compact authority. The court may rescind or modify at any time the terms and conditions theretofore imposed by it upon the probationer. However, if the court withholds adjudication of guilt or imposes a period of incarceration as a condition of probation, the period shall not exceed 364 days, and incarceration shall be restricted to either a county facility, a probation and restitution center under the jurisdiction of the Department of Corrections, a probation program drug punishment phase I secure residential treatment institution, or a community residential facility owned or operated by any entity providing such services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 20519, 1941; s. 5, ch. 77-452; s. 1, ch. 81-198; s. 3, ch. 83-75; s. 16, ch. 83-131; s. 192, ch. 83-216; s. 3, ch. 83-256; s. 8, ch. 84-363; s. 15, ch. 85-288; s. 5, ch. 87-211; s. 11, ch. 88-96; ss. 70, 71, ch. 88-122; s. 37, ch. 89-526; s. 10, ch. 90-287; ss. 8, 17, ch. 90-337; s. 11, ch. 91-225; s. 4, ch. 91-280; s. 23, ch. 92-310; s. 10, ch. 93-37; s. 15, ch. 93-227; s. 1, ch. 94-294; s. 1, ch. 95-189; ss. 53, 59, ch. 95-283; s. 1, ch. 96-170; s. 4, ch. 96-232; s. 54, ch. 96-312; s. 6, ch. 96-409; s. 22, ch. 97-78; s. 1877, ch. 97-102; s. 11, ch. 97-107; s. 27, ch. 97-234; s. 44, ch. 97-271; s. 3, ch. 97-308; s. 14, ch. 98-81; s. 15, ch. 98-251; s. 122, ch. 99-3; s. 13, ch. 99-201; s. 3, ch. 2000-246; s. 6, ch. 2001-50; s. 1045, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2003-18; s. 1, ch. 2003-63; s. 136, ch. 2003-402; ss. 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, ch. 2004-373; s. 116, ch. 2006-1; s. 28, ch. 2008-172; s. 18, ch. 2010-64.</History>
</Section>