<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0425.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of trustees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business and affairs of a cooperative shall be managed by a board of not less than five trustees, each of whom shall be a member of the cooperative or of another cooperative which shall be a member thereof. The bylaws shall prescribe the number of trustees, their qualifications, other than those provided for in this chapter, the manner of holding meetings of the board of trustees and of the election of successors to trustees who shall resign, die, or otherwise be incapable of acting. The bylaws may also provide for the removal of trustees from office and for the election of their successors. Without approval of the members, trustees shall not receive any salaries for their services as trustees and, except in emergencies, shall not be employed by the cooperative in any capacity involving compensation. The bylaws may, however, provide that a fixed fee and expenses of attendance, if any, may be allowed to each trustee for attendance at each meeting of the board of trustees and that such may be allowed for the performance of other cooperative business, provided it has prior approval of the board of trustees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The trustees of a cooperative named in any articles of incorporation, consolidation, merger or conversion, as the case may be, shall hold office until the next following annual meeting of the members or until their successors shall have been elected and qualified. At each annual meeting or, in case of failure to hold the annual meeting as specified in the bylaws, at a special meeting called for that purpose, the members shall elect trustees to hold office until the next following annual meeting of the members, except as hereinafter otherwise provided. Each trustee shall hold office for the term for which he or she is elected or until a successor shall have been elected and qualified.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bylaws may provide that, in lieu of electing the whole number of trustees annually, the trustees may be divided into three classes at the first or any subsequent annual meeting, each class to be as nearly equal in number as possible, with the term of office of the trustees of the first class to expire at the next succeeding annual meeting and the term of the second class to expire at the second succeeding annual meeting and the term of the third class to expire at the third succeeding annual meeting. At each annual meeting after such classification a number of trustees equal to the number of the class whose term expires at the time of such meeting shall be elected to hold office until the third succeeding annual meeting.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of the board of trustees shall constitute a quorum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a husband and wife hold a joint membership in a cooperative, either one, but not both, may be elected a trustee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees may exercise all of the powers of a cooperative except such as are conferred upon the members by this chapter, or its articles of incorporation or bylaws.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 19138, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 6494(52); s. 1, ch. 28053, 1953; s. 1, ch. 74-33; s. 93, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>