<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0425.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cooperative shall have power:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and be sued, in its corporate name;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have perpetual existence;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt a corporate seal and alter the same at pleasure;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To generate, manufacture, purchase, acquire, accumulate and transmit electric energy, and to distribute, sell, supply, and dispose of electric energy in rural areas to its members, to governmental agencies and political subdivisions, and to other persons not in excess of 10 percent of the number of its members; to process, treat, sell, and dispose of water and water rights; to purchase, construct, own and operate water systems; to own and operate sanitary sewer systems; and to supply water and sanitary sewer services. However, no cooperative shall distribute or sell any electricity, or electric energy to any person residing within any town, city or area which person is receiving adequate central station service or who at the time of commencing such service, or offer to serve, by a cooperative, is receiving adequate central station service from any utility agency, privately or municipally owned individual partnership or corporation;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make loans to persons to whom electric energy is or will be supplied by the cooperative for the purpose of, and otherwise to assist such person in, wiring their premises and installing therein electric and plumbing fixtures, appliances, apparatus and equipment of any and all kinds and character, and in connection therewith, to purchase, acquire, lease, sell, distribute, install and repair such electric and plumbing fixtures, appliances, apparatus and equipment, and to accept or otherwise acquire, and to sell, assign, transfer, endorse, pledge, hypothecate and otherwise dispose of notes, bonds and other evidences of indebtedness and any and all types of security therefor;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make loans to persons to whom electric energy is or will be supplied by the cooperative for the purpose of, and otherwise to assist such persons in, constructing, maintaining and operating electric refrigeration plants;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To become a member in one or more other cooperatives or corporations or to own stock therein;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To construct, purchase, take, receive, lease as lessee, or otherwise acquire, and to own, hold, use, equip, maintain, and operate, and to sell, assign, transfer, convey, exchange, lease as lessor, mortgage, pledge, or otherwise dispose of or encumber, electric transmission and distribution lines or systems, electric generating plants, electric refrigeration plants, lands, buildings, structures, dams, plants and equipment, and any and all kinds and classes of real or personal property whatsoever, which shall be deemed necessary, convenient or appropriate to accomplish the purpose for which the cooperative is organized;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To purchase or otherwise acquire; to own, hold, use and exercise; and to sell, assign, transfer, convey, mortgage, pledge, hypothecate, or otherwise dispose of or encumber, franchises, rights, privileges, licenses, rights-of-way and easement;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To borrow money and otherwise contract indebtedness; to issue notes, bonds, and other evidences of indebtedness therefor; and to secure the payment thereof by mortgage, pledge, deed of trust, or any other encumbrance upon any or all of its then owned or after-acquired real or personal property, assets, franchises, revenues or income;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To construct, maintain, and operate electric transmission and distribution lines along, upon, under and across all public thoroughfares, including without limitation, all roads, highways, streets, alleys, bridges and causeways, and upon, under and across all publicly owned lands, subject, however, to the requirements in respect of the use of such thoroughfares and lands that are imposed by the respective authorities having jurisdiction thereof upon corporations constructing or operating electric transmission and distribution lines or systems;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To exercise the power of eminent domain in the manner provided by the laws of this state for the exercise of that power by corporations constructing or operating electric transmission and distribution lines or systems;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conduct its business and exercise any or all of its powers within or without this state;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt, amend and repeal bylaws; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To do and perform any and all other acts and things, and to have and exercise any and all other powers which may be necessary, convenient or appropriate to accomplish the purpose for which the cooperative is organized.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">To promote economic development, an electric cooperative may provide any energy or nonenergy services to its membership.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 19138, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 6494(46); s. 1, ch. 71-83; s. 108, ch. 99-251.</History></Section>