<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0674.403" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Customer’s right to stop payment; burden of proof of loss.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A customer or any person authorized to draw on the account if there is more than one person may stop payment of any item drawn on the customer’s account or close the account by a written order to the bank describing the item or account with certainty received by an officer of the bank during a banking day and at a time and in a manner that affords the bank a reasonable opportunity to act on it before any action by the bank with respect to the item described in s. 674.303. If the signature of more than one person is required to draw on an account, any of these persons may stop payment or close the account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A stop-payment order is effective for 6 months. A stop-payment order may be renewed for additional 6-month periods by a writing given to the bank within a period during which the stop-payment order is effective.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bank may be liable to its customer for the actual loss incurred by the customer resulting from the wrongful payment of an item contrary to a valid and binding stop-payment order or order to close an account. The burden of establishing the fact and amount of loss resulting from the payment of an item contrary to a stop-payment order or order to close an account is on the customer. The loss from payment of an item contrary to a stop-payment order may include damages for dishonor of subsequent items under s. 674.402.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">Art. 10, s. 1, ch. 65-254; s. 40, ch. 92-82.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">s. 4-403, U.C.C.; supersedes s. 659.32.</Text></Note></Section>