<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0384.34" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of s. 384.24(1) commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of s. 384.26 or s. 384.29 commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who maliciously disseminates any false information or report concerning the existence of any sexually transmissible disease commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in ss. 775.082, 775.083, and 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of the department’s rules pertaining to sexually transmissible diseases may be punished by a fine not to exceed $500 for each violation. Any penalties enforced under this subsection shall be in addition to other penalties provided by this chapter. The department may enforce this section and adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates s. 384.24(2) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. Any person who commits multiple violations of s. 384.24(2) commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who obtains information that identifies an individual who has a sexually transmissible disease, who knew or should have known the nature of the information and maliciously, or for monetary gain, disseminates this information or otherwise makes this information known to any other person, except by providing it either to a physician or nurse employed by the Department of Health or to a law enforcement agency, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 90, ch. 86-220; s. 38, ch. 88-380; s. 63, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 96-179; s. 2, ch. 97-37; s. 18, ch. 98-151; s. 21, ch. 98-191; s. 1, ch. 2010-64; s. 3, ch. 2010-113.</History>
</Section>