<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0384.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reporting required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who makes a diagnosis of or treats a person with a sexually transmissible disease and each laboratory that performs a test that concludes with a positive result for a sexually transmissible disease or a result indicative of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) shall report such facts as may be required by the department by rule, within a time period as specified by rule of the department, but in no case to exceed 2 weeks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules specifying the information required and the maximum time period for reporting a sexually transmissible disease. In adopting such rules, the department shall consider the need for information, protections for the privacy and confidentiality of the patient, and the practical ability of persons and laboratories to report in a reasonable fashion.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To ensure the confidentiality of persons infected with the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), reporting of HIV infection and AIDS must be conducted using a system developed by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention of the United States Public Health Service or an equivalent system.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules requiring each physician and laboratory to report any newborn or infant up to 18 months of age who has been exposed to HIV. Such rules may include the method and time period for reporting, which may not exceed 2 weeks, information to be included in the report, enforcement requirements, and followup activities by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reporting may not affect or relate to anonymous HIV testing programs conducted pursuant to s. 381.004(3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After notification of the test subject, the department may, with the consent of the test subject, notify school superintendents of students and school personnel whose HIV tests are positive.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who violates the provisions of this section or the rules adopted hereunder may be fined by the department up to $500 for each offense. The department shall report each violation of this section to the regulatory agency responsible for licensing each health care professional and each laboratory to which these provisions apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 90, ch. 86-220; s. 28, ch. 88-380; s. 8, ch. 89-350; s. 1, ch. 93-264; s. 675, ch. 95-148; s. 2, ch. 96-179; s. 5, ch. 96-221; s. 189, ch. 97-101; s. 3, ch. 98-171; s. 2, ch. 2005-169; s. 119, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>