<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0384.285" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of appeal; immediate release.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is aggrieved by the entry of an order under s. 384.27, s. 384.28, or s. 384.281 shall have the period of time provided by the Rules of Appellate Procedure within which to appeal said order. Every order entered under the terms of ss. 384.27, 384.28, and 384.281 shall be executed immediately unless the court entering such order or the appellate court, in its discretion, enters a supersedeas order and fixes the terms and conditions thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is examined, treated, hospitalized, placed in another health care or residential facility, isolated in his or her residence, or placed in emergency hold as a result of an order entered under s. 384.27, s. 384.28, or s. 384.281 may at any time petition the circuit court for immediate release and termination of the order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person petitioning a court for immediate release and termination of the order entered under authority of s. 384.27, s. 384.28, or s. 384.281 must show that the original order was issued by mistake or fraud, or:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That there has been a substantial change in the original facts and circumstances upon which the order was issued; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That he or she no longer poses an immediate and substantial threat to the health and welfare of the public.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When considering a petition for immediate release, and prior to making any release, the court shall consult the department and the patient’s physician, if any, concerning the patient’s medical condition and any other related factors that may affect the present and future danger to the public that may be caused by the patient’s release.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When granting a petition for immediate release, the court may impose those conditions it believes reasonably necessary to protect the public from infection with a sexually transmissible disease.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 88-380; s. 680, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>