<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0384.28" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hospitalization, placement, and residential isolation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of subsections (2) and (3), the department may petition the circuit court to order a person to be isolated, hospitalized, placed in another health care or residential facility, or isolated from the general public in his or her own or another’s residence, or a place to be made off limits to the public as a result of the probable spread of a sexually transmissible disease, until such time as the condition can be corrected or the threat to the public’s health eliminated or reduced in such a manner that a substantial threat to the public’s health no longer exists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may be ordered to be isolated, hospitalized, placed in another health care or residential facility, or isolated from the public in his or her own or another’s residence, and no place may be ordered to be made off limits, except upon the order of a court of competent jurisdiction and upon proof:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the department by clear and convincing evidence that the public’s health and welfare are significantly endangered by a person with a sexually transmissible disease or by a place where there is a significant amount of sexual activity likely to spread a sexually transmissible disease;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the person with the sexually transmissible disease has been counseled about the disease, about the significant threat the disease poses to other members of the public, and about methods to minimize the risk to the public and despite such counseling indicates an intent to expose the public to infection from the sexually transmissible disease; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all other reasonable means of correcting the problem have been exhausted and no less restrictive alternative exists.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may be ordered to be hospitalized, placed in another health care or residential facility, or isolated in his or her own or another’s residence by a court unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hearing has been held of which the person has received at least 72 hours’ prior written notification and unless the person has received a list of the proposed actions to be taken and the reasons for each one.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has the right to attend the hearing, to cross-examine witnesses, and to present evidence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has a right to an attorney to represent him or her, and to have an attorney appointed on the person’s behalf if he or she cannot afford one.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order for hospitalization, placement in another health or residential facility, or isolation from the general public in his or her own or another’s residence, if issued, will be valid for no more than 120 days, or for a shorter period of time if the department, or the court upon petition, determines that the person no longer poses a substantial threat to the community. Orders for hospitalization, placement, or isolation in a residence may contain additional requirements for adherence to a treatment plan or participation in counseling or education programs as appropriate. Such orders may not be renewed without affording the person all rights conferred in subsections (2) and (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No order for hospitalization or placement in another health care or residential facility may require the placement of a person under the age of 18 years in a unit of a facility where adults reside or have been hospitalized or placed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No order for hospitalization or placement in another health care or residential facility shall require the placement of a person in a facility designated for the treatment of acquired immune deficiency syndrome, acquired immune deficiency syndrome related complex, or human immunodeficiency virus infection when that facility contains the maximum number of persons for which the Legislature has appropriated funds in the annual appropriations act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to establish, directly or by contract, facilities to serve persons ordered to be hospitalized or placed in another health care or residential facility pursuant to a court order under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, counsel, and local law enforcement officials, as appropriate, shall consult with the department to determine advisable infection control procedures to be taken during any court hearing or detention concerning a person infected with a sexually transmissible disease.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 90, ch. 86-220; s. 30, ch. 88-380; s. 677, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>