<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0984.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Intake.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intake shall be performed by the department. A report or complaint alleging that a child is from a family in need of services shall be made to the intake office operating in the county in which the child is found or in which the case arose. Any person or agency, including, but not limited to, the parent or legal custodian, the local school district, a law enforcement agency, or the Department of Children and Family Services, having knowledge of the facts may make a report or complaint.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the department shall make a preliminary determination as to whether the report or complaint is complete. The criteria for the completeness of a report or complaint with respect to a child alleged to be from a family in need of services while subject to compulsory school attendance shall be governed by s. 984.03(27). In any case in which the representative of the department finds that the report or complaint is incomplete, the representative of the department shall return the report or complaint without delay to the person or agency originating the report or complaint or having knowledge of the facts or to the appropriate law enforcement agency having investigative jurisdiction and request additional information in order to complete the report or complaint.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the representative of the department determines that in his or her judgment the interests of the family, the child, and the public will be best served by providing the family and child services and treatment voluntarily accepted by the child and the parents or legal custodians, the departmental representative may refer the family or child to an appropriate service and treatment provider. As part of the intake procedure, the departmental representative shall inform the parent or legal custodian, in writing, of the services and treatment available to the child and family by department providers or community agencies and the rights and responsibilities of the parent or legal guardian under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department has reasonable grounds to believe that the child has been abandoned, abused, or neglected, it shall proceed pursuant to the provisions of chapter 39.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 87-133; s. 3, ch. 88-319; s. 234, ch. 95-147; s. 4, ch. 95-152; s. 8, ch. 95-280; s. 22, ch. 96-398; s. 168, ch. 97-101; s. 96, ch. 97-238; s. 5, ch. 97-281; s. 68, ch. 98-280; s. 166, ch. 98-403; s. 17, ch. 2000-135.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.423.</Text></Note></Section>