<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0984.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Case staffing; services and treatment to a family in need of services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriate representative of the department shall request a meeting of the family and child with a case staffing committee to review the case of any family or child who the department determines is in need of services or treatment if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The family or child is not in agreement with the services or treatment offered;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The family or child will not participate in the services or treatment selected; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The representative of the department needs assistance in developing an appropriate plan for services. The time and place selected for the meeting shall be convenient for the child and family.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The composition of the case staffing committee shall be based on the needs of the family and child. It shall include a representative from the child’s school district and a representative of the Department of Juvenile Justice, and may include a supervisor of the department’s contracted provider; a representative from the area of health, mental health, substance abuse, social, or educational services; a representative of the state attorney; the alternative sanctions coordinator; and any person recommended by the child, family, or department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The case staffing committee shall reach a timely decision to provide the child or family with needed services and treatment through the development of a plan for services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan for services shall contain the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Statement of the problems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Needs of the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Needs of the parents, guardian, or legal custodian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Measurable objectives that address the identified problems and needs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services and treatment to be provided, to include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Type of services or treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Frequency of services or treatment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Location.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accountable service providers or staff.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Timeframes for achieving objectives.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of the plan, the child and family shall acknowledge their position by accepting or rejecting the services and provisions in writing. If the plan is accepted, it shall be implemented as soon as is practicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A case manager shall be designated by the case staffing committee to be responsible for implementing the plan. The case manager shall periodically review the progress towards achieving the objectives of the plan in order to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the case staffing committee of the need to make adjustments to the plan; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminate the case as indicated by successful or substantial achievement of the objectives of the plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent, guardian, or legal custodian may convene a meeting of the case staffing committee, and any other member of the committee may convene a meeting if the member finds that doing so is in the best interest of the family or child. A case staffing committee meeting requested by a parent, guardian, or legal custodian must be convened within 7 days, excluding weekends and legal holidays, after the date the department’s representative receives the request in writing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 7 days after meeting, the case staffing committee shall provide the parent, guardian, or legal custodian with a written report that details the reasons for the committee’s decision to recommend, or decline to recommend, that the department file a petition alleging that the child is a child in need of services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 87-133; s. 9, ch. 91-45; s. 19, ch. 95-267; s. 9, ch. 95-280; s. 4, ch. 96-369; s. 24, ch. 96-398; s. 98, ch. 97-238; s. 7, ch. 97-281.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.426.</Text></Note></Section>