<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0984.16" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Process and service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal appearance of any person in a hearing before the court shall obviate the necessity of serving process on that person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a petition containing allegations of facts which, if true, would constitute the child therein being named a child in need of services, and upon the request of the petitioner, the clerk or deputy clerk shall issue a summons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The summons shall require the person on whom it is served to appear for a hearing at a time and place specified. Except in cases of medical emergency, the time shall not be less than 24 hours after service of the summons. The summons may require the custodian to bring the child to court if the court determines that the child’s presence is necessary. A copy of the petition shall be attached to the summons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The summons shall be directed to, and shall be served upon, the following persons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The legal custodian, actual custodian, and guardian ad litem.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The child.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of the court shall attach to the child and the parent, custodian, or legal guardian of the child and the case when the summons is served upon the child or a parent or legal or actual custodian of the child or when the child is taken into custody with or without service of summons and after filing of a petition for a child in need of services, and thereafter the court may control the child and case in accordance with this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the application of a party or the petitioner, the clerk or deputy clerk shall issue, and the court on its own motion may issue, subpoenas requiring attendance and testimony of witnesses and production of records, documents, or other tangible objects at any hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All process and orders issued by the court shall be served or executed as other process and orders of the circuit court and, in addition, may be served or executed by authorized agents of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subpoenas may be served within the state by any person over 18 years of age who is not a party to the proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No fee shall be paid for service of any process or other papers by an agent of the department. If any process, orders, or other papers are served or executed by any sheriff, the sheriff’s fees shall be paid by the county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the party to whom an order is directed is present or represented at the final hearing, service of such order shall not be required.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 87-133; s. 12, ch. 92-170; s. 28, ch. 96-398; s. 102, ch. 97-238; s. 70, ch. 98-280.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.437.</Text></Note></Section>