<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0984.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Taking into custody a child alleged to be from a family in need of services or to be a child in need of services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child may be taken into custody:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a law enforcement officer when the officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the child has run away from his or her parents, guardian, or other legal custodian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a law enforcement officer when the officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the child is absent from school without authorization or is suspended or expelled and is not in the presence of his or her parent or legal guardian, for the purpose of delivering the child without unreasonable delay to the appropriate school system site. For the purpose of this paragraph, “school system site” includes, but is not limited to, a center approved by the superintendent of schools for the purpose of counseling students and referring them back to the school system or an approved alternative to a suspension or expulsion program. If a student is suspended or expelled from school without assignment to an alternative school placement, the law enforcement officer shall deliver the child to the parent or legal guardian, to a location determined by the parent or guardian, or to a designated truancy interdiction site until the parent or guardian can be located.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to an order of the circuit court based upon sworn testimony before or after a petition is filed under s. 984.15.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By a law enforcement officer when the child voluntarily agrees to or requests services pursuant to this chapter or placement in a shelter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person taking the child into custody shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Release the child to a parent, guardian, legal custodian, or responsible adult relative or to a department-approved family-in-need-of-services and child-in-need-of-services provider if the person taking the child into custody has reasonable grounds to believe the child has run away from a parent, guardian, or legal custodian; is truant; or is beyond the control of the parent, guardian, or legal custodian; following such release, the person taking the child into custody shall make a full written report to the intake office of the department within 3 days; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver the child to the department, stating the facts by reason of which the child was taken into custody and sufficient information to establish probable cause that the child is from a family in need of services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the child is taken into custody by, or is delivered to, the department, the appropriate representative of the department shall review the facts and make such further inquiry as necessary to determine whether the child shall remain in custody or be released. Unless shelter is required as provided in s. 984.14(1), the department shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Release the child to his or her parent, guardian, or legal custodian, to a responsible adult relative, to a responsible adult approved by the department, or to a department-approved family-in-need-of-services and child-in-need-of-services provider; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorize temporary services and treatment that would allow the child alleged to be from a family in need of services to remain at home.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 87-133; s. 1, ch. 89-20; s. 232, ch. 95-147; s. 6, ch. 95-280; s. 20, ch. 96-398; s. 99, ch. 97-238; s. 23, ch. 2000-235.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.421.</Text></Note></Section>