<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0984.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of disposition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court finds that services and treatment have not been provided or utilized by a child or family, the court having jurisdiction of the child shall have the power to direct the least intrusive and least restrictive disposition, as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order the parent, guardian, or custodian and the child to participate in treatment, services, and any other alternative identified as necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order the parent, guardian, or custodian to pay a fine or fee based on the recommendations of the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any child is adjudicated by the court to be a child in need of services, the court having jurisdiction of the child and parent, guardian, or custodian shall have the power, by order, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place the child under the supervision of the department’s contracted provider of programs and services for children in need of services and families in need of services. “Supervision,” for the purposes of this section, means services as defined by the contract between the department and the provider.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place the child in the temporary legal custody of an adult willing to care for the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commit the child to a licensed child-caring agency willing to receive the child and to provide services without compensation from the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order the child, and, if the court finds it appropriate, the parent, guardian, or custodian of the child, to render community service in a public service program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any child is adjudicated by the court to be a child in need of services and temporary legal custody of the child has been placed with an adult willing to care for the child, a licensed child-caring agency, the Department of Juvenile Justice, or the Department of Children and Family Services, the court shall order the natural or adoptive parents of such child, including the natural father of such child born out of wedlock who has acknowledged his paternity in writing before the court, or the guardian of such child’s estate if possessed of assets which under law may be disbursed for the care, support, and maintenance of such child, to pay child support to the adult relative caring for the child, the licensed child-caring agency, the Department of Juvenile Justice, or the Department of Children and Family Services. When such order affects the guardianship estate, a certified copy of such order shall be delivered to the judge having jurisdiction of such guardianship estate. If the court determines that the parent is unable to pay support, placement of the child shall not be contingent upon issuance of a support order. The department may employ a collection agency for the purpose of receiving, collecting, and managing the payment of unpaid and delinquent fees. The collection agency must be registered and in good standing under chapter 559. The department may pay to the collection agency a fee from the amount collected under the claim or may authorize the agency to deduct the fee from the amount collected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All payments of fees made to the department under this chapter, or child support payments made to the department pursuant to subsection (3), shall be deposited in the General Revenue Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the court shall order the child, family, parent, guardian, or custodian of a child who is found to be a child in need of services to participate in family counseling and other professional counseling activities or other alternatives deemed necessary for the rehabilitation of the child.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The participation and cooperation of the family, parent, guardian, or custodian, and the child with court-ordered services, treatment, or community service are mandatory, not merely voluntary. The court may use its contempt powers to enforce its order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 12, ch. 87-133; s. 31, ch. 88-337; s. 18, ch. 93-120; s. 240, ch. 95-147; s. 32, ch. 96-398; s. 169, ch. 97-101; s. 108, ch. 97-238; s. 11, ch. 97-281; s. 73, ch. 98-280; s. 72, ch. 2006-227.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 39.442.</Text></Note></Section>