<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0349.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Chapter complete and additional authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers conferred by this chapter shall be in addition and supplemental to the existing powers of said board and the Department of Transportation, and this chapter shall not be construed as repealing any of the provisions of any other law, general, special, or local, but to supersede such other laws in the exercise of the powers provided in this chapter, and to provide a complete method for the exercise of the powers granted in this chapter. The refunding of any of the bonds of Florida State Improvement Commission heretofore issued to finance part of the cost of said Jacksonville Expressway System, and the completion, extension, and improvement of said system, and the issuance of bonds hereunder to finance all or part of the cost thereof, may be accomplished upon compliance with the provisions of this chapter without regard to or necessity for compliance with the provisions, limitations, or restrictions contained in any other general, special, or local law, including, without limitation, s. 215.821, and no approval of any bonds issued under this chapter by the qualified electors or qualified electors who are freeholders in the state or in said County of Duval, or in said City of Jacksonville, or in any other political subdivision of the state, shall be required for the issuance of such bonds pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter shall not be deemed to repeal, rescind, or modify any other law or laws relating to said State Board of Administration, said Department of Transportation, or said Florida State Improvement Commission but shall be deemed to and shall supersede such other law or laws in the exercise of the powers provided in this chapter insofar as such other law or laws are inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, including, without limitation, s. 215.821.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 29996, 1955; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 15, ch. 2009-111.</History></Section>