<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0827.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Abuse, aggravated abuse, and neglect of a child; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Aggravated child abuse” occurs when a person:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commits aggravated battery on a child;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully tortures, maliciously punishes, or willfully and unlawfully cages a child; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly or willfully abuses a child and in so doing causes great bodily harm, permanent disability, or permanent disfigurement to the child.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child abuse” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentional infliction of physical or mental injury upon a child;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intentional act that could reasonably be expected to result in physical or mental injury to a child; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Active encouragement of any person to commit an act that results or could reasonably be expected to result in physical or mental injury to a child.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Maliciously” means wrongfully, intentionally, and without legal justification or excuse. Maliciousness may be established by circumstances from which one could conclude that a reasonable parent would not have engaged in the damaging acts toward the child for any valid reason and that the primary purpose of the acts was to cause the victim unjustifiable pain or injury.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mental injury” means injury to the intellectual or psychological capacity of a child as evidenced by a discernible and substantial impairment in the ability of the child to function within the normal range of performance and behavior as supported by expert testimony.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Neglect of a child” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A caregiver’s failure or omission to provide a child with the care, supervision, and services necessary to maintain the child’s physical and mental health, including, but not limited to, food, nutrition, clothing, shelter, supervision, medicine, and medical services that a prudent person would consider essential for the well-being of the child; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A caregiver’s failure to make a reasonable effort to protect a child from abuse, neglect, or exploitation by another person.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Except as otherwise provided in this section, neglect of a child may be based on repeated conduct or on a single incident or omission that results in, or could reasonably be expected to result in, serious physical or mental injury, or a substantial risk of death, to a child.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OFFENSES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who commits aggravated child abuse commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who willfully or by culpable negligence neglects a child and in so doing causes great bodily harm, permanent disability, or permanent disfigurement to the child commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who knowingly or willfully abuses a child without causing great bodily harm, permanent disability, or permanent disfigurement to the child commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who willfully or by culpable negligence neglects a child without causing great bodily harm, permanent disability, or permanent disfigurement to the child commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXPERT TESTIMONY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (b), a physician may not provide expert testimony in a criminal child abuse case unless the physician is a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 or has obtained certification as an expert witness pursuant to s. 458.3175.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician may not provide expert testimony in a criminal child abuse case regarding mental injury unless the physician is a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 who has completed an accredited residency in psychiatry or has obtained certification as an expert witness pursuant to s. 458.3175.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A psychologist may not give expert testimony in a criminal child abuse case regarding mental injury unless the psychologist is licensed under chapter 490.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expert testimony requirements of this subsection apply only to criminal child abuse cases and not to family court or dependency court cases.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 4721, 1899; s. 1, ch. 4971, 1901; GS 3236, 3238; RGS 5069, 5071; s. 1, ch. 9331, 1923; CGL 7171, 7173; s. 1, ch. 65-113; s. 1, ch. 70-8; s. 940, ch. 71-136; s. 49, ch. 74-383; s. 30, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 84-238; s. 8, ch. 96-322; s. 16, ch. 99-168; s. 1, ch. 2003-130; s. 9, ch. 2012-155.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 828.04.</Text></Note></Section>