<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0843.167" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful use of police communications; enhanced penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intercept any police radio communication by use of a scanner or any other means for the purpose of using that communication to assist in committing a crime or to escape from or avoid detection, arrest, trial, conviction, or punishment in connection with the commission of such crime.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Divulge the existence, contents, substance, purport, effect, or meaning of a police radio communication to any person he or she knows to be a suspect in the commission of a crime with the intent that the suspect may escape from or avoid detention, arrest, trial, conviction, or punishment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is charged with a crime and who, during the time such crime was committed, possessed or used a police scanner or similar device capable of receiving police radio transmissions is presumed to have violated paragraph (1)(a).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The penalty for a crime that is committed by a person who violates paragraph (1)(a) shall be enhanced as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the second degree shall be punished as if it were a misdemeanor of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A misdemeanor of the first degree shall be punished as if it were a felony of the third degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the third degree shall be punished as if it were a felony of the second degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the second degree shall be punished as if it were a felony of the first degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the first degree shall be punished as if it were a life felony.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates paragraph (1)(b) commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2001-127.</History></Section>