<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0843.0855" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Criminal actions under color of law or through use of simulated legal process.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “legal process” means a document or order issued by a court or filed or recorded for the purpose of exercising jurisdiction or representing a claim against a person or property, or for the purpose of directing a person to appear before a court or tribunal, or to perform or refrain from performing a specified act. “Legal process” includes, but is not limited to, a summons, lien, complaint, warrant, injunction, writ, notice, pleading, subpoena, or order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “person” means an individual, public or private group incorporated or otherwise, legitimate or illegitimate legal tribunal or entity, informal organization, official or unofficial agency or body, or any assemblage of individuals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “public officer” means a public officer as defined by s. 112.061.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “public employee” means a public employee as defined by s. 112.061.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who deliberately impersonates or falsely acts as a public officer or tribunal, public employee or utility employee, including, but not limited to, marshals, judges, prosecutors, sheriffs, deputies, court personnel, or any law enforcement authority in connection with or relating to any legal process affecting persons and property, or otherwise takes any action under color of law against persons or property, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who simulates legal process, including, but not limited to, actions affecting title to real estate or personal property, indictments, subpoenas, warrants, injunctions, liens, orders, judgments, or any legal documents or proceedings, knowing or having reason to know the contents of any such documents or proceedings or the basis for any action to be fraudulent, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who falsely under color of law attempts in any way to influence, intimidate, or hinder a public officer or law enforcement officer in the discharge of his or her official duties by means of, but not limited to, threats of or actual physical abuse or harassment, or through the use of simulated legal process, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall make unlawful any act of any law enforcement officer or legal tribunal which is performed under lawful authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall prohibit individuals from assembling freely to express opinions or designate group affiliation or association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall prohibit or in any way limit a person’s lawful and legitimate access to the courts or prevent a person from instituting or responding to legitimate and lawful legal process.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-203.</History></Section>