<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1010.83" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Institutional Assessment Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 99-32, Laws of Florida, re-created the Institutional Assessment Trust Fund to be administered by the Department of Education pursuant to this section and rules of the State Board of Education. The trust fund shall consist of all fees and fines imposed upon nonpublic colleges and schools pursuant to this chapter and chapter 1005, including all fees collected from nonpublic colleges and schools for participation in the Student Protection Fund and the statewide course numbering system. The department shall maintain separate accounts for the operation of the Commission for Independent Education; the Student Protection Fund; and the Department of Education.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds from the trust fund shall be used for purposes including, but not limited to, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorized expenses of the Commission for Independent Education in carrying out its required duties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorized expenses from the Department of Education account incurred as a result of the inclusion of nonpublic colleges in the statewide course numbering system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses authorized by the Commission for Independent Education from the Student Protection Fund account to complete the training of students enrolled in an institution that terminates a program or ceases operation while the student is enrolled or to facilitate the retrieval or safekeeping of records from a closed institution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commission for Independent Education may utilize other individuals or entities to administer the programs authorized in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 595, ch. 2002-387; s. 5, ch. 2005-202.</History></Section>