<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1010.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Administration to act as fiscal agent in issuance and sale of motor vehicle anticipation certificates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In aid of the provisions of s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885 as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution and the additional provisions of s. 9(d), the State Board of Administration may upon request of the State Board of Education, act as fiscal agent for the State Board of Education in the issuance and sale of any or all bonds or motor vehicle tax anticipation certificates, including any refunding of bonds, certificates or interest coupons thereon which may be issued pursuant to the above cited provisions of the State Constitution and upon request of the State Board of Education the State Board of Administration may take over the management, control, bond trusteeship, administration, custody and payment of any or all debt service or other funds or assets now or hereafter available for any bonds or certificates issued for the purpose of obtaining funds for the use of any district school board or to pay, fund or refund any bonds or certificates theretofore issued for such purpose. The State Board of Education may from time to time provide by its duly adopted resolution or resolutions the duties said fiscal agent shall perform as authorized by this section and such duties may be changed, modified or repealed by subsequent resolution or resolutions as the State Board of Education may deem appropriate, provided, however, that such changes shall only affect the duties of the State Board of Administration as fiscal agent and shall not affect or modify the paramount constitutional authority of the State Board of Education nor affect, modify, or impair the contract rights of persons holding or owning the obligations so authorized to be issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No such bonds or motor vehicle tax anticipation certificates shall ever be issued by the State Board of Administration until after the adoption of a resolution requesting the issuance thereof by the State Board of Education for and on behalf of the district for which the obligations are to be issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All such bonds or certificates issued pursuant to this part shall be issued in the name of the State Board of Education but shall be issued for and on behalf of the district school board requesting the issuance thereof and shall be issued pursuant to any rules adopted by the State Board of Education which are not in conflict with the provisions of s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885 as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution, and the additional provisions of s. 9(d).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of any sale of original bonds or original certificates shall be deposited in the State Treasury to the credit of the particular construction account for which the original bonds or original certificates were issued and shall be under the direct control and supervision of the State Board of Education, and withdrawals from such construction accounts shall be made only upon warrants signed by the Chief Financial Officer. Such warrants shall be issued by the Chief Financial Officer only when the vouchers requesting such warrants are accompanied by the certificates of the State Board of Education to the effect that such withdrawals are proper expenditures for the cost of the particular construction account against which the requested warrants are to be drawn.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Administration shall annually determine the amounts necessary to meet the debt service requirements of all bonds or certificates administered by it pursuant to this section and shall certify to the State Board of Education said amounts needed. The State Board of Education, upon being satisfied that the amounts are correct, shall pay the amounts directly to the State Board of Administration for application by the State Board of Administration as provided under the terms of the resolutions authorizing the issuance of the bonds or certificates and as provided in s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885 as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution, and the additional provisions of s. 9(d).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expenses of the State Board of Administration incident to the issuance and sale of any bonds or certificates issued under the provisions of the constitution and under the provisions of this section shall be paid from the proceeds of the sale of the bonds or certificates or from the funds distributable to each county under the provisions of s. 18(a), Art. XII of the Constitution of 1885 as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution. All other expenses of the State Board of Administration for services rendered specifically for, or which are properly chargeable to the account of any bonds or certificates issued for and on behalf of any district school board under the above cited provisions of the State Constitution shall be paid from the funds distributable to each county under the provisions of s. 18(a), Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885 as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution; but general expenses of the State Board of Administration for services rendered all the districts alike shall be prorated among them and paid from the funds distributable to each district on the same basis as such funds are distributable under the provisions of s. 18(a), Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885 as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section contemplate that it will aid the State Board of Education and better serve the purposes contemplated by s. 18, Art. XII of the State Constitution of 1885 as adopted by s. 9(d), Art. XII, 1968 revised constitution, and the additional provisions of s. 9(d) and not be inconsistent therewith.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 565, ch. 2002-387; s. 1966, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>