<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1010.215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Educational funding accountability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrative personnel” means those employees responsible for management functions such as the development of broad policies and implementation of those policies through the direction of personnel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Educational support personnel” means district-based and school-based employees, including professional staff, technicians, secretaries, clerks, skilled workers, transportation employees, food service employees, and custodial and maintenance workers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Instructional personnel” means classroom teachers, including substitute teachers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Instructional specialists” means staff members responsible for providing student personnel services, librarians, and media specialists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Instructional support personnel” means aides or assistants to instructional personnel or instructional specialists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Managers” means instructional and noninstructional employees with some managerial and supervisory functions, although primarily responsible for general operations. This category includes only district-based employees.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board must classify each employee of the district school board into one of the following categories:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instructional personnel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instructional specialists;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instructional support personnel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrative personnel;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managers; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational support personnel.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The district school board shall notify each employee of such classification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The school public accountability report to parents must include the number of employees in each of the categories listed in subsection (2), by work location. However, this does not include the number of temporary substitute employees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any teacher-to-student ratio or class size measure required by law or State Board of Education rule must be computed by dividing the number of students in membership at the school by the number of full-time equivalent instructional personnel pursuant to paragraph (2)(a). Class size reports for exceptional student education shall be computed by dividing the number of exceptional students in membership by the number of full-time equivalent exceptional education classroom teachers who are classified as instructional personnel pursuant to paragraph (2)(a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All expenditures within the general and special revenue funds for each district school board, including salaries, benefits, purchased services, energy services, materials and supplies, capital outlay, and miscellaneous expenditures, for the following purposes are classified as administrative expenditures:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">District school board.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">General administration.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School administration, excluding support expenditures.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities acquisition and construction at the district level.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fiscal services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Central services at the district level.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All expenditures within the general and special revenue funds for each district school board, including salaries, benefits, purchased services, energy services, materials and supplies, capital outlay, and miscellaneous expenditures, for the following purposes are classified as instructional expenditures:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instruction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Instructional support services, including student personnel services, instructional media services, instruction and curriculum development, and instructional staff training services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School administration, including support expenditures.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities acquisition and construction at the school level.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Central services at the school level.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Student transportation services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operation of plant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of plant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Definitions for the functions specified in this subsection are specified in State Board of Education rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual school public accountability report required by ss. 1001.42(18) and 1008.345 must include a school financial report. The purpose of the school financial report is to better inform parents and the public concerning how funds were spent to operate the school during the prior fiscal year. Each school’s financial report must follow a uniform, districtwide format that is easy to read and understand.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Total revenue must be reported at the school, district, and state levels. The revenue sources that must be addressed are state and local funds, other than lottery funds; lottery funds; federal funds; and private donations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenditures must be reported as the total expenditures per unweighted full-time equivalent student at the school level and the average expenditures per full-time equivalent student at the district and state levels in each of the following categories and subcategories:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Teachers, excluding substitute teachers, and education paraprofessionals who provide direct classroom instruction to students enrolled in programs classified by s. 1011.62 as:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Basic programs;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Students-at-risk programs;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special programs for exceptional students;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Career education programs; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult programs.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substitute teachers.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other instructional personnel, including school-based instructional specialists and their assistants.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracted instructional services, including training for instructional staff and other contracted instructional services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School administration, including school-based administrative personnel and school-based education support personnel.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following materials, supplies, and operating capital outlay:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Textbooks;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Computer hardware and software;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other instructional materials;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other materials and supplies; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Library media materials.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Food services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other support services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operation and maintenance of the school plant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The school financial report must also identify the types of district-level expenditures that support the school’s operations. The total amount of these district-level expenditures must be reported and expressed as total expenditures per full-time equivalent student.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on the classifications in this section, each district school board shall annually submit a report by January 1, which identifies and summarizes administrative expenditures and instructional expenditures by fund for the preceding fiscal year. The report shall also state the number of unweighted full-time equivalent students enrolled in the school district. The total amount of administrative expenditures shall be divided by the number of unweighted full-time equivalent students to determine the administrative expenditures per student. This calculation is to be made separately for the general and the special revenue funds. In addition, the report shall reflect the number of employees in each category outlined in subsection (2) and the percentage of employees in each category, excluding the number of temporary substitute employees. This report shall be submitted to the commissioner and shall be made available to the public. The school public accountability report shall contain notification of the availability of this report.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 539, ch. 2002-387; s. 63, ch. 2004-41; s. 23, ch. 2008-108.</History></Section>