<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1010.87" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund within the Department of Education.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund is created within the Department of Education, to be administered by such department. The trust fund shall be used for the purpose of providing funds for the payment of all expenses in respect to the administration of programs for the rehabilitation and reemployment of injured workers, pursuant to legislative appropriation or an approved amendment to the department’s operating budget pursuant to the provisions of chapter 216.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds appropriated by nonoperating transfer from the Department of Financial Services Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund which remain unencumbered as of June 30 or undisbursed as of September 30 shall revert to the Department of Financial Services Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-398; s. 2, ch. 2003-208; s. 26, ch. 2005-3; s. 22, ch. 2010-155; s. 1, ch. 2012-135.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Repealed June 30, 2013, by s. 1, ch. 2012-135.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 2, ch. 2012-135, provides that: </Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund, FLAIR number 48-2-795, within the Department of Education is terminated.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The balance remaining in, and all revenues of, the trust fund shall be transferred to the Workers’ Compensation Administration Trust Fund within the Department of Financial Services.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(3) The Division of Vocational Rehabilitation within the Department of Education shall pay any outstanding debts or obligations of the terminated trust fund as soon as practicable, and the Chief Financial Officer shall close out and remove the terminated trust fund from the various state accounting systems using generally accepted accounting principles concerning warrants outstanding, assets, and liabilities.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>