<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1010.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Uniform records and accounts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial records and accounts of each school district, Florida College System institution, and other institution or agency under the supervision of the State Board of Education shall be prepared and maintained as prescribed by law and rules of the State Board of Education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial records and accounts of each state university under the supervision of the Board of Governors shall be prepared and maintained as prescribed by law and rules of the Board of Governors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules of the State Board of Education and rules of the Board of Governors shall incorporate the requirements of law and accounting principles generally accepted in the United States. Such rules shall include a uniform classification of accounts.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state university shall annually file with the Board of Governors financial statements prepared in conformity with accounting principles generally accepted by the United States and the uniform classification of accounts prescribed by the Board of Governors. The Board of Governors’ rules shall prescribe the filing deadline for the financial statements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Required financial accounts and reports shall include provisions that are unique to each of the following: K-12 school districts, Florida College System institutions, and state universities, and shall provide for the data to be reported to the National Center of Educational Statistics and other governmental and professional educational data information services as appropriate.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 526, ch. 2002-387; s. 142, ch. 2007-217; s. 149, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>