<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0103.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of party name; political advertising.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall use the name, abbreviation, or symbol of any political party, the name, abbreviation, or symbol of which is filed with the Department of State, in political advertising in newspapers, other publications, handbills, radio or television, or any other form of advertising in connection with any political activities in support of a candidate of any other party, unless such person shall first obtain the written permission of the chair of the state executive committee of the party the name, abbreviation, or symbol of which is to be used.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person or group of persons shall use the name, abbreviation, or symbol of any political party, the name, abbreviation, or symbol of which is filed with the Department of State, in connection with any club, group, association, or organization of any kind unless approval and permission have been given in writing by the state executive committee of such party. This subsection shall not apply to county executive committees of such parties and organizations which are chartered by the national executive committee of the party the name, abbreviation, or symbol of which is to be used, or to organizations using the name of any political party which organizations have been in existence and organized on a statewide basis for a period of 10 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A political party may file with the Department of State names of groups or committees associated with the political party. Such filed names may not be used without first obtaining the written permission of the chair of the state executive committee of the party.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, an affiliated party committee shall be entitled to use the name, abbreviation, or symbol of the political party of its leader as defined in s. 103.092.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 6469, 1913; RGS 304; CGL 360; s. 7, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 26, ch. 29934, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-202; s. 1, ch. 61-424; s. 3, ch. 67-353; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 32, ch. 77-175; s. 606, ch. 95-147; s. 35, ch. 2007-30; ss. 1, 30, ch. 2011-6; HJR 7105, 2011 Regular Session.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 102.06.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>