<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0103.121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of executive committees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state and county executive committee of a political party shall have the power and duty:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt a constitution by two-thirds vote of the full committee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt such bylaws as it may deem necessary by majority vote of the full committee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conduct its meetings according to generally accepted parliamentary practice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make party nomination when required by law.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conduct campaigns for party nominees.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To raise and expend party funds. Such funds may not be expended or committed to be expended except after written authorization by the chair of the state or county executive committee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county executive committee shall receive payment of assessments upon candidates to be voted for in a single county except state senators, state representatives, and representatives to the Congress of the United States; an affiliated party committee controlled by a leader of the Senate as defined in s. 103.092 shall receive payment of assessments upon candidates for the office of state senator, and an affiliated party committee controlled by a leader of the House of Representatives as defined in s. 103.092 shall receive payment of assessments upon candidates for the office of state representative; and the state executive committees shall receive all other assessments authorized. All party assessments shall be 2 percent of the annual salary of the office sought by the respective candidate. All such committee assessments shall be remitted to the state executive committee of the appropriate party and distributed in accordance with subsection (5), except that assessments for candidates for the office of state senator or state representative shall be remitted to the appropriate affiliated party committee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The chair and treasurer of an executive committee of any political party shall be accountable for the funds of such committee and jointly liable for their proper expenditure for authorized purposes only. The funds of each such state executive committee shall be publicly audited at the end of each calendar year and a copy of such audit furnished to the Department of State for its examination prior to April 1 of the ensuing year. When filed with the Department of State, copies of such audit shall be public documents. The treasurer of each county executive committee shall maintain adequate records evidencing receipt and disbursement of all party funds received by him or her, and such records shall be publicly audited at the end of each calendar year and a copy of such audit filed with the supervisor of elections and the state executive committee prior to April 1 of the ensuing year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any chair or treasurer of a state or county executive committee of any political party who knowingly misappropriates, or makes an unlawful expenditure of, or a false or improper accounting for, the funds of such committee is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The central committee or other equivalent governing body of each state executive committee shall adopt a rule which governs the time and manner in which the respective county executive committees of such party may endorse, certify, screen, or otherwise recommend one or more candidates for such party’s nomination for election. Upon adoption, such rule shall provide the exclusive method by which a county committee may so endorse, certify, screen, or otherwise recommend. No later than the date on which qualifying for public office begins pursuant to s. 99.061, the chair of each county executive committee shall notify in writing the supervisor of elections of his or her county whether the county executive committee has endorsed or intends to endorse, certify, screen, or otherwise recommend candidates for nomination pursuant to party rule. A copy of such notification shall be provided to the Secretary of State and to the chair of the appropriate state executive committee.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state chair of each state executive committee shall return the 2-percent committee assessment for county candidates to the appropriate county executive committees only upon receipt of a written statement that such county executive committee chooses not to endorse, certify, screen, or otherwise recommend one or more candidates for such party’s nomination for election and upon the state chair’s determination that the county executive committee is in compliance with all Florida statutes and all state party rules, bylaws, constitutions, and requirements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 20, 21, 23, 28, ch. 6469, 1913; RGS 324, 325, 327, 332; CGL 381, 382, 384, 389; s. 1, ch. 25389, 1949; s. 9, ch. 26329, 1949; s. 7, ch. 26870, 1951; s. 41, ch. 28156, 1953; s. 2, ch. 29935, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-743; s. 1, ch. 61-157; s. 1, ch. 63-97; ss. 6, 7, 8, ch. 67-353; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 26, ch. 77-104; s. 32, ch. 77-175; s. 50, ch. 79-400; s. 1, ch. 82-160; s. 25, ch. 83-217; s. 2, ch. 83-242; s. 1, ch. 89-256; s. 609, ch. 95-147; s. 64, ch. 2005-277; ss. 3, 30, ch. 2011-6; HJR 7105, 2011 Regular Session.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 102.27, 102.28, 102.30, 102.35.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>