<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0265.284" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Chief cultural officer; director of division; powers and duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of State is the chief cultural officer of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is the state arts administrative agency and shall be headed by a director who shall serve at the pleasure of the secretary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall directly administer and oversee all of the programs authorized by this act. In furtherance thereof, the division shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept and administer state and federal funds appropriated by the Legislature or funds received from other public or private sources.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advance funds for grants on a quarterly basis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements for awarding grants or other contracts with any person, firm, performing arts company, educational institution, arts organization, corporation, or governmental agency as may be necessary or advisable to carry out its functions under this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, or at its own initiative, consult with and advise other individuals, groups, organizations, or state agencies and officials, particularly the Governor and the Cabinet, concerning the acquisition by gift or purchase of fine art works, the appropriate use and display of state-owned art treasures for maximum public benefit, and the suitability of any structures or fixtures, including framing, primarily intended for ornamental or decorative purposes in the interior of public buildings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept on behalf of the state donations of money, property, art objects, and antiquities. Such donations of money and any cash income may be received from the disposal of any donations of property, art objects, or antiquities, which shall be deposited into the Grants and Donations Trust Fund and are hereby appropriated for use by the division for the purposes authorized in this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sponsor performances and exhibits; promote and encourage the study and appreciation of arts and culture; and collect, publish, and print pamphlets, papers, newsletters, and other materials related to arts and cultural programs available throughout the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct and support cultural programs and cultural exchanges by coordinating with the appropriate state agencies and other organizations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept funding and other forms of support for the purposes in this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 287.022 or s. 287.025(1)(e), enter into contracts to insure museum collections, artifacts, relics, and fine arts to which it holds title or which are on loan to the division.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-319; s. 1, ch. 92-61; s. 194, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 5, ch. 95-282; s. 2, ch. 95-333; s. 52, ch. 98-200; s. 48, ch. 2001-61; s. 4, ch. 2003-401; s. 7, ch. 2005-207; s. 6, ch. 2009-72; s. 2, ch. 2010-20.</History>
</Section>