<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0265.285" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Council on Arts and Culture; membership, duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Council on Arts and Culture is created within the department as an advisory body, as defined in s. 20.03(7), consisting of 15 members. Seven members shall be appointed by the Governor, four members shall be appointed by the President of the Senate, and four members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives. The appointments, to be made in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall recognize the need for geographical representation. Council members appointed by the Governor shall be appointed for 4-year terms beginning on January 1 of the year of appointment. Council members appointed by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall be appointed for 2-year terms beginning on January 1 of the year of appointment. A member of the council who serves two 4-year terms or two 2-year terms is not eligible for reappointment for 1 year following the expiration of the member’s second term. A member whose term has expired shall continue to serve on the council until such time as a replacement is appointed. Any vacancy on the council shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as for the original appointment. Members should have a substantial history of community service in the performing or visual arts, which includes, but is not limited to, theatre, dance, folk arts, music, architecture, photography, literature, and media arts, or in the areas of science, history, or children’s museums. In addition, it is desirable that members have successfully served on boards of cultural institutions such as museums and performing arts centers or are recognized as patrons of the arts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members shall elect a chair from their number annually. The council shall meet at the call of its chair, at the request of the division, or at such times as may be prescribed by its rules. A majority of the members of the council constitutes a quorum, and a meeting may not be held with less than a quorum present. The affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the council present is necessary for any official action by the council.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council and panels may not receive any compensation for their services but shall be reimbursed for travel and expenses incurred in the performance of their duties, as provided in s. 112.061.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a member of the council is absent from two consecutive meetings or any two regularly scheduled meetings in any calendar year, the council member’s appointment shall be terminated unless the original appointing authority determines that extenuating circumstances exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The original appointing authority may remove any of his or her appointees from the council for misconduct or malfeasance in office, neglect of duty, incompetence, or permanent inability to perform official duties or if there has been an adjudication that the member is guilty of a felony.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advocate for arts and culture by encouraging the study and presentation of arts and cultural activities that are of public interest and encourage participation in such activities throughout the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the secretary in matters pertaining to arts and cultural programs and grants administered by the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage the participation in and appreciation of arts and culture to meet the needs and aspirations of persons in all parts of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage public interest in the state’s cultural heritage and expand its cultural resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage and assist freedom of artistic expression that is essential for the well-being of the arts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise the secretary in matters concerning the awarding of grants for arts and culture as authorized in this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review applications for grants for the acquisition, renovation, or construction of cultural facilities and recommend a priority for the receipt of such grants, as provided in s. 265.701.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 4, ch. 80-319; ss. 2, 4, 5, ch. 81-127; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-46; s. 2, ch. 83-265; s. 1, ch. 84-8; s. 6, ch. 88-137; ss. 9, 12, 13, ch. 90-267; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 195, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 155, ch. 95-148; s. 1, ch. 96-151; s. 1, ch. 2002-202; s. 19, ch. 2004-5; s. 2, ch. 2006-111; s. 7, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>