<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0265.7025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to historic programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of ss. 265.7025-265.709, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means any state, county, or municipal officer, department, division, board, bureau, commission, or other separate unit of government created or established by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Cultural Affairs of the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Florida history museum” means a public or private nonprofit institution that is established permanently in this state for the purpose of promoting and encouraging knowledge and appreciation of Florida history through the collection, preservation, exhibition, and interpretation of artifacts and other historical properties related to Florida history and the primary role of which is to collect and care for artifacts and other objects of intrinsic historical or archaeological value and exhibit them regularly through a facility or facilities owned or operated by the institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Historic property” or “historic resource” means any prehistoric or historic district, site, building, object, or other real or personal property of historical, architectural, or archaeological value, and folklife resources. These properties or resources may include, but are not limited to, monuments, memorials, Indian habitations, ceremonial sites, abandoned settlements, sunken or abandoned ships, engineering works, treasure troves, artifacts, or other objects having intrinsic historical or archaeological value, or any part thereof, relating to the history, government, or culture of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preservation” or “historic preservation” means the identification, evaluation, recordation, documentation, analysis, recovery, interpretation, curation, acquisition, protection, management, rehabilitation, restoration, stabilization, maintenance, or reconstruction of historic properties.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2008-199.</History></Section>