<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0265.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent; Florida Medal of Honor Wall; duties of the Department of Veterans’ Affairs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Florida Legislature to recognize and honor those who are accredited, or associated by birth, to the State of Florida, who through their conspicuous bravery and gallantry during wartime, and at considerable risk to their own lives, were made recipients of the Medal of Honor. In doing so, these members of our Armed Forces brought great credit upon themselves, their military units, and the State of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby established the Florida Medal of Honor Wall. The Department of Management Services shall, in consultation with the Department of Veterans’ Affairs, designate an appropriate area on the Plaza Level of the Capitol Building in Tallahassee for this purpose. The department shall also subsequently consult with the Department of Veterans’ Affairs regarding the design and theme of such area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each recipient who is accredited, or associated by birth, to the State of Florida and has been awarded the Medal of Honor shall have a plaque or similar designation approved by the Department of Veterans’ Affairs placed on the Medal of Honor Wall, which designation shall provide information regarding the Floridian’s particular act of heroism as well as other information relating to the nature of the act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Verification of residency, dates of the receipt of the award, and other specific information pertaining to each recipient shall be the responsibility of the Department of Veterans’ Affairs, which shall certify eligibility for inclusion of individuals to be added to the Florida Medal of Honor Wall.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 96-208; s. 42, ch. 98-279; s. 2, ch. 2008-84.</History></Section>