<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0265.001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Women’s Hall of Fame.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to recognize and honor those women who, through their works and lives, have made significant contributions to the improvement of life for women and for all citizens of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby established the Florida Women’s Hall of Fame. The Department of Management Services shall set aside an area on the Plaza Level of the Capitol Building and shall consult with the Florida Commission on the Status of Women regarding the design and theme of such area.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who is selected as a member shall have a designation placed in the Florida Women’s Hall of Fame, which designation shall provide information regarding the member’s particular discipline or contribution and any vital information relating to the member.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every year, the commission shall accept nominations for persons to be recommended as members of the Florida Women’s Hall of Fame. The commission shall recommend to the Governor 10 persons from which up to three members shall be selected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In making recommendations pursuant to this subsection, the commission shall recommend women who were born in Florida or adopted Florida as their home state and base of operation and who have made a significant contribution to the enhancement of women in this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Commission on the Status of Women may set specific time periods for acceptance of nominations and the selection of members to coincide with the appropriate activities of the Florida Women’s Hall of Fame.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-48; s. 15, ch. 95-143; s. 41, ch. 98-279; s. 41, ch. 2000-158; s. 3, ch. 2000-340.</History></Section>