<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0265.704" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Historical museums; powers and duties of the Division of Cultural Affairs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to administer the provisions of ss. 265.7025-265.709.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may make and enter into all contracts and agreements with other agencies, organizations, associations, corporations, and individuals or with federal agencies as it may determine are necessary, expedient, or incidental to the performance of its duties or the execution of its powers under ss. 265.7025-265.709.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may accept gifts, grants, bequests, loans, and endowments for purposes not inconsistent with its responsibilities under this chapter. The division may also establish an endowment that is consistent with the responsibilities under ss. 265.7025-265.709.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the duty of the division to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote and encourage throughout the state knowledge and appreciation of Florida history by encouraging the people of the state to engage in the preservation and care of artifacts, museum items, treasure troves, and other historical properties; the collection, research, fabrication, exhibition, preservation, and interpretation of historical materials; the publicizing of the state’s history through public information media; and other activities in historical and allied fields.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourage, promote, maintain, and operate historical museums, including, but not limited to, mobile museums, junior museums, and the Museum of Florida History in the state capital.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plan and develop, in cooperation with other state agencies and with municipalities, programs to promote and encourage the teaching of Florida’s history and heritage in Florida schools and other educational institutions and other such educational programs as may be appropriate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish professional standards for the preservation, exclusive of acquisition, of historical resources in state ownership or control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take such other actions as are necessary or appropriate to locate, acquire, protect, preserve, operate, interpret, and promote the location, acquisition, protection, preservation, operation, and interpretation of historical resources to foster an appreciation of Florida history and culture.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2008-199.</History></Section>