<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0265.283" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following definitions shall apply to ss. 265.281-265.709:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Council” means the Florida Council on Arts and Culture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the Director of the Division of Cultural Affairs of the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Cultural Affairs of the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Panel” means a grant review panel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secretary” means the Secretary of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Arts and cultural disciplines” include, but are not limited to, music, dance, theatre, creative writing, literature, architecture, painting, sculpture, folk arts, photography, crafts, media arts, visual arts, programs of museums, and other such allied, major art forms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local arts agency” means a public or private nonprofit organization located in Florida and operating on a permanent basis for the primary purpose of strengthening, supporting, and stabilizing the activities of one or more county art and cultural constituencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Historical museum” means a department or agency of state or local government or a public or private nonprofit organization located in Florida and operating on a permanent basis for the primary purpose of sponsoring, producing, and exhibiting educational programs that are related to the historical resources of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Science museum” means a public or private nonprofit organization located in Florida and operating on a permanent basis for the primary purpose of sponsoring, producing, and exhibiting programs for the observation and study of various types of natural science and science technology.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Youth and children’s museum” means a public or private nonprofit organization located in Florida and operating on a permanent basis for the primary purpose of sponsoring, producing, and exhibiting multidisciplinary and participatory programs for visitors who are 6 months to 15 years old, and their families, teachers, and caregivers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State service organization” means a public or private nonprofit organization located in Florida operating on a permanent basis for the primary purpose of implementing programs that have cultural significance and that emphasize American creativity and the maintenance and encouragement of professional excellence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Arts in education grants” means grants used to cultivate the learning and artistic development of all students and teachers by promoting, encouraging, and supporting arts and culture as an integral part of education and lifelong learning for residents and visitors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cultural support grants” means grants that provide support for general programs and specific cultural projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State touring program grants” means grants used to provide performances, activities, and exhibitions by Florida artists to communities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Underserved arts community assistance program grants” means grants used by qualified organizations under the Rural Economic Development Initiative, pursuant to ss. 288.0656 and 288.06561, for the purpose of economic and organizational development for underserved cultural organizations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Culture Builds Florida grants” means grants used for the purpose of connecting the arts to key areas of the division’s long-term strategic plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-319; s. 1, ch. 81-127; s. 8, ch. 90-267; s. 5, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>