<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.3131" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Costs and fees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petitioner may not be required to pay a filing fee or other costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an obligee prevails, a responding tribunal may assess against an obligor filing fees, reasonable attorney’s fees, other costs, and necessary travel and other reasonable expenses incurred by the obligee and the obligee’s witnesses. The tribunal may not assess fees, costs, or expenses against the obligee or the support enforcement agency of either the initiating or the responding state, except as provided by other law. Attorney’s fees may be taxed as costs, and may be ordered paid directly to the attorney, who may enforce the order in the attorney’s own name. Payment of support owed to the obligee has priority over fees, costs, and expenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tribunal shall order the payment of costs and reasonable attorney’s fees if it determines that a hearing was requested primarily for delay. In a proceeding under part VI, a hearing is presumed to have been requested primarily for delay if a registered support order is confirmed or enforced without change.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 96-189; s. 27, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.” Section 27, ch. 2011-92, amended subsection (2), to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) If an obligee prevails, a responding tribunal of this state may assess against an obligor filing fees, reasonable attorney’s fees, other costs, and necessary travel and other reasonable expenses incurred by the obligee and the obligee’s witnesses. The tribunal may not assess fees, costs, or expenses against the obligee or the support enforcement agency of either the initiating or the responding state or foreign country, except as provided by other law. Attorney’s fees may be taxed as costs, and may be ordered paid directly to the attorney, who may enforce the order in the attorney’s own name. Payment of support owed to the obligee has priority over fees, costs, and expenses.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>