<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.3071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duties of support enforcement agency.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A support enforcement agency of this state, upon request, shall provide services to a petitioner in a proceeding under this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A support enforcement agency that is providing services to the petitioner as appropriate shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take all steps necessary to enable an appropriate tribunal in this state or another state to obtain jurisdiction over the respondent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Request an appropriate tribunal to set a date, time, and place for a hearing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make a reasonable effort to obtain all relevant information, including information as to income and property of the parties.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of a written notice from an initiating, responding, or registering tribunal, send a copy of the notice to the petitioner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of a written communication from the respondent or the respondent’s attorney, send a copy of the communication to the petitioner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the petitioner if jurisdiction over the respondent cannot be obtained.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act does not create or negate a relationship of attorney and client or other fiduciary relationship between a support enforcement agency or the attorney for the agency and the individual being assisted by the agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 96-189; s. 23, ch. 97-170; s. 22, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.” Section 22, ch. 2011-92, amended s. 88.3071, to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">88.3071 Duties of support enforcement agency.</Font><EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) In a proceeding under this act, a support enforcement agency of this state, upon request:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Shall provide services to a petitioner residing in a state;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Shall provide services to a petitioner requesting services through a central authority of a foreign country as described in s. 88.1011(5)(a) or (d); and</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) May provide services to a petitioner who is an individual not residing in a state.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) A support enforcement agency that is providing services to the petitioner as appropriate shall:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Take all steps necessary to enable an appropriate tribunal in this state, another state, or a foreign country to obtain jurisdiction over the respondent.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Request an appropriate tribunal to set a date, time, and place for a hearing.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) Make a reasonable effort to obtain all relevant information, including information as to income and property of the parties.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) Within 10 days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of a written notice from an initiating, responding, or registering tribunal, send a copy of the notice to the petitioner.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) Within 10 days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of a written communication from the respondent or the respondent’s attorney, send a copy of the communication to the petitioner.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(f) Notify the petitioner if jurisdiction over the respondent cannot be obtained.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) A support enforcement agency of this state that requests registration of a child support order in this state for enforcement or for modification shall make reasonable efforts:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) To ensure that the order to be registered is the controlling order; or</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) If two or more child support orders exist and the identity of the controlling order has not been determined, to ensure that a request for such a determination is made in a tribunal having jurisdiction to do so.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) A support enforcement agency of this state that requests registration and enforcement of a support order, arrears, or judgment stated in a foreign currency shall convert the amounts stated in the foreign currency into the equivalent amounts in dollars under the applicable official or market exchange rate as publicly reported.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) A support enforcement agency of this state shall issue or request a tribunal of this state to issue a child support order and an income-withholding order that redirect payment of current support, arrears, and interest if requested to do so by a support enforcement agency of another state pursuant to s. 88.3191.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) This act does not create or negate a relationship of attorney and client or other fiduciary relationship between a support enforcement agency or the attorney for the agency and the individual being assisted by the agency.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>