<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.7081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recognition and enforcement of convention support order.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2), a tribunal of this state shall recognize and enforce a registered convention support order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following grounds are the only grounds on which a tribunal of this state may refuse recognition and enforcement of a registered convention support order:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognition and enforcement of the order is manifestly incompatible with public policy, including the failure of the issuing tribunal to observe minimum standards of due process, which include notice and an opportunity to be heard;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuing tribunal lacked personal jurisdiction consistent with s. 88.2011;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order is not enforceable in the issuing country;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order was obtained by fraud in connection with a matter of procedure;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A record transmitted in accordance with s. 88.7061 lacks authenticity or integrity;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proceeding between the same parties and having the same purpose is pending before a tribunal of this state and that proceeding was the first to be filed;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order is incompatible with a more recent support order involving the same parties and having the same purpose if the more recent support order is entitled to recognition and enforcement under this act in this state;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment, to the extent alleged arrears have been paid in whole or in part;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a case in which the respondent neither appeared nor was represented in the proceeding in the issuing foreign country:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the law of that country provides for prior notice of proceedings, the respondent did not have proper notice of the proceedings and an opportunity to be heard; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the law of that country does not provide for prior notice of the proceedings, the respondent did not have proper notice of the order and an opportunity to be heard in a challenge or appeal on fact or law before a tribunal; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order was made in violation of s. 88.7111.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a tribunal of this state does not recognize a convention support order under paragraph (2)(b), paragraph (2)(d), paragraph (2)(f), or paragraph (2)(i):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tribunal may not dismiss the proceeding without allowing a reasonable time for a party to request the establishment of a new convention support order; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall take all appropriate measures to request a child support order for the obligee if the application for recognition and enforcement was received under s. 88.7041.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 66, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 66, ch. 2011-92, created s. 88.7081, to be effective on a date contingent upon the provisions of s. 81, ch. 2011-92. Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>