<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.3111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pleadings and accompanying documents.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Reference Number="1"/>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petitioner seeking to establish or modify a support order or to determine parentage in a proceeding under this act must verify the petition or comparable pleading. Unless otherwise ordered under s. 88.3121 (nondisclosure of information in exceptional circumstances), the petition or comparable pleading or the documents accompanying either the petition or comparable pleading must provide, so far as known, the name, residential address, and social security numbers of the obligor and the obligee, and the name, sex, residential address, social security number, and date of birth of each child for whom support is sought. The petition must be accompanied by a certified copy of any support order in effect. The petition may include any other information that may assist in locating or identifying the respondent.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition must specify the relief sought. The petition and accompanying documents must conform substantially with the requirements imposed by the forms mandated by federal law for use in cases filed by a support enforcement agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 96-189; s. 25, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.” Section 25, ch. 2011-92, amended subsection (1), to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) In a proceeding under this act, a petitioner seeking to establish a support order, to determine parentage of a child, or to register and modify a support order of a tribunal of another state or a foreign country must file a petition or comparable pleading. Unless otherwise ordered under s. 88.3121, the petition or comparable pleading or the documents accompanying either the petition or comparable pleading must provide, so far as known, the name, residential address, and social security numbers of the obligor and the obligee or the parent and alleged parent, and the name, sex, residential address, social security number, and date of birth of each child for whose benefit support is sought or whose parentage of a child is to be determined. Unless filed at the time of registration, the petition must be accompanied by a copy of any support order known to have been issued by another tribunal. The petition may include any other information that may assist in locating or identifying the respondent.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>