<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.7041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Initiation by Department of Revenue of support proceeding under convention.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a support proceeding under this part, the Department of Revenue shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transmit and receive applications; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate or facilitate the institution of a proceeding regarding an application in a tribunal of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following support proceedings are available to an obligee under the convention:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognition or recognition and enforcement of a foreign support order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcement of a support order issued or recognized in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of a support order if there is no existing order, including, where necessary, determination of parentage of a child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of a support order if recognition of a foreign support order is refused under s. 88.7081(2)(b), (d), or (i).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of another state or a foreign country.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following support proceedings are available under the convention to an obligor against whom there is an existing support order:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognition of an order suspending or limiting enforcement of an existing support order of a tribunal of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of another state or foreign country.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tribunal of this state may not require security, bond, or deposit, however described, to guarantee the payment of costs and expenses in proceedings under the convention.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 62, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 62, ch. 2011-92, created s. 88.7041, to be effective on a date contingent upon the provisions of s. 81, ch. 2011-92. Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>