<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.6041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Choice of law.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The law of the issuing state governs the nature, extent, amount, and duration of current payments and other obligations of support and the payment of arrearages under the order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding for arrearages, the statute of limitation under the laws of this state or of the issuing state, whichever is longer, applies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 96-189; s. 47, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.” Section 47, ch. 2011-92, amended s. 88.6041, to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">88.6041 Choice of law.</Font><EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4), the law of the issuing state or foreign country governs:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The nature, extent, amount, and duration of current payments under a registered support order;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The computation and payment of arrearages and accrual of interest on the arrearages under the order; and</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The existence and satisfaction of other obligations under the support order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) In a proceeding for arrears under a registered support order, the statute of limitation of this state or of the issuing state or foreign country, whichever is longer, applies.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) A responding tribunal of this state shall apply the procedures and remedies of this state to enforce current support and collect arrears and interest due on a support order of another state or foreign country registered in this state.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) After a tribunal of this or another state determines which is the controlling order and issues an order consolidating arrears, if any, a tribunal of this state shall prospectively apply the law of the state or foreign country issuing the controlling order, including its law on interest on arrears, on current and future support, and on consolidated arrears.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>