<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.7071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contest of registered convention support order.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this part, ss. 88.6051-88.6081 apply to a contest of a registered convention support order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party contesting a registered convention support order shall file a contest not later than 30 days after notice of the registration, but if the contesting party does not reside in the United States, the contest must be filed not later than 60 days after notice of the registration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the nonregistering party fails to contest the registered convention support order by the time specified in subsection (2), the order is enforceable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A contest of a registered convention support order may be based only on grounds set forth in s. 88.7081. The contesting party bears the burden of proof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a contest of a registered convention support order, a tribunal of this state:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is bound by the findings of fact on which the foreign tribunal based its jurisdiction; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not review the merits of the order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A tribunal of this state deciding a contest of a registered convention support order shall promptly notify the parties of its decision.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A challenge or appeal, if any, does not stay the enforcement of a convention support order unless there are exceptional circumstances.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 65, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 65, ch. 2011-92, created s. 88.7071, to be effective on a date contingent upon the provisions of s. 81, ch. 2011-92. Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>