<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.6071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contest of registration or enforcement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A party contesting the validity or enforcement of a registered order or seeking to vacate the registration has the burden of proving one or more of the following defenses:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuing tribunal lacked personal jurisdiction over the contesting party;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order was obtained by fraud;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order has been vacated, suspended, or modified by a later order;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuing tribunal has stayed the order pending appeal;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a defense under the law of this state to the remedy sought;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full or partial payment has been made; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statute of limitation under s. 88.6041 precludes enforcement of some or all of the arrearages.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a party presents evidence establishing a full or partial defense under subsection (1), a tribunal may stay enforcement of the registered order, continue the proceeding to permit production of additional relevant evidence, and issue other appropriate orders. An uncontested portion of the registered order may be enforced by all remedies available under the law of this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the contesting party does not establish a defense under subsection (1) to the validity or enforcement of the order, the registering tribunal shall issue an order confirming the order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 96-189; s. 50, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.” Section 50, ch. 2011-92, amended s. 88.6071, to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">88.6071 Contest of registration or enforcement.</Font><EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) A party contesting the validity or enforcement of a registered support order or seeking to vacate the registration has the burden of proving one or more of the following defenses:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The issuing tribunal lacked personal jurisdiction over the contesting party;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The order was obtained by fraud;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The order has been vacated, suspended, or modified by a later order;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) The issuing tribunal has stayed the order pending appeal;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) There is a defense under the law of this state to the remedy sought;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(f) Full or partial payment has been made;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(g) The statute of limitation under s. 88.6041 precludes enforcement of some or all of the alleged arrearages; or</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(h) The alleged controlling order is not the controlling order.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) If a party presents evidence establishing a full or partial defense under subsection (1), a tribunal may stay enforcement of a registered support order, continue the proceeding to permit production of additional relevant evidence, and issue other appropriate orders. An uncontested portion of the registered support order may be enforced by all remedies available under the law of this state.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) If the contesting party does not establish a defense under subsection (1) to the validity or enforcement of a registered support order, the registering tribunal shall issue an order confirming the order.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>