<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0088.3121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nondisclosure of information in exceptional circumstances.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon a finding, which may be made ex parte, that the health, safety, or liberty of a party or child would be unreasonably put at risk by the disclosure of identifying information, or if an existing order so provides, a tribunal shall order that the address of the child or party or other identifying information not be disclosed in a pleading or other document filed in a proceeding under this act.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 96-189; s. 26, ch. 2011-92.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 81, ch. 2011-92, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect upon the earlier of 90 days following Congress amending 42 U.S.C. s. 666(f) to allow or require states to adopt the 2008 version of the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, or 90 days following the state obtaining a waiver of its state plan requirement under Title IV-D of the Social Security Act.” Section 26, ch. 2011-92, amended s. 88.3121, to read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">88.3121 Nondisclosure of information in exceptional circumstances.</Font><EmDash/>If a party alleges in an affidavit or a pleading under oath that the health, safety, or liberty of a party or child would be jeopardized by disclosure of specific identifying information, that information must be sealed and may not be disclosed to the other party or the public. After a hearing in which a tribunal takes into consideration the health, safety, or liberty of the party or child, the tribunal may order disclosure of information that the tribunal determines to be in the interest of justice.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>