<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0215.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain income and certain trust funds to contribute to the General Revenue Fund.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A service charge of 8 percent, representing the estimated pro rata share of the cost of general government paid from the General Revenue Fund, is hereby appropriated from all income of a revenue nature deposited in all trust funds except those enumerated in s. 215.22. Income of a revenue nature shall include all earnings received or credited by such trust funds, including the interest or benefit received from the investment of the principal of such trust funds as may be permitted by law. This provision shall be construed in favor of the General Revenue Fund in each instance. All such appropriations shall be deposited in the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1), the trust funds of the Department of Citrus and the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, including funds collected in the General Inspection Trust Fund for marketing orders and in the Florida Citrus Advertising Trust Fund, shall be subject to a 4 percent service charge, which is hereby appropriated to the General Revenue Fund. This paragraph does not apply to the Conservation and Recreation Lands Program Trust Fund, the Citrus Inspection Trust Fund, the Florida Forever Program Trust Fund, the Market Improvements Working Capital Trust Fund, the Pest Control Trust Fund, the Plant Industry Trust Fund, or other funds collected in the General Inspection Trust Fund in the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) does not prohibit the applicability of s. 215.24 should the Governor determine that for the reasons mentioned in s. 215.24 the money or trust funds should be exempt herefrom, as it is the purpose of this law to exempt income from its force and effect when, by the operation of this law, federal matching funds or contributions or private grants to any trust fund would be lost to the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is appropriated from the proper respective trust funds from time to time such sums as may be necessary to pay to the General Revenue Fund the service charges imposed by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 20890, 1941; s. 1, ch. 61-493; s. 1, ch. 63-567; s. 1, ch. 83-339; s. 10, ch. 90-110; s. 75, ch. 90-132; s. 103, ch. 91-112; s. 86, ch. 92-33; ss. 24, 59, ch. 93-120; s. 1, ch. 94-167; s. 9, ch. 95-250; s. 61, ch. 95-280; s. 128, ch. 95-417; s. 11, ch. 96-321; s. 35, ch. 96-418; s. 170, ch. 98-166; s. 70, ch. 99-255; s. 21, ch. 2001-56; s. 4, ch. 2001-225; s. 2, ch. 2002-46; s. 920, ch. 2002-387; ss. 60, 61, ch. 2002-402; ss. 199, 200, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2003-400; s. 20, ch. 2004-234; s. 18, ch. 2005-2; s. 4, ch. 2006-79; s. 4, ch. 2006-162; s. 3, ch. 2007-14; s. 4, ch. 2008-9; s. 13, ch. 2008-240; s. 191, ch. 2008-247; s. 3, ch. 2009-71; s. 1, ch. 2009-78.</History>
</Section>