<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0215.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Repayment of funds paid into State Treasury through error.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer may refund to the person who paid same, or his or her heirs, personal representatives, or assigns, any moneys paid into the State Treasury which constitute:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An overpayment of any tax, license, or account due;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A payment where no tax, license, or account is due; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any payment made into the State Treasury in error;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and if any such payment has been credited to an appropriation, such appropriation shall at the time of making any such refund, be charged therewith. There are appropriated from the proper respective funds from time to time such sums as may be necessary for such refunds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Application for refunds as provided by this section must be filed with the Chief Financial Officer, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, within 3 years after the right to the refund has accrued or else the right is barred. Except as provided in chapter 198 and ss. 220.23 and 624.50921, an application for a refund of a tax enumerated in s. 72.011, which tax was paid after September 30, 1994, and before July 1, 1999, must be filed with the Chief Financial Officer within 5 years after the date the tax is paid, and within 3 years after the date the tax was paid for taxes paid on or after July 1, 1999. The Chief Financial Officer may delegate the authority to accept an application for refund to any state agency, or the judicial branch, vested by law with the responsibility for the collection of any tax, license, or account due. The application for refund must be on a form approved by the Chief Financial Officer and must be supplemented with additional proof the Chief Financial Officer deems necessary to establish the claim; provided, the claim is not otherwise barred under the laws of this state. Upon receipt of an application for refund, the judicial branch or the state agency to which the funds were paid shall make a determination of the amount due. If an application for refund is denied, in whole or in part, the judicial branch or such state agency shall notify the applicant stating the reasons therefor. Upon approval of an application for refund, the judicial branch or such state agency shall furnish the Chief Financial Officer with a properly executed voucher authorizing payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No refund of moneys referred to in this section shall be made of an amount which is less than $1, except upon application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is the exclusive procedure and remedy for refund claims between individual funds and accounts in the State Treasury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a taxpayer has pursued administrative remedies before the Department of Revenue pursuant to s. 213.21 and has failed to comply with the time limitations and conditions provided in ss. 72.011 and 120.80(14)(b), a claim of refund under subsection (1) shall be denied by the Chief Financial Officer. However, the Chief Financial Officer may entertain a claim for refund under this subsection when the taxpayer demonstrates that his or her failure to pursue remedies under chapter 72 was not due to neglect or for the purpose of delaying payment of lawfully imposed taxes and can demonstrate reasonable cause for such failure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A taxpayer may contest a denial of refund of tax, interest, or penalty paid under a section or chapter specified in s. 72.011(1) pursuant to the provisions of s. 72.011.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 22008, 1943; s. 14, ch. 57-1; s. 1, ch. 57-18; s. 1, ch. 59-181; s. 1, ch. 63-271; s. 2, ch. 78-352; s. 28, ch. 83-339; s. 18, ch. 86-152; s. 3, ch. 91-112; s. 10, ch. 92-142; s. 10, ch. 94-314; ss. 26, 50, ch. 94-353; s. 1506, ch. 95-147; s. 43, ch. 96-410; s. 10, ch. 99-239; s. 206, ch. 2003-261; s. 21, ch. 2005-280.</History></Section>