<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0215.473" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Divestiture by the State Board of Administration; Sudan; Iran.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this act, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Active business operations” means all business operations that are not inactive business operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Business operations” means engaging in commerce in any form in Sudan or Iran, including, but not limited to, acquiring, developing, maintaining, owning, selling, possessing, leasing, or operating equipment, facilities, personnel, products, services, personal property, real property, or any other apparatus of business or commerce.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Company” means any sole proprietorship, organization, association, corporation, partnership, joint venture, limited partnership, limited liability partnership, limited liability company, or other entity or business association, including all wholly owned subsidiaries, majority-owned subsidiaries, parent companies, or affiliates of such entities or business associations, that exists for the purpose of making profit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Complicit” means taking actions during any preceding 20-month period which have directly supported or promoted the genocidal campaign in Darfur, including, but not limited to, preventing Darfur’s victimized population from communicating with each other; encouraging Sudanese citizens to speak out against an internationally approved security force for Darfur; actively working to deny, cover up, or alter the record on human rights abuses in Darfur; or other similar actions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Direct holdings” in a company means all securities of that company that are held directly by the public fund or in an account or fund in which the public fund owns all shares or interests.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Government of Iran” means the government of Iran, its instrumentalities, and companies owned or controlled by the government of Iran.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Government of Sudan” means the government in Khartoum, Sudan, that is led by the National Congress Party, formerly known as the National Islamic Front, or any successor government formed on or after October 13, 2006, including the coalition National Unity Government agreed upon in the Comprehensive Peace Agreement for Sudan, and does not include the regional government of southern Sudan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Inactive business operations” means the mere continued holding or renewal of rights to property previously operated for the purpose of generating revenues but not presently deployed for such purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Indirect holdings” in a company means all securities of that company that are held in an account or fund, such as a mutual fund, managed by one or more persons not employed by the public fund, in which the public fund owns shares or interests together with other investors not subject to the provisions of this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Iran” means the Islamic Republic of Iran.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Marginalized populations of Sudan” include, but are not limited to, the portion of the population in the Darfur region that has been genocidally victimized; the portion of the population of southern Sudan victimized by Sudan’s north-south civil war; the Beja, Rashidiya, and other similarly underserved groups of eastern Sudan; the Nubian and other similarly underserved groups in Sudan’s Abyei, Southern Blue Nile, and Nuba Mountain regions; and the Amri, Hamadab, Manasir, and other similarly underserved groups of northern Sudan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Military equipment” means weapons, arms, military supplies, and equipment that may readily be used for military purposes, including, but not limited to, radar systems, military-grade transport vehicles, or supplies or services sold or provided directly or indirectly to any force actively participating in armed conflict in Sudan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mineral-extraction activities” include the exploring, extracting, processing, transporting, or wholesale selling or trading of elemental minerals or associated metal alloys or oxides (ore), including gold, copper, chromium, chromite, diamonds, iron, iron ore, silver, tungsten, uranium, and zinc, as well as facilitating such activities, including providing supplies or services in support of such activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Oil-related activities” include, but are not limited to, owning rights to oil blocks; exporting, extracting, producing, refining, processing, exploring for, transporting, selling, or trading of oil; constructing, maintaining, or operating a pipeline, refinery, or other oil-field infrastructure; and facilitating such activities, including providing supplies or services in support of such activities, except that the mere retail sale of gasoline and related consumer products is not considered an oil-related activity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Petroleum resources” means petroleum, petroleum byproducts, or natural gas.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Power-production activities” means any business operation that involves a project commissioned by the National Electricity Corporation (NEC) of Sudan or other similar entity of the government of Sudan whose purpose is to facilitate power generation and delivery, including, but not limited to, establishing power-generating plants or hydroelectric dams, selling or installing components for the project, providing service contracts related to the installation or maintenance of the project, as well as facilitating such activities, including providing supplies or services in support of such activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public fund” means all funds, assets, trustee, and other designates under the State Board of Administration pursuant to chapter 121.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Scrutinized active business operations” means active business operations that have resulted in a company becoming a scrutinized company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Scrutinized business operations” means business operations that have resulted in a company becoming a scrutinized company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Scrutinized company” means any company that meets any of the following criteria:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The company has business operations that involve contracts with or provision of supplies or services to the government of Sudan, companies in which the government of Sudan has any direct or indirect equity share, consortiums or projects commissioned by the government of Sudan, or companies involved in consortiums or projects commissioned by the government of Sudan, and:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">More than 10 percent of the company’s revenues or assets linked to Sudan involve oil-related activities or mineral-extraction activities; less than 75 percent of the company’s revenues or assets linked to Sudan involve contracts with or provision of oil-related or mineral-extracting products or services to the regional government of southern Sudan or a project or consortium created exclusively by that regional government; and the company has failed to take substantial action; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">More than 10 percent of the company’s revenues or assets linked to Sudan involve power-production activities; less than 75 percent of the company’s power-production activities include projects whose intent is to provide power or electricity to the marginalized populations of Sudan; and the company has failed to take substantial action.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The company is complicit in the Darfur genocide.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The company supplies military equipment within Sudan, unless it clearly shows that the military equipment cannot be used to facilitate offensive military actions in Sudan or the company implements rigorous and verifiable safeguards to prevent use of that equipment by forces actively participating in armed conflict. Examples of safeguards include post-sale tracking of such equipment by the company, certification from a reputable and objective third party that such equipment is not being used by a party participating in armed conflict in Sudan, or sale of such equipment solely to the regional government of southern Sudan or any internationally recognized peacekeeping force or humanitarian organization.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The company has business operations that involve contracts with or provision of supplies or services to the government of Iran, companies in which the government of Iran has any direct or indirect equity share, consortiums, or projects commissioned by the government of Iran, or companies involved in consortiums or projects commissioned by the government of Iran and:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">More than 10 percent of the company’s total revenues or assets are linked to Iran and involve oil-related activities or mineral-extraction activities; and the company has failed to take substantial action; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The company has, with actual knowledge, on or after August 5, 1996, made an investment of $20 million or more, or any combination of investments of at least $10 million each, which in the aggregate equals or exceeds $20 million in any 12-month period, and which directly or significantly contributes to the enhancement of Iran’s ability to develop the petroleum resources of Iran.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Social-development company” means a company whose primary purpose in Sudan is to provide humanitarian goods or services, including medicine or medical equipment; agricultural supplies or infrastructure; educational opportunities; journalism-related activities; information or information materials; spiritual-related activities; services of a purely clerical or reporting nature; food, clothing, or general consumer goods that are unrelated to oil-related activities; mineral-extraction activities; or power-production activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substantial action specific to Iran” means adopting, publicizing, and implementing a formal plan to cease scrutinized business operations within 1 year and to refrain from any such new business operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="w"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substantial action specific to Sudan” means adopting, publicizing, and implementing a formal plan to cease scrutinized business operations within 1 year and to refrain from any such new business operations; undertaking humanitarian efforts in conjunction with an international organization, the government of Sudan, the regional government of southern Sudan, or a nonprofit entity evaluated and certified by an independent third party to be substantially in a relationship to the company’s Sudan business operations and of benefit to one or more marginalized populations of Sudan; or, through engagement with the government of Sudan, materially improving conditions for the genocidally victimized population in Darfur.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IDENTIFICATION OF COMPANIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days after the effective date of this act, the public fund shall make its best efforts to identify all scrutinized companies in which the public fund has direct or indirect holdings or could possibly have such holdings in the future. Such efforts include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing and relying, as appropriate in the public fund’s judgment, on publicly available information regarding companies having business operations in Sudan, including information provided by nonprofit organizations, research firms, international organizations, and government entities;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contacting asset managers contracted by the public fund that invest in companies having business operations in Sudan; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contacting other institutional investors that have divested from or engaged with companies that have business operations in Sudan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing the laws of the United States regarding the levels of business activity that would cause application of sanctions for companies conducting business or investing in countries that are designated state sponsors of terror.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the first meeting of the public fund following the 90-day period described in paragraph (a), the public fund shall assemble all scrutinized companies that fit criteria specified in subparagraphs (1)(t)1., 2., and 3. into a “Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List” and shall assemble all scrutinized companies that fit criteria specified in subparagraph (1)(t)4. into a “Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public fund shall update and make publicly available quarterly the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List and the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List based on evolving information from, among other sources, those listed in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this act, a social-development company that is not complicit in the Darfur genocide is not considered a scrutinized company under subparagraph (1)(t)1., subparagraph (1)(t)2., or subparagraph (1)(t)3.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REQUIRED ACTIONS.<EmDash />The public fund shall adhere to the following procedure for assembling companies on the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List and the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Engagement.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public fund shall immediately determine the companies on the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List and the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List in which the public fund owns direct or indirect holdings.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each company identified in this paragraph that has only inactive business operations, the public fund shall send a written notice informing the company of this act and encouraging it to continue to refrain from initiating active business operations in Sudan or Iran until it is able to avoid scrutinized business operations. The public fund shall continue such correspondence semiannually.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each company newly identified under this paragraph that has active business operations, the public fund shall send a written notice informing the company of its scrutinized company status and that it may become subject to divestment by the public fund. The notice must inform the company of the opportunity to clarify its Sudan-related or Iran-related activities and encourage the company, within 90 days, to cease its scrutinized business operations or convert such operations to inactive business operations in order to avoid qualifying for divestment by the public fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, within 90 days after the public fund’s first engagement with a company pursuant to this paragraph, that company ceases scrutinized business operations, the company shall be removed from the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List and the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List, and the provisions of this act shall cease to apply to that company unless that company resumes scrutinized business operations. If, within 90 days after the public fund’s first engagement, the company converts its scrutinized active business operations to inactive business operations, the company is subject to all provisions relating to inactive business operations. A company may be removed from one list but remain on the other list, in which case the company shall be subject to the provisions applicable to the list on which the company remains.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Divestment.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, after 90 days following the public fund’s first engagement with a company pursuant to paragraph (a), the company continues to have scrutinized active business operations, and only while such company continues to have scrutinized active business operations, the public fund shall sell, redeem, divest, or withdraw all publicly traded securities of the company, except as provided in paragraph (d), from the public fund’s assets under management within 12 months after the company’s most recent appearance on the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List or on the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a company that ceased scrutinized active business operations following engagement pursuant to paragraph (a) resumes such operations, this paragraph immediately applies, and the public fund shall send a written notice to the company. The company shall also be immediately reintroduced onto the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List or on the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List, as applicable.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Prohibition.</Font><EmDash />The public fund may not acquire securities of companies on the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List or the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List that have active business operations, except as provided in paragraph (d).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Exemption.</Font><EmDash />A company that the United States Government affirmatively declares to be excluded from its present or any future federal sanctions regime relating to Sudan or Iran is not subject to divestment or the investment prohibition pursuant to paragraphs (b) and (c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Excluded securities.</Font><EmDash />Notwithstanding the provisions of this act, paragraphs (b) and (c) do not apply to indirect holdings in actively managed investment funds. However, the public fund shall submit letters to the managers of such investment funds containing companies that have scrutinized active business operations requesting that they consider removing such companies from the fund or create a similar actively managed fund having indirect holdings devoid of such companies. If the manager creates a similar fund, the public fund shall replace all applicable investments with investments in the similar fund in an expedited timeframe consistent with prudent investing standards. For the purposes of this section, a private equity fund is deemed to be an actively managed investment fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Further exclusions.</Font><EmDash />Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, the public fund, when discharging its responsibility for operation of a defined contribution plan, shall engage the manager of the investment offerings in such plans requesting that they consider removing scrutinized companies from the investment offerings or create an alternative investment offering devoid of scrutinized companies. If the manager creates an alternative investment offering and the offering is deemed by the public fund to be consistent with prudent investor standards, the public fund shall consider including such investment offering in the plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORTING.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public fund shall file a report with each member of the Board of Trustees of the State Board of Administration, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives that includes the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List and the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List within 30 days after the list is created. This report shall be made available to the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At each quarterly meeting of the Board of Trustees thereafter, the public fund shall file a report, which shall be made available to the public and to each member of the Board of Trustees of the State Board of Administration, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and send a copy of that report to the United States Presidential Special Envoy to Sudan and the United States Presidential Special Envoy to Iran, or an appropriate designee or successor, which includes:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary of correspondence with companies engaged by the public fund under subparagraphs (3)(a)2. and 3.;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All investments sold, redeemed, divested, or withdrawn in compliance with paragraph (3)(b);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All prohibited investments under paragraph (3)(c);</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any progress made under paragraph (3)(e); and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of all publicly traded securities held directly by this state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXPIRATION.<EmDash />This act expires upon the occurrence of all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the following occur, the public fund shall no longer scrutinize companies according to subparagraphs (1)(t)1., 2., and 3. and shall no longer assemble the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List, shall cease engagement and divestment of such companies, and may reinvest in such companies as long as such companies do not satisfy the criteria for inclusion in the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Congress or President of the United States, affirmatively and unambiguously states, by means including, but not limited to, legislation, executive order, or written certification from the President to Congress, that the Darfur genocide has been halted for at least 12 months;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States revokes all sanctions imposed against the government of Sudan;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Congress or President of the United States affirmatively and unambiguously states, by means including, but not limited to, legislation, executive order, or written certification from the President to Congress, that the government of Sudan has honored its commitments to cease attacks on civilians, demobilize and demilitarize the Janjaweed and associated militias, grant free and unfettered access for deliveries of humanitarian assistance, and allow for the safe and voluntary return of refugees and internally displaced persons; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Congress or President of the United States affirmatively and unambiguously states, by means including, but not limited to, legislation, executive order, or written certification from the President to Congress, that mandatory divestment of the type provided for in this act interferes with the conduct of United States foreign policy.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the following occur, the public fund shall no longer scrutinize companies according to subparagraph (1)(t)4. and shall no longer assemble the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in the Iran Petroleum Energy Sector List and shall cease engagement, investment prohibitions, and divestment. The public fund may reinvest in such companies as long as such companies do not satisfy the criteria for inclusion in the Scrutinized Companies with Activities in Sudan List:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Congress or President of the United States affirmatively and unambiguously states, by means including, but not limited to, legislation, executive order, or written certification from the President to Congress, that the government of Iran has ceased to acquire weapons of mass destruction and support international terrorism;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The United States revokes all sanctions imposed against the government of Iran; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Congress or President of the United States affirmatively and unambiguously declares, by means including, but not limited to, legislation, executive order, or written certification from the President to Congress, that mandatory divestment of the type provided for in this act interferes with the conduct of United States foreign policy.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT POLICY STATEMENT OBLIGATIONS.<EmDash />The public fund’s actions taken in compliance with this act, including all good faith determinations regarding companies as required by this act, shall be adopted and incorporated into the public fund’s investment policy statement (the IPS) as set forth in s. 215.475.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REINVESTMENT IN CERTAIN COMPANIES HAVING SCRUTINIZED ACTIVE BUSINESS OPERATIONS.<EmDash />Notwithstanding any other provision of this act to the contrary, the public fund may cease divesting from certain scrutinized companies pursuant to paragraph (3)(b) or reinvest in certain scrutinized companies from which it divested pursuant to paragraph (3)(b) if clear and convincing evidence shows that the value of all assets under management by the public fund becomes equal to or less than 99.50 percent, or 50 basis points, of the hypothetical value of all assets under management by the public fund assuming no divestment for any company had occurred under paragraph (3)(b). Cessation of divestment, reinvestment, or any subsequent ongoing investment authorized by this act is limited to the minimum steps necessary to avoid the contingency set forth in this subsection or that no divestment of any company is required for less than fair value. For any cessation of divestment, reinvestment, or subsequent ongoing investment authorized by this act, the public fund shall provide a written report to each member of the Board of Trustees of the State Board of Administration, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives in advance of initial reinvestment, updated semiannually thereafter as applicable, setting forth the reasons and justification, supported by clear and convincing evidence, for its decisions to cease divestment, reinvest, or remain invested in companies having scrutinized active business operations. This act does not apply to reinvestment in companies on the grounds that they have ceased to have scrutinized active business operations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2007-88.</History></Section>