<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0215.616" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State bonds for federal aid highway construction.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the request of the Department of Transportation, the Division of Bond Finance is authorized pursuant to s. 11, Art. VII of the State Constitution and the State Bond Act to issue revenue bonds, for and on behalf of the Department of Transportation, for the purpose of financing or refinancing the construction, reconstruction, and improvement of projects that are eligible to receive federal-aid highway funds. The Division of Bond Finance is authorized to consider innovative financing technologies which may include, but are not limited to, innovative bidding and structures of potential financings that may result in negotiated transactions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bonds issued pursuant to this section shall be payable primarily from a prior and superior claim on all federal highway aid reimbursements received each year with respect to federal-aid projects undertaken in accordance with the provisions of Title 23 of the United States Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of the bonds shall not exceed a term of 12 years. Prior to the issuance of bonds, the Department of Transportation shall determine that annual debt service on all bonds issued pursuant to this section does not exceed 10 percent of annual apportionments to the department for federal highway aid in accordance with the provisions of Title 23 of the United States Code.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bonds issued under this section shall not constitute a debt or general obligation of the state or a pledge of the full faith and credit or taxing power of the state. The bonds shall be secured by and are payable from the revenues pledged in accordance with this section and the resolution authorizing their issuance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state does covenant with the holders of bonds issued under this section that it will not repeal, impair, or amend this section in any manner which will materially and adversely affect the rights of bondholders as long as the bonds authorized by this section are outstanding.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any complaint for such validation of bonds issued pursuant to this section shall be filed in the circuit court of the county where the seat of state government is situated, the notice required to be published by s. 75.06 shall be published only in the county where the complaint is filed, and the complaint and order of the circuit court shall be served only on the state attorney of the circuit in which the action is pending.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 68, ch. 99-385; s. 12, ch. 2000-257; s. 82, ch. 2012-174.</History>
</Section>