<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0215.615" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fixed-guideway transportation systems funding.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The issuance of revenue bonds by the Division of Bond Finance, on behalf of the Department of Transportation, pursuant to s. 11, Art. VII of the State Constitution, is authorized, pursuant to the State Bond Act, to finance or refinance fixed capital expenditures for fixed-guideway transportation systems, as defined in s. 341.031, including facilities appurtenant thereto, costs of issuance, and other amounts relating to such financing or refinancing. The Division of Bond Finance is authorized to consider innovative financing techniques that may include, but are not limited to, innovative bidding and structures of potential financings that may result in negotiated transactions. The following conditions apply to the issuance of revenue bonds for fixed-guideway transportation systems:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and any participating commuter rail authority or regional transportation authority established under chapter 343, local governments, or local governments collectively by interlocal agreement having jurisdiction of a fixed-guideway transportation system may enter into an interlocal agreement to promote the efficient and cost-effective financing or refinancing of fixed-guideway transportation system projects by revenue bonds issued pursuant to this subsection. The terms of such interlocal agreements shall include provisions for the Department of Transportation to request the issuance of the bonds on behalf of the parties; shall provide that after reimbursement pursuant to interlocal agreement, the department’s share may be up to 50 percent of the eligible project cost, which may include a share of annual debt service requirements of such bonds; and shall include any other terms, provisions, or covenants necessary to the making of and full performance under such interlocal agreement. Repayments made to the department under any interlocal agreement are not pledged to the repayment of bonds issued hereunder, and failure of the local governmental authority to make such payment shall not affect the obligation of the department to pay debt service on the bonds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revenue bonds issued pursuant to this subsection shall not constitute a general obligation of, or a pledge of the full faith and credit of, the State of Florida. Bonds issued pursuant to this section shall be payable from funds available pursuant to s. 206.46(3), or other funds available to the project, subject to annual appropriation. The amount of revenues available for debt service shall never exceed a maximum of 2 percent of all state revenues deposited into the State Transportation Trust Fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The projects to be financed or refinanced with the proceeds of the revenue bonds issued hereunder are designated as state fixed capital outlay projects for purposes of s. 11(d), Art. VII of the State Constitution, and the specific projects to be financed or refinanced shall be determined by the Department of Transportation in accordance with state law and appropriations from the State Transportation Trust Fund. Each project to be financed with the proceeds of the bonds issued pursuant to this subsection must first be approved by the Legislature by an act of general law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any complaint for validation of bonds issued pursuant to this section shall be filed in the circuit court of the county where the seat of state government is situated, the notice required to be published by s. 75.06 shall be published only in the county where the complaint is filed, and the complaint and order of the circuit court shall be served only on the state attorney of the circuit in which the action is pending.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state does hereby covenant with holders of such revenue bonds or other instruments of indebtedness issued hereunder that it will not repeal or impair or amend these provisions in any manner that will materially and adversely affect the rights of such holders as long as bonds authorized by this subsection are outstanding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection supersedes any inconsistent provisions in existing law.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding this subsection, the lien of revenue bonds issued pursuant to this subsection on moneys deposited into the State Transportation Trust Fund shall be subordinate to the lien on such moneys of bonds issued under ss. 215.605, 320.20, and 215.616, and any pledge of such moneys to pay operating and maintenance expenses under s. 206.46(5) and chapter 348, as may be amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for participation, fixed-guideway transportation system projects must be found to be consistent, to the maximum extent feasible, with approved local government comprehensive plans of the local governments in which such projects are located and must be included in the work program of the Department of Transportation pursuant to the provisions under s. 339.135. The department shall certify that the expected useful life of the transportation improvements will equal or exceed the maturity date of the debt to be issued.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 99-385; s. 5, ch. 2000-152; s. 61, ch. 2002-20; s. 1, ch. 2007-66; s. 15, ch. 2007-196.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 15, ch. 2007-196. For a description of multiple acts in the same session affecting a statutory provision, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">see</Font> preface to the <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida Statutes</Font>, “Statutory Construction.” Paragraph (1)(a) was also amended by s. 1, ch. 2007-66, and that version reads:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The department and any participating commuter rail authority or regional transportation authority established under chapter 343, local governments, or local governments collectively by interlocal agreement having jurisdiction of a fixed-guideway transportation system may enter into an interlocal agreement to promote the efficient and cost-effective financing or refinancing of fixed-guideway transportation system projects by revenue bonds issued pursuant to this subsection. The terms of such interlocal agreements shall include provisions for the Department of Transportation to request the issuance of the bonds on behalf of the parties; shall provide that the department’s share may be up to 50 percent of the eligible project cost, which may include a share of the annual debt service requirements of such bonds; and shall include any other terms, provisions, or covenants necessary to the making of and full performance under such interlocal agreement. Repayments made to the department under any interlocal agreement are not pledged to the repayment of bonds issued hereunder, and failure of the local governmental authority to make such payment shall not affect the obligation of the department to pay debt service on the bonds.</Text></Note></Section>