<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0215.96" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coordinating council and design and coordination staff.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer, as chief fiscal officer of the state, shall establish a coordinating council to function on a continuing basis. The coordinating council shall review and recommend to the board solutions and policy alternatives to ensure coordination between functional owners of the various information subsystems described in ss. 215.90-215.96 to the extent necessary to unify all the subsystems into a financial management information system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coordinating council shall consist of the Chief Financial Officer; the Commissioner of Agriculture; the secretary of the Department of Management Services; the Attorney General; and the Director of Planning and Budgeting, Executive Office of the Governor, or their designees. The Chief Financial Officer, or his or her designee, shall be chair of the coordinating council, and the design and coordination staff shall provide administrative and clerical support to the council and the board. The design and coordination staff shall maintain the minutes of each meeting and shall make such minutes available to any interested person. The Auditor General, the State Courts Administrator, an executive officer of the Florida Association of State Agency Administrative Services Directors, and an executive officer of the Florida Association of State Budget Officers, or their designees, shall serve without voting rights as ex officio members on the coordinating council. The chair may call meetings of the coordinating council as often as necessary to transact business; however, the coordinating council shall meet at least once a year. Action of the coordinating council shall be by motion, duly made, seconded and passed by a majority of the coordinating council voting in the affirmative for approval of items that are to be recommended for approval to the Financial Management Information Board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The coordinating council, assisted by the design and coordination staff, shall have the following duties, powers, and responsibilities pertaining to the Florida Financial Management Information System:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To conduct such studies and to establish committees, workgroups, and teams to develop recommendations for rules, policies, procedures, principles, and standards to the board as necessary to assist the board in its efforts to design, implement, and perpetuate a financial management information system, including, but not limited to, the establishment of common data codes, and the development of integrated financial management policies that address the information and management needs of the functional owner subsystems. The coordinating council shall make available a copy of the approved plan in writing or through electronic means to each of the coordinating council members, the fiscal committees of the Legislature, and any interested person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To recommend to the board solutions, policy alternatives, and legislative budget request issues that will ensure a framework for the timely, positive, preplanned, and prescribed data transfer between information subsystems and to recommend to the board solutions, policy alternatives, and legislative budget request issues that ensure the availability of data and information that support state planning, policy development, management, evaluation, and performance monitoring.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To report to the board all actions taken by the coordinating council for final action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To review the annual work plans of the functional owner information subsystems by October 1 of each year. The review shall be conducted to assess the status of the Florida Financial Management Information System and the functional owner subsystems in regard to the provisions of s. 215.91. The coordinating council, as part of the review process, may make recommendations for modifications to the functional owner information subsystems annual work plans.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-45; s. 1, ch. 82-46; s. 9, ch. 83-92; s. 2, ch. 87-137; ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 89-2; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 86, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 11, ch. 94-226; s. 1508, ch. 95-147; s. 25, ch. 97-286; s. 25, ch. 98-73; s. 85, ch. 99-2; s. 1, ch. 2001-61; s. 12, ch. 2003-6; s. 52, ch. 2003-399; ss. 26, 76, ch. 2004-269; s. 10, ch. 2004-390; s. 17, ch. 2007-105; s. 3, ch. 2009-20.</History></Section>