<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0215.58" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to State Bond Act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following words or terms when used in this act shall have the following meanings:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Governor” means the Governor of the state or any Acting Governor or other person then exercising the duties of the office of Governor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” means the State of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Bond Finance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board” means the governing board of the division, which shall be composed of the Governor and Cabinet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the chief administrator of the division, who shall act on behalf of the division when authorized by the board, as provided by this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State agency” means any board, commission, authority, or other state agency heretofore or hereafter created by the constitution or statutes of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bonds” means state bonds, or any revenue bonds, certificates or other obligations heretofore or hereafter authorized to be issued by said division or by any state agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State bonds” means bonds pledging the full faith and credit of the State of Florida.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Legislature” means the State Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Constitution” means the existing constitution of the state, or any constitution hereafter adopted by the people of the state, together with all amendments thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Original issue discount” means the amount by which the par value of a bond exceeds its public offering price at the time it is originally offered to an investor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Governmental agency” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state or any department, commission, agency, or other instrumentality thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or municipality or any department, commission, agency, or other instrumentality thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any school board or special district, authority, or governmental entity.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 69-230; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 87-308; s. 4, ch. 89-287; s. 151, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 84, ch. 99-2; s. 225, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>