<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0215.56021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions from public records and public meetings requirements; peer review panels.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That portion of a meeting of a peer review panel in which applications for biomedical research grants under s. 215.5602 or s. 381.922 are discussed is exempt from s. 286.011 and s. 24(b), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any records generated by the peer review panel relating to review of applications for biomedical research grants, except final recommendations, are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research grant applications provided to the peer review panel are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information which is held confidential and exempt under this section may be disclosed with the express written consent of the individual to whom the information pertains or the individual’s legally authorized representative, or by court order upon showing good cause.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1), (2), (3), and (4) are subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15 and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2017, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2012-15.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also published at s. 381.92201.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>