<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0215.431" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of bond anticipation notes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each of the counties, school boards, districts, authorities, municipalities, and agencies of municipalities in the state shall have power, at any time and from time to time after the issuance of bonds thereof shall have been authorized, whether such bonds be general, special, revenue or other obligations of such county, school board, district, authority, municipality, or agency of a municipality, and, if the approval of such bonds at an election is required after the holding of such election, to borrow money for the purposes for which such bonds are to be issued in anticipation of the receipt of the proceeds of the sale of such bonds and within the authorized maximum amount of such bond issue. Any such loan shall be paid within 5 years after the date on which the bond anticipation notes shall have been issued or, if such bonds shall have been approved at an election, within 5 years after the date on which such election shall have been held. Bond anticipation notes shall be issued for all moneys borrowed under the provisions of this law, and such notes may be renewed from time to time; but all such notes shall mature within the time above limited for the payment of the original loan. Such notes shall be authorized by resolution of the governing body of the issuer and shall be in such denomination or denominations, shall bear interest at such rate or rates not exceeding the maximum rate permitted by law or by the resolution or ordinance authorizing the issuance of the bonds, whichever shall be the lesser, shall be in such form, and shall be executed in such manner, all as such governing body shall prescribe. Such notes may be sold at either public or private sale; or, if such notes shall be renewal notes, they may be exchanged for notes then outstanding on such terms as the governing body shall determine. The governing body may, in its discretion, retire any such notes by means of current revenues, in lieu of retiring them by means of bonds; however, before the retirement of such notes by any means other than the issuance of bonds, it shall amend or repeal the resolution or ordinance authorizing the issuance of the bonds in anticipation of the proceeds of the sale of which such notes shall have been issued so as to reduce the authorized amount of the bond issue by the amount of the notes so retired. Such amendatory or repealing resolution or ordinance shall take effect upon its passage and need not be published. All powers and rights conferred by this law shall be in addition to and supplemental to those conferred by any other general or special law and shall be liberally construed to effectuate the purposes hereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 80-42, Laws of Florida, shall be applicable to any bond anticipation notes heretofore issued and now outstanding or authorized but unissued upon July 1, 1980, as well as any bond anticipation notes authorized and issued after July 1, 1980.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-127; ss. 1, 2, ch. 80-42; s. 122, ch. 81-259.</History></Section>