<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0215.85" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Direct deposit of public funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This act shall be known and may be cited as the “Direct Deposit of Public Funds Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is the legislative intent that this act shall constitute authorization for all public agencies, and the judicial branch, to withdraw, pay, or disburse all public funds in their control by direct deposit to the account of the person entitled to receive such funds. This act is not intended to limit existing statutory authority for the direct deposit of public funds, but rather to allow in similar fashion all public agencies, and the judicial branch, to employ this method.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “governing board or officer” means each individual or group of individuals, including, but not limited to, trustees, having lawful authority to withdraw, pay, or disburse public funds from the depository thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “public funds” means all moneys under the jurisdiction or control of the state, a county, or a municipality, including any district, authority, commission, board, or agency thereof and the judicial branch, and includes all manner of pension and retirement funds and all other funds held, as trust funds or otherwise, for any public purpose.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISBURSEMENT OF PUBLIC FUNDS; DIRECT DEPOSIT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of providing for the direct deposit of public funds under the circumstances herein specified, each governing board or officer is authorized to establish the form or forms of checks, warrants, or other instruments for the withdrawal, payment, or disbursement of the public funds under its control, and to change the form thereof from time to time. However, nothing in this section shall be construed as eliminating or impairing the requirements of any statute, rule, or ordinance relating to any official or other action or signatures necessary to authorize the withdrawal, payment, or disbursement of such public funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If authorized in writing by the person entitled to the withdrawal, payment, or disbursement of public funds, such checks, warrants, or other instruments may provide for direct deposit of the public funds to the account of the person entitled to receive the same in any financial institution which is designated in writing by such person and which has lawful authority to accept such deposits. The written authorization of the person entitled to receive such public funds shall be filed with the appropriate governing board or officer. Direct deposit of public funds may be by any electronic or other medium approved for such purpose by the governing board or officer having jurisdiction or control of such public funds.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROCEDURES FOR WIRE TRANSFER OF FUNDS.<EmDash />Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the governing board or officer of any local government who has the authority to deposit or withdraw funds is authorized to transfer funds from one depository to another or within a depository or to another institution, and may transfer funds to pay expenses, expenditures, or other disbursements, evidenced by an invoice or other appropriate documentation. Such transfer may be made by electronic, telephonic, or other medium; and each transfer shall be confirmed in writing and signed by the designee of the governing board or officer of the local government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT OF PUBLIC FUNDS.<EmDash />Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the governing board or officer of any local government who has the authority to invest funds is authorized to transfer funds by electronic or other medium for purposes of investment to any depository authorized by law to receive funds or in the Local Government Surplus Funds Trust Fund. A written record shall be kept of all transfers made pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, ch. 78-406; s. 3, ch. 82-104; s. 27, ch. 92-142; s. 1, ch. 2003-60.</History></Section>