<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0215.322" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Acceptance of credit cards, charge cards, debit cards, or electronic funds transfers by state agencies, units of local government, and the judicial branch.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to encourage state agencies, the judicial branch, and units of local government to make their goods, services, and information more convenient to the public through the acceptance of payments by credit cards, charge cards, debit cards, or other means of electronic funds transfers to the maximum extent practicable when the benefits to the participating agency and the public substantiate the cost of accepting these types of payments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state agency as defined in s. 216.011, or the judicial branch, may accept credit cards, charge cards, debit cards, or electronic funds transfers in payment for goods and services with the prior approval of the Chief Financial Officer. If the Internet or other related electronic methods are to be used as the collection medium, the Agency for Enterprise Information Technology shall review and recommend to the Chief Financial Officer whether to approve the request with regard to the process or procedure to be used.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall adopt rules governing the establishment and acceptance of credit cards, charge cards, debit cards, or electronic funds transfers by state agencies or the judicial branch, including, but not limited to, the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of a standardized contract between the financial institution or other appropriate intermediaries and the agency or judicial branch which shall be developed by the Chief Financial Officer or approval by the Chief Financial Officer of a substitute agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures that permit an agency or officer accepting payment by credit card, charge card, debit card, or electronic funds transfer to impose a convenience fee upon the person making the payment. However, the total amount of such convenience fees may not exceed the total cost to the state agency. A convenience fee is not refundable to the payor. However, this section does not permit the imposition of surcharges on any other credit card purchase in violation of s. 501.0117.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All service fees payable pursuant to this section shall be invoiced and paid by state warrant or such other manner that is satisfactory to the Chief Financial Officer in accordance with the time periods specified in s. 215.422, if practicable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission of information to the Chief Financial Officer concerning the acceptance of credit cards, charge cards, debit cards, or electronic funds transfers by all state agencies or the judicial branch.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A methodology for agencies to use when completing the cost-benefit analysis referred to in subsection (1). The methodology must consider all quantifiable cost reductions, other benefits to the agency, and the potential impact on general revenue. The methodology must also consider nonquantifiable benefits such as the convenience to individuals and businesses that would benefit from the ability to pay for state goods and services through the use of credit cards, charge cards, debit cards, or electronic funds transfers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer may establish contracts with one or more financial institutions, credit card companies, or other entities that may lawfully provide such services, in a manner consistent with chapter 287, for processing credit card, charge card, debit card, or electronic funds transfer collections for deposit into the State Treasury or another qualified public depository. Any state agency, or the judicial branch, which accepts payment by credit card, charge card, debit card, or electronic funds transfer shall use at least one of the contractors established by the Chief Financial Officer, unless the state agency or judicial branch obtains authorization from the Chief Financial Officer to use another contractor that is more advantageous to the state agency or the judicial branch. The contracts may authorize a unit of local government to use the services upon the same terms and conditions for deposit of credit card, charge card, debit card, or electronic funds transfer transactions into its qualified public depositories.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A unit of local government, including a municipality, special district, or board of county commissioners or other governing body of a county, a consolidated or metropolitan government, and any clerk of the circuit court, sheriff, property appraiser, tax collector, or supervisor of elections, is authorized to accept payment by use of credit cards, charge cards, bank debit cards, and electronic funds transfers for financial obligations that are owing to such unit of local government and to surcharge the person who uses a credit card, charge card, bank debit card, or electronic funds transfer in payment of taxes, license fees, tuition, fines, civil penalties, court-ordered payments, or court costs, or other statutorily prescribed revenues an amount sufficient to pay the service fee charges by the financial institution, vending service company, or credit card company for such services. A unit of local government shall verify both the validity of any credit card, charge card, bank debit card, or electronic funds transfer used pursuant to this subsection and the existence of appropriate credit with respect to the person using the card or transfer. The unit of local government does not incur any liability as a result of such verification or any subsequent action taken.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action required to be performed by a state officer or agency pursuant to this section shall be performed within 10 working days after receipt of the request for approval or be deemed approved if not acted upon within that time.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> This section does not prohibit a state agency or the judicial branch from continuing to accept charge cards, debit cards, or electronic funds transfers pursuant to a contract that was lawfully entered into before the effective date of this act, unless specifically directed otherwise in the General Appropriations Act. However, such contract may not be extended or renewed after the effective date of this act unless such renewal and extension conforms to the requirements of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When deemed administratively necessary, a state agency, as defined in s. 216.011, or the judicial branch may adopt rules requiring that payments for goods, services, or anything of value be made by electronic means, including, but not limited to, credit cards, charge cards, debit cards, or electronic funds transfers. However, the rules may not conflict with any similar rules adopted by the Chief Financial Officer. The rules must provide a method to reasonably accommodate persons who, because of technological, financial, or other hardship, may not be able to make payment by electronic means.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For payment programs in which credit cards, charge cards, or debit cards are accepted by state agencies, the judicial branch, or units of local government, the Chief Financial Officer, in consultation with the Agency for Enterprise Information Technology, may adopt rules to establish uniform security safeguards for cardholder data and to ensure compliance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 83-332; s. 15, ch. 88-119; s. 53, ch. 90-360; s. 18, ch. 92-142; s. 1, ch. 92-300; s. 16, ch. 96-324; s. 69, ch. 96-406; s. 11, ch. 97-241; s. 30, ch. 2000-164; s. 212, ch. 2003-261; s. 3, ch. 2007-251; s. 2, ch. 2008-116; s. 7, ch. 2010-151.</History>
</Section>