<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0060.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Abatement of nuisances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any nuisance as defined in s. 823.05 exists, the Attorney General, state attorney, city attorney, county attorney, or any citizen of the county may sue in the name of the state on his or her relation to enjoin the nuisance, the person or persons maintaining it, and the owner or agent of the building or ground on which the nuisance exists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may allow a temporary injunction without bond on proper proof being made. If it appears by evidence or affidavit that a temporary injunction should issue, the court, pending the determination on final hearing, may enjoin:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintaining of a nuisance;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operating and maintaining of the place or premises where the nuisance is maintained;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or agent of the building or ground upon which the nuisance exists;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct, operation, or maintenance of any business or activity operated or maintained in the building or on the premises in connection with or incident to the maintenance of the nuisance.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The injunction shall specify the activities enjoined and shall not preclude the operation of any lawful business not conducive to the maintenance of the nuisance complained of. At least 3 days’ notice in writing shall be given defendant of the time and place of application for the temporary injunction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of the general reputation of the alleged nuisance and place is admissible to prove the existence of the nuisance. No action filed by a citizen shall be dismissed unless the court is satisfied that it should be dismissed. Otherwise the action shall continue and the state attorney notified to proceed with it. If the action is brought by a citizen and the court finds that there was no reasonable ground for the action, the costs shall be taxed against the citizen.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On trial if the existence of a nuisance is shown, the court shall issue a permanent injunction and order the costs to be paid by the persons establishing or maintaining the nuisance and shall adjudge that the costs are a lien on all personal property found in the place of the nuisance and on the failure of the property to bring enough to pay the costs, then on the real estate occupied by the nuisance. No lien shall attach to the real estate of any other than said persons unless 5 days’ written notice has been given to the owner or his or her agent who fails to begin to abate the nuisance within said 5 days. In a proceeding abating a nuisance pursuant to s. 823.10 or s. 823.05, if a tenant has been convicted of an offense under chapter 893 or s. 796.07, the court may order the tenant to vacate the property within 72 hours if the tenant and owner of the premises are parties to the nuisance abatement action and the order will lead to the abatement of the nuisance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the action was brought by the Attorney General, a state attorney, or any other officer or agency of state government; if the court finds either before or after trial that there was no reasonable ground for the action; and if judgment is rendered for the defendant, the costs and reasonable attorney’s fees shall be taxed against the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, 4, ch. 7367, 1917; RGS 3223-3226; CGL 5029-5032; s. 1, ch. 20467, 1941; s. 2, ch. 29737, 1955; s. 15, ch. 67-254; s. 1, ch. 71-268; s. 14, ch. 73-334; s. 1, ch. 77-268; s. 8, ch. 87-243; s. 318, ch. 95-147; s. 1, ch. 96-237.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 64.11-64.14.</Text></Note></Section>