<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0558.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice and opportunity to repair.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In actions brought alleging a construction defect, the claimant shall, at least 60 days before filing any action, or at least 120 days before filing an action involving an association representing more than 20 parcels, serve written notice of claim on the contractor, subcontractor, supplier, or design professional, as applicable, which notice shall refer to this chapter. If the construction defect claim arises from work performed under a contract, the written notice of claim must be served on the person with whom the claimant contracted. The notice of claim must describe the claim in reasonable detail sufficient to determine the general nature of each alleged construction defect and a description of the damage or loss resulting from the defect, if known. The claimant shall endeavor to serve the notice of claim within 15 days after discovery of an alleged defect, but the failure to serve notice of claim within 15 days does not bar the filing of an action, subject to s. 558.003. This subsection does not preclude a claimant from filing an action sooner than 60 days, or 120 days as applicable, after service of written notice as expressly provided in subsection (6), subsection (7), or subsection (8).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after service of the notice of claim, or within 50 days after service of the notice of claim involving an association representing more than 20 parcels, the person served with the notice of claim under subsection (1) is entitled to perform a reasonable inspection of the property or of each unit subject to the claim to assess each alleged construction defect. An association’s right to access property for either maintenance or repair includes the authority to grant access for the inspection. The claimant shall provide the person served with notice under subsection (1) and such person’s contractors or agents reasonable access to the property during normal working hours to inspect the property to determine the nature and cause of each alleged construction defect and the nature and extent of any repairs or replacements necessary to remedy each defect. The person served with notice under subsection (1) shall reasonably coordinate the timing and manner of any and all inspections with the claimant to minimize the number of inspections. The inspection may include destructive testing by mutual agreement under the following reasonable terms and conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person served with notice under subsection (1) determines that destructive testing is necessary to determine the nature and cause of the alleged defects, such person shall notify the claimant in writing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall describe the destructive testing to be performed, the person selected to do the testing, the estimated anticipated damage and repairs to or restoration of the property resulting from the testing, the estimated amount of time necessary for the testing and to complete the repairs or restoration, and the financial responsibility offered for covering the costs of repairs or restoration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the claimant promptly objects to the person selected to perform the destructive testing, the person served with notice under subsection (1) shall provide the claimant with a list of three qualified persons from which the claimant may select one such person to perform the testing. The person selected to perform the testing shall operate as an agent or subcontractor of the person served with notice under subsection (1) and shall communicate with, submit any reports to, and be solely responsible to the person served with notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The testing shall be done at a mutually agreeable time.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The claimant or a representative of the claimant may be present to observe the destructive testing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The destructive testing shall not render the property uninhabitable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no construction lien rights under part I of chapter 713 for the destructive testing caused by a person served with notice under subsection (1) or for restoring the area destructively tested to the condition existing prior to testing, except to the extent the owner contracts for the destructive testing or restoration.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the claimant refuses to agree and thereafter permit reasonable destructive testing, the claimant shall have no claim for damages which could have been avoided or mitigated had destructive testing been allowed when requested and had a feasible remedy been promptly implemented.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 days after service of the notice of claim, or within 30 days after service of the notice of claim involving an association representing more than 20 parcels, the person served with notice under subsection (1) may serve a copy of the notice of claim to each contractor, subcontractor, supplier, or design professional whom it reasonably believes is responsible for each defect specified in the notice of claim and shall note the specific defect for which it believes the particular contractor, subcontractor, supplier, or design professional is responsible. The notice described in this subsection may not be construed as an admission of any kind. Each such contractor, subcontractor, supplier, and design professional may inspect the property as provided in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 15 days after service of a copy of the notice of claim pursuant to subsection (3), or within 30 days after service of the copy of the notice of claim involving an association representing more than 20 parcels, the contractor, subcontractor, supplier, or design professional must serve a written response to the person who served a copy of the notice of claim. The written response shall include a report, if any, of the scope of any inspection of the property, the findings and results of the inspection, a statement of whether the contractor, subcontractor, supplier, or design professional is willing to make repairs to the property or whether such claim is disputed, a description of any repairs they are willing to make to remedy the alleged construction defect, and a timetable for the completion of such repairs. This response may also be served on the initial claimant by the contractor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 45 days after service of the notice of claim, or within 75 days after service of a copy of the notice of claim involving an association representing more than 20 parcels, the person who was served the notice under subsection (1) must serve a written response to the claimant. The response shall be served to the attention of the person who signed the notice of claim, unless otherwise designated in the notice of claim. The written response must provide:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written offer to remedy the alleged construction defect at no cost to the claimant, a detailed description of the proposed repairs necessary to remedy the defect, and a timetable for the completion of such repairs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written offer to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment, that will not obligate the person’s insurer, and a timetable for making payment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written offer to compromise and settle the claim by a combination of repairs and monetary payment, that will not obligate the person’s insurer, that includes a detailed description of the proposed repairs and a timetable for the completion of such repairs and making payment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written statement that the person disputes the claim and will not remedy the defect or compromise and settle the claim; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written statement that a monetary payment, including insurance proceeds, if any, will be determined by the person’s insurer within 30 days after notification to the insurer by means of serving the claim, which service shall occur at the same time the claimant is notified of this settlement option, which the claimant may accept or reject. A written statement under this paragraph may also include an offer under paragraph (c), but such offer shall be contingent upon the claimant also accepting the determination of the insurer whether to make any monetary payment in addition thereto. If the insurer for the person served with the claim makes no response within the 30 days following service, then the claimant shall be deemed to have met all conditions precedent to commencing an action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person served with a notice of claim pursuant to subsection (1) disputes the claim and will neither remedy the defect nor compromise and settle the claim, or does not respond to the claimant’s notice of claim within the time provided in subsection (5), the claimant may, without further notice, proceed with an action against that person for the claim described in the notice of claim. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to preclude a partial settlement or compromise of the claim as agreed to by the parties and, in that event, the claimant may, without further notice, proceed with an action on the unresolved portions of the claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claimant who receives a timely settlement offer must accept or reject the offer by serving written notice of such acceptance or rejection on the person making the offer within 45 days after receiving the settlement offer. If a claimant initiates an action without first accepting or rejecting the offer, the court shall stay the action upon timely motion until the claimant complies with this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the claimant timely and properly accepts the offer to repair an alleged construction defect, the claimant shall provide the offeror and the offeror’s agents reasonable access to the claimant’s property during normal working hours to perform the repair by the agreed-upon timetable as stated in the offer. If the offeror does not make the payment or repair the defect within the agreed time and in the agreed manner, except for reasonable delays beyond the control of the offeror, including, but not limited to, weather conditions, delivery of materials, claimant’s actions, or issuance of any required permits, the claimant may, without further notice, proceed with an action against the offeror based upon the claim in the notice of claim. If the offeror makes payment or repairs the defect within the agreed time and in the agreed manner, the claimant is barred from proceeding with an action for the claim described in the notice of claim or as otherwise provided in the accepted settlement offer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit or limit the claimant from making any necessary emergency repairs to the property as are required to protect the health, safety, and welfare of the claimant. In addition, any offer or failure to offer pursuant to subsection (5) to remedy an alleged construction defect or to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment does not constitute an admission of liability with respect to the defect and is not admissible in an action brought under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claimant’s service of the written notice of claim under subsection (1) tolls the applicable statute of limitations relating to any person covered by this chapter and any bond surety until the later of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ninety days, or 120 days, as applicable, after service of the notice of claim pursuant to subsection (1); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirty days after the end of the repair period or payment period stated in the offer, if the claimant has accepted the offer. By stipulation of the parties, the period may be extended and the statute of limitations is tolled during the extension.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedures in this chapter apply to each alleged construction defect. However, a claimant may include multiple defects in one notice of claim. The initial list of construction defects may be amended by the claimant to identify additional or new construction defects as they become known to the claimant. The court shall allow the action to proceed to trial only as to alleged construction defects that were noticed and for which the claimant has complied with this chapter and as to construction defects reasonably related to, or caused by, the construction defects previously noticed. Nothing in this subsection shall preclude subsequent or further actions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bar or limit any rights, including the right of specific performance to the extent such right would be available in the absence of this chapter, any causes of action, or any theories on which liability may be based, except as specifically provided in this chapter;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bar or limit any defense, or create any new defense, except as specifically provided in this chapter; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create any new rights, causes of action, or theories on which liability may be based.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not relieve the person who is served a notice of claim under subsection (1) from complying with all contractual provisions of any liability insurance policy as a condition precedent to coverage for any claim under this section. However, notwithstanding the foregoing or any contractual provision, the providing of a copy of such notice to the person’s insurer, if applicable, shall not constitute a claim for insurance purposes. Nothing in this section shall be construed to impair technical notice provisions or requirements of the liability policy or alter, amend, or change existing Florida law relating to rights between insureds and insurers except as otherwise specifically provided herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent that an arbitration clause in a contract for the sale, design, construction, or remodeling of real property conflicts with this section, this section shall control.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, the claimant and any person served with notice pursuant to subsection (1) shall exchange, within 30 days after service of a written request, which request must cite this subsection and include an offer to pay the reasonable costs of reproduction, any design plans, specifications, and as-built plans; any documents detailing the design drawings or specifications; photographs, videos, and expert reports that describe any defect upon which the claim is made; subcontracts; and purchase orders for the work that is claimed defective or any part of such materials. In the event of subsequent litigation, any party who failed to provide the requested materials shall be subject to such sanctions as the court may impose for a discovery violation. Expert reports exchanged between the parties may not be used in any subsequent litigation for any purpose, unless the expert, or a person affiliated with the expert, testifies as a witness or the report is used or relied upon by an expert who testifies on behalf of the party for whom the report was prepared.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2003-49; s. 4, ch. 2004-342; s. 110, ch. 2005-2; s. 3, ch. 2006-281; s. 3, ch. 2009-203.</History></Section>