<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0098.077" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Update of voter signature.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered voter may update his or her signature on file in the statewide voter registration system at any time using a voter registration application submitted to a voter registration official.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and supervisors of elections shall include in any correspondence, other than postcard notifications and notices relating to eligibility, sent to a registered voter information regarding when, where, and how to update the voter’s signature and shall provide the voter information on how to obtain a voter registration application from a voter registration official which can be returned to update the signature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least once during each general election year, the supervisor shall publish in a newspaper of general circulation or other newspaper in the county deemed appropriate by the supervisor a notice specifying when, where, or how a voter can update his or her signature that is on file and how a voter can obtain a voter registration application from a voter registration official.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All signature updates for use in verifying absentee and provisional ballots must be received by the appropriate supervisor of elections no later than the start of the canvassing of absentee ballots by the canvassing board. The signature on file at the start of the canvass of the absentee ballots is the signature that shall be used in verifying the signature on the absentee and provisional ballot certificates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2002-189; s. 10, ch. 2005-277; s. 22, ch. 2005-278; s. 8, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>