<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0098.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statewide voter registration system; implementation, operation, and maintenance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of State, as chief election officer of the state, shall be responsible for implementing, operating, and maintaining, in a uniform and nondiscriminatory manner, a single, uniform, official, centralized, interactive, computerized statewide voter registration system as required by the Help America Vote Act of 2002. The department may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statewide voter registration system must contain the name and registration information of every legally registered voter in the state. All voters shall be assigned a unique identifier. The system shall be the official list of registered voters in the state and shall provide secured access by authorized voter registration officials. The system shall enable voter registration officials to provide, access, and update voter registration information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not contract with any other entity for the operation of the statewide voter registration system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The implementation of the statewide voter registration system shall not prevent any supervisor of elections from acquiring, maintaining, or using any hardware or software necessary or desirable to carry out the supervisor’s responsibilities related to the use of voter registration information or the conduct of elections, provided that such hardware or software does not conflict with the operation of the statewide voter registration system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules governing the access, use, and operation of the statewide voter registration system to ensure security, uniformity, and integrity of the system.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2005-278.</History></Section>