<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0077.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of writ before judgment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before judgment has been obtained by the plaintiff against the defendant:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A writ of garnishment shall be issued by the court or by the clerk on order of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To obtain issuance of the writ, the plaintiff, or the plaintiff’s agent or attorney, shall file in the court where the action is pending a verified motion or affidavit alleging by specific facts the nature of the cause of action; the amount of the debt and that the debt for which the plaintiff sues is just, due, and unpaid; that the garnishment is not sued out to injure either the defendant or the garnishee; and that the plaintiff believes that the defendant will not have in his or her possession, after execution is issued, tangible or intangible property in this state and in the county in which the action is pending on which a levy can be made sufficient to satisfy the plaintiff’s claim. The writ of garnishment shall set forth a notice to the defendant of the right to an immediate hearing for dissolution of such writ pursuant to s. 77.07. Upon issuance of the writ of garnishment, the clerk of the court shall provide by mail a copy of the writ to the defendant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except when the plaintiff has had an attachment writ issued, no writ of garnishment before judgment shall issue until the plaintiff, or the plaintiff’s agent or attorney, gives a bond with surety to be approved by the clerk payable to the defendant in at least double the amount of the debt demanded, conditioned to pay all costs, damages, and attorney’s fees that the defendant sustains in consequence of the plaintiff’s improperly suing out the writ of garnishment. A garnishment bond is not void or voidable because of an informality in it, nor shall the obligors be discharged because of the informality, even though the garnishment is dissolved because of the informality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The motion or pleading need not negative any exemptions of the defendant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 43, 1845; RS 1680; s. 1, ch. 4393, 1895; GS 2144; s. 2, ch. 6910, 1915; RGS 3446; CGL 5299; s. 2, ch. 29737, 1955; s. 27, ch. 67-254; s. 1, ch. 83-97; s. 8, ch. 85-80; s. 384, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 77.18.</Text></Note></Section>