<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0077.041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice to individual defendant for claim of exemption from garnishment; procedure for hearing.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application for a writ of garnishment by a plaintiff, if the defendant is an individual, the clerk of the court shall attach to the writ the following “Notice to Defendant”:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">NOTICE TO DEFENDANT OF RIGHT AGAINST<NewLine />GARNISHMENT OF WAGES, MONEY,<NewLine />AND OTHER PROPERTY</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">The Writ of Garnishment delivered to you with this Notice means that wages, money, and other property belonging to you have been garnished to pay a court judgment against you. HOWEVER, YOU MAY BE ABLE TO KEEP OR RECOVER YOUR WAGES, MONEY, OR PROPERTY. READ THIS NOTICE CAREFULLY.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">State and federal laws provide that certain wages, money, and property, even if deposited in a bank, savings and loan, or credit union, may not be taken to pay certain types of court judgments. Such wages, money, and property are exempt from garnishment. The major exemptions are listed below on the form for Claim of Exemption and Request for Hearing. This list does not include all possible exemptions. You should consult a lawyer for specific advice.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush">TO KEEP YOUR WAGES, MONEY, AND OTHER PROPERTY FROM BEING GARNISHED, OR TO GET BACK ANYTHING ALREADY TAKEN, YOU MUST COMPLETE A FORM FOR CLAIM OF EXEMPTION AND REQUEST FOR HEARING AS SET FORTH BELOW AND HAVE THE FORM NOTARIZED. YOU MUST FILE THE FORM WITH THE CLERK’S OFFICE WITHIN 20 DAYS AFTER THE DATE YOU RECEIVE THIS NOTICE OR YOU MAY LOSE IMPORTANT RIGHTS. YOU MUST ALSO MAIL OR DELIVER A COPY OF THIS FORM TO THE PLAINTIFF AND THE GARNISHEE AT THE ADDRESSES LISTED ON THE WRIT OF GARNISHMENT.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">If you request a hearing, it will be held as soon as possible after your request is received by the court. The plaintiff must file any objection within 3 business days if you hand delivered to the plaintiff a copy of the form for Claim of Exemption and Request for Hearing or, alternatively, 8 business days if you mailed a copy of the form for claim and request to the plaintiff. If the plaintiff files an objection to your Claim of Exemption and Request for Hearing, the clerk will notify you and the other parties of the time and date of the hearing. You may attend the hearing with or without an attorney. If the plaintiff fails to file an objection, no hearing is required, the writ of garnishment will be dissolved and your wages, money, or property will be released.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush">YOU SHOULD FILE THE FORM FOR CLAIM OF EXEMPTION IMMEDIATELY TO KEEP YOUR WAGES, MONEY, OR PROPERTY FROM BEING APPLIED TO THE COURT JUDGMENT. THE CLERK CANNOT GIVE YOU LEGAL ADVICE. IF YOU NEED LEGAL ASSISTANCE YOU SHOULD SEE A LAWYER. IF YOU CANNOT AFFORD A PRIVATE LAWYER, LEGAL SERVICES MAY BE AVAILABLE. CONTACT YOUR LOCAL BAR ASSOCIATION OR ASK THE CLERK’S OFFICE ABOUT ANY LEGAL SERVICES PROGRAM IN YOUR AREA.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">CLAIM OF EXEMPTION AND<NewLine />REQUEST FOR HEARING</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">I claim exemptions from garnishment under the following categories as checked:</Text>
			<Table Width="100" SpaceBelow="true">
				<ColumnDefinitions>
					<Column Width="20" />
					<Column Width="80" />
				</ColumnDefinitions>
				<Body>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">1. Head of family wages. (You must check a. or b. below.)</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">a. I provide more than one-half of the support for a child or other dependent and have net earnings of $750 or less per week.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">b. I provide more than one-half of the support for a child or other dependent, have net earnings of more than $750 per week, but have not agreed in writing to have my wages garnished.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">2. Social Security benefits.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">3. Supplemental Security Income benefits.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">4. Public assistance (welfare).</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">5. Workers’ Compensation.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">6. Reemployment assistance or unemployment compensation.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">7. Veterans’ benefits.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">8. Retirement or profit-sharing benefits or pension money.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">9. Life insurance benefits or cash surrender value of a life insurance policy or proceeds of annuity contract.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">10. Disability income benefits.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">11. Prepaid College Trust Fund or Medical Savings Account.</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
					<Row>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
						</Cell>
						<Cell VerticalAlign="Top">
							<Text xml:space="preserve">12. Other exemptions as provided by law.<NewLine /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />(explain)</Text>
						</Cell>
					</Row>
				</Body>
			</Table>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">I request a hearing to decide the validity of my claim. Notice of the hearing should be given to me at:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Address: <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Telephone number:<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">The statements made in this request are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Defendant’s signature</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Date<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF FLORIDA</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">COUNTY OF</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn and subscribed to before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(month and year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Notary Public/Deputy Clerk</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />OR Produced Identification<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plaintiff must mail, by first class, a copy of the writ of garnishment, a copy of the motion for writ of garnishment, and, if the defendant is an individual, the “Notice to Defendant” to the defendant’s last known address within 5 business days after the writ is issued or 3 business days after the writ is served on the garnishee, whichever is later. However, if such documents are returned as undeliverable by the post office, or if the last known address is not discoverable after diligent search, the plaintiff must mail, by first class, the documents to the defendant at the defendant’s place of employment. The plaintiff shall file in the proceeding a certificate of such service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing by a defendant of a claim of exemption and request for hearing, a hearing will be held as soon as is practicable to determine the validity of the claimed exemptions. If the plaintiff does not file a sworn written statement that contests the defendant’s claim of exemption within 3 business days after hand delivering the claim and request or, alternatively, 8 business days, if the claim and request were served by mail, no hearing is required and the clerk must automatically dissolve the writ and notify the parties of the dissolution by mail.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 2000-258; s. 15, ch. 2001-154; s. 15, ch. 2005-241; s. 2, ch. 2010-97; s. 40, ch. 2012-30.</History>
</Section>