<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0190.008" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Budget; reports and reviews.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district shall provide financial reports in such form and such manner as prescribed pursuant to this chapter and chapter 218.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before each June 15, the district manager shall prepare a proposed budget for the ensuing fiscal year to be submitted to the board for board approval. The proposed budget shall include at the direction of the board an estimate of all necessary expenditures of the district for the ensuing fiscal year and an estimate of income to the district from the taxes, assessments, and other revenues provided in this act. The board shall consider the proposed budget item by item and may either approve the budget as proposed by the district manager or modify the same in part or in whole. The board shall indicate its approval of the budget by resolution, which resolution shall provide for a hearing on the budget as approved. Notice of the hearing on the budget shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the area of the district once a week for 2 consecutive weeks, except that the first publication shall be not fewer than 15 days prior to the date of the hearing. The notice shall further contain a designation of the day, time, and place of the public hearing. At the time and place designated in the notice, the board shall hear all objections to the budget as proposed and may make such changes as the board deems necessary. At the conclusion of the budget hearing, the board shall, by resolution, adopt the budget as finally approved by the board. The budget shall be adopted prior to October 1 of each year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 60 days prior to adoption, the district board shall submit to the local governing authorities having jurisdiction over the area included in the district, for purposes of disclosure and information only, the proposed annual budget for the ensuing fiscal year and any proposed long-term financial plan or program of the district for future operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The local governing authorities may review the proposed annual budget and any long-term financial plan or program and may submit written comments to the board for its assistance and information in adopting its annual budget and long-term financial plan or program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 80-407; s. 5, ch. 2007-160.</History></Section>