<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0190.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preemption; sole authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act constitutes the sole authorization for the future establishment of independent community development districts which have any of the specialized functions and powers provided by this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adoption of chapter 84-360, Laws of Florida, does not affect the validity of the establishment of any community development district or other special district existing on June 29, 1984; and existing community development districts will be subject to the provisions of chapter 190, as amended. All actions taken prior to July 1, 2000, by a community development district existing on June 29, 1984, if taken pursuant to the authority contained in chapter 80-407, Laws of Florida, or this chapter are hereby deemed to have adequate statutory authority. Nothing herein shall affect the validity of any outstanding indebtedness of a community development district established prior to June 29, 1984, and such district is hereby authorized to continue to comply with all terms and requirements of trust indentures or loan agreements relating to such outstanding indebtedness.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The establishment of an independent community development district as provided in this act is not a development order within the meaning of chapter 380. All governmental planning, environmental, and land development laws, regulations, and ordinances apply to all development of the land within a community development district. Community development districts do not have the power of a local government to adopt a comprehensive plan, building code, or land development code, as those terms are defined in the Community Planning Act. A district shall take no action which is inconsistent with applicable comprehensive plans, ordinances, or regulations of the applicable local general-purpose government.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exclusive charter for a community development district shall be the uniform community development district charter as set forth in ss. 190.006-190.041, including the special powers provided by s. 190.012.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 80-407; s. 3, ch. 84-360; s. 27, ch. 85-55; s. 34, ch. 87-224; s. 34, ch. 99-378; s. 9, ch. 2000-304; s. 39, ch. 2011-139.</History>
</Section>