<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0190.005" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Establishment of district.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exclusive and uniform method for the establishment of a community development district with a size of 1,000 acres or more shall be pursuant to a rule, adopted under chapter 120 by the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission, granting a petition for the establishment of a community development district.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for the establishment of a community development district shall be filed by the petitioner with the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission. The petition shall contain:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A metes and bounds description of the external boundaries of the district. Any real property within the external boundaries of the district which is to be excluded from the district shall be specifically described, and the last known address of all owners of such real property shall be listed. The petition shall also address the impact of the proposed district on any real property within the external boundaries of the district which is to be excluded from the district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written consent to the establishment of the district by all landowners whose real property is to be included in the district or documentation demonstrating that the petitioner has control by deed, trust agreement, contract, or option of 100 percent of the real property to be included in the district, and when real property to be included in the district is owned by a governmental entity and subject to a ground lease as described in s. 190.003(14), the written consent by such governmental entity.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A designation of five persons to be the initial members of the board of supervisors, who shall serve in that office until replaced by elected members as provided in s. 190.006.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed name of the district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A map of the proposed district showing current major trunk water mains and sewer interceptors and outfalls if in existence.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based upon available data, the proposed timetable for construction of the district services and the estimated cost of constructing the proposed services. These estimates shall be submitted in good faith but are not binding and may be subject to change.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A designation of the future general distribution, location, and extent of public and private uses of land proposed for the area within the district by the future land use plan element of the effective local government comprehensive plan of which all mandatory elements have been adopted by the applicable general-purpose local government in compliance with the Community Planning Act.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of estimated regulatory costs in accordance with the requirements of s. 120.541.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to filing the petition, the petitioner shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay a filing fee of $15,000 to the county, if located within an unincorporated area, or to the municipality, if located within an incorporated area, and to each municipality the boundaries of which are contiguous with, or contain all or a portion of the land within, the external boundaries of the district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a copy of the petition to the county, if located within an unincorporated area, or to the municipality, if located within an incorporated area, and to each municipality the boundaries of which are contiguous with, or contain all or a portion of, the land within the external boundaries of the district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If land to be included within a district is located partially within the unincorporated area of one or more counties and partially within a municipality or within two or more municipalities, pay a $15,000 filing fee to each entity. Districts established across county boundaries shall be required to maintain records, hold meetings and hearings, and publish notices only in the county where the majority of the acreage within the district lies.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such county and each such municipality required by law to receive a petition may conduct a public hearing to consider the relationship of the petition to the factors specified in paragraph (e). The public hearing shall be concluded within 45 days after the date the petition is filed unless an extension of time is requested by the petitioner and granted by the county or municipality. The county or municipality holding such public hearing may by resolution express its support of, or objection to the granting of, the petition by the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission. A resolution must base any objection to the granting of the petition upon the factors specified in paragraph (e). Such county or municipality may present its resolution of support or objection at the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission hearing and shall be afforded an opportunity to present relevant information in support of its resolution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local public hearing on the petition shall be conducted by a hearing officer in conformance with the applicable requirements and procedures of the Administrative Procedure Act. The hearing shall include oral and written comments on the petition pertinent to the factors specified in paragraph (e). The hearing shall be held at an accessible location in the county in which the community development district is to be located. The petitioner shall cause a notice of the hearing to be published in a newspaper at least once a week for the 4 successive weeks immediately prior to the hearing. Such notice shall give the time and place for the hearing, a description of the area to be included in the district, which description shall include a map showing clearly the area to be covered by the district, and any other relevant information which the establishing governing bodies may require. The advertisement shall not be placed in that portion of the newspaper where legal notices and classified advertisements appear. The advertisement shall be published in a newspaper of general paid circulation in the county and of general interest and readership in the community, not one of limited subject matter, pursuant to chapter 50. Whenever possible, the advertisement shall appear in a newspaper that is published at least 5 days a week, unless the only newspaper in the community is published fewer than 5 days a week. In addition to being published in the newspaper, the map referenced above must be part of the online advertisement required pursuant to s. 50.0211. All affected units of general-purpose local government and the general public shall be given an opportunity to appear at the hearing and present oral or written comments on the petition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission shall consider the entire record of the local hearing, the transcript of the hearing, resolutions adopted by local general-purpose governments as provided in paragraph (c), and the following factors and make a determination to grant or deny a petition for the establishment of a community development district:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether all statements contained within the petition have been found to be true and correct.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the establishment of the district is inconsistent with any applicable element or portion of the state comprehensive plan or of the effective local government comprehensive plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area of land within the proposed district is of sufficient size, is sufficiently compact, and is sufficiently contiguous to be developable as one functional interrelated community.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the district is the best alternative available for delivering community development services and facilities to the area that will be served by the district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the community development services and facilities of the district will be incompatible with the capacity and uses of existing local and regional community development services and facilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the area that will be served by the district is amenable to separate special-district government.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission shall not adopt any rule which would expand, modify, or delete any provision of the uniform community development district charter as set forth in ss. 190.006-190.041, except as provided in s. 190.012. A rule establishing a community development district shall only contain the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A metes and bounds description of the external boundaries of the district and any real property within the external boundaries of the district which is to be excluded.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of five persons designated to be the initial members of the board of supervisors.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the district.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission may adopt rules setting forth its procedures for considering petitions to establish, expand, modify, or delete uniform community development districts or portions thereof consistent with the provisions of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exclusive and uniform method for the establishment of a community development district of less than 1,000 acres in size shall be pursuant to an ordinance adopted by the county commission of the county having jurisdiction over the majority of land in the area in which the district is to be located granting a petition for the establishment of a community development district as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for the establishment of a community development district shall be filed by the petitioner with the county commission. The petition shall contain the same information as required in paragraph (1)(a).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public hearing on the petition shall be conducted by the county commission in accordance with the requirements and procedures of paragraph (1)(d).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county commission shall consider the record of the public hearing and the factors set forth in paragraph (1)(e) in making its determination to grant or deny a petition for the establishment of a community development district.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county commission shall not adopt any ordinance which would expand, modify, or delete any provision of the uniform community development district charter as set forth in ss. 190.006-190.041. An ordinance establishing a community development district shall only include the matters provided for in paragraph (1)(f) unless the commission consents to any of the optional powers under s. 190.012(2) at the request of the petitioner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If all of the land in the area for the proposed district is within the territorial jurisdiction of a municipal corporation, then the petition requesting establishment of a community development district under this act shall be filed by the petitioner with that particular municipal corporation. In such event, the duties of the county, hereinabove described, in action upon the petition shall be the duties of the municipal corporation. If any of the land area of a proposed district is within the land area of a municipality, the county commission may not create the district without municipal approval. If all of the land in the area for the proposed district, even if less than 1,000 acres, is within the territorial jurisdiction of two or more municipalities, the petition shall be filed with the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission and proceed in accordance with subsection (1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, within 90 days after a petition for the establishment of a community development district has been filed pursuant to this subsection, the governing body of the county or municipal corporation may transfer the petition to the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission, which shall make the determination to grant or deny the petition as provided in subsection (1). A county or municipal corporation shall have no right or power to grant or deny a petition that has been transferred to the Florida Land and Water Adjudicatory Commission.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of any existing special district, created to provide one or more of the public improvements and community facilities authorized by this act, may petition for reestablishment of the existing district as a community development district pursuant to this act. The petition shall contain the information specified in subparagraphs (1)(a)1., 3., 4., 5., 6., and 7. and shall not require payment of a fee pursuant to paragraph (1)(b). In such case, the new district so formed shall assume the existing obligations, indebtedness, and guarantees of indebtedness of the district so subsumed, and the existing district shall be terminated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 80-407; ss. 4, 5, ch. 84-360; s. 28, ch. 85-55; s. 35, ch. 87-224; s. 34, ch. 96-410; s. 6, ch. 98-146; s. 35, ch. 99-378; s. 34, ch. 2000-364; s. 2, ch. 2007-160; s. 33, ch. 2008-4; s. 4, ch. 2009-142; s. 40, ch. 2011-139; s. 6, ch. 2012-212.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-212, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act, this act shall take effect July 1, 2012, and shall apply to legal notices that must be published on or after that date.”</Text></Note></Section>