<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0016.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legal Affairs Revolving Trust Fund.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created in the State Treasury the Legal Affairs Revolving Trust Fund, from which the Legislature may appropriate funds for the purpose of funding investigation, prosecution, and enforcement by the Attorney General of the provisions of the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organization Act, the Florida Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act, the Florida False Claims Act, or state or federal antitrust laws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirty percent of all moneys recovered by the Attorney General on behalf of the state, its agencies, or units of state government, local governments, or persons resident in this state or, alternatively, attorneys’ fees and costs, whichever is greater, in any civil action for violation of state or federal antitrust laws shall be deposited in the fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys recovered by the Attorney General under s. 68.086(1) in any civil action for violation of the Florida False Claims Act shall be deposited in the fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of s. 895.09, when the Attorney General files an action pursuant to s. 895.05, funds provided to the Department of Legal Affairs pursuant to s. 895.09(2)(a) or, alternatively, attorneys’ fees and costs, whichever is greater, shall be deposited in the fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a forfeiture action pursuant to s. 895.05, the remainder of the moneys recovered shall be distributed as set forth in s. 895.09.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In other actions brought pursuant to the provisions of the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organization Act or pursuant to the state or federal antitrust laws, the remainder of the moneys recovered on behalf of the state, its agencies, or units of state government shall be deposited in the General Revenue Fund; in the case of other governmental units, transferred to the appropriate fund of such government; or in the case of persons, distributed to such persons or for their benefit, as approved by a court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Moneys recovered” means damages or penalties or any other monetary payment, including monetary proceeds from property forfeited to the state pursuant to s. 895.05 remaining after satisfaction of any valid claims made pursuant to s. 895.09(1)(a)-(c), which damages, penalties, or other monetary payment is made by any defendant by reason of any decree or settlement in any Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organization Act or state or federal antitrust action prosecuted by the Attorney General, but excludes attorneys’ fees and costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any moneys remaining in the fund at the end of any fiscal year in excess of 3 times the amount of the combined budgets for the antitrust and racketeering sections of the Attorney General’s office for the forthcoming fiscal year shall be transferred to the General Revenue Fund unallocated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-301; s. 1, ch. 83-116; s. 2, ch. 84-249; s. 1, ch. 86-277; s. 2, ch. 89-102; ss. 12, 14, ch. 94-316.</History></Section>