<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0016.616" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Direct-support organization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Legal Affairs shall establish a direct-support organization that is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida corporation, not for profit, incorporated under the provisions of chapter 617 and approved by the Secretary of State.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organized and operated exclusively to solicit funds; request and receive grants, gifts, and bequests of money; acquire, receive, hold, invest, and administer, in its own name, property and funds; and make expenditures for the benefit of the purposes as specified by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified by the department, after review, to be operating in a manner consistent with the statutory goals of the organization and in the best interests of the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct-support organization shall operate under written contract with the Department of Legal Affairs. The contract must provide for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approval of the articles of incorporation and bylaws of the direct-support organization by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission of an annual budget for the approval by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification by the department that the direct-support organization is complying with the terms of the contract and in a manner consistent with the statutory goals and purposes and in the best interests of the state. Such certification must be made annually.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reversion to the department of moneys and property held in trust by the direct-support organization if the direct-support organization is no longer approved to operate or ceases to exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The disclosure of material provisions of the contract and the distinction between the board of directors and the direct-support organization to donors of gifts, contributions, or bequests, as well as on all promotional and fundraising publications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual financial audit in accordance with s. 215.981.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fiscal year of the direct-support organization, to begin July 1 of each year and end June 30 of the following year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appointment of the board of directors to be made pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authority of the board of directors of the direct-support organization to hire an executive director.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of the direct-support organization shall consist of 13 members. Each member of the board of directors shall be appointed to a 4-year term; however, for the purpose of providing staggered terms, the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate shall each initially appoint two members to serve a 2-year term, and the Attorney General and the chair of the Council on the Social Status of Black Men and Boys shall each initially appoint one member to serve a 2-year term. All subsequent appointments shall be for 4-year terms. Any vacancy that occurs shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment and shall be for the unexpired term of that seat. The board of directors shall be appointed as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members of the Council on the Social Status of Black Men and Boys, appointed by the council chair.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members appointed by the Attorney General.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members appointed by the President of the Senate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conjunction with the Council on the Social Status of Black Men and Boys, and funded exclusively by the direct-support organization, the direct-support organization shall form strategic partnerships to foster the development of community and private sector resources and shall act as a liaison with state agencies, other state governments, and the public and private sectors on matters that relate to underlying conditions that affect black men and boys to bring about an environment that promotes the values of learning, family, prosperity, unity, and self-worth. To that end, the direct-support organization is charged with the following duties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a strategic program and funding initiative to expand the 5000 Role Models of Excellence in Miami-Dade and Pinellas Counties and implement the 5000 Role Models of Excellence in Broward, Palm Beach, Duval, Orange, and Hillsborough Counties. The strategic program and funding initiative shall be reported to the Legislature by February 15, 2009.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a strategic program and funding initiative to implement the Reading 4 Success Program by the 100 Black Men of Florida in Broward, Miami-Dade, Palm Beach, Duval, Orange, Pinellas, and Hillsborough Counties. The strategic program and funding initiative shall be reported to the Legislature by February 15, 2009.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a strategic program and funding initiative to implement the One Church, One Child program statewide. The strategic program and funding initiative shall be reported to the Legislature by February 15, 2009.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a strategic program and funding initiative to implement the Mapping the Future for Black Males Program within community colleges identified by the Council on the Social Status of Black Men and Boys. The strategic program and funding initiative shall be reported to the Legislature by February 15, 2009.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a public awareness and marketing campaign showcasing programs funded by the direct-support organization, as well as other opportunities to implement the statutory duties of the direct-support organization and the Council on the Social Status of Black Men and Boys, pursuant to s. 16.615(4). The campaign should also encourage the idea that each one of us has a responsibility to make a difference in the community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fund the clerical and administrative costs of the Council on the Social Status of Black Men and Boys, as may be necessary for carrying out the council’s duties under s. 16.615.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct-support organization may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a strategic program and funding initiative to implement a health screening program using mobile screening services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold a statewide Black Policy Summit in conjunction with a university in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Create a compendium of intervention programs in each county, which can be used to determine how to maximize existing resources and address under-served populations or unmet needs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direct-support organization shall consider the participation of counties, in addition to those specified in subsection (4), that demonstrate a willingness to participate and an ability to be successful in any programs funded by the direct-support organization.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2008-130.</History></Section>