<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0016.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Residence, office, and duties of Attorney General.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall reside at the seat of government and shall keep his or her office in the capitol.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall perform the duties prescribed by the Constitution of this state and also perform such other duties appropriate to his or her office as may from time to time be required of the Attorney General by law or by resolution of the Legislature.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, shall, on the written requisition of the Governor, a member of the Cabinet, the head of a department in the executive branch of state government, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, or the Minority Leader of the Senate, and may, upon the written requisition of a member of the Legislature, other state officer, or officer of a county, municipality, other unit of local government, or political subdivision, give an official opinion and legal advice in writing on any question of law relating to the official duties of the requesting officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall appear in and attend to, in behalf of the state, all suits or prosecutions, civil or criminal or in equity, in which the state may be a party, or in anywise interested, in the Supreme Court and district courts of appeal of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall appear in and attend to such suits or prosecutions in any other of the courts of this state or in any courts of any other state or of the United States. This subsection is not intended to authorize the joinder of the Attorney General as a party in such suits or prosecutions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall act as co-counsel of record in capital collateral proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall have and perform all powers and duties incident or usual to such office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall make and keep in his or her office a record of all his or her official acts and proceedings, containing copies of all official opinions, reports, and correspondence, and also keep and preserve in the office all official letters and communications to him or her and cause a registry and index thereof to be made and kept, all of which official papers and records shall be subject to the inspection of the Governor of the state and to the disposition of the Legislature by act or resolution thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May periodically publish a report of his or her official opinions and may prepare and publish an index or consolidated index or indexes of opinions.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2, 1845; ch. 1845, 1871; RS 85; GS 87; RGS 101; CGL 125; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; s. 7, ch. 59-1; s. 1, ch. 78-399; s. 1, ch. 79-159; s. 7, ch. 81-259; s. 1, ch. 85-123; s. 45, ch. 95-147; s. 10, ch. 97-313; s. 6, ch. 2001-266.</History></Section>