<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0016.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public records mediation program within the Office of the Attorney General; creation; duties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “mediation” means a process whereby a neutral third person, called the mediator, acts to encourage and facilitate the resolution of a dispute between two or more parties. It is a formal, nonadversarial process that has the objective of helping the disputing parties reach a mutually acceptable, voluntary agreement. In mediation, decisionmaking authority rests with the parties. The role of the mediator includes, but is not limited to, assisting the parties in identifying issues, fostering joint problem solving, and exploring settlement alternatives.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public records mediation program is created within the Office of the Attorney General.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of the Attorney General shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ one or more mediators to mediate disputes involving access to public records. A person may not be employed by the department as a mediator unless that person is a member in good standing of The Florida Bar.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the Legislature needed legislation governing access to public records.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist the Department of State in preparing training seminars regarding access to public records.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is intended to provide a method for resolving disputes relating to public records, and is intended to be supplemental to, not a substitution for, the other powers given to the Attorney General by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 95-296; s. 3, ch. 2000-158; s. 2, ch. 2000-324; s. 13, ch. 2012-116.</History>
</Section>