<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0016.52" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Participation in preserving constitutional integrity of state.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to provide for independent action and cooperative participation by the state in a program of concerted action among the states, and independent procedure to oppose any existing or proposed federal legislative encroachments upon constitutional state powers, it is hereby made a duty of the Department of Legal Affairs to make a study of federal legislation<EmDash />existing and proposed—to determine whether such legislation has resulted, or may result, in objectionable or harmful encroachments upon the constitutional integrity of state governments, and with due regard to this state’s full contribution to the national war effort, in cooperation with the attorneys general of other states, or alone, to pursue that course best calculated to preserve and safeguard the constitutional state powers of the government of this state. It shall furnish to each of the several representatives in the Congress from this state, a written statement giving the reasons for any action being considered, or about to be taken hereunder at the time; and if possible, shall procure the assistance of such representatives therein and therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the Department of Legal Affairs of this state to render opinions to the representatives in Congress from this state, on any question arising within the scope of the subject matter of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In performing the duties imposed upon it under the provisions of this section, the Department of Legal Affairs is hereby authorized to employ therefor the services of the Council of State Governments, a national conference organization, or its successors in name or organization, or any other similar organization, in such manner not inconsistent with its powers and duties, as it may deem desirable; provided, that the cost of such employment, if any, shall be paid from the necessary and regular appropriation of the Department of Legal Affairs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, ch. 21679, 1943; ss. 11, 35, ch. 69-106.</History></Section>