<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0311.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Strategic Port Investment Initiative.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Strategic Port Investment Initiative within the Department of Transportation. Beginning in fiscal year 2012-2013, a minimum of $35 million annually shall be made available from the State Transportation Trust Fund to fund the Strategic Port Investment Initiative. The Department of Transportation shall work with the deepwater ports listed in s. 311.09 to develop and maintain a priority list of strategic investment projects. Project selection shall be based on projects that meet the state’s economic development goal of becoming a hub for trade, logistics, and export-oriented activities by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing important access and major on-port capacity improvements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing capital improvements to strategically position the state to maximize opportunities in international trade, logistics, or the cruise industry;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Achieving state goals of an integrated intermodal transportation system; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrating the feasibility and availability of matching funds through local or private partners.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to making final project allocations, the Department of Transportation shall schedule a publicly noticed workshop with the Department of Economic Opportunity and the deepwater ports listed in s. 311.09 to review the proposed projects. After considering the comments received, the Department of Transportation shall finalize a prioritized list of potential projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation shall, to the maximum extent feasible, include the seaport projects proposed to be funded under this section in the tentative work program developed under s. 339.135(4).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s.  6, ch. 2012-128; s. 11, ch. 2012-174.</History></Section>