<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0311.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Intermodal Logistics Center Infrastructure Support Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of Transportation the Intermodal Logistics Center Infrastructure Support Program. The purpose of the program is to provide funds for roads, rail facilities, or other means for the conveyance or shipment of goods through a seaport, thereby enabling the state to respond to private sector market demands and meet the state’s economic development goal of becoming a hub for trade, logistics, and export-oriented activities. The department may provide funds to assist with local government projects or projects performed by private entities that meet the public purpose of enhancing transportation facilities for the conveyance or shipment of goods through a seaport to or from an intermodal logistics center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “intermodal logistics center,” including, but not limited to, an “inland port,” means a facility or group of facilities serving as a point of intermodal transfer of freight in a specific area physically separated from a seaport where activities relating to transport, logistics, goods distribution, consolidation, or value-added activities are carried out and whose activities and services are designed to support or be supported by conveyance or shipping through one or more seaports listed in s. 311.09.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must consider, but is not limited to, the following criteria when evaluating projects for Intermodal Logistics Center Infrastructure Support Program assistance:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability of the project to serve a strategic state interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability of the project to facilitate the cost-effective and efficient movement of goods.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the project contributes to economic activity, including job creation, increased wages, and revenues.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the project efficiently interacts with and supports the transportation network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commitment of a funding match.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of investment or commitments made by the owner or developer of the existing or proposed facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the owner has commitments, including memoranda of understanding or memoranda of agreements, with private sector businesses planning to locate operations at the intermodal logistics center.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated local financial support and commitment to the project.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall coordinate and consult with the Department of Economic Opportunity in the selection of projects to be funded by this program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department <Reference Number="1" />is authorized to administer contracts on behalf of the entity selected to receive funding for a project under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide up to 50 percent of project costs for eligible projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in fiscal year 2012-2013, up to $5 million per year shall be made available from the State Transportation Trust Fund for the program. The Department of Transportation shall include projects proposed to be funded under this section in the tentative work program developed pursuant <Reference Number="2" />to s. 339.135(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation <Reference Number="1" />is authorized to adopt rules to <Reference Number="3" />implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2012-128; s. 12, ch. 2012-174.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 12, ch. 2012-174. Section 311.101 was also created by s. 7, ch. 2012-128, and that version uses the word “may” instead of the words “is authorized to.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “to” was substituted for the word “so” by the editors.</Text></Note><Note Reference="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 12, ch. 2012-174. Section 311.101 was also created by s. 7, ch. 2012-128, and that version uses the word “administer” instead of the word “implement.”</Text></Note></Section>