<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0311.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida seaport transportation and economic development funding.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program within the Department of Transportation to finance port transportation or port facilities projects that will improve the movement and intermodal transportation of cargo or passengers in commerce and trade and support the interests, purposes, and requirements of <Reference Number="1" />all ports listed in s. 311.09.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minimum of $15 million per year shall be made available from the State Transportation Trust Fund to fund the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program. The Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council created in s. 311.09 shall develop guidelines for project funding. Council staff, the Department of Transportation, and the Department of Economic Opportunity shall work in cooperation to review projects and allocate funds in accordance with the schedule required for the Department of Transportation to include these projects in the tentative work program developed pursuant to s. 339.135(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Reference Number="2" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program funds shall be used to fund approved projects on a 50-50 matching basis with any of the deepwater ports, as listed in s. 311.09, which is governed by a public body or any other deepwater port which is governed by a public body and which complies with the water quality provisions of s. 403.061, the comprehensive master plan requirements of s. 163.3178(2)(k), and the local financial management and reporting provisions of part III of chapter 218. However, program funds used to fund projects that involve the rehabilitation of wharves, docks, berths, bulkheads, or similar structures shall require a 25-percent match of funds, except for such projects for ports located in counties designated as a rural area of critical economic concern, as defined in s. 288.0656, which are eligible for waiver of match requirements. Program funds also may be used by the Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council for data and analysis that will assist Florida’s seaports and international trade.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projects eligible for funding by grants under the program are limited to the following port facilities or port transportation projects:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation facilities within the jurisdiction of the port.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dredging or deepening of channels, turning basins, or harbors.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction or rehabilitation of wharves, docks, structures, jetties, piers, storage facilities, cruise terminals, automated people mover systems, or any facilities necessary or useful in connection with any of the foregoing.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition of vessel tracking systems, container cranes, or other mechanized equipment used in the movement of cargo or passengers in international commerce.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition of land to be used for port purposes.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The acquisition, improvement, enlargement, or extension of existing port facilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Environmental protection projects which are necessary because of requirements imposed by a state agency as a condition of a permit or other form of state approval; which are necessary for environmental mitigation required as a condition of a state, federal, or local environmental permit; which are necessary for the acquisition of spoil disposal sites and improvements to existing and future spoil sites; or which result from the funding of eligible projects listed in this paragraph.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transportation facilities as defined in s. 334.03(30) which are not otherwise part of the Department of Transportation’s adopted work program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intermodal access projects.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Construction or rehabilitation of port facilities as defined in s. 315.02, excluding any park or recreational facilities, in ports listed in s. 311.09(1) with operating revenues of $5 million or less, provided that such projects create economic development opportunities, capital improvements, and positive financial returns to such ports.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seaport master plan or strategic plan development or updates, including the purchase of data to support such plans.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for consideration by the council pursuant to this section, a project must be consistent with the port comprehensive master plan which is incorporated as part of the approved local government comprehensive plan as required by s. 163.3178(2)(k) or other provisions of the Community Planning Act, part II of chapter 163.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any port which receives funding under the program shall institute procedures to ensure that jobs created as a result of the state funding shall be subject to equal opportunity hiring practices in the manner provided in s. 110.112.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation may subject any project that receives funds pursuant to this section and s. 320.20 to a final audit. The department may adopt rules and perform such other acts as are necessary or convenient to ensure that the final audits are conducted and that any deficiency or questioned costs noted by the audit are resolved.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 65, ch. 90-136; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 55, ch. 93-120; s. 20, ch. 94-237; s. 130, ch. 96-320; s. 48, ch. 97-278; s. 5, ch. 97-280; s. 40, ch. 2000-152; s. 3, ch. 2000-266; s. 99, ch. 2001-266; s. 1, ch. 2002-190; s. 51, ch. 2004-269; s. 7, ch. 2006-2; s. 2, ch. 2010-201; s. 46, ch. 2011-139; s. 57, ch. 2011-213; ss. 35, 36, ch. 2012-119; s. 4, ch. 2012-128; s. 9, ch. 2012-174.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 9, ch. 2012-174. The amendment by s. 4, ch. 2012-128, used the word “the” instead of the word “all.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 35, ch. 2012-119, amended s. 311.07(3)(a) “[i]n order to implement Specific Appropriation 1922 of the 2012-2013 General Appropriations Act.” Related proviso language was vetoed. See ch. 2012-118, the 2012-2013 General Appropriations Act.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 36, ch. 2012-119, provides that “[t]he amendment to s. 311.07(3)(a), Florida Statutes, shall expire July 1, 2013, and the text of that paragraph shall revert to that in existence on June 30, 2012, except that any amendments to such text enacted other than by this act shall be preserved and continue to operate to the extent that such amendments are not dependent upon the portions of text which expire pursuant to this section.” Effective July 1, 2013, paragraph (3)(a), as amended by s. 36, ch. 2012-119; s. 4, ch. 2012-128; and s. 9, ch. 2012-174, will read:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3)(a) Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Program funds shall be used to fund approved projects on a 50-50 matching basis with any of the deepwater ports, as listed in s. 311.09, which is governed by a public body or any other deepwater port which is governed by a public body and which complies with the water quality provisions of s. 403.061, the comprehensive master plan requirements of s. 163.3178(2)(k), and the local financial management and reporting provisions of part III of chapter 218. However, program funds used to fund projects that involve the rehabilitation of wharves, docks, berths, bulkheads, or similar structures shall require a 25-percent match of funds. Program funds also may be used by the Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council for data and analysis that will assist Florida’s seaports and international trade.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">C. Section 55, ch. 2012-119, provides that “[a]ny section of this act which implements a specific appropriation or specifically identified proviso language in the 2012-2013 General Appropriations Act is void if the specific appropriation or specifically identified proviso language is vetoed. Any section of this act which implements more than one specific appropriation or more than one portion of specifically identified proviso language in the 2012-2013 General Appropriations Act is void if all the specific appropriations or portions of specifically identified proviso language are vetoed.” Specific Appropriation 1922 was not vetoed, although proviso language authorizing use of up to $5,000,000 for port projects involving bulkhead repairs for those ports located in counties designated as Rural Areas of Critical Economic Concern (RACEC) and eligibility for funding as provided in s. 311.07(3)(a) was vetoed.</Text></Note></Section>