<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0311.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Seaport planning.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Transportation shall develop, in coordination with the ports listed in s. 311.09(1) and other partners, a Statewide Seaport and Waterways System Plan. This plan shall be consistent with the goals of the Florida Transportation Plan developed pursuant to s. 339.155 and shall consider needs identified in individual port master plans and those from the seaport strategic plans required under this section. The plan will identify 5-year, 10-year, and 20-year needs for the seaport system and will include seaport, waterway, road, and rail projects that are needed to ensure the success of the transportation system as a whole in supporting state economic development goals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each port shall develop a strategic plan with a 10-year horizon. Each plan must include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An economic development component that identifies targeted business opportunities for increasing business and attracting new business for which a particular facility has a strategic advantage over its competitors, identifies financial resources and other inducements to encourage growth of existing business and acquisition of new business, and provides a projected schedule for attainment of the plan’s goals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An infrastructure development and improvement component that identifies all projected infrastructure improvements within the plan area which require improvement, expansion, or development in order for a port to attain a strategic advantage for competition with national and international competitors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A component that identifies all intermodal transportation facilities, including sea, air, rail, or road facilities, which are available or have potential, with improvements, to be available for necessary national and international commercial linkages and provides a plan for the integration of port, airport, and railroad activities with existing and planned transportation infrastructure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A component that identifies physical, environmental, and regulatory barriers to achievement of the plan’s goals and provides recommendations for overcoming those barriers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intergovernmental coordination component that specifies modes and methods to coordinate plan goals and missions with the missions of the Department of Transportation, other state agencies, and affected local, general-purpose governments.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">To the extent feasible, the port strategic plan must be consistent with the local government comprehensive plans of the units of local government in which the port is located. Upon approval of a plan by the port’s board, the plan shall be submitted to the Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Seaport Transportation and Economic Development Council shall review the strategic plans submitted by each port and prioritize strategic needs for inclusion in the Florida Seaport Mission Plan prepared pursuant to s. 311.09(3).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 69, ch. 99-251; s. 3, ch. 2011-164; s. 14, ch. 2012-174.</History></Section>