<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0311.122" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Seaport law enforcement agency; authorization; requirements; powers; training.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each seaport in the state is authorized to create a seaport law enforcement agency for its facility, which authority in no way precludes the seaport from contracting with local governments or law enforcement agencies to comply with the security standards required by this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each seaport law enforcement agency shall meet all of the standards set by the state under certified law enforcement guidelines and requirements and shall be certified as provided under chapter 943.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a seaport creates a seaport law enforcement agency for its facility, a minimum of 30 percent of the aggregate personnel of each seaport law enforcement agency shall be sworn state-certified law enforcement officers with additional Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002 seaport training; a minimum of 30 percent of on-duty personnel of each seaport law enforcement agency shall be sworn state-certified law enforcement officers with additional Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002 seaport training; and at least one on-duty supervisor must be a sworn state-certified law enforcement officer with additional Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002 seaport training.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this chapter, where applicable, seaport law enforcement agency officers shall have the same powers as university police officers as provided in s. 1012.97; however, such powers do not extend beyond the property of the seaport except in connection with an investigation initiated on seaport property or in connection with an immediate, imminent threat to the seaport.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this chapter, sworn state-certified seaport security officers shall have the same law enforcement powers with respect to the enforcement of traffic laws on seaport property as university police officers under s. 1012.97, community college police officers under s. 1012.88, and airport police officers under the provisions of s. 316.640(1)(a)1.d.(I) and (II).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified seaport security officers shall have the authority to immediately tow any vehicle parked illegally as indicated by an existing sign or during an emergency as deemed necessary to maintain seaport security.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2006-193; s. 57, ch. 2010-5.</History>
</Section>