<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0777.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Attempts, solicitation, and conspiracy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who attempts to commit an offense prohibited by law and in such attempt does any act toward the commission of such offense, but fails in the perpetration or is intercepted or prevented in the execution thereof, commits the offense of criminal attempt, ranked for purposes of sentencing as provided in subsection (4). Criminal attempt includes the act of an adult who, with intent to commit an offense prohibited by law, allures, seduces, coaxes, or induces a child under the age of 12 to engage in an offense prohibited by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who solicits another to commit an offense prohibited by law and in the course of such solicitation commands, encourages, hires, or requests another person to engage in specific conduct which would constitute such offense or an attempt to commit such offense commits the offense of criminal solicitation, ranked for purposes of sentencing as provided in subsection (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who agrees, conspires, combines, or confederates with another person or persons to commit any offense commits the offense of criminal conspiracy, ranked for purposes of sentencing as provided in subsection (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in ss. 104.091(2), 379.2431(1), 828.125(2), 849.25(4), 893.135(5), and 921.0022, the offense of criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy is ranked for purposes of sentencing under chapter 921 and determining incentive gain-time eligibility under chapter 944 one level below the ranking under s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023 of the offense attempted, solicited, or conspired to. If the criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy is of an offense ranked in level 1 or level 2 under s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023, such offense is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the offense attempted, solicited, or conspired to is a capital felony, the offense of criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 893.135(5), if the offense attempted, solicited, or conspired to is a life felony or a felony of the first degree, the offense of criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 104.091(2), s. 379.2431(1), s. 828.125(2), or s. 849.25(4), if the offense attempted, solicited, or conspired to is a:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the second degree;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Burglary that is a felony of the third degree; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Felony of the third degree ranked in level 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, or 10 under s. 921.0022 or s. 921.0023,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the offense of criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 104.091(2), s. 379.2431(1), s. 849.25(4), or paragraph (d), if the offense attempted, solicited, or conspired to is a felony of the third degree, the offense of criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in s. 104.091(2), if the offense attempted, solicited, or conspired to is a misdemeanor of the first or second degree, the offense of criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a defense to a charge of criminal attempt, criminal solicitation, or criminal conspiracy that, under circumstances manifesting a complete and voluntary renunciation of his or her criminal purpose, the defendant:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abandoned his or her attempt to commit the offense or otherwise prevented its commission;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After soliciting another person to commit an offense, persuaded such other person not to do so or otherwise prevented commission of the offense; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After conspiring with one or more persons to commit an offense, persuaded such persons not to do so or otherwise prevented commission of the offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, sub-ch. 11, ch. 1637, 1868; RS 2594; GS 3517; RGS 5403; CGL 7544; s. 701, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 72-245; s. 1, ch. 73-142; s. 12, ch. 74-383; s. 5, ch. 75-298; s. 1, ch. 83-98; s. 2, ch. 86-50; s. 170, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 93-406; s. 14, ch. 95-184; s. 1195, ch. 97-102; s. 17, ch. 97-194; s. 2, ch. 2002-214; s. 2, ch. 2003-59; s. 204, ch. 2008-247.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 776.04.</Text></Note></Section>