<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0672.509" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Risk of loss in the absence of breach.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the contract requires or authorizes the seller to ship the goods by carrier:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it does not require her or him to deliver them at a particular destination, the risk of loss passes to the buyer when the goods are duly delivered to the carrier even though the shipment is under reservation (s. 672.505); but</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it does require her or him to deliver them at a particular destination and the goods are there duly tendered while in the possession of the carrier, the risk of loss passes to the buyer when the goods are there duly so tendered as to enable the buyer to take delivery.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the goods are held by a bailee to be delivered without being moved, the risk of loss passes to the buyer:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On her or his receipt of possession or control of a negotiable document of title covering the goods; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On acknowledgment by the bailee of the buyer’s right to possession of the goods; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After her or his receipt of possession or control of a nonnegotiable document of title or other direction to deliver in a record, as provided in s. 672.503(4)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case not within subsection (1) or (2), the risk of loss passes to the buyer on her or his receipt of the goods if the seller is a merchant; otherwise the risk passes to the buyer on tender of delivery.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are subject to contrary agreement of the parties and to the provisions of this chapter on sale on approval (s. 672.327) and on effect of breach on risk of loss (s. 672.510).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-254; s. 584, ch. 97-102; s. 13, ch. 2010-131.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">s. 2-509, U.C.C.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>