<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Home solicitation sale; definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 501.021-501.055:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home solicitation sale” means a sale, lease, or rental of consumer goods or services with a purchase price in excess of $25 which includes all interest, service charges, finance charges, postage, freight, insurance, and service or handling charges, whether under single or multiple contracts, made pursuant to an installment contract, a loan agreement, other evidence of indebtedness, or a cash transaction or other consumer credit transaction, in which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The seller or a person acting for him or her engages in a personal solicitation of the sale, lease, or rental at a place other than at the seller’s fixed location business establishment where goods or services are offered or exhibited for sale, lease, or rental, and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The buyer’s agreement or offer to purchase is given to the seller and the sale, lease, or rental is consummated at a place other than at the seller’s fixed location business establishment,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">including a transaction unsolicited by the consumer and consummated by telephone and without any other contact between the buyer and the seller or its representative prior to delivery of the goods or performance of the services. It does not include a sale, lease, or rental made at any fair or similar commercial exhibit or a sale, lease, or rental that results from a request for specific goods or services by the purchaser or lessee or a sale made by a motor vehicle dealer licensed under s. 320.27 which occurs at a location or facility open to the general public or to a designated group.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Business day” means any calendar day except Sunday or a federal holiday.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Future delivery” means delivery more than 3 business days after the buyer signs an agreement or offer to purchase.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 4, ch. 70-363; s. 1, ch. 71-65; s. 1, ch. 77-350; s. 1, ch. 86-144; s. 1, ch. 87-344; s. 610, ch. 97-103; s. 10, ch. 97-250.</History></Section>