<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.919" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enforcement; stop-sale order.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department finds any lot of antifreeze being distributed in violation of ss. 501.91-501.923 or any of the rules duly promulgated thereunder, the department shall issue and enforce a written “stop-sale” order. The stop-sale order shall warn the distributor not to dispose of any of that lot of antifreeze in any manner until written permission is given by the department. Copies of stop-sale orders shall also be sent to the registrant. The department shall release for distribution the lot of antifreeze under a stop-sale order when s. 501.918 and applicable rules have been complied with. If compliance is not obtained within 30 days, the department may begin proceedings for confiscation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lot of antifreeze not in compliance with said provisions and rules shall be subject to confiscation upon complaint of the department, or any of its agents, to the circuit court in the county in which said antifreeze is located. In the event the court finds the antifreeze to be in violation of this act, it may then order the condemnation of the antifreeze, and the same shall be disposed of in any manner consistent with the rules of the department and the laws of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this act shall be construed to require the department to report for prosecution or for institution of libel proceedings any minor violations of the act whenever it believes that the public interest will be best served by a suitable notice of warning in writing to the violator.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 78-199; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 5, ch. 89-4; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 65, ch. 92-291; s. 3, ch. 99-391.</History></Section>