<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.918" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited activity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribute any antifreeze which has not been registered in accordance with s. 501.913 or whose labeling is different from that accepted for registration. However, if the registration of an antifreeze which was registered in the immediately preceding registration period is not renewed, then any unsold inventory of that antifreeze which exists at the wholesale level or retail level shall be disposed of within 90 days by methods approved by rule of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribute any antifreeze which is adulterated, fails to meet minimum standards, or is mislabeled.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refuse to permit entry or inspection or to permit the acquisition of a sample of the antifreeze as authorized by s. 501.917.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dispose of any antifreeze which is under a stop-sale order in accordance with s. 501.919.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribute any antifreeze unless it is in the registrant’s unbroken package, or is installed by the seller in the cooling system of the purchaser’s vehicle directly from the registrant’s package and the label on such package is less than 5 gallons, or the labeling of such package, if 5 gallons or more, does not bear the information required by s. 501.916. However, the department may by rule establish labeling and other reasonable requirements for the sale of a properly registered antifreeze from a bulk container into a container supplied by or for the purchaser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refill any container bearing a registered label, other than a customer’s container, without first obtaining permission from the registrant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refuse, when requested, to permit a purchaser to see the container from which antifreeze is drawn for installation into the purchaser’s vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribute any antifreeze for which a practical, rapid means for measuring the freeze protection by the user is not readily available, whether by hydrometer or other means.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disseminate any false or misleading advertisement relating to an antifreeze product.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 78-199; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 5, ch. 89-4; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 64, ch. 92-291; s. 2, ch. 93-142.</History></Section>