<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.0118" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restrictions on information printed on receipts for payment-card transactions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cardholder” means the person or organization named on the face of a payment card to whom or for whose benefit the payment card is issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Merchant” means a person who receives from a cardholder a payment card, or information from a payment card, as the instrument for obtaining, purchasing, or receiving goods, services, money, or anything else of value from the person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Payment card” means a credit card, charge card, debit card, or any other card that is issued to a cardholder and that allows the cardholder to obtain, purchase, or receive goods, services, money, or anything else of value from a merchant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A merchant who accepts a payment card for the transaction of business may not print more than the last five digits of the payment card’s account number or print the payment card’s expiration date on a receipt provided to the cardholder. This subsection applies only to receipts described in subsection (3) and does not apply to a transaction in which the sole means of recording the payment card’s account number or expiration date is by handwriting or by an imprint or copy of the payment card.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2003, this section applies to receipts that are electronically printed using a cash register or other machine or device that is first used on or after July 1, 2003.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2005, this section applies to all receipts that are electronically printed, including those printed using a cash register or other machine or device that is first used before July 1, 2003.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A merchant who violates this section commits a noncriminal violation as defined in s. 775.08, punishable by a fine of $250 for the first violation and $1,000 for a second or subsequent violation in accordance with s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office of the state attorney may bring an action to enforce this section for each violation that occurs in or affects the judicial circuit under the office’s jurisdiction. The appropriate county court has jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-170.</History></Section>