<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Final judgment” means a judgment, including any supporting opinion, that determines the rights of the parties and concerning which appellate remedies have been exhausted or the time for appeal has expired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enforcing authority” means the office of the state attorney if a violation of this part occurs in or affects the judicial circuit under the office’s jurisdiction. “Enforcing authority” means the Department of Legal Affairs if the violation occurs in or affects more than one judicial circuit or if the office of the state attorney defers to the department in writing, or fails to act upon a violation within 90 days after a written complaint has been filed with the state attorney.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Violation of this part” means any violation of this act or the rules adopted under this act and may be based upon any of the following as of July 1, 2006:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any rules promulgated pursuant to the Federal Trade Commission Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 41 et seq.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The standards of unfairness and deception set forth and interpreted by the Federal Trade Commission or the federal courts;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law, statute, rule, regulation, or ordinance which proscribes unfair methods of competition, or unfair, deceptive, or unconscionable acts or practices.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Legal Affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Order” means a cease and desist order issued by the enforcing authority as set forth in s. 501.208.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Interested party or person” means any person affected by a violation of this part or any person affected by an order of the enforcing authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consumer” means an individual; child, by and through its parent or legal guardian; business; firm; association; joint venture; partnership; estate; trust; business trust; syndicate; fiduciary; corporation; any commercial entity, however denominated; or any other group or combination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trade or commerce” means the advertising, soliciting, providing, offering, or distributing, whether by sale, rental, or otherwise, of any good or service, or any property, whether tangible or intangible, or any other article, commodity, or thing of value, wherever situated. “Trade or commerce” shall include the conduct of any trade or commerce, however denominated, including any nonprofit or not-for-profit person or activity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Thing of value” may include, without limitation, any moneys, donation, membership, credential, certificate, prize, award, benefit, license, interest, professional opportunity, or chance of winning.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-124; s. 1, ch. 79-386; s. 1, ch. 90-190; s. 2, ch. 93-38; s. 24, ch. 97-98; s. 1, ch. 2001-39; s. 22, ch. 2001-214; s. 1, ch. 2006-196.</History></Section>