<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0501.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Health studios; registration requirements and fees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each health studio shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Register each of its business locations with the department in a form and manner as required by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remit an annual registration fee of $300 to the department at the time of registration for each of the health studio’s business locations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File a security as required by s. 501.016 at the time of registration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Post at the registration desk or front desk, whichever is more prominent, at each business location the proof of registration certificate provided by the department at the time of registration or renewal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Include the registration number issued by the department in all printed advertisements, contracts, and publications utilized by the health studio for a business location.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be considered a new health studio and shall be subject to the requirements of s. 501.016 each time the health studio changes ownership or, in the case of corporate ownership, each time the stock ownership is changed so as to effectively put the health studio under new management or control, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 501.016(6). A change of ownership does not occur within the meaning of this subsection if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substantially the same stockholders form a new corporate entity;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the opinion of the department, the change does not effectively place the health studio under new management and control; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health studio has a satisfactory complaint history with the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person applying for or renewing a local business tax receipt to engage in business as a health studio must exhibit an active registration certificate from the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services before the local business tax receipt may be issued or reissued.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the General Inspection Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 90-312; s. 14, ch. 91-201; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 56, ch. 92-291; s. 1, ch. 93-116; s. 7, ch. 97-250; s. 18, ch. 2012-67.</History>
</Section>