<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.608" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License or affidavit of exemption; occupational license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue to each approved applicant a license in such form and size as is prescribed by the department and, in the case of a commercial telephone seller who is not exempt under the provisions of s. 501.604, shall issue a license for each location at which the commercial telephone seller proposes to do business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any commercial telephone seller claiming to be exempt from the act under s. 501.604(2), (3), (5), (6), (9), (10), (11), (12), (17), (21), (22), (24), or (26) must file with the department a notarized affidavit of exemption. The affidavit of exemption must be on forms prescribed by the department and must require the name of the commercial telephone seller, the name of the business, and the business address. Any commercial telephone seller maintaining more than one business may file a single notarized affidavit of exemption that clearly indicates the location of each place of business. If a change of ownership occurs, the commercial telephone seller must notify the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The affidavit of exemption may be used for the purpose of obtaining an occupational license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each license issued under this part must show the name and address of the person to whom it is issued, as well as the license number, if any, and date of issuance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee or person claiming an exemption shall prominently display his or her license or a copy of his or her affidavit of exemption at each location where he or she does business. Each licensee or person claiming an exemption shall make the license or the copy of the affidavit of exemption available for inspection by any governmental agency upon request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to display a license or a copy of the affidavit of exemption is sufficient grounds for the department to issue an immediate cease and desist order, which shall act as an immediate final order under s. 120.569(2)(n). The order may remain in effect until the commercial telephone seller or a person claiming to be exempt shows the authorities that he or she is licensed or exempt. The department may order the business to cease operations and shall order the phones to be shut off. Failure of a salesperson to display a license may result in the salesperson being summarily ordered by the department to leave the office until he or she can produce a license for the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person applying for or renewing a local occupational license to engage in business as a commercial telephone seller must exhibit an active license or a copy of the affidavit of exemption before the local occupational license may be issued or reissued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affidavit of exemption has no bearing on a person’s burden of proof in any civil or criminal proceeding as provided in s. 501.624.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 91-237; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 92-186; s. 2, ch. 93-235; s. 4, ch. 96-252; s. 241, ch. 96-410; s. 1162, ch. 97-103; s. 46, ch. 2000-154; s. 63, ch. 2003-1.</History></Section>