<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0501.0575" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Weight-Loss Consumer Bill of Rights.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Weight-Loss Consumer Bill of Rights shall consist of the following provisions:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(A) WARNING: RAPID WEIGHT LOSS MAY CAUSE SERIOUS HEALTH PROBLEMS. RAPID WEIGHT LOSS IS WEIGHT LOSS OF MORE THAN 1<Fraction>1/2</Fraction> POUNDS TO 2 POUNDS PER WEEK OR WEIGHT LOSS OF MORE THAN 1 PERCENT OF BODY WEIGHT PER WEEK AFTER THE SECOND WEEK OF PARTICIPATION IN A WEIGHT-LOSS PROGRAM.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(B) CONSULT YOUR PERSONAL PHYSICIAN BEFORE STARTING ANY WEIGHT-LOSS PROGRAM.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(C) ONLY PERMANENT LIFESTYLE CHANGES, SUCH AS MAKING HEALTHFUL FOOD CHOICES AND INCREASING PHYSICAL ACTIVITY, PROMOTE LONG-TERM WEIGHT LOSS.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(D) QUALIFICATIONS OF THIS PROVIDER ARE AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(E) YOU HAVE A RIGHT TO:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. ASK QUESTIONS ABOUT THE POTENTIAL HEALTH RISKS OF THIS PROGRAM AND ITS NUTRITIONAL CONTENT, PSYCHOLOGICAL SUPPORT, AND EDUCATIONAL COMPONENTS.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. RECEIVE AN ITEMIZED STATEMENT OF THE ACTUAL OR ESTIMATED PRICE OF THE WEIGHT-LOSS PROGRAM, INCLUDING EXTRA PRODUCTS, SERVICES, SUPPLEMENTS, EXAMINATIONS, AND LABORATORY TESTS.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. KNOW THE ACTUAL OR ESTIMATED DURATION OF THE PROGRAM.</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">4. KNOW THE NAME, ADDRESS, AND QUALIFICATIONS OF THE DIETITIAN OR NUTRITIONIST WHO HAS REVIEWED AND APPROVED THE WEIGHT-LOSS PROGRAM ACCORDING TO s. 468.505(1)(j), FLORIDA STATUTES.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The copies of the Weight-Loss Consumer Bill of Rights to be posted according to s. 501.0573(6) shall be printed in at least 24-point boldfaced type on one side of a sign. The palm-sized copies to be distributed according to s. 501.0573(5) shall be in boldfaced type and legible. Each weight-loss provider shall be responsible for producing and printing appropriate copies of the Weight-Loss Consumer Bill of Rights.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 93-274; s. 45, ch. 2000-154.</History>
</Section>