<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delivery of crated goods; written statement of satisfaction; right to cancel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “statement of satisfaction” means any receipt, statement, or document by which any retail noncommercial buyer of goods, which goods are to be delivered or are delivered in any box, crate, or other covering which hides the goods from view, is requested or required, as a condition upon receipt of any such purchased goods, to attest satisfaction with the condition or operation of any goods delivered or to be delivered by a seller or her or his representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every statement of satisfaction requested or required to be attested or agreed to in this state shall be evidenced by a writing as provided in this section.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person or business entity requesting or requiring any such statement of satisfaction shall present to and obtain from the buyer her or his signature to the statement of satisfaction which designates, as the date of the attestation of or agreement to the statement, the date on which the buyer actually signs and which contains a statement of buyer’s rights which complies with paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statement must:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appear under the conspicuous caption, “BUYER’S RIGHT TO CANCEL.”</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Read as follows: “If the goods you have received are not in satisfactory condition or operation, you may cancel this statement of satisfaction by mailing a notice to the seller. This notice must indicate that you do not want the goods in the condition in which they were delivered and must be postmarked before midnight of the fifth business day after you sign this statement.”</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any statement of satisfaction agreed or attested to which is not in compliance with the provisions of this section shall be null, void, and of no force or effect.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-346; s. 625, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>