<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.0583" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Selling, delivering, bartering, furnishing, or giving weight-loss pills to persons under age 18; penalties; defense.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “weight-loss pill” means a pill that is available without a prescription, the marketing, advertising, or packaging of which indicates that its primary purpose is for facilitating or causing weight loss. The term includes a pill that contains at least one of the following ingredients: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">ephedra</Font> species, ephedrine alkaloid containing dietary supplements, or <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Sida cordifolia</Font>. However, the term does not include a pill containing one or more of such ingredients which is marketed or intended for a primary purpose other than weight loss.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful to sell, deliver, barter, furnish, or give, directly or indirectly, a weight-loss pill to a person under 18 years of age. However, it is a defense to a charge of violating this subsection if the buyer or recipient of the weight-loss pill displayed to the person alleged to have committed the violation a driver’s license or identification card issued by this state or another state, a passport, or a United States armed services identification card that indicated that the buyer or recipient was 18 years of age or older and the appearance of the buyer or recipient was such that a prudent person would reasonably believe that the buyer or recipient was not under 18 years of age.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A first violation of subsection (2) or this subsection is punishable by a fine of $100. A second violation of subsection (2) or this subsection is punishable by a fine of $250. A third violation of subsection (2) or this subsection is punishable by a fine of $500. A fourth or subsequent violation of subsection (2) or this subsection is punishable by a fine as determined by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, not to exceed $1,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services is authorized to adopt rules to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-24.</History></Section>