<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.616" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful acts and practices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any commercial telephone seller or salesperson to require that payment be by credit card authorization or otherwise to announce a preference for that method of payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any commercial telephone seller to employ, or be affiliated with, any unlicensed salesperson.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any salesperson to be employed by, or affiliated with, an unlicensed commercial telephone seller.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any commercial telephone seller or salesperson to be unlicensed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any salesperson or commercial telephone seller to otherwise violate the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any commercial telephone seller or salesperson to make a commercial telephone solicitation phone call before 8:00 a.m. or after 9:00 p.m. local time at the called person’s location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any commercial telephone seller or salesperson making telephonic solicitations to take any intentional action to prevent transmission of the telephone solicitor’s name or telephone number to the party called when the equipment or service used by the telephone solicitor is capable of creating and transmitting the telephone solicitor’s name or telephone number.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 91-237; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 8, ch. 99-307.</History></Section>