<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Home solicitation sale; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of any of the provisions of ss. 501.025-501.047 is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who conducts or attempts to conduct a home solicitation sale without first obtaining and having in her or his possession a valid, current permit as required by s. 501.022 or who uses or attempts to use an expired, suspended, or revoked home solicitation sale permit in a home solicitation sale is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Upon second or subsequent conviction for violation of this subsection, the offender is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who uses a false or fictitious name in any application for a home solicitation sale permit or certificate as provided for in s. 501.022 or who makes a false statement, conceals a material fact, or otherwise commits a fraud in any such application is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Upon a second or subsequent conviction for violation of this subsection, the offender is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. The obtaining of two or more permits which are in different names or the possession of two or more such permits shall be prima facie evidence that this subsection has been violated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 70-363; s. 457, ch. 71-136; s. 5, ch. 86-144; s. 4, ch. 87-344; s. 122, ch. 91-224; s. 615, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>