<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0501.95" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gift certificates and credit memos.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Credit memo” means a certificate, card, stored value card, or similar instrument issued in exchange for returned merchandise when the certificate, card, or similar instrument is redeemable for merchandise, food, or services regardless of whether any cash may be paid to the owner of the certificate, card, or instrument as part of the redemption transaction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gift certificate” means a certificate, gift card, stored value card, or similar instrument purchased for monetary consideration when the certificate, card, or similar instrument is redeemable for merchandise, food, or services regardless of whether any cash may be paid to the owner of the certificate, card, or instrument as part of the redemption transaction, but this term shall not include tickets as specified in s. 717.1355 or manufacturer or retailer discounts and coupons.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A gift certificate purchased or credit memo issued in this state may not have an expiration date, expiration period, or any type of postsale charge or fee imposed on the gift certificate or credit memo, including, but not limited to, service charges, dormancy fees, account maintenance fees, or cash-out fees. However, a gift certificate may have an expiration date of not less than 3 years if it is provided as a charitable contribution, or not less than 1 year if it is provided as a benefit pursuant to an employee-incentive program, and the expiration date is prominently disclosed in writing to the consumer at the time it is provided. In addition, a gift certificate may have an expiration date if it is provided to the recipient, or to a purchaser for transfer to the recipient, as part of a loyalty or promotional program when the recipient does not pay a separate identifiable charge for the certificate, or if it is provided in conjunction with a convention, conference, vacation, or sporting or fine arts event having a limited duration so long as the majority of the value paid by the recipient is attributable to the convention, conference, vacation, or event. An issuer may honor a gift certificate that has expired on or before the effective date of this act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (a) does not apply to a gift certificate or credit memo sold or issued by a financial institution, as defined in s. 655.005, or by a money services business, as defined in s. 560.103, if the gift certificate or credit memo is redeemable by multiple unaffiliated merchants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforcement of this section shall be as provided in s. 501.142(3), (4), and (5) for violations of this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-256; s. 1, ch. 2007-334; s. 50, ch. 2008-177.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 3, ch. 2007-78, provides that “[s]ection 501.95(2)(a), Florida Statutes, as created in CS for CS for CS for SB 1638 or similar legislation, does not apply to prepaid calling arrangements as defined in s. 212.05(1)(e), Florida Statutes, including prepaid cards for wireless or wireline telecommunications service.”</Text></Note></Section>