<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0040.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Clerks to disburse money; payments to jurors and witnesses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys drawn from the treasury under the provisions of this chapter by the clerk of the court shall be disbursed by the clerk of the court as far as needed in payment of witnesses, except for expert witnesses paid under a contract or other professional services agreement pursuant to ss. 29.004, 29.005, 29.006, and 29.007, for the legal compensation for service during the quarterly fiscal period for which the moneys were drawn and for no other purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment of jurors and the payment of expenses for meals and lodging for jurors under the provisions of this chapter are court-related functions that the clerk of the court shall fund from filing fees, service charges, court costs, and fines as part of the maximum annual budget under ss. 28.35 and 28.36.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Jurors and witnesses shall be paid by the clerk of the court either in cash or by warrant within 20 days after completion of jury service or of completion of service as a witness.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the clerk of the court pays a juror or witness by cash, the juror or witness shall sign the payroll in the presence of the clerk, a deputy clerk, or some other person designated by the clerk.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the clerk pays a juror or witness by warrant, he or she shall endorse on the payroll opposite the juror’s or witness’s name the words “Paid by warrant,” giving the number and date of the warrant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 4121, 1893; GS 1594; s. 4, ch. 7262, 1917; RGS 2796; CGL 4482; s. 1, ch. 59-88; s. 1, ch. 61-494; s. 4, ch. 65-483; s. 5, ch. 68-7; s. 9, ch. 73-334; s. 15, ch. 79-235; s. 255, ch. 95-147; s. 4, ch. 99-259; s. 39, ch. 2004-265; s. 18, ch. 2008-111.</History></Section>