<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1012.58" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transition to Teaching Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />The Transition to Teaching Program is created to encourage and assist midcareer professionals who want to become teachers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">GRANTS; ELIGIBLE APPLICANTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education shall design the process for receiving and evaluating grant proposals in accordance with state and federal appropriations guidelines. Grants may be awarded only to the extent that funding is provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education shall request proposals from eligible applicants to participate in the program. Each application must:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe the target group of career-changing professionals upon which the applicant will focus in carrying out its program, including a description of the characteristics of the target group that shows how the knowledge and experience of its members are likely to improve their ability to become effective teachers.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe how the applicant will identify and recruit program participants.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe how the applicant will ensure that program participants are placed and teach in eligible school districts in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe the teacher support services that program participants will receive throughout at least their first year of teaching.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe how the applicant will collaborate with other institutions, agencies, or organizations to recruit, train, place, and support program participants, including evidence of the commitment of those institutions, agencies, or organizations to the applicant’s program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education must require an evaluation process to measure the progress and effectiveness of the program. This evaluation must include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s goals and objectives.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance indicators that the applicant will use to measure the program’s progress.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The outcome measures that will be used to determine the program’s effectiveness.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assurance that the applicant will provide the commissioner with information the commissioner finds necessary to determine the overall effectiveness of the programs.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM IMPLEMENTATION; AUTHORIZED EXPENDITURES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant shall estimate the funds required for the proposed program. All funds provided for a program must be used as authorized in federal guidelines.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligible applicants are encouraged to implement the program using the following components:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recruiting program participants, including informing them of opportunities under the program and putting them in contact with other institutions, agencies, or organizations that will train, place, and support them in the teaching profession.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting providers of teacher training to tailor their training to meet the particular needs of professionals who are changing their careers to teaching.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placement activities, including identifying eligible local education agencies with a need for the skills and characteristics of the newly trained program participants and assisting those participants to obtain employment in those school districts.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postplacement support activities for program participants.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBLE PARTICIPANTS; REQUIREMENTS FOR GRANT REPAYMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each participant who receives a grant from the program to pursue a teacher preparation program must agree to teach in an eligible school district in this state for at least 3 years after certification. To be eligible, a school district must meet the requirements established in regulations that implement the Omnibus Appropriations Bill of 2000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioner shall establish conditions under which a participant must repay all or a portion of the training stipend if the participant fails to complete his or her service obligation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 732, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>