<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1012.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department of Education duties; K-12 personnel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERIODIC CRIMINAL HISTORY RECORD CHECKS.<EmDash />In cooperation with the Florida Department of Law Enforcement, the Department of Education may periodically perform criminal history record checks on individuals who hold a certificate pursuant to s. 1012.56 or s. 1012.57.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPUTER DATABASE OF CERTAIN PERSONS WHOSE EMPLOYMENT WAS TERMINATED.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall establish a computer database containing the names of persons whose employment is terminated under s. 1012.33(1)(a) or (4)(c), which information shall be available to the district school superintendents and their designees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school superintendent shall report to the Department of Education the name of any person terminated under s. 1012.33(1)(a) or (4)(c) within 10 working days after the date of final action by the district school board on the termination, and the department shall immediately enter the information in the computer records.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUSPENSION OR DENIAL OF TEACHING CERTIFICATE DUE TO CHILD SUPPORT DELINQUENCY.<EmDash />The Department of Education shall work cooperatively with the Department of Revenue to establish an automated method for periodically disclosing information relating to individuals who hold a certificate pursuant to s. 1012.56 or s. 1012.57 to the Department of Revenue, the state’s Title IV-D agency. The purpose of this section is to promote the public policy of this state relating to child support as established in s. 409.2551. The department shall, when directed by the court or the Department of Revenue pursuant to s. 409.2598, deny or suspend the application of any applicant found not to be in compliance with a support order, a subpoena, an order to show cause, or a written agreement with the Department of Revenue. The department shall issue or reinstate the certificate without additional charge to the certificateholder when notified by the court or the Department of Revenue that the certificateholder has complied with the terms of the support order. The department is not liable for any certificate denial or suspension resulting from the discharge of its duties under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONFERENCES OF PUBLIC SCHOOL PERSONNEL.<EmDash />As a means of stimulating the professional improvement of personnel in service, the Department of Education may call conferences of personnel of the public schools on matters relating solely to education, which conferences, if held on a school day within the period of time covered by a contract, shall be attended with pay by all who may be designated in the call of the Department of Education, provided that the call of the Department of Education may indicate that attendance is optional, and that in any case of those absent from their usual duties during the time of the conference, only those actually in attendance at the conference shall be entitled to pay for time covered by the conference.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCHOOL-RELATED EMPLOYEE OF THE YEAR PROGRAM.<EmDash />The Department of Education shall, by rule, provide for a School-Related Employee of the Year Program. In addition to any other provision, the department shall include in such rules that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall apply to school-related employees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall be modeled after the Teacher of the Year Program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One school-related employee of the year shall be nominated by each district school board in the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A selection process shall be instituted to select the school-related employee of the year so that the top five finalists receive awards under the program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORTING.<EmDash />The Department of Education shall annually post online links to each school district’s collective bargaining contracts and the salary and benefits of the personnel or officers of any educator association which were paid by the school district pursuant to s. 1012.22.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 696, ch. 2002-387; s. 55, ch. 2006-74; s. 179, ch. 2007-5; s. 9, ch. 2008-92.</History></Section>