<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1012.2315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assignment of teachers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE FINDINGS AND INTENT.<EmDash />The Legislature finds disparities between teachers assigned to teach in a majority of schools that do not need improvement and schools that do need improvement pursuant to s. 1008.33. The disparities may be found in the assignment of temporarily certified teachers, teachers in need of improvement, and out-of-field teachers and in the performance of the students. It is the intent of the Legislature that district school boards have flexibility through the collective bargaining process to assign teachers more equitably across the schools in the district.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ASSIGNMENT TO SCHOOLS GRADED “D” or “F”.<EmDash />School districts may not assign a higher percentage than the school district average of temporarily certified teachers, teachers in need of improvement, or out-of-field teachers to schools graded “D” or “F” pursuant to s. 1008.34. Each school district shall annually certify to the Commissioner of Education that this requirement has been met. If the commissioner determines that a school district is not in compliance with this subsection, the State Board of Education shall be notified and shall take action pursuant to s. 1008.32 in the next regularly scheduled meeting to require compliance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SALARY INCENTIVES.<EmDash />District school boards are authorized to provide salary incentives to meet the requirement of subsection (2). A district school board may not sign a collective bargaining agreement that precludes the school district from providing sufficient incentives to meet this requirement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COLLECTIVE BARGAINING.<EmDash />Notwithstanding provisions of chapter 447 relating to district school board collective bargaining, collective bargaining provisions may not preclude a school district from providing incentives to high-quality teachers and assigning such teachers to low-performing schools.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By July 1, 2012, the Department of Education shall annually report on its website, in a manner that is accessible to the public, the performance rating data reported by district school boards under s. 1012.34. The report must include the percentage of classroom teachers, instructional personnel, and school administrators receiving each performance rating aggregated by school district and by school.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 1012.31(3)(a)2., each school district shall annually report to the parent of any student who is assigned to a classroom teacher or school administrator having two consecutive annual performance evaluation ratings of unsatisfactory under s. 1012.34, two annual performance evaluation ratings of unsatisfactory within a 3-year period under s. 1012.34, or three consecutive annual performance evaluation ratings of needs improvement or a combination of needs improvement and unsatisfactory under s. 1012.34.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 2006-74; s. 5, ch. 2009-144; s. 10, ch. 2011-1; s. 12, ch. 2012-194.</History>
</Section>