<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1012.97" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">University police.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each university is empowered and directed to provide for police officers for the university, and such police officers shall hereafter be known and designated as the “university police.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university police are declared to be law enforcement officers of the state and conservators of the peace and have the right to arrest, in accordance with the laws of this state, any person for violation of state law or applicable county or city ordinances when such violations occur on or within 1,000 feet of any property or facilities that are under the guidance, supervision, regulation, or control of the state university, a direct-support organization of such university, or any other organization controlled by the state university, or when such violations occur within a specified jurisdictional area as agreed upon in a mutual aid agreement entered into with a law enforcement agency pursuant to s. 23.1225(1). Arrest may be made off campus when hot pursuit originates on or within 1,000 feet of any such property or facilities, or as agreed upon in accordance with the mutual aid agreement. Such officers have full authority to bear arms in the performance of their duties and to execute search warrants within their territorial jurisdiction. University police, when requested by the sheriff or local police authority, may serve subpoenas or other legal process and may make arrest of any person against whom a warrant has been issued or any charge has been made of violation of federal or state laws or county or city ordinances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">University police shall promptly deliver all persons arrested and charged with a felony to the sheriff of the county within which the university is located, and all persons arrested and charged with misdemeanors shall be delivered to the applicable authority as may be provided by law, but otherwise to the sheriff of the county in which the university is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">University police must meet the minimum standards established by the Criminal Justice Standards and Training Commission and chapter 943. Each police officer shall, before entering into the performance of his or her duties, take the oath of office as established by the university; and the university may obtain and approve a bond on each officer, payable to the Governor and his or her successors in office, conditioned on the faithful performance of the duties of such university police officer. The university may determine the amount of the bond. In determining the amount of the bond, the university may consider the amount of money or property likely to be in the custody of the officer at any one time. The university shall provide a uniform set of identification credentials for each university police officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In performance of any of the powers, duties, and functions authorized by law or this section, university police shall have the same rights, protections, and immunities afforded other peace or law enforcement officers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university, in concurrence with the Department of Law Enforcement, shall adopt rules, including, but not limited to, the appointment, employment, and removal of university police and, further, establish in writing a policy manual, including, but not limited to, routine and emergency law enforcement situations. A policy manual shall be furnished to each university police officer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 787, ch. 2002-387; s. 3, ch. 2009-216.</History></Section>