<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1012.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public school personnel; powers and duties of the district school board.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board shall:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designate positions to be filled, prescribe qualifications for those positions, and provide for the appointment, compensation, promotion, suspension, and dismissal of employees as follows, subject to the requirements of this chapter:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Positions, qualifications, and appointments.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board shall act upon written recommendations submitted by the district school superintendent for positions to be filled, for minimum qualifications for personnel for the various positions, and for the persons nominated to fill such positions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board may reject for good cause any employee nominated.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the third nomination by the district school superintendent for any position is rejected for good cause, if the district school superintendent fails to submit a nomination for initial employment within a reasonable time as prescribed by the district school board, or if the district school superintendent fails to submit a nomination for reemployment within the time prescribed by law, the district school board may proceed on its own motion to fill such position.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board’s decision to reject a person’s nomination does not give that person a right of action to sue over the rejection and may not be used as a cause of action by the nominated employee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Time to act on nominations.</Font><EmDash />The district school board shall act not later than 3 weeks following the receipt of FCAT scores and data, including school grades, or June 30, whichever is later, on the district school superintendent’s nominations of supervisors, principals, and members of the instructional staff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Compensation and salary schedules.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Definitions.<EmDash />As used in this paragraph:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adjustment” means an addition to the base salary schedule that is not a bonus and becomes part of the employee’s permanent base salary and shall be considered compensation under s. 121.021(22).</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Grandfathered salary schedule” means the salary schedule or schedules adopted by a district school board before July 1, 2014, pursuant to subparagraph 4.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Instructional personnel” means instructional personnel as defined in s. 1012.01(2)(a)-(d), excluding substitute teachers.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Performance salary schedule” means the salary schedule or schedules adopted by a district school board pursuant to subparagraph 5.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Salary schedule” means the schedule or schedules used to provide the base salary for district school board personnel.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“School administrator” means a school administrator as defined in s. 1012.01(3)(c).</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="g">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supplement” means an annual addition to the base salary for the term of the negotiated supplement as long as the employee continues his or her employment for the purpose of the supplement. A supplement does not become part of the employee’s continuing base salary but shall be considered compensation under s. 121.021(22).</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cost-of-living adjustment.<EmDash />A district school board may provide a cost-of-living salary adjustment if the adjustment:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not discriminate among comparable classes of employees based upon the salary schedule under which they are compensated.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not exceed 50 percent of the annual adjustment provided to instructional personnel rated as effective.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advanced degrees.<EmDash />A district school board may not use advanced degrees in setting a salary schedule for instructional personnel or school administrators hired on or after July 1, 2011, unless the advanced degree is held in the individual’s area of certification and is only a salary supplement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grandfathered salary schedule.<EmDash /></Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board shall adopt a salary schedule or salary schedules to be used as the basis for paying all school employees hired before July 1, 2014. Instructional personnel on annual contract as of July 1, 2014, shall be placed on the performance salary schedule adopted under subparagraph 5. Instructional personnel on continuing contract or professional service contract may opt into the performance salary schedule if the employee relinquishes such contract and agrees to be employed on an annual contract under s. 1012.335. Such an employee shall be placed on the performance salary schedule and may not return to continuing contract or professional service contract status. Any employee who opts into the performance salary schedule may not return to the grandfathered salary schedule.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the grandfathered salary schedule for instructional personnel, a district school board must base a portion of each employee’s compensation upon performance demonstrated under s. 1012.34 and shall provide differentiated pay for both instructional personnel and school administrators based upon district-determined factors, including, but not limited to, additional responsibilities, school demographics, critical shortage areas, and level of job performance difficulties.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Reference Number="1"/>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performance salary schedule.<EmDash />By July 1, 2014, the district school board shall adopt a performance salary schedule that provides annual salary adjustments for instructional personnel and school administrators based upon performance determined under s. 1012.34. Employees hired on or after July 1, 2014, or employees who choose to move from the grandfathered salary schedule to the performance salary schedule shall be compensated pursuant to the performance salary schedule once they have received the appropriate performance evaluation for this purpose. However, a classroom teacher whose performance evaluation utilizes student learning growth measures established under s. 1012.34(7)(e) shall remain under the grandfathered salary schedule until his or her teaching assignment changes to a subject for which there is an assessment or the school district establishes equally appropriate measures of student learning growth as defined under s. 1012.34 and rules of the State Board of Education.</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Base salary.<EmDash />The base salary shall be established as follows:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The base salary for instructional personnel or school administrators who opt into the performance salary schedule shall be the salary paid in the prior year, including adjustments only.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning July 1, 2014, instructional personnel or school administrators new to the district, returning to the district after a break in service without an authorized leave of absence, or appointed for the first time to a position in the district in the capacity of instructional personnel or school administrator shall be placed on the performance salary schedule.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Salary adjustments.<EmDash />Salary adjustments for highly effective or effective performance shall be established as follows:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual salary adjustment under the performance salary schedule for an employee rated as highly effective must be greater than the highest annual salary adjustment available to an employee of the same classification through any other salary schedule adopted by the district.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The annual salary adjustment under the performance salary schedule for an employee rated as effective must be equal to at least 50 percent and no more than 75 percent of the annual adjustment provided for a highly effective employee of the same classification.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance salary schedule shall not provide an annual salary adjustment for an employee who receives a rating other than highly effective or effective for the year.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Salary supplements.<EmDash />In addition to the salary adjustments, each district school board shall provide for salary supplements for activities that must include, but are not limited to:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assignment to a Title I eligible school.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assignment to a school that earned a grade of “F” or three consecutive grades of “D” pursuant to s. 1008.34 such that the supplement remains in force for at least 1 year following improved performance in that school.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification and teaching in critical teacher shortage areas. Statewide critical teacher shortage areas shall be identified by the State Board of Education under s. 1012.07. However, the district school board may identify other areas of critical shortage within the school district for purposes of this sub-sub-subparagraph and may remove areas identified by the state board which do not apply within the school district.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assignment of additional academic responsibilities.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If budget constraints in any given year limit a district school board’s ability to fully fund all adopted salary schedules, the performance salary schedule shall not be reduced on the basis of total cost or the value of individual awards in a manner that is proportionally greater than reductions to any other salary schedules adopted by the district.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Contracts and terms of service.</Font><EmDash />The district school board shall provide written contracts for all regular members of the instructional staff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Transfer and promotion.</Font><EmDash />The district school board shall act on recommendations of the district school superintendent regarding transfer and promotion of any employee. The district school superintendent’s primary consideration in recommending an individual for a promotion must be the individual’s demonstrated effectiveness under s. 1012.34.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Suspension, dismissal, and return to annual contract status.</Font><EmDash />The district school board shall suspend, dismiss, or return to annual contract members of the instructional staff and other school employees; however, no administrative assistant, supervisor, principal, teacher, or other member of the instructional staff may be discharged, removed, or returned to annual contract except as provided in this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Awards and incentives.</Font><EmDash />The district school board shall provide for recognition of district employees, students, school volunteers, and advisory committee members who have contributed outstanding and meritorious service in their fields or service areas. After considering recommendations of the district school superintendent, the district school board shall adopt rules establishing and regulating the meritorious service awards necessary for the efficient operation of the program. An award or incentive granted under this paragraph may not be considered in determining the salary schedules required by paragraph (c). Monetary awards shall be limited to persons who propose procedures or ideas adopted by the board which will result in eliminating or reducing district school board expenditures or improving district or school center operations. Nonmonetary awards shall include, but are not limited to, certificates, plaques, medals, ribbons, and photographs. The district school board may expend funds for such recognition and awards. No award granted under this paragraph shall exceed $2,000 or 10 percent of the first year’s gross savings, whichever is greater.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Planning and training time for teachers.</Font><EmDash />The district school board shall adopt rules to make provisions for teachers to have time for lunch, professional planning, and professional development time when they will not be directly responsible for the children if some adult supervision is furnished for the students during such periods.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Comprehensive program of staff development.</Font><EmDash />The district school board shall establish a comprehensive program of staff development that incorporates school improvement plans pursuant to s. 1001.42 and is aligned with principal leadership training pursuant to s. 1012.986 as a part of the plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt policies relating to personnel leave as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Annual leave.</Font><EmDash />The district school board may adopt rules that provide for the earning of annual leave by employees, including educational support employees, who are employed for 12 calendar months a year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Sick leave.</Font><EmDash />The district school board may adopt rules relating to sick leave, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Illness-in-line-of-duty leave.</Font><EmDash />The district school board may adopt rules relating to illness-in-the-line-of-duty leave, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Sabbatical leave.</Font><EmDash />The district school board may adopt rules relating to sabbatical leave, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 697, ch. 2002-387; s. 50, ch. 2003-391; s. 56, ch. 2006-74; s. 7, ch. 2007-3; s. 180, ch. 2007-5; s. 4, ch. 2011-1; s. 11, ch. 2012-194.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 17, ch. 2011-1, provides that “[c]hapter 2010-279, Laws of Florida, does not apply to any rulemaking required to administer this act.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>