<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1012.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment of substitute teachers, teachers of adult education, nondegreed teachers of career education, and career specialists; students performing clinical field experience.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding ss. 1012.32, 1012.55, 1012.56, and 1012.57, or any other provision of law or rule to the contrary, each district school board shall establish the minimal qualifications for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substitute teachers to be employed pursuant to s. 1012.35. The qualifications shall require the filing of a complete set of fingerprints in the same manner as required by s. 1012.32; documentation of a minimum education level of a high school diploma or equivalent; and completion of an initial orientation and training program in district policies and procedures addressing school safety and security procedures, educational liability laws, professional responsibilities, and ethics.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Part-time and full-time teachers in adult education programs. The qualifications shall require the filing of a complete set of fingerprints in the same manner as required by s. 1012.32. Faculty employed solely to conduct postsecondary instruction may be exempted from this requirement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Part-time and full-time nondegreed teachers of career programs. Qualifications shall be established for nondegreed teachers of career and technical education courses for program clusters that are recognized in the state and are based primarily on successful occupational experience rather than academic training. The qualifications for such teachers shall require:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a complete set of fingerprints in the same manner as required by s. 1012.32. Faculty employed solely to conduct postsecondary instruction may be exempted from this requirement.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation of education and successful occupational experience including documentation of:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A high school diploma or the equivalent.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completion of 6 years of full-time successful occupational experience or the equivalent of part-time experience in the teaching specialization area. The district school board may establish alternative qualifications for teachers with an industry certification in the career area in which they teach.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completion of career education training conducted through the local school district inservice master plan.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For full-time teachers, completion of professional education training in teaching methods, course construction, lesson planning and evaluation, and teaching special needs students. This training may be completed through coursework from an accredited or approved institution or an approved district teacher education program.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstration of successful teaching performance.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation of industry certification when state or national industry certifications are available and applicable.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substitute, adult education, and nondegreed career education teachers who are employed pursuant to this section shall have the same rights and protection of laws as certified teachers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student who is enrolled in a state-approved teacher preparation program in a postsecondary educational institution that is approved by rules of the State Board of Education and who is jointly assigned by the postsecondary educational institution and a district school board to perform a clinical field experience under the direction of a regularly employed and certified educator shall, while serving such supervised clinical field experience, be accorded the same protection of law as that accorded to the certified educator except for the right to bargain collectively as an employee of the district school board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 714, ch. 2002-387; s. 13, ch. 2004-295; s. 132, ch. 2004-357; s. 34, ch. 2011-175.</History>
</Section>