<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1012.885" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Remuneration of Florida College System institution presidents; limitations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Appropriated state funds” means funds appropriated from the General Revenue Fund or funds appropriated from state trust funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cash-equivalent compensation” means any benefit that may be assigned an equivalent cash value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Remuneration” means salary, bonuses, and cash-equivalent compensation paid to a Florida College System institution president by his or her employer for work performed, excluding health insurance benefits and retirement benefits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIMITATION ON COMPENSATION.<EmDash />Notwithstanding any other law, resolution, or rule to the contrary, a Florida College System institution president may not receive more than $225,000 in remuneration annually from appropriated state funds. Only compensation, as defined in s. 121.021(22), provided to a Florida College System institution president may be used in calculating benefits under chapter 121.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXCEPTIONS.<EmDash />This section does not prohibit any party from providing cash or cash-equivalent compensation from funds that are not appropriated state funds to a Florida College System institution president in excess of the limit in subsection (2). If a party is unable or unwilling to fulfill an obligation to provide cash or cash-equivalent compensation to a Florida College System institution president as permitted under this subsection, appropriated state funds may not be used to fulfill such obligation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIMITATION ON REMUNERATION.<EmDash />Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, for the 2012-2013 fiscal year, a Florida College System institution president may not receive more than $200,000 in remuneration from appropriated state funds. Only compensation, as defined in s. 121.021(22), provided to a Florida College System institution president may be used in calculating benefits under chapter 121.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 2010-155; s. 197, ch. 2011-5; s. 39, ch. 2011-63; s. 38, ch. 2012-134.</History>
</Section>