<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1012.986" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">William Cecil Golden Professional Development Program for School Leaders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established the William Cecil Golden Professional Development Program for School Leaders to provide high standards and sustained support for principals as instructional leaders. The program shall consist of a collaborative network of state and national professional leadership organizations to respond to instructional leadership needs throughout the state. The network shall support the human-resource development needs of principals, principal leadership teams, and candidates for principal leadership positions using the framework of leadership standards adopted by the State Board of Education, the Southern Regional Education Board, and the National Staff Development Council. The goal of the network leadership program is to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide resources to support and enhance the principal’s role as the instructional leader.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a clearinghouse and disseminate data-supported information related to enhanced student achievement, based on educational research and best practices.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Build the capacity to increase the quality of programs for preservice education for aspiring principals and inservice professional development for principals and principal leadership teams.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Support best teaching and research-based instructional practices through dissemination and modeling at the preservice and inservice levels for both teachers and principals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall coordinate through the network identified in subsection (1) to offer the program through multiple delivery systems, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approved school district training programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interactive technology-based instruction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional consortium service organizations pursuant to s. 1001.451.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State, regional, or local leadership academies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 63, ch. 2006-74.</History></Section>