<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1012.63" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Illness-in-line-of-duty leave.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any district school board employee shall be entitled to illness-in-line-of-duty leave when he or she has to be absent from his or her duties because of a personal injury received in the discharge of duty or because of illness from any contagious or infectious disease contracted in school work. The following requirements shall be observed:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DURATION OF LEAVE AND COMPENSATION.<EmDash />Leave of the district school board employee shall be authorized for a total of not to exceed 10 school days during any school year for illness contracted, or injury incurred, from the causes prescribed above. However, in the case of sickness or injury occurring under such circumstances as in the opinion of the district school board warrant it, additional emergency sick leave may be granted out of local funds for such term and under such conditions as the district school board deems proper. The district school board may carry insurance to safeguard the district school board against excessive payments during any year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CLAIMS.<EmDash />Any district school board employee who has any claim for compensation while absent because of illness contracted or injury incurred as prescribed herein shall file a claim in the manner prescribed in s. 1012.61(2)(b) within 5 working days following the employee’s return from such absence. The school board of the district in which such person is employed shall approve the claims and authorize the payment thereof if the district school board is satisfied that the claim correctly states the facts and that the claim is entitled to payment in accordance with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 739, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>