<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1012.315" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disqualification from employment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is ineligible for educator certification, and instructional personnel and school administrators, as defined in s. 1012.01, are ineligible for employment in any position that requires direct contact with students in a district school system, charter school, or private school that accepts scholarship students under s. 1002.39 or s. 1002.395, if the person, instructional personnel, or school administrator has been convicted of:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any felony offense prohibited under any of the following statutes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 393.135, relating to sexual misconduct with certain developmentally disabled clients and reporting of such sexual misconduct.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 394.4593, relating to sexual misconduct with certain mental health patients and reporting of such sexual misconduct.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 415.111, relating to adult abuse, neglect, or exploitation of aged persons or disabled adults.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 782.04, relating to murder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 782.07, relating to manslaughter, aggravated manslaughter of an elderly person or disabled adult, aggravated manslaughter of a child, or aggravated manslaughter of an officer, a firefighter, an emergency medical technician, or a paramedic.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.021, relating to aggravated assault.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.045, relating to aggravated battery.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.075, relating to battery on a detention or commitment facility staff member or a juvenile probation officer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 787.01, relating to kidnapping.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 787.02, relating to false imprisonment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 787.025, relating to luring or enticing a child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 787.04(2), relating to leading, taking, enticing, or removing a minor beyond the state limits, or concealing the location of a minor, with criminal intent pending custody proceedings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 787.04(3), relating to leading, taking, enticing, or removing a minor beyond the state limits, or concealing the location of a minor, with criminal intent pending dependency proceedings or proceedings concerning alleged abuse or neglect of a minor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 790.115(1), relating to exhibiting firearms or weapons at a school-sponsored event, on school property, or within 1,000 feet of a school.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 790.115(2)(b), relating to possessing an electric weapon or device, destructive device, or other weapon at a school-sponsored event or on school property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 794.011, relating to sexual battery.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 794.041, relating to sexual activity with or solicitation of a child by a person in familial or custodial authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 794.05, relating to unlawful sexual activity with certain minors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 794.08, relating to female genital mutilation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 796, relating to prostitution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 800, relating to lewdness and indecent exposure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 806.01, relating to arson.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 810.14, relating to voyeurism.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 810.145, relating to video voyeurism.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="y">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 812.014(6), relating to coordinating the commission of theft in excess of $3,000.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="z">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 812.0145, relating to theft from persons 65 years of age or older.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="aa">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 812.019, relating to dealing in stolen property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="bb">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 812.13, relating to robbery.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="cc">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 812.131, relating to robbery by sudden snatching.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="dd">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 812.133, relating to carjacking.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ee">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 812.135, relating to home-invasion robbery.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ff">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 817.563, relating to fraudulent sale of controlled substances.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="gg">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 825.102, relating to abuse, aggravated abuse, or neglect of an elderly person or disabled adult.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="hh">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 825.103, relating to exploitation of an elderly person or disabled adult.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ii">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 825.1025, relating to lewd or lascivious offenses committed upon or in the presence of an elderly person or disabled person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="jj">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 826.04, relating to incest.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="kk">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 827.03, relating to child abuse, aggravated child abuse, or neglect of a child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ll">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 827.04, relating to contributing to the delinquency or dependency of a child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="mm">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 827.071, relating to sexual performance by a child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="nn">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 843.01, relating to resisting arrest with violence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="oo">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 847, relating to obscenity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="pp">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 874.05, relating to causing, encouraging, soliciting, or recruiting another to join a criminal street gang.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="qq">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chapter 893, relating to drug abuse prevention and control, if the offense was a felony of the second degree or greater severity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="rr">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 916.1075, relating to sexual misconduct with certain forensic clients and reporting of such sexual misconduct.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ss">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 944.47, relating to introduction, removal, or possession of contraband at a correctional facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="tt">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 985.701, relating to sexual misconduct in juvenile justice programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="uu">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 985.711, relating to introduction, removal, or possession of contraband at a juvenile detention facility or commitment program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any misdemeanor offense prohibited under any of the following statutes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 784.03, relating to battery, if the victim of the offense was a minor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 787.025, relating to luring or enticing a child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any criminal act committed in another state or under federal law which, if committed in this state, constitutes an offense prohibited under any statute listed in subsection (1) or subsection (2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any delinquent act committed in this state or any delinquent or criminal act committed in another state or under federal law which, if committed in this state, qualifies an individual for inclusion on the Registered Juvenile Sex Offender List under s. 943.0435(1)(a)1.d.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 2008-108; s. 18, ch. 2010-24.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 20, ch. 2010-24, provides that “[t]he Department of Revenue is authorized and all conditions are deemed met, to adopt emergency rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54, Florida Statutes, to administer the provisions of this act. The emergency rules shall remain in effect for 6 months after the rules are adopted and the rules may be renewed during the pendency of procedures to adopt permanent rules addressing the subject of the emergency rules.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>