<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0383.309" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimum standards for birth centers; rules and enforcement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt and enforce rules to administer ss. 383.30-383.335 and part II of chapter 408, which rules shall include, but are not limited to, reasonable and fair minimum standards for ensuring that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient numbers and qualified types of personnel and occupational disciplines are available at all times to provide necessary and adequate patient care and safety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Infection control, housekeeping, sanitary conditions, disaster plan, and medical record procedures that will adequately protect patient care and provide safety are established and implemented.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed facilities are established, organized, and operated consistent with established programmatic standards.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may not establish any rule governing the design, construction, erection, alteration, modification, repair, or demolition of birth centers. It is the intent of the Legislature to preempt that function to the Florida Building Commission and the State Fire Marshal through adoption and maintenance of the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code. However, the agency shall provide technical assistance to the commission and the State Fire Marshal in updating the construction standards of the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code which govern birth centers. In addition, the agency may enforce the special-occupancy provisions of the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code which apply to birth centers in conducting any inspection authorized under this chapter or part II of chapter 408.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 23, 27, ch. 84-283; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 10, ch. 98-171; s. 19, ch. 2000-141; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372; s. 6, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>