<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0383.313" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Performance of laboratory and surgical services; use of anesthetic and chemical agents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LABORATORY SERVICES.<EmDash />A birth center may collect specimens for those tests that are requested under protocol. A birth center may perform simple laboratory tests, as defined by rule of the agency, and is exempt from the requirements of chapter 483, provided no more than five physicians are employed by the birth center and testing is conducted exclusively in connection with the diagnosis and treatment of clients of the birth center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SURGICAL SERVICES.<EmDash />Surgical procedures shall be limited to those normally performed during uncomplicated childbirths, such as episiotomies and repairs and shall not include operative obstetrics or caesarean sections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ADMINISTRATION OF ANALGESIA AND ANESTHESIA.<EmDash />General and conduction anesthesia may not be administered at a birth center. Systemic analgesia may be administered, and local anesthesia for pudendal block and episiotomy repair may be performed if procedures are outlined by the clinical staff and performed by personnel with statutory authority to do so.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTRAPARTAL USE OF CHEMICAL AGENTS.<EmDash />Labor may not be inhibited, stimulated, or augmented with chemical agents during the first or second stage of labor unless prescribed by personnel with statutory authority to do so and unless in connection with and prior to emergency transport.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 14, 15, 16, 27, ch. 84-283; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 13, ch. 98-171.</History></Section>