<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0383.33625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Stephanie Saboor Grieving Parents Act; disposition of fetus; notification; forms developed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be known by the popular name the “Stephanie Saboor Grieving Parents Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care practitioner licensed pursuant to chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 464, or chapter 467 having custody of fetal remains following a spontaneous fetal demise occurring after a gestation period of less than 20 completed weeks must notify the mother of her option to arrange for the burial or cremation of the fetal remains, as well as the procedures provided by general law. Notification may also include other options such as, but not limited to, a ceremony, a certificate, or common burial of the fetal remains.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall adopt rules to develop forms to be used for notifications and elections by the health care practitioner, and the health care practitioner shall provide the forms to the mother.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility licensed pursuant to chapter 383 or chapter 395 having custody of fetal remains following a spontaneous fetal demise occurring after a gestation period of less than 20 completed weeks must notify the mother of her option to arrange for the burial or cremation of the fetal remains, as well as the procedures provided by general law. Notification may also include other options such as, but not limited to, a ceremony, a certificate, or common burial of the fetal remains.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the mother chooses the option of using the procedures provided by general law, the facility or health care practitioner in custody of fetal remains shall follow the procedures set forth in general law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall adopt rules to develop forms to be used for notifications and elections by the facility, and the hospital shall provide the forms to the mother.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-52.</History></Section>