<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0383.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prenatally diagnosed conditions; patient to be provided information; definitions; information clearinghouse; advisory council.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Down syndrome” means a chromosomal disorder caused by an error in cell division which results in the presence of an extra whole or partial copy of chromosome 21.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Developmental disability” includes Down syndrome and other developmental disabilities defined by s. 393.063(9).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care provider” means a practitioner licensed or registered under chapter 458 or chapter 459 or an advanced registered nurse practitioner certified under chapter 464.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prenatally diagnosed condition” means an adverse fetal health condition identified by prenatal testing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prenatal test” or “prenatal testing” means a diagnostic procedure or screening procedure performed on a pregnant woman or her unborn offspring to obtain information about the offspring’s health or development.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a developmental disability is diagnosed based on the results of a prenatal test, the health care provider who ordered the prenatal test, or his or her designee, shall provide the patient with current information about the nature of the developmental disability, the accuracy of the prenatal test, and resources for obtaining relevant support services, including hotlines, resource centers, and information clearinghouses related to Down syndrome or other prenatally diagnosed developmental disabilities; support programs for parents and families; and developmental evaluation and intervention services under s. 391.303.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall establish on its Internet website a clearinghouse of information related to developmental disabilities concerning providers of supportive services, information hotlines specific to Down syndrome and other prenatally diagnosed developmental disabilities, resource centers, educational programs, other support programs for parents and families, and developmental evaluation and intervention services under s. 391.303. Such information shall be made available to health care providers for use in counseling pregnant women whose unborn children have been prenatally diagnosed with developmental disabilities.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established an advisory council within the Department of Health which consists of health care providers and caregivers who perform health care services for persons who have developmental disabilities, including Down syndrome and autism. This group shall consist of nine members as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members appointed by the Governor;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members appointed by the President of the Senate; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory council shall provide technical assistance to the Department of Health in the establishment of the information clearinghouse and give the department the benefit of the council members’ knowledge and experience relating to the needs of patients and families of patients with developmental disabilities and available support services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall elect a chairperson and a vice chairperson. The elected chairperson and vice chairperson shall serve in these roles until their terms of appointment on the council expire.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The advisory council shall meet quarterly to review this clearinghouse of information, and may meet more often at the call of the chairperson or as determined by a majority of members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council members shall be appointed to 4-year terms, except that, to provide for staggered terms, one initial appointee each from the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall be appointed to a 2-year term, one appointee each from these officials shall be appointed to a 3-year term, and the remaining initial appointees shall be appointed to 4-year terms. All subsequent appointments shall be for 4-year terms. A vacancy shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without compensation. Meetings of the council may be held in person, without reimbursement for travel expenses, or by teleconference or other electronic means.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall provide administrative support for the advisory council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 72, ch. 2012-184.</History>
</Section>