<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0383.216" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community-based prenatal and infant health care.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall cooperate with localities which wish to establish prenatal and infant health care coalitions, and shall acknowledge and incorporate, if appropriate, existing community children’s services organizations, pursuant to this section within the resources allocated. The purpose of this program is to establish a partnership among the private sector, the public sector, state government, local government, community alliances, and maternal and child health care providers, for the provision of coordinated community-based prenatal and infant health care. The prenatal and infant health care coalitions must work in a coordinated, nonduplicative manner with local health planning councils established pursuant to s. 408.033.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each prenatal and infant health care coalition shall develop, in coordination with the Department of Health, a plan which shall include at a minimum provision to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform community assessments, using the Planned Approach to Community Health (PATCH) process, to identify the local need for comprehensive preventive and primary prenatal and infant health care. These assessments shall be used to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the priority target groups for receipt of care.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine outcome performance objectives jointly with the department.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify potential local providers of services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the type of services required to serve the identified priority target groups.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify the unmet need for services for the identified priority target groups.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Design a prenatal and infant health care services delivery plan which is consistent with local community objectives and this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicit and select local service providers based on reliability and availability, and define the role of each in the services delivery plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the allocation of available federal, state, and local resources to prenatal and infant health care providers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review, monitor, and advise the department concerning the performance of the services delivery system, and make any necessary annual adjustments in the design of the delivery system, the provider composition, the targeting of services, and other factors necessary for achieving projected outcomes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Build broad-based community support.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervision of the prenatal and infant health care coalitions is the responsibility of the department. The department shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist in the formation and development of the coalitions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Define the core services package so that it is consistent with the prenatal and infant health care services delivery plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide data and technical assistance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assure implementation of a quality management system within the provider coalition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Define statewide, uniform eligibility and fee schedules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate provider performance based on outcome measures established by the prenatal and infant health care coalition and the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In those communities which do not elect to establish a prenatal and infant health care coalition, the Department of Health is responsible for all of the functions delegated to the coalitions in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The membership of each prenatal and infant health care coalition shall represent health care providers, the recipient community, and the community at large; shall represent the racial, ethnic, and gender composition of the community; and shall include at least the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consumers of family planning, primary care, or prenatal care services, at least two of whom are low-income or Medicaid eligible.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care providers, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County health departments.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Migrant and community health centers.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospitals.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local medical societies.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local health planning organizations.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local health advocacy interest groups and community organizations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">County and municipal governments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social service organizations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local education communities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prenatal and infant health care coalitions may be established for single counties or for services delivery catchment areas. A prenatal and infant health care coalition shall be initiated at the local level on a voluntary basis. Once a coalition has been organized locally and includes the membership specified in subsection (5), the coalition must submit a list of its members to the State Surgeon General to carry out the responsibilities outlined in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 1992, the Department of Health shall provide up to $150,000 to each prenatal and infant health care coalition that petitions for recognition, meets the membership criteria, demonstrates the commitment of all the designated members to participate in the coalition, and provides a local cash or in-kind contribution match of 25 percent of the costs of the coalition. An in-kind contribution match may be in the form of staff time, office facilities, or supplies or other materials necessary for the functioning of the coalition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local prenatal and infant health care coalitions may hire staff or contract for independent staffing and support to enable them to carry out the objectives of this section. Staff shall have knowledge and expertise in community health and related resources and planning, grant writing, public information and communication techniques, organizational development, and data compilation and analysis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local prenatal and infant health care coalitions shall incorporate as not-for-profit corporations for the purpose of seeking and receiving grants from federal, state, and local government and other contributors. However, a coalition need not be designated as a tax-exempt organization under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall adopt rules necessary to administer this section, including rules defining acceptable “in-kind” contributions and rules providing definitions of terms, coalition responsibilities, coalition operations and standards, and conditions for establishing and approving a coalition. A coalition may not be a direct provider of prenatal and infant-care services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 91-282; s. 69, ch. 95-143; s. 62, ch. 97-101; s. 20, ch. 2000-242; s. 38, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>