<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0383.013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prenatal care.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a statewide prenatal care program for low-income pregnant women, which includes early, regular prenatal care by practitioners trained in prenatal care and delivery.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a risk factor analysis to identify women at risk for a preterm birth, or other high-risk conditions, and provide education regarding maintaining healthy birth conditions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitor the availability and accessibility of prenatal care services and the development of special outreach programs for medically underserved and rural areas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish by rule the eligibility criteria for prenatal care for indigent pregnant women when state funds are used for prenatal care.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop guidelines for expediting the provision of prenatal care for eligible women and monitor the implementation of the guidelines to determine the need for further action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expand, to the extent possible, training of state and local health providers in programs and practices pertaining to improved pregnancy outcomes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide regional perinatal intensive care satellite clinics to deliver Level III obstetric outpatient services to women diagnosed as being high risk, which includes an interdisciplinary team to deliver specialized high-risk obstetric care. The provision of satellite clinics is subject to the availability of moneys and the limitations established by the General Appropriations Act or chapter 216.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-379; s. 24, ch. 91-282; s. 55, ch. 97-101.</History></Section>