<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0383.307" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration of birth center.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each birth center shall have a governing body which is responsible for the overall operation and maintenance of the birth center.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body shall develop and display a table of organization which shows the structure of the birth center and identifies the governing body, the birth center director, the clinical director, the clinical staff, and the medical consultant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body shall develop and make available to staff, clinicians, consultants, and licensing authorities a manual which documents policies, procedures, and protocols, including the roles and responsibilities of all personnel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be an adequate number of licensed personnel to provide clinical services needed by mothers and newborns and a sufficient number of qualified personnel to provide services for families and to maintain the birth center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All clinical staff members and consultants shall hold current licenses from this state to practice their respective disciplines.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical staff members and consultants shall adopt bylaws which are subject to the approval of the governing body and which shall include recommendations for clinical staff or consultation appointments, delineation of clinical privileges, and the organization of the clinical staff.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 7, 27, ch. 84-283; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 48, ch. 99-397.</History></Section>