<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0516.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigations and complaints.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall, at intermittent periods, make such investigations and examinations of any licensee or other person as it deems necessary to determine compliance with this chapter. For such purposes, the office may examine the books, accounts, records, and other documents or matters of any licensee or other person and compel the production of all relevant books, records, and other documents and materials relative to an examination or investigation. Examinations of a licensee may not be made more often than once a year unless the office has reason to believe the licensee is not complying with this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall conduct all examinations at a convenient location in this state unless the office determines that it is more effective or cost-efficient to perform an examination at the licensee’s out-of-state location. For an examination performed at the licensee’s out-of-state location, the licensee shall pay the travel expense and per diem subsistence at the rate provided by law for up to thirty 8-hour days per year for each examiner who participates in such an examination. However, if the examination involves or reveals possible fraudulent conduct of the licensee, the licensee shall pay the travel expenses and per diem subsistence provided by law, without limitation, for each participating examiner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has reason to believe that this chapter has been or will be violated may file a written complaint with the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 10177, 1925; CGL 4008; s. 4, ch. 20728, 1941; s. 6, ch. 57-201; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 73-192; s. 1, ch. 77-356; s. 2, ch. 81-299; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 8, 16, 17, ch. 88-342; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 2, ch. 94-108; s. 4, ch. 99-164; s. 575, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>