<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0516.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consumer finance borrower” or “borrower” means a person who has incurred either direct or contingent liability to repay a consumer finance loan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consumer finance loan” means a loan of money, credit, goods, or choses in action, including, except as otherwise specifically indicated, provision of a line of credit, in an amount or to a value of $25,000 or less for which the lender charges, contracts for, collects, or receives interest at a rate greater than 18 percent per annum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commission” means the Financial Services Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Office” means the Office of Financial Regulation of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Interest” means the cost of obtaining a consumer finance loan and includes any profit or advantage of any kind whatsoever that a lender may charge, contract for, collect, receive, or in anywise obtain, including by means of any collateral sale, purchase, or agreement, as a condition for a consumer finance loan. Charges specifically permitted by this chapter, including commissions received for insurance written as permitted by this chapter, shall not be deemed interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means a permit issued under this chapter to make and collect loans in accordance with this chapter at a single place of business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means a person to whom a license is issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Control person” means an individual, partnership, corporation, trust, or other organization that possesses the power, directly or indirectly, to direct the management or policies of a company, whether through ownership of securities, by contract, or otherwise. A person is presumed to control a company if, with respect to a particular company, that person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a director, general partner, or officer exercising executive responsibility or having similar status or functions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directly or indirectly may vote 10 percent or more of a class of a voting security or sell or direct the sale of 10 percent or more of a class of voting securities; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a partnership, may receive upon dissolution or has contributed 10 percent or more of the capital.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 10177, 1925; CGL 4016; s. 6, ch. 20728, 1941; s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; s. 1, ch. 57-201; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 193, ch. 71-377; s. 189, ch. 77-104; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 86-100; ss. 1, 16, 17, ch. 88-342; s. 1, ch. 90-104; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 569, ch. 2003-261; s. 24, ch. 2006-213.</History></Section>