<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0516.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Records to be kept by licensee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall keep and use in her or his business such books, accounts, and records in accordance with sound and accepted accounting practices to enable the office to determine whether such licensee is complying with the provisions of this chapter and with the rules lawfully made by the commission. Every licensee shall preserve such books, accounts, and records, including cards used in the card system, if any, for at least 2 years after making the final entry on any loan recorded therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee, operating two or more licensed places of business in this state, may maintain the books, accounts, and records of all such offices at any one of such offices, or at any other office maintained by such licensee, upon the filing of a written request with the office designating in the written request the office at which such records are maintained. However, the licensee shall make all books, accounts, and records available at a convenient location in this state upon request of the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may prescribe by rule the minimum information to be shown in the books, accounts, records, and documents of licensees for purposes of enabling the office to determine the licensee’s compliance with ss. 516.001-516.36. In addition, the commission may prescribe by rule the requirements for the destruction of books, accounts, records, and documents retained by the licensee after completion of the time period specified in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 10177, 1925; CGL 4009; s. 5, ch. 20728, 1941; s. 7, ch. 57-201; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 73-192; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 85-27; ss. 16, 17, ch. 88-342; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 94-108; s. 679, ch. 97-103; s. 5, ch. 99-164; s. 576, ch. 2003-261; s. 30, ch. 2006-213.</History></Section>