<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0542.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties for violation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any natural person who violates any of the provisions of s. 542.18 or s. 542.19 shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $100,000. Any other person who violates any of the provisions of s. 542.18 or s. 542.19 shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $1 million.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly violates any of the provisions of s. 542.18 or s. 542.19, or who knowingly aids in or advises such violation, is guilty of a felony, punishable by a fine not exceeding $1 million if a corporation, or, if any other person, $100,000 or imprisonment not exceeding 3 years, or by both said punishments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement of trial seeking civil penalties in any action under this section shall bar any subsequent criminal prosecution against the same person for violation of s. 542.18 or s. 542.19, based upon the same acts. The commencement of trial in a criminal prosecution for violation of s. 542.18 or s. 542.19 shall bar any subsequent action against the same person for recovery of civil penalties under this section based upon the same acts, but shall not bar a subsequent suit for damages or injunctive relief under ss. 542.22 and 542.23.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No action under this section or s. 542.23 shall be commenced by the Attorney General against any person who, at the time, is a defendant in a suit filed by the United States for violation or alleged violation of the federal antitrust laws involving substantially the same subject matter and seeking substantially the same relief.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 80-28.</History></Section>