<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0267.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">The Grove Advisory Council; creation; membership; purposes.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Call/Collins House, commonly known as “The Grove,” located in Tallahassee, Leon County, shall be utilized as a house museum of history for the educational benefit of the citizens of this state. The utilization of The Grove as a museum of history shall emphasize the lives and accomplishments of The Grove’s first owner, Richard Keith Call, Florida’s last Territorial Governor, and LeRoy Collins, Florida’s 33rd Governor, who, with his wife, Mary Call Darby Collins, were the last owners of The Grove. The faithful restoration and maintenance of The Grove undertaken by LeRoy Collins and Mary Call Darby Collins during the nearly six decades of Collins family ownership and stewardship which has preserved the original plan of construction and design of The Grove shall be continued as provided for in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created within the Department of State The Grove Advisory Council for the purpose of advising the Division of Historical Resources on the operation, maintenance, preservation, and protection of the Call/Collins House, commonly known as “The Grove,” its grounds, cemetery, and all structures thereon; the furniture and furnishings located therein; any changes in the architecture, structure, furnishings, or landscaping deemed necessary or desirable by the council; and the design and development of interpretive programs and exhibits in connection therewith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Grove Advisory Council shall be composed of eight members, as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five members shall be private citizens appointed by the Secretary of State.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be the Secretary of Management Services or his or her designee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member shall be the director of the Division of Historical Resources of the Department of State.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least one member shall be a direct descendant of Mary Call Darby Collins appointed by the Secretary of State with the advice of the oldest living generation of lineal descendants of Mary Call Darby Collins.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Of the citizen members, at least one member shall have professional curatorial and museum expertise, one member shall have professional architectural expertise in the preservation of historic buildings, and one member shall have professional landscape expertise. The five citizen members of the council appointed by the Secretary of State and the member of the council who is a direct descendant of Mary Call Darby Collins appointed by the Secretary of State shall be appointed for staggered 4-year terms. The Secretary of State shall fill the remainder of unexpired terms for the five citizen members of the council and the member of the council who is a direct descendant of Mary Call Darby Collins.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall annually elect a chair from among the five citizen members of the council appointed by the Secretary of State and the member of the council who is a direct descendant of Mary Call Darby Collins appointed by the Secretary of State. The chair shall serve for a term of 1 year. Meetings of the council shall be held at the call of the chair, at the request of a majority of its membership, at the request of the Secretary of State, or at such times as may be prescribed by rules of the council. The council shall meet at least twice annually. A majority of the council shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall obtain clerical, expert, technical, or other services from the Division of Historical Resources. The Department of Management Services shall provide reasonable assistance to the Department of State in carrying out the purposes of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council shall serve without compensation or honorarium but shall be entitled to receive reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061. All expenses of the council shall be paid from appropriations to be made by the Legislature to the Department of State. All vouchers shall be approved by the Division of Historical Resources before being submitted to the Chief Financial Officer for payment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Historical Resources, with the advice and assistance of the council, shall maintain the structure, style, character, and landscaping of The Grove, its grounds, its private family cemetery, and all structures thereon consistent with the character, plan, and design of The Grove at the time the state takes physical possession of The Grove and its surrounding property from Mary Call Darby Collins. It shall preserve and protect the antique furnishings and other articles of furniture, fixtures, and decorative objects and articles used or displayed in the premises.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Historical Resources shall catalog and maintain a descriptive, photographic inventory of the furnishings, fixtures, and decorative objects and articles used or displayed in the premises.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Historical Resources may receive, on behalf of the state, contributions, bequests, and gifts of money, furniture, works of art, memorabilia, or other property consistent with the use of The Grove as described in this section. Title to all property which is received in this manner shall vest in the state and shall be held in trust by the Division of Historical Resources solely to further the purposes of this section. No furniture, furnishings, fixtures, or decorative objects acquired from the Collins family or any of its members shall be used for any purpose except as a permanent part of The Grove’s furniture, furnishings, fixtures, or decorative objects, and any such item not so utilized shall forthwith revert to the Collins family member or members from whom it was acquired. No gifts, contributions, or bequests shall be accepted for The Grove without the advice and recommendation of the council.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Historical Resources shall adopt rules governing the maintenance and use of The Grove; the selection, acquisition, and disposition of furnishings and decorations for the premises; and the acceptance of gifts, contributions, bequests, or loans of property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 97-305; s. 24, ch. 99-399; s. 284, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>