<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0267.031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Division of Historical Resources; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement provisions of this chapter conferring duties upon it.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may make and enter into all contracts and agreements with other agencies, organizations, associations, corporations and individuals, or federal agencies as it may determine are necessary, expedient, or incidental to the performance of its duties or the execution of its powers under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may accept gifts, grants, bequests, loans, and endowments for purposes not inconsistent with its responsibilities under this chapter. The division may also establish an endowment that is consistent with the responsibilities of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All law enforcement agencies and offices are authorized and directed to assist the division in carrying out its duties under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the responsibility of the division to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with federal and state agencies, local governments, and private organizations and individuals to direct and conduct a comprehensive statewide survey of historic resources and to maintain an inventory of such resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a comprehensive statewide historic preservation plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identify and nominate through the State Historic Preservation Officer eligible properties to the National Register of Historic Places and otherwise administer applications for listing historic properties in the National Register.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with federal and state agencies, local governments, and organizations and individuals to ensure that historic resources are taken into consideration at all levels of planning and development.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and assist, as appropriate, federal and state agencies and local governments in carrying out their historic preservation responsibilities and programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide public information, education, and technical assistance relating to historic preservation programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate with local governments and organizations and individuals in the development of local historic preservation programs, including the Main Street Program of the National Trust for Historic Preservation, or any similar programs that may be developed by the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Carry out on behalf of the state the programs of the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, as amended, and to establish, maintain, and administer a state historic preservation program meeting the requirements of an approved program and fulfilling the responsibilities of state historic preservation programs as provided in s. 101(b) of that act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Take such other actions necessary or appropriate to locate, acquire, protect, preserve, operate, interpret, and promote the location, acquisition, protection, preservation, operation, and interpretation of historic resources to foster an appreciation of Florida history and culture. Prior to the acquisition, preservation, interpretation, or operation of a historic property by a state agency, the division shall be provided a reasonable opportunity to review and comment on the proposed undertaking and shall determine that there exists historical authenticity and a feasible means of providing for the preservation, interpretation, and operation of such property. Expenditures by the division to protect or preserve historic properties leased by the division from the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund may be exempt from the competitive bid requirements of chapters 255 and 287.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cooperate and coordinate with the Division of Recreation and Parks of the Department of Environmental Protection in the operation and management of historic properties or resources subject to review under s. 267.061(2) by the Division of Historical Resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish professional standards for the preservation, exclusive of acquisition, of historic resources in state ownership or control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish guidelines for state agency responsibilities under s. 267.061(2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and maintain a central inventory of historic properties for the state which shall consist of all such properties as may be reported to the division. This inventory shall be known as the Florida Master Site File.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protect and administer historical resources abandoned on state-owned lands or on state-owned sovereignty submerged lands. The division may issue permits for survey and exploration activities to identify historical resources and may issue permits for excavation and salvage activities to recover historical resources. The division may issue permits for archaeological excavation for scientific or educational purposes on state-owned lands or on state-owned sovereignty submerged lands. The division may also issue permits for exploration and salvage of historic shipwreck sites by commercial salvors on state-owned sovereignty submerged lands. The division shall adopt rules to administer the issuance of permits for all such activities. In addition, the division shall adopt rules to administer the transfer of objects recovered by commercial salvors under permit in exchange for recovery services provided to the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advise and assist, as appropriate, federal and state agencies, local governments, and organizations and individuals in the recognition, protection, and preservation of the archaeological sites and artifacts of this state, directly and through a memorandum of agreement with a network of public archaeology centers as described in s. 267.145.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may enter into a memorandum of agreement with the University of West Florida to coordinate the establishment and operation of a network of regional public archaeology centers to provide public outreach and assistance to local governments in identifying, evaluating, developing, and preserving the archaeology in their local areas and in assisting the division in its archaeological responsibilities as outlined in this chapter and the memorandum of agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall employ a State Archaeologist, and such other archaeologists as deemed necessary, who shall possess such qualifications as the division may prescribe. The State Archaeologist shall serve at the pleasure of the division director and shall have his or her duties prescribed by the division director.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall employ a State Historic Preservation Officer, qualified by special training or experience in the field of historic preservation, and such other specialists in the field of historic preservation as deemed necessary, who shall possess such qualifications as the division may prescribe. The State Historic Preservation Officer shall be designated as such by the Governor, upon the recommendation of the Secretary of State, and shall serve at the pleasure of the Secretary of State. The State Historic Preservation Officer shall conduct relations with representatives of the Federal Government and the respective states concerning matters of historic preservation, and shall perform such other duties as prescribed by the Secretary of State.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 67-50; ss. 10, 25, 27, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 73, ch. 71-377; s. 1, ch. 73-280; s. 4, ch. 78-323; s. 1, ch. 81-173; s. 11, ch. 83-85; s. 130, ch. 83-217; s. 44, ch. 86-163; s. 54, ch. 98-200; s. 10, ch. 2001-75; s. 3, ch. 2001-199; s. 1, ch. 2004-91; s. 13, ch. 2005-207; s. 2, ch. 2008-141.</History></Section>