<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0267.0731" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Great Floridians Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall establish and administer a program, to be entitled the Great Floridians Program, which shall be designed to recognize and record the achievements of Floridians, living and deceased, who have made major contributions to the progress and welfare of this state.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall nominate present or former citizens of this state, living or deceased, who during their lives have made major contributions to the progress of the nation or this state and its citizens. Nominations shall be submitted to the Secretary of State who shall select from those nominated not less than two persons each year who shall be honored with the designation “Great Floridian,” provided no person whose contributions have been through elected or appointed public service shall be selected while holding any such office.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enhance public participation and involvement in the identification of any person worthy of being nominated as a Great Floridian, the division shall seek advice and assistance from persons qualified through the demonstration of special interest, experience, or education in the dissemination of knowledge about the state’s history.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually, the division shall convene an ad hoc committee composed of representatives of the Governor, each member of the Florida Cabinet, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Secretary of State. This committee shall meet at least twice. The committee shall nominate not fewer than two persons whose names shall be submitted to the Secretary of State with the recommendation that they be honored with the designation “Great Floridian.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon designation of a person as a Great Floridian by the Secretary of State, the division shall undertake appropriate activities intended to achieve wide public knowledge of the person designated.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may seek to initiate production of a film or videotape depicting the life and contributions of the designee to this state and to the nation. If technology surpasses the use of film or videotape, another medium of equal quality may be used.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State shall be the repository of the original negative, the original master tape, and all cuttings, of any film or videotape produced under the authority of this paragraph. The division also may exercise the right of trademark over the terms “Great Floridian” or “Great Floridians” pursuant to s. 286.031.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall arrange for the distribution of copies of all films to the general public, public television stations, educational institutions, and others and may establish a reasonable charge to recover costs associated with production and to provide a source of revenue to assist with reproduction, marketing, and distribution of Great Floridians films. Proceeds from such charges shall be deposited into the Historical Resources Operating Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deceased persons designated as Great Floridians typically shall be recognized by markers affixed to properties significantly associated with the major contributions of the designee. Such markers shall be erected pursuant to the provisions of s. 267.074.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-305; s. 35, ch. 2000-258; s. 10, ch. 2001-199; s. 17, ch. 2005-207; s. 11, ch. 2008-199.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 267.072(1)(d).</Text></Note></Section>