<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0267.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Citizen support organizations; use of state administrative services and property; audit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CITIZEN SUPPORT ORGANIZATIONS.<EmDash />The division may support the establishment of citizen support organizations to provide assistance, funding, and promotional support for the archaeology, museum, folklife, and historic preservation programs of the division. For the purposes of this section, a “citizen support organization” shall mean an organization which is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida corporation not for profit incorporated under the provisions of chapter 617 and approved by the Department of State;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organized and operated to conduct programs and activities; raise funds; request and receive grants, gifts, and bequests of money; acquire, receive, hold, invest, and administer, in its own name, securities, funds, objects of value, or other property, real or personal; and make expenditures to or for the direct or indirect benefit of the division or individual program units of the division;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determined by the division to be consistent with the goals of the division and in the best interests of the state; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approved in writing by the division to operate for the direct or indirect benefit of the division; such approval shall be given in a letter of agreement from the division.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">USE OF ADMINISTRATIVE SERVICES AND PROPERTY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may fix and collect charges for the rental of facilities and properties managed by the division and may permit, without charge, appropriate use of administrative services, property, and facilities of the division by a citizen support organization, subject to the provisions of this section. Such use must be directly in keeping with the approved purposes of the citizen support organization and may not be made at times or places that would unreasonably interfere with opportunities for the general public to use such facilities for established purposes. Any moneys received from rentals of facilities and properties managed by the division may be held in the operating trust fund of the division or in a separate depository account in the name of the citizen support organization and subject to the provisions of the letter of agreement with the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may prescribe by rule any condition with which a citizen support organization shall comply in order to use division administrative services, property, or facilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall not permit the use of any administrative services, property, or facilities of the state by a citizen support organization which does not provide equal membership and employment opportunities to all persons regardless of race, color, religion, sex, age, or national origin.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL AUDIT.<EmDash />Each citizen support organization shall provide for an annual financial audit in accordance with s. 215.981. The identity of donors who desire to remain anonymous shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1), and that anonymity shall be maintained in the auditor’s report.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 62, ch. 86-163; s. 6, ch. 89-55; s. 99, ch. 90-360; s. 127, ch. 96-406; s. 3, ch. 98-337; s. 90, ch. 2001-266; s. 9, ch. 2003-401.</History></Section>