<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0267.173" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Historic preservation in West Florida; goals; contracts for historic preservation; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the goal of the state to continue to ensure long-term preservation and interpretation of state-owned historic properties while facilitating an educational program at the University of West Florida that will be responsive to the state’s needs for professionals in historic preservation, archaeology, cultural resource management, and museum administration and will help meet needs of West Florida communities through educational internships and practicums.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon agreement by all parties to the contracts for the management of the various state-owned properties managed by the Historic Pensacola Preservation Board of Trustees prior to July 1, 2001, all existing management contracts shall be rescinded upon execution of a contract between the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund and the University of West Florida for the management of those properties. The University of West Florida shall provide for the management of these state-owned properties and may contract for such management with its direct-support organization as described in s. 267.1732. Any contract for the management of the properties shall provide that the University of West Florida or its direct-support organization shall use all proceeds derived from the management of the state-owned properties for the purposes of advancing historic preservation, historic preservation research, and historic preservation education.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund may transfer ownership and responsibility to any artifacts, documents, equipment, and other forms of tangible personal property to the University of West Florida to assist the university in the transition of the management of the state-owned properties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The University of West Florida is the governing body for the management and maintenance of state-owned properties contracted by this section and shall exercise those powers provided through the contract with the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund as well as performing all lawful acts necessary, convenient, and incident to the effectuating of the contract, its management and function, and the purposes under this section and s. 267.1732. The University of West Florida may contract with its direct-support organization described in s. 267.1732 to perform all acts that are lawful and permitted for not-for-profit corporations under chapter 617 in assisting the university in carrying out its responsibilities for historic preservation, historic preservation research, and historic preservation education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university or its direct-support organization, if permitted in its contract with the university, shall have the power to engage in any lawful business or activity to establish, maintain, and operate the state-owned facilities and properties governed by this section, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The renting or leasing for revenue of any land, improved or restored real estate, or personal property directly related to carrying out the purposes for historic preservation, historic preservation research, and historic preservation education under terms and conditions of the contract with the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund and deemed by the university to be in the best interest of the state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selling of craft products created through the operation and demonstration of historical museums, craft shops, and other facilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited selling of merchandise relating to Florida history and archaeology.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university or its direct-support organization, if permitted in the contract with the university, shall have the authority to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements to accept credit card payments as compensation, and establish accounts in credit card banks for the deposit of credit card sales invoices.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fix and collect charges for admission to any of the state-owned facilities governed by this section.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permit the acceptance of tour vouchers issued by tour organizations or travel agents for payment of admissions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and enforce reasonable rules, regulations, or policies to govern the conduct of the visiting public.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 287.057, the University of West Florida or its direct-support organization may enter into contracts or agreements with or without competitive bidding, in its discretion, for the protection, enhancement, or preservation of historic properties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 273.055, the University of West Florida may exchange, sell, or otherwise transfer any artifact, document, equipment and other form of tangible personal property if its direct-support organization recommends such exchange, sale, or transfer to the president of the university and if it is determined that the object is no longer appropriate for the purpose of advancing historic preservation. However, any artifact, document, or other form of tangible personal property that has intrinsic historical or archaeological value relating to the history, government, or culture of the state may not be exchanged, sold, or otherwise transferred without prior authorization from the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the University of West Florida and its direct-support organization are eligible to match state funds in the University Major Gifts Program established pursuant to s. 1011.94 and in the Alec P. Courtelis University Facility Enhancement Challenge Grant Program established pursuant to s. 1013.79.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2001-199; s. 932, ch. 2002-387; s. 21, ch. 2003-1; s. 20, ch. 2005-207; s. 4, ch. 2007-18; s. 3, ch. 2008-141; s. 1, ch. 2008-186.</History></Section>