<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0267.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Historical Resources of the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means any state, county, or municipal officer, department, division, board, bureau, commission, or other separate unit of government created or established by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Historic property” or “historic resource” means any prehistoric or historic district, site, building, object, or other real or personal property of historical, architectural, or archaeological value, and folklife resources. These properties or resources may include, but are not limited to, monuments, memorials, Indian habitations, ceremonial sites, abandoned settlements, sunken or abandoned ships, engineering works, treasure trove, artifacts, or other objects with intrinsic historical or archaeological value, or any part thereof, relating to the history, government, and culture of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preservation” or “historic preservation” means the identification, evaluation, recordation, documentation, analysis, recovery, interpretation, curation, acquisition, protection, management, rehabilitation, restoration, stabilization, maintenance, or reconstruction of historic properties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“National Register of Historic Places” means the list of historic properties significant in American history, architecture, archaeology, engineering, and culture, maintained by the Secretary of the Interior, as established by the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Folklife” means the traditional expressive culture shared within the various groups in Florida: familial, ethnic, occupational, religious, and regional. Expressive culture includes a wide range of creative and symbolic forms such as custom, belief, technical skill, language, literature, art, architecture, music, play, dance, drama, ritual, pageantry, and handicraft, which forms are generally learned orally, by imitation, or in performance and are maintained or perpetuated without formal instruction or institutional direction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Florida history museum” means a public or private nonprofit institution which is established permanently in this state for the purpose of promoting and encouraging knowledge and appreciation of Florida history through the collection, preservation, exhibition, and interpretation of artifacts and other historical properties related to Florida history and the primary role of which is to collect and care for artifacts and other objects of intrinsic historical or archaeological value and exhibit them regularly through a facility or facilities owned or operated by the institution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Official Florida Historical Marker” means any marker, plaque, or similar device awarded, approved, or administered by the Division of Historical Resources for the purpose of recognizing and informing the general public about historic properties, persons, events, and other topics relating to the history and culture of the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 67-50; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 72, ch. 71-377; s. 3, ch. 79-322; s. 1, ch. 81-124; s. 1, ch. 85-281; s. 43, ch. 86-163; s. 4, ch. 89-359; s. 2, ch. 94-190; s. 1, ch. 98-266.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (6) former s. 265.135.</Text></Note></Section>