<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0267.1735" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Historic preservation in St. Augustine; goals; contracts for historic preservation; powers and duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The goal for contracting with the University of Florida is to ensure long-term preservation and interpretation of state-owned historic properties in St. Augustine while facilitating an educational program at the University of Florida that will be responsive to the state’s needs for professionals in historic preservation, archaeology, cultural resource management, cultural tourism, and museum administration and will help meet needs of St. Augustine and the state through educational internships and practicums.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon agreement by all parties to the contracts for the management of the various state-owned properties presently subleased to and managed by the City of St. Augustine and by the University of Florida to assume the management of those properties, all existing management contracts shall be rescinded upon execution of a contract between the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund and the University of Florida for the management of those properties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract shall provide that the University of Florida shall use all proceeds derived from the management of these state-owned properties for the purpose of advancing historic preservation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund may transfer ownership and responsibility of any artifacts, documents, equipment, and other forms of tangible personal property to the University of Florida to assist the university in the transition of the management of the state-owned properties. All records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, or other funds associated with the state-owned properties shall be transferred to the University of Florida to be used for its historic preservation activities and responsibilities as provided in the contract with the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund. The transfer of segregated funds must be made in such a manner that the relation between program and revenue source as provided by law is retained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The University of Florida is the governing body for the management and maintenance of state-owned properties contracted by this section and shall exercise those powers delegated to it by contract as well as perform all lawful acts necessary, convenient, and incident to the effectuating of its function and purpose under this section and s. 267.1736. The University of Florida may contract with its direct-support organization described in s. 267.1736 to perform all acts that are lawful and permitted for not-for-profit corporations under chapter 617 in assisting the university in carrying out its historic preservation and historic preservation education responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university or its direct-support organization, if permitted in its contract with the university, shall have the power to engage in any lawful business or activity to establish, maintain, and operate the state-owned facilities and properties under contract with the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The renting or leasing for revenue of any land, improved or restored real estate, or personal property directly related to carrying out the purposes for historic preservation under terms and conditions of the contract with the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund and deemed by the university to be in the best interest of the state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The selling of craft products created through the operation and demonstration of historical museums, craft shops, and other facilities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited selling of merchandise relating to the historical and antiquarian period of St. Augustine and its surrounding territory and the historical period of East Florida from the Apalachicola River to the eastern boundaries of the state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The university or its direct-support organization, if permitted in its contract with the university, shall have the authority to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements to accept credit card payments as compensation and establish accounts in credit card banks for the deposit of credit card sales invoices.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fix and collect charges for admission to any of the state-owned facilities under contract with the Board of Trustees of the Internal Improvement Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permit the acceptance of tour vouchers issued by tour organizations or travel agents for payment of admissions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt and enforce reasonable rules to govern the conduct of the visiting public.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 287.057, the University of Florida or its direct-support organization may enter into contracts or agreements with or without competitive bidding, in its discretion, for the protection or preservation of historic properties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 273.055, the University of Florida may exchange, sell, or otherwise transfer any artifact, document, equipment, and other form of tangible personal property if its direct-support organization recommends such exchange, sale, or transfer to the president of the university and if it is determined that the object is no longer appropriate for the purpose of advancing historic preservation. However, any artifacts, documents, or other forms of tangible personal property that have intrinsic historical or archaeological value relating to the history, government, or culture of the state may not be exchanged, sold, or otherwise transferred without prior authorization from the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the University of Florida and its direct-support organization are eligible to match state funds in the University Major Gifts Program established in s. 1011.94.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2007-54.</History></Section>