<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0267.0625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Abrogation of offensive and derogatory geographic place names.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that certain place names for geographic sites are offensive or derogatory to the state’s people, history, and heritage. The state encourages tolerance and understanding between all of its residents and these geographic place names are a barrier to that effort. The Legislature finds that these offensive or derogatory place names should be replaced by names that reflect the state’s people, history, and heritage without resorting to offensive stereotypes, slurs, names, words, or phrases.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commission” means the Florida Historical Commission within the Department of State.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Geographic site” means a location or publicly owned structure in this state, and includes, but is not limited to, rivers and other navigable waters of the state, geographic features, and parks, or state or local roads, bridges, and publicly owned buildings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Offensive or derogatory place names” means a place name that is a racial, ethnic, or religious slur.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By October 1, 2004, each state agency or political subdivision that owns or manages public land, waters, or structures in this state shall identify any geographic sites under its jurisdiction which contain offensive or derogatory place names as defined in subsection (2) and shall file a report identifying those names with the division. A political subdivision shall also include a recommended replacement name for each identified offensive or derogatory place name.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall compile the reports required to be filed pursuant to this section and provide a copy to the commission. The commission shall advise the division in its review of recommended place names and in the development of alternative names to replace offensive or derogatory place names with place names that reflect the state’s diversity and culture.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By March 1, 2005, the division shall choose a new name for each geographic site reported by an agency or political subdivision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify each entity that has reported an offensive or derogatory place name pursuant to subsection (3) of the alternative name selected by the division; each agency or political subdivision shall ensure that whenever it updates a map or recorded plat, or replaces a sign, interpretive marker, or any other marker because of wear or vandalism, the new name is used.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the Department of Transportation, the Department of Economic Opportunity, the Department of Management Services, and any other entity that compiles information for or develops maps or markers for the state of the name change so that it may be reflected on subsequent editions of any maps, informational literature, or markers produced by those entities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place a formal request with the United States Board on Geographic Names to render a decision on each proposed name change so that each new name will be reflected on all maps of the United States Board on Geographic Names.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report to the Governor and the Legislature by no later than July 1, 2005, regarding implementation of the provisions of this section by the department. The report shall identify at least the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each offensive or derogatory place name identified by an agency or political subdivision.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The replacement name selected by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether any markers and maps have been changed to reflect the name changes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date that requests to change names were filed with the United States Board of Geographic Names and whether those changes have been made.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other relevant information that the department finds appropriate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-96; s. 122, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>