<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0414.157" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Diversion program for victims of domestic violence.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The diversion program for victims of domestic violence is intended to provide services and one-time payments to assist victims of domestic violence and their children in making the transition to independence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before finding an applicant family eligible for the diversion program created under this section, a determination must be made that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant family includes a pregnant woman or a parent with one or more minor children or a caretaker relative with one or more minor children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The services or one-time payment provided are not considered assistance under federal law or guidelines.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in ss. 414.075, 414.085, and 414.095, a family meeting the criteria of subsection (2) who is determined by the domestic violence program to be in need of services or one-time payment due to domestic violence shall be considered a needy family and is eligible under this section for services through a certified domestic violence shelter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One-time payments provided under this section shall not exceed $1,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receipt of services or a one-time payment under this section does not preclude eligibility for, or receipt of, other assistance or services under this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 99-241; s. 42, ch. 2000-165.</History></Section>