<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0414.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fraud.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails, by false statement, misrepresentation, impersonation, or other fraudulent means, to disclose a material fact used in making a determination as to such person’s qualification to receive public assistance under any state or federally funded assistance program;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails to disclose a change in circumstances in order to obtain or continue to receive any such public assistance to which he or she is not entitled or in an amount larger than that to which he or she is entitled; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aids and abets another person in the commission of any such act,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a crime and shall be punished as provided in subsection (5).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses, transfers, acquires, traffics, alters, forges, or possesses, or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempts to use, transfer, acquire, traffic, alter, forge, or possess, or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aids and abets another person in the use, transfer, acquisition, traffic, alteration, forgery, or possession of,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">a food assistance identification card, an authorization, including, but not limited to, an electronic authorization, for the expenditure of food assistance benefits, a certificate of eligibility for medical services, or a Medicaid identification card in any manner not authorized by law commits a crime and shall be punished as provided in subsection (5). </Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person having duties in the administration of a state or federally funded public assistance program or in the distribution of public assistance, or authorizations or identifications to obtain public assistance, under a state or federally funded public assistance program and who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulently misappropriates, attempts to misappropriate, or aids and abets in the misappropriation of, food assistance, an authorization for food assistance, a food assistance identification card, a certificate of eligibility for prescribed medicine, a Medicaid identification card, or public assistance from any other state or federally funded program with which he or she has been entrusted or of which he or she has gained possession by virtue of his or her position, or who knowingly fails to disclose any such fraudulent activity; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly misappropriates, attempts to misappropriate, or aids or abets in the misappropriation of, funds given in exchange for food assistance program benefits or for any form of food assistance benefits authorization,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a crime and shall be punished as provided in subsection (5).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly files, attempts to file, or aids and abets in the filing of, a claim for services to a recipient of public assistance under any state or federally funded public assistance program for services that were not rendered; knowingly files a false claim or a claim for nonauthorized items or services under such a program; or knowingly bills the recipient of public assistance under such a program, or his or her family, for an amount in excess of that provided for by law or regulation;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly fails to credit the state or its agent for payments received from social security, insurance, or other sources; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any way knowingly receives, attempts to receive, or aids and abets in the receipt of, unauthorized payment or other unauthorized public assistance or authorization or identification to obtain public assistance as provided herein,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a crime and shall be punished as provided in subsection (5).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the public assistance or identification wrongfully received, retained, misappropriated, sought, or used is less than an aggregate value of $200 in any 12 consecutive months, such person commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the public assistance or identification wrongfully received, retained, misappropriated, sought, or used is of an aggregate value of $200 or more in any 12 consecutive months, such person commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the value of a food assistance authorization benefit is the cash or exchange value unlawfully obtained by the fraudulent act committed in violation of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, “fraud” includes the introduction of fraudulent records into a computer system, the unauthorized use of computer facilities, the intentional or deliberate alteration or destruction of computerized information or files, and the stealing of financial instruments, data, and other assets.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person providing service for which compensation is paid under any state or federally funded public assistance program who solicits, requests, or receives, either actually or constructively, any payment or contribution through a payment, assessment, gift, devise, bequest or other means, whether directly or indirectly, from a recipient of public assistance from such public assistance program, or from the family of such a recipient, shall notify the Department of Children and Family Services, on a form provided by the department, of the amount of such payment or contribution and of such other information as specified by the department, within 10 days after the receipt of such payment or contribution or, if said payment or contribution is to become effective at some time in the future, within 10 days of the consummation of the agreement to make such payment or contribution. Failure to notify the department within the time prescribed is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repayment of public assistance benefits or services or return of authorization or identification wrongfully obtained is not a defense to, or ground for dismissal of, criminal charges brought under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The introduction into evidence of a paid state warrant made to the order of the defendant is prima facie evidence that the defendant did receive public assistance from the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The introduction into evidence of a transaction history generated by a Personal Identification Number (PIN) establishing a purchase or withdrawal by electronic benefit transfer is prima facie evidence that the identified recipient received public assistance from the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All records relating to investigations of public assistance fraud in the custody of the department and the Agency for Health Care Administration are available for examination by the Department of Financial Services pursuant to s. 414.411 and are admissible into evidence in proceedings brought under this section as business records within the meaning of s. 90.803(6).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall create an error-prone or fraud-prone case profile within its public assistance information system and shall screen each application for public assistance, including food assistance, Medicaid, and temporary cash assistance, against the profile to identify cases that have a potential for error or fraud. Each case so identified shall be subjected to preeligibility fraud screening.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-268; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-255; s. 354, ch. 71-136; s. 1, ch. 76-20; s. 2, ch. 92-125; s. 42, ch. 96-175; s. 218, ch. 97-101; s. 1037, ch. 97-103; s. 30, ch. 97-173; s. 9, ch. 99-333; s. 67, ch. 2000-153; s. 46, ch. 2000-165; s. 10, ch. 2010-144; s. 30, ch. 2010-209.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 409.325.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>