<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0414.115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited temporary cash assistance for children born to families receiving temporary cash assistance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide limited additional temporary cash assistance to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An existing temporary-cash-assistance case due to the birth of a child when the birth occurs more than 10 months after August 1, 1996; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A new temporary-cash-assistance case when the birth occurs more than 10 months after August 1, 1996, and the application or reapplication for temporary cash assistance.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of this subsection, “an existing temporary-cash-assistance case” means a case that is receiving temporary assistance on August 1, 1996, and, if it closes any time after August 1, 1996, is closed for less than 6 continuous months; “a new temporary-cash-assistance case” means a case that was not receiving benefits on August 1, 1996; “reapplication” means a new application by a parent or other caretaker relative who has previously received temporary cash assistance in a case that has been closed for 6 continuous months or more prior to the new application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) does not apply:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a program participant who is a victim of rape or incest if the victim files a police report on the rape or incest within 30 days after the incident;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a program participant who is confirmed by the Title IV-D child support agency as having been granted an exemption from participating in requirements for the enforcement of child support due to circumstances consistent with the conception of the child as a result of rape, incest, or sexual exploitation. A child for whom an exemption is claimed under this paragraph and for whom an application has been made for a good-cause exemption from the requirements of s. 414.095 shall receive temporary benefits until a determination is made on the application for a good-cause exemption from the requirements of s. 414.095;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To children who are the firstborn, including all children in the case of multiple birth, of minors included in a temporary cash assistance group who as minors become first-time parents;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a child when parental custody has been legally transferred; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a child who is no longer able to live with his or her parents as a result of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The death of the child’s parent or parents;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The incapacity of the child’s parent or parents as documented by a physician, such that the parent or parents are unable to care for the child;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legal transfer of the custody of the child to another individual;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incarceration of the child’s parent or parents, except that the child shall not receive temporary cash assistance if a parent is subsequently released and reunited with the child; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A situation in which the child’s parent’s or parents’ institutionalization is expected to be for an extended period, as defined by the department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child born subject to this section shall be considered a recipient of temporary cash assistance for all purposes, including Medicaid eligibility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the first child born to a recipient under subsection (1), the department shall provide temporary cash assistance equal to 50 percent of the maximum allowable amount for an individual. This provision does not apply to a child who is born into a family that does not include other children.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a second or subsequent child born to a recipient under subsection (1), the department shall provide no additional temporary cash assistance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 96-175; s. 1032, ch. 97-103; s. 11, ch. 97-173; s. 8, ch. 98-57.</History></Section>