<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0414.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibitions and restrictions with respect to food assistance program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COOPERATION WITH CHILD SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT AGENCY.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A parent or caretaker relative who receives temporary cash assistance or food assistance on behalf of a child under 18 years of age who has an absent parent is ineligible for food assistance unless the parent or caretaker relative cooperates with the state agency that administers the child support enforcement program in establishing the paternity of the child, if the child is born out of wedlock, and in obtaining support for the child or for the parent or caretaker relative and the child. This paragraph does not apply if the state agency that administers the food assistance program determines that the parent or caretaker relative has good cause for failing to cooperate. The Department of Revenue shall determine good cause for failure to cooperate if the Department of Children and Family Services obtains written authorization from the United States Department of Agriculture approving such arrangements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A putative or identified noncustodial parent of a child under 18 years of age is ineligible for food assistance if the parent fails to cooperate with the state agency that administers the child support enforcement program in establishing the paternity of the child, if the child is born out of wedlock, or fails to provide support for the child. This paragraph does not apply if the state agency that administers the child support enforcement program determines that the noncustodial parent has good cause for refusing to cooperate in establishing the paternity of the child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REDUCTION OR DENIAL OF TEMPORARY CASH ASSISTANCE.<EmDash />The food assistance allotment shall be reduced or terminated as otherwise provided in this chapter if cash assistance under the Temporary Cash Assistance Program is reduced or denied because an individual in the family fails to perform an action required under the program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DENIAL OF FOOD ASSISTANCE BENEFITS FOR RECEIPT OF MULTIPLE FOOD ASSISTANCE BENEFITS.<EmDash />An individual is ineligible to participate in the food assistance program individually, or as a member of any assistance group, for 10 years following a conviction in federal or state court of having made a fraudulent statement or representation with respect to the identity or place of residence of the individual in order to receive multiple benefits simultaneously under the food assistance program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DENIAL OF FOOD ASSISTANCE BENEFITS TO FLEEING FELONS.<EmDash />An individual is ineligible to participate in the food assistance program during any period when the individual is fleeing to avoid prosecution, custody, or confinement after committing a crime, attempting to commit a crime that is a felony under the laws of the place from which the individual flees or a high misdemeanor in the State of New Jersey, or violating a condition of probation or parole imposed under federal or state law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 96-175; s. 26, ch. 97-173; s. 34, ch. 98-397; s. 47, ch. 2001-158; s. 4, ch. 2005-61; s. 25, ch. 2010-209.</History>
</Section>