<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0859.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Provisions concerning poisons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person not a registered pharmacist to retail any poisons enumerated below: Arsenic and all its preparations, corrosive sublimate, white and red precipitate, biniodide of mercury, cyanide of potassium, hydrocyanic acid, strychnine, and all other poisonous vegetable alkaloids and their salts, and the essential oil of almonds, opium, and its preparations of opium containing less than two grains to the ounce, aconite, belladonna, colchicum, conium, nux vomica, henbane, savin, ergot, cotton root, cantharides, creosote, veratrum digitalis, and their pharmaceutical preparations, croton oil, chloroform, chloral hydrate, sulphate of zinc, mineral acids, carbolic and oxalic acids; and she or he shall label the box, vessel, or paper in which said poison is contained with the name of the article, the word “poison,” and the name and place of business of the seller.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall deliver or sell any poisons enumerated above unless upon due inquiry it be found that the purchaser is aware of its poisonous character and represents that it is to be used for a legitimate purpose. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the dispensing of poisons in not unusual quantities or doses upon the prescriptions of practitioners of medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of this section shall render the principal of said store guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.083. However, this section shall not apply to manufacturers making and selling at wholesale any of the above poisons. Each box, vessel, or paper in which said poison is contained shall be labeled with the name of the article, the word “poison,” and the name and place of business of the seller.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 3380, 1889; RS 822; GS 3606; RGS 5528; CGL 7694; s. 1081, ch. 71-136; s. 1386, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>