<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0282.605" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not apply to electronic information and information technology of the Department of Military Affairs or the Florida National Guard if the function, operation, or use of the information or technology involves intelligence activities or cryptologic activities related to national security, the command and control of military forces, equipment that is an integral part of a weapon or weapons system, or systems that are critical to the direct fulfillment of military or intelligence missions. Systems that are critical to the direct fulfillment of military or intelligence missions do not include a system that is used for routine administrative and business applications, including, but not limited to, payroll, finance, logistics, and personnel management applications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not apply to electronic information and information technology of a state agency if the function, operation, or use of the information or technology involves criminal intelligence activities. Such activities do not include information or technology that is used for routine administrative and business applications, including, but not limited to, payroll, finance, logistics, and personnel management applications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not apply to electronic information and information technology that is acquired by a contractor and that is incidental to the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part applies to competitive solicitations issued or new systems developed by a state agency on or after July 1, 2006.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 73, ch. 2006-227.</History></Section>