<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0282.709" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State agency law enforcement radio system and interoperability network.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may acquire and administer a statewide radio communications system to serve law enforcement units of state agencies, and to serve local law enforcement agencies through mutual aid channels.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, in conjunction with the Department of Law Enforcement and the Division of Emergency Management, establish policies, procedures, and standards to be incorporated into a comprehensive management plan for the use and operation of the statewide radio communications system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall bear the overall responsibility for the design, engineering, acquisition, and implementation of the statewide radio communications system and for ensuring the proper operation and maintenance of all common system equipment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may rent or lease space on any tower under its control and refuse to lease space on any tower at any site.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may rent, lease, or sublease ground space as necessary to locate equipment to support antennae on the towers. The costs for the use of such space shall be established by the department for each site if it is determined to be practicable and feasible to make space available.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may rent, lease, or sublease ground space on lands acquired by the department for the construction of privately owned or publicly owned towers. The department may, as a part of such rental, lease, or sublease agreement, require space on such towers for antennae as necessary for the construction and operation of the state agency law enforcement radio system or any other state need.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected by the department for rents, leases, and subleases under this subsection shall be deposited directly into the State Agency Law Enforcement Radio System Trust Fund established in subsection (3) and may be used by the department to construct, maintain, or support the system.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The positions necessary for the department to accomplish its duties under this subsection shall be established in the General Appropriations Act and funded by the Law Enforcement Radio Operating Trust Fund or other revenue sources.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall exercise its powers and duties under this part to plan, manage, and administer the mutual aid channels in the statewide radio communication system.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In implementing such powers and duties, the department shall consult and act in conjunction with the Department of Law Enforcement and the Division of Emergency Management, and shall manage and administer the mutual aid channels in a manner that reasonably addresses the needs and concerns of the involved law enforcement agencies and emergency response agencies and entities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may make the mutual aid channels available to federal agencies, state agencies, and agencies of the political subdivisions of the state for the purpose of public safety and domestic security.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may allow other state agencies to use the statewide radio communications system under terms and conditions established by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Joint Task Force on State Agency Law Enforcement Communications is created adjunct to the department to advise the department of member-agency needs relating to the planning, designing, and establishment of the statewide communication system.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Joint Task Force on State Agency Law Enforcement Communications shall consist of the following members:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation who shall be appointed by the secretary of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Division of Florida Highway Patrol of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles who shall be appointed by the executive director of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Department of Law Enforcement who shall be appointed by the executive director of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission who shall be appointed by the executive director of the commission.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Department of Corrections who shall be appointed by the secretary of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Division of State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services who shall be appointed by the State Fire Marshal.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the Department of Transportation who shall be appointed by the secretary of the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each appointed member of the joint task force shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing official. Any vacancy on the joint task force shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. A joint task force member may, upon notification to the chair before the beginning of any scheduled meeting, appoint an alternative to represent the member on the task force and vote on task force business in his or her absence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The joint task force shall elect a chair from among its members to serve a 1-year term. A vacancy in the chair of the joint task force must be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term by an election of the joint task force members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The joint task force shall meet as necessary, but at least quarterly, at the call of the chair and at the time and place designated by him or her.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The per diem and travel expenses incurred by a member of the joint task force in attending its meetings and in attending to its affairs shall be paid pursuant to s. 112.061, from funds budgeted to the state agency that the member represents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide technical support to the joint task force.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Agency Law Enforcement Radio System Trust Fund is established in the department and funded from surcharges collected under ss. 318.18, 320.0802, and 328.72. Upon appropriation, moneys in the trust fund may be used by the department to acquire by competitive procurement the equipment, software, and engineering, administrative, and maintenance services it needs to construct, operate, and maintain the statewide radio system. Moneys in the trust fund from surcharges shall be used to help fund the costs of the system. Upon completion of the system, moneys in the trust fund may also be used by the department for payment of the recurring maintenance costs of the system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Reference Number="1"/>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds from the State Agency Law Enforcement Radio System Trust Fund may be used by the department to fund mutual aid buildout maintenance and sustainment and the interoperability network created under subsection (4) as appropriated by law. This paragraph expires July 1, 2013.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may create and administer an interoperability network to enable interoperability between various radio communications technologies and to serve federal agencies, state agencies, and agencies of political subdivisions of the state for the purpose of public safety and domestic security.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, in conjunction with the Department of Law Enforcement and the Division of Emergency Management, exercise its powers and duties pursuant to this chapter to plan, manage, and administer the interoperability network. The office may:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into mutual aid agreements among federal agencies, state agencies, and political subdivisions of the state for the use of the interoperability network.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish the cost of maintenance and operation of the interoperability network and charge subscribing federal and local law enforcement agencies for access and use of the network. The department may not charge state law enforcement agencies identified in paragraph (2)(a) to use the network.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In consultation with the Department of Law Enforcement and the Division of Emergency Management, amend and enhance the statewide radio communications system as necessary to implement the interoperability network.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the Joint Task Force on State Agency Law Enforcement Communications, and in conjunction with the Department of Law Enforcement and the Division of Emergency Management, shall establish policies, procedures, and standards to incorporate into a comprehensive management plan for the use and operation of the interoperability network.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-144; s. 1, ch. 92-72; s. 224, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 30, ch. 94-218; s. 111, ch. 94-356; s. 860, ch. 95-148; s. 5, ch. 95-283; s. 1, ch. 96-312; s. 5, ch. 96-357; s. 10, ch. 96-388; s. 14, ch. 96-390; s. 6, ch. 98-251; s. 69, ch. 98-279; s. 81, ch. 99-245; s. 3, ch. 99-289; s. 37, ch. 99-399; s. 11, ch. 2000-164; s. 16, ch. 2001-261; s. 2, ch. 2003-153; s. 308, ch. 2003-261; s. 24, ch. 2009-80; s. 24, ch. 2011-47; s. 125, ch. 2011-142; s. 10, ch. 2012-88; s. 21, ch. 2012-119.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 21, ch. 2012-119, amended paragraph (3)(b) “[i]n order to implement Specific Appropriation 2890 of the 2012-2013 General Appropriation Act.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 282.1095.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>