<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd" Number="0282.34"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statewide e-mail service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statewide e-mail service that includes the delivery and support of e-mail, messaging, and calendaring capabilities is established as an enterprise information technology service as defined in s. 282.0041. The service shall be designed to meet the needs of all executive branch agencies and may also be used by nonstate agency entities. The primary goals of the service are to minimize the state investment required to establish, operate, and support the statewide service; reduce the cost of current e-mail operations and the number of duplicative e-mail systems; and eliminate the need for each state agency to maintain its own e-mail staff.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Southwood Shared Resource Center, a primary data center, shall be the provider of the statewide e-mail service for all state agencies. The center shall centrally host, manage, operate, and support the service, or outsource the hosting, management, operational, or support components of the service in order to achieve the primary goals identified in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Enterprise Information Technology, in cooperation and consultation with all state agencies, shall prepare and submit for approval by the Legislative Budget Commission at a meeting scheduled before June 30, 2011, a proposed plan for the migration of all state agencies to the statewide e-mail service. The plan for migration must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cost-benefit analysis that compares the total recurring and nonrecurring operating costs of the current agency e-mail systems, including monthly mailbox costs, staffing, licensing and maintenance costs, hardware, and other related e-mail product and service costs to the costs associated with the proposed statewide e-mail service. The analysis must also include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A comparison of the estimated total 7-year life-cycle cost of the current agency e-mail systems versus the feasibility of funding the migration and operation of the statewide e-mail service.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An estimate of recurring costs associated with the energy consumption of current agency e-mail equipment, and the basis for the estimate.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An identification of the overall cost savings resulting from state agencies migrating to the statewide e-mail service and decommissioning their agency e-mail systems.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proposed migration date for all state agencies to be migrated to the statewide e-mail service. The Agency for Enterprise Information Technology shall work with the Executive Office of the Governor to develop the schedule for migrating all state agencies to the statewide e-mail service except for the Department of Legal Affairs. The Department of Legal Affairs shall provide to the Agency for Enterprise Information Technology by June 1, 2011, a proposed migration date based upon its decision to participate in the statewide e-mail service and the identification of any issues that require resolution in order to migrate to the statewide e-mail service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A budget amendment, submitted pursuant to chapter 216, for adjustments to each agency’s approved operating budget necessary to transfer sufficient budget resources into the appropriate data processing category to support its statewide e-mail service costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A budget amendment, submitted pursuant to chapter 216, for adjustments to the Southwood Shared Resource Center approved operating budget to include adjustments in the number of authorized positions, salary budget and associated rate, necessary to implement the statewide e-mail service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contingent upon approval by the Legislative Budget Commission, the Southwood Shared Resource Center may contract for the provision of a statewide e-mail service. Executive branch agencies must be completely migrated to the statewide e-mail service based upon the migration date included in the proposed plan approved by the Legislative Budget Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding chapter 216, general revenue funds may be increased or decreased for each agency provided the net change to general revenue in total for all agencies is zero or less.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequent to the approval of the consolidated budget amendment to reflect budget adjustments necessary to migrate to the statewide e-mail service, an agency may make adjustments subject to s. 216.177, notwithstanding provisions in chapter 216 which may require such adjustments to be approved by the Legislative Budget Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No agency may initiate a new e-mail service or execute a new e-mail contract or amend a current e-mail contract, other than with the Southwood Shared Resource Center, for nonessential products or services unless the Legislative Budget Commission denies approval for the Southwood Shared Resource Center to enter into a contract for the statewide e-mail service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Enterprise Information Technology shall work with the Southwood Shared Resource Center to develop an implementation plan that identifies and describes the detailed processes and timelines for an agency’s migration to the statewide e-mail service based on the migration date approved by the Legislative Budget Commission. The agency may establish and coordinate workgroups consisting of agency e-mail management, information technology, budget, and administrative staff to assist the agency in the development of the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each executive branch agency shall provide all information necessary to develop the implementation plan, including, but not limited to, required mailbox features and the number of mailboxes that will require migration services. Each agency must also identify any known business, operational, or technical plans, limitations, or constraints that should be considered when developing the plan.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 2009-80; s. 6, ch. 2010-148; s. 11, ch. 2011-50; s. 124, ch. 2011-142.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 14, ch. 2011-50, provides that “[t]he Agency for Enterprise Information Technology, in coordination with the Southwood Shared Resource Center, shall provide a written status report to the Executive Office of the Governor and to the chairs of the legislative appropriations committees detailing the progress made by the agencies required to migrate to the statewide e-mail service by the required migration date. The status report must be provided every 6 months, beginning September 1, 2011, until implementation is complete.”</Text></Note></Section>