<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0282.602" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Accessible electronic information and information technology” means electronic information and information technology that conforms to the standards for accessible electronic information and information technology as set forth by s. 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended, and 29 U.S.C. s. 794(d), including the regulations set forth under 36 C.F.R. part 1194.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alternate methods” means a different means of providing information to people with disabilities, including product documentation. The term includes, but is not limited to, voice, facsimile, relay service, TTY, Internet posting, captioning, text-to-speech synthesis, and audio description.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electronic information and information technology” includes information technology and any equipment or interconnected system or subsystem of equipment that is used in creating, converting, or duplicating data or information. The term includes, but is not limited to, telecommunications products such as telephones, information kiosks and transaction machines, Internet websites, multimedia systems, and office equipment such as copiers and facsimile machines. The term does not include any equipment that contains embedded information technology that is an integral part of the product if the principal function of the technology is not the acquisition, storage, manipulation, management, movement, control, display, switching, interchange, transmission, or reception of data or information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Information technology” means any equipment or interconnected system or subsystem of equipment that is used in the automatic acquisition, storage, manipulation, management, movement, control, display, switching, interchange, transmission, or reception of data or information. The term includes computers, ancillary equipment, software, firmware and similar procedures, services, and support services, and related resources.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Undue burden” means significant difficulty or expense. In determining whether an action would result in an undue burden, a state agency shall consider all agency resources that are available to the program or component for which the product is being developed, procured, maintained, or used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State agency” means any agency of the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of state government.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 73, ch. 2006-227.</History></Section>