<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0946.517" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corporation records.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corporation records are public records; however, proprietary confidential business information shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. However, the Legislature, the Chief Financial Officer, and the Governor, pursuant to their oversight and auditing functions, shall have access to all proprietary confidential business information upon request and without subpoena and shall retain the confidentiality of information so received. “Proprietary confidential business information” means information regardless of form or characteristics, that is owned or controlled by the corporation; is intended to be and is treated by the corporation as private and the disclosure of the information would cause harm to the corporation’s business operations; has not been disclosed unless disclosed pursuant to a statutory provision, an order of a court or administrative body, a legislative proceeding pursuant to s. 5, Art. III of the State Constitution, or a private agreement that provides that the information may be released to the public; and, which is information regarding:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Internal auditing controls and reports of internal auditors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Matters reasonably encompassed in privileged attorney-client communications.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Security measures, systems, or procedures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning bids or other contractual data, banking records, and credit agreements, the disclosure of which would impair the efforts of the corporation to contract for goods or services on favorable terms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information relating to private contractual data, the disclosure of which would impair the competitive interest of the provider of the information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corporate officer, employee personnel, or inmate worker information unrelated to compensation, duties, qualifications, or responsibilities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-209; s. 4, ch. 87-286; s. 1, ch. 94-331; s. 450, ch. 96-406; s. 1934, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 946.19.</Text></Note></Section>