<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0946.516" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Corporation status report and annual financial audit report.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall submit to the Governor and the Legislature, on or before July 1 of each year, a report on the status of the correctional work programs, including, but not limited to, the proposed use of the profits from such programs, a breakdown of the amount of noninmate labor used, work subcontracted to other vendors, use of consultants, finished goods purchased for resale, and the number of inmates working in the correctional work programs at the time of such report. In addition, the corporation shall submit to the department, the Governor, the Legislature, and the Auditor General an annual financial audit report and such other information as may be requested by the Legislature, together with recommendations relating to provisions for reasonable tax incentives to private enterprises which employ inmates, parolees, or former inmates who have participated in correctional work programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall include, as a portion of its annual report, a report on postrelease job placement and the rate of subsequent contact with the correctional system for those inmates who have participated in the correctional work programs operated by the corporation and by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall have an annual financial audit of its accounts and records by an independent certified public accountant retained by it and paid from its funds. The Auditor General or the director of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability may, pursuant to his or her own authority or at the direction of the Joint Legislative Auditing Committee, conduct an audit of the corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall be governed by the generally accepted accounting principles as established by the Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB) in order to carry out the intent of s. 946.502(2) and (5).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-209; s. 4, ch. 87-286; s. 29, ch. 89-526; s. 8, ch. 96-270; s. 15, ch. 99-333; s. 9, ch. 2001-242.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 946.18.</Text></Note></Section>