<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0946.525" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Participation by the corporation in the state group health insurance and prescription drug programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of the corporation established under this part may apply for participation in the state group health insurance program authorized in s. 110.123 and the prescription drug coverage program authorized by s. 110.12315 by submitting an application along with a $500 nonrefundable fee to the Department of Management Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a prerequisite to the adoption of a resolution for participation in the state group health insurance and prescription drug coverage program, the corporation shall seek proposals to provide health insurance and prescription drug coverages which coverages are equivalent to those offered currently by the corporation and coverages equivalent to the state group health insurance and prescription drug coverage program. The corporation shall review and consider all responsive proposals prior to the adoption of any resolution for participation in the state group health insurance and prescription drug coverage program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Department of Management Services determines that the corporation is eligible to enroll, the corporation must agree to the following terms and conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minimum enrollment or contractual period will be 3 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation must pay to the Department of Management Services an initial administrative fee not less than $2.61 per enrollee per month, or such other amount established annually to fully reimburse the Department of Management Services for its costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Termination of participation of the corporation requires written notice 1 year before the termination date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If participation is terminated, the corporation may not reapply for participation for a period of 2 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall reimburse the state for 100 percent of its costs, including administrative costs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the corporation fails to make the payments required by this section to fully reimburse the state, the Department of Revenue or the Department of Financial Services shall, upon the request of the Department of Management Services, deduct the amount owed by the employer from any funds to be distributed by it to the corporation. The amounts so deducted shall be transferred to the Department of Management Services for further distribution to the trust funds in accordance with this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall furnish the Department of Management Services any information requested by the Department of Management Services which the Department of Management Services considers necessary to administer the state group health insurance program and the prescription drug program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of ss. 624.436-624.446 do not apply to the State Group Insurance Program or to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Management Services may adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 2001-242; s. 1936, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 17, ch. 2001-242, provides that “[t]his act shall take effect upon becoming a law, except that [s. 946.525] shall take effect only when the Department of Management Services receives the favorable letters requested by section 15. If the favorable letters are not received, [s. 946.525] shall not take effect.”</Text></Note></Section>