<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0946.511" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inmate labor to operate correctional work programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inmates shall be evaluated and identified during the reception process to determine basic literacy, employment skills, academic skills, vocational skills, and remedial and rehabilitative needs. The evaluation shall prescribe education, work, and work-training for each inmate. Assignment to programs shall be based on the evaluation and the length of time the inmate will be in the custody of the department. Assignment to programs shall be reviewed every 6 months to ensure proper placement based on bed space availability. Assignment of inmates shall be governed by the following objectives and priorities:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inmates shall be assigned to meet the needs of the work requirements of the Department of Corrections, including essential operational functions and revenue-generating contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inmates shall be assigned to correctional education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inmates shall be assigned to meet all other work requirements of the department, including remaining operational functions and nonrevenue-generating contracts.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">As used in this subsection, the term “revenue-generating contracts” includes contracts with the Department of Transportation, the corporation authorized to conduct the correctional work programs under this part, the corporation and private sector businesses operating programs authorized under s. 946.523, and federal, state, or local governmental entities or subdivisions authorized under s. 944.10(7).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall establish policies and procedures relating to the use of inmates in its correctional work program, which shall be submitted to the department for approval. Any policies and procedures in effect on the effective date of this act do not require approval.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-209; s. 4, ch. 87-286; s. 28, ch. 89-526; s. 2, ch. 91-298; s. 6, ch. 97-227; s. 7, ch. 2001-242.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 946.09.</Text></Note></Section>