<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0946.503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions to be used with respect to correctional work programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporation” means the private nonprofit corporation established pursuant to s. 946.504(1), or a private nonprofit corporation whose sole member is the private nonprofit corporation established pursuant to s. 946.504(1), and at least 51 percent of the board of which contains members of the board of directors of the private nonprofit corporation established pursuant to s. 946.504(1), to carry out this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Correctional work program” means any program presently a part of the prison industries program operated by the department or any other correctional work program carried on at any state correctional facility presently or in the future, but the term does not include any program authorized by s. 945.091 or s. 946.40.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Corrections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Facilities” means the buildings and land used in the operation of an industry program on state property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Inmate” means any person incarcerated within any state, county, municipal, or private correctional facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Private correctional facility” means a facility authorized by chapter 944 or chapter 957.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-209; s. 2, ch. 83-345; s. 2, ch. 84-280; ss. 4, 6, ch. 87-286; s. 3, ch. 96-270; s. 2, ch. 97-227; s. 4, ch. 2001-242.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 946.02.</Text></Note></Section>