<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0946.523" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prison industry enhancement (PIE) programs.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may operate or contract with the private sector for substantial involvement in a prison industry enhancement (PIE) program that includes, but is not limited to, contracts for the operation of a direct private sector business within a prison and the hiring of inmates. Any contract authorized by this subsection must be in compliance with federal law governing inmate work programs and must not result in the significant displacement of employed workers in the community. The purposes and objectives of this program are to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Increase the benefits to the general public by reimbursing the state for a portion of the costs of incarceration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide purposeful work for inmates.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Increase job skills.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide additional opportunities for rehabilitating inmates who are otherwise ineligible to work outside the prisons, such as maximum security inmates.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and establish new models for prison-based businesses that create jobs approximating conditions of private sector employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Draw upon the economic base of operations for deposit into the Crimes Compensation Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substantially involve the private sector and its capital, management skills, and expertise in the design, development, and operation of businesses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the financial basis for an inmate to contribute to the support of his or her family.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the payment of state and federal taxes on an inmate’s wages, which are paid at the rate of the prevailing or minimum wage rate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide savings for the inmate to have available for his or her use upon the inmate’s eventual release from prison.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, including s. 440.15(8), private sector employers shall provide workers’ compensation coverage to inmates who participate in prison industry enhancement (PIE) programs under subsection (1). However, inmates are not entitled to reemployment assistance benefits.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 99-260; s. 38, ch. 2003-412; s. 85, ch. 2012-30.</History>
</Section>