<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0946.502" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent with respect to operation of correctional work programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that a nonprofit corporation lease and manage the correctional work programs of the Department of Corrections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is further the intent of the Legislature that, once one such nonprofit corporation is organized, no other nonprofit corporation be organized for the purpose of carrying out this part. In carrying out this part, the corporation is not an “agency” within the meaning of s. 20.03(11).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is further the intent of the Legislature that the corporation shall lease all correctional work programs from the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is further the intent of the Legislature that the state shall have a continuing interest in assuring continuity and stability in the operation of correctional work programs and that this part be construed in furtherance of such goals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is further the intent of the Legislature that, although the state has a continuing interest in correctional work programs, such programs can best operate independently of state government.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is further the intent of the Legislature that the corporation will devise and operate correctional work programs to utilize inmates of all custody levels, with specific emphasis on reducing idleness among close custody inmates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-209; ss. 1, 2, ch. 83-345; s. 1, ch. 84-280; ss. 4, 5, ch. 87-286; s. 27, ch. 89-526; s. 1, ch. 96-270; s. 1, ch. 2001-242.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 946.01.</Text></Note></Section>