<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0946.509" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance of property leased or acquired by the corporation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Risk Management Trust Fund created under s. 284.30 shall insure all property eligible for coverage under part I of chapter 284 which is leased by the department to the corporation or which is subsequently acquired and owned or leased by the corporation and subject to the reversionary ownership interest of the state established in s. 946.505.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coverage under the State Risk Management Trust Fund of property leased to or otherwise acquired by the corporation shall be secured and maintained through the existing policy and account of the Department of Corrections with the Division of Risk Management of the Department of Financial Services. All matters, including premium calculations, assessments and payments, retrospective premium adjustments, reporting requirements, and other requirements, concerning coverage of such property under the State Risk Management Trust Fund shall be conducted as if all such property were owned solely by the department. Except as required by chapter 284, if the corporation finds that it is more economical to do so, the corporation may secure private insurance coverage on all or a portion of the activities of or properties used by the corporation. If coverage through the State Risk Management Trust Fund is not secured, the corporation must present documentation of insurance coverage to the Division of Risk Management equal to the coverage that could otherwise be provided by the State Risk Management Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-209; ss. 4, 12, ch. 87-286; s. 6, ch. 96-270; s. 65, ch. 96-418; s. 37, ch. 97-93; s. 5, ch. 97-227; s. 24, ch. 2000-122; s. 6, ch. 2001-242; s. 1931, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 946.081.</Text></Note></Section>