<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0946.515" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of goods and services produced in correctional work programs.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any service or item manufactured, processed, grown, or produced by the corporation in a correctional work program may be furnished or sold to any legislative, executive, or judicial agency of the state, any political subdivision, any other state, any foreign entity or agent thereof, any agency of the Federal Government, to any contract vendor for such agencies or any subcontractor of the contract vendor, or to any person, firm, or business entity if not prohibited by federal law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No similar product or service of comparable price and quality found necessary for use by any state agency may be purchased from any source other than the corporation if the corporation certifies that the product is manufactured by, or the service is provided by, inmates and the product or service meets the comparable performance specifications and comparable price and quality requirements as specified under s. 287.042(1)(f) or as determined by an individual agency as provided in this section. The purchasing authority of any such state agency may make reasonable determinations of need, price, and quality with reference to products or services available from the corporation. In the event of a dispute between the corporation and any purchasing authority based upon price or quality under this section or s. 287.042(1)(f), either party may request a hearing with the Department of Management Services and if not resolved, either party may request a proceeding pursuant to ss. 120.569 and 120.57, which shall be referred to the Division of Administrative Hearings within 60 days after such request, to resolve any dispute under this section. No party is entitled to any appeal pursuant to s. 120.68.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agricultural commodities, including, but not limited to, sugar cane, vegetables, beef, and dairy products, may be sold to private entities or may be sold or disposed of as provided in subsections (1) and (2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of part I of chapter 287 do not apply to any purchases of commodities or contractual services made by any legislative, executive, or judicial agency of the state from the corporation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition, the corporation may contract to provide inmate services or inmate goods to private enterprise, where such services or goods are under the direct supervision of the corporation and, further, where it is determined by the Governor that the corporation by the provision of such services or goods does not unreasonably seek to compete with other businesses in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, pursuant to a contract between any legislative, executive, or judicial agency of the state and any private contract vendor, a product or service is required by the Department of Management Services or on behalf of any state agency, is certified by or is available from the corporation identified in this chapter, and has been approved in accordance with subsection (2), the contract must contain the following language:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">IT IS EXPRESSLY UNDERSTOOD AND AGREED THAT ANY ARTICLES WHICH ARE THE SUBJECT OF, OR REQUIRED TO CARRY OUT, THIS CONTRACT SHALL BE PURCHASED FROM THE CORPORATION IDENTIFIED UNDER CHAPTER 946, F.S., IN THE SAME MANNER AND UNDER THE SAME PROCEDURES SET FORTH IN SECTION 946.515(2), AND (4), F.S.; AND FOR PURPOSES OF THIS CONTRACT THE PERSON, FIRM, OR OTHER BUSINESS ENTITY CARRYING OUT THE PROVISIONS OF THIS CONTRACT SHALL BE DEEMED TO BE SUBSTITUTED FOR THIS AGENCY INSOFAR AS DEALINGS WITH SUCH CORPORATION ARE CONCERNED.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 946.518 do not apply to this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On June 30, 2012, each state agency must submit a report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives which lists products or services obtained from a source other than the corporation when a comparable product or service could have been obtained from the corporation. The report must include an explanation of why the product or service was not obtained from the corporation. This subsection expires July 1, 2012.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-209; s. 1, ch. 85-194; s. 46, ch. 86-183; ss. 4, 14, ch. 87-286; s. 6, ch. 91-298; s. 318, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 38, ch. 95-283; s. 7, ch. 96-270; s. 323, ch. 96-410; s. 9, ch. 97-227; s. 105, ch. 98-279; s. 7, ch. 99-260; s. 17, ch. 2000-155; s. 80, ch. 2011-47.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 946.15.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>