<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0776.085" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Defense to civil action for damages; party convicted of forcible or attempted forcible felony.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be a defense to any action for damages for personal injury or wrongful death, or for injury to property, that such action arose from injury sustained by a participant during the commission or attempted commission of a forcible felony. The defense authorized by this section shall be established by evidence that the participant has been convicted of such forcible felony or attempted forcible felony, or by proof of the commission of such crime or attempted crime by a preponderance of the evidence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “forcible felony” shall have the same meaning as in s. 776.08.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any civil action in which the defense recognized by this section is raised shall be stayed by the court on the motion of the civil defendant during the pendency of any criminal action which forms the basis for the defense, unless the court finds that a conviction in the criminal action would not form a valid defense under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any civil action where a party prevails based on the defense created by this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The losing party, if convicted of and incarcerated for the crime or attempted crime, shall, as determined by the court, lose any privileges provided by the correctional facility, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Canteen purchases;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Telephone access;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Outdoor exercise;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of the library; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Visitation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee to be paid to the prevailing party in equal amounts by the losing party and the losing party’s attorney; however, the losing party’s attorney is not personally responsible if he or she has acted in good faith, based on the representations of his or her client. If the losing party is incarcerated for the crime or attempted crime and has insufficient assets to cover payment of the costs of the action and the award of fees pursuant to this paragraph, the party shall, as determined by the court, be required to pay by deduction from any payments the prisoner receives while incarcerated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the losing party is incarcerated for the crime or attempted crime, the court shall issue a written order containing its findings and ruling pursuant to paragraphs (a) and (b) and shall direct that a certified copy be forwarded to the appropriate correctional institution or facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 87-187; s. 72, ch. 96-388.</History></Section>