<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0471.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board by rule may establish fees to be paid for applications, examination, reexamination, licensing and renewal, inactive status application and reactivation of inactive licenses, and recordmaking and recordkeeping. The board may also establish by rule a delinquency fee. The board shall establish fees that are adequate to ensure the continued operation of the board. Fees shall be based on department estimates of the revenue required to implement this chapter and the provisions of law with respect to the regulation of engineers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial application and examination fee shall not exceed $125 plus the actual per applicant cost to the management corporation to purchase the examination from the National Council of Examiners for Engineering and Surveying or a similar national organization. The examination fee shall be in an amount which covers the cost of obtaining and administering the examination and shall be refunded if the applicant is found ineligible to sit for the examination. The application fee shall be nonrefundable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial license fee shall not exceed $125.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for a certificate of authorization shall not exceed $125.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The biennial renewal fee shall not exceed $125.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for a temporary registration or certificate to practice engineering shall not exceed $25 for an individual or $50 for a business firm.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for licensure by endorsement shall not exceed $150.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for application for inactive status or for reactivation of an inactive license shall not exceed $150.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 42, ch. 79-243; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 20, ch. 88-205; ss. 6, 14, 15, ch. 89-30; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 212, ch. 94-119; s. 1, ch. 97-312; s. 34, ch. 2000-356; s. 5, ch. 2000-372.</History></Section>