<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0471.013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examinations; prerequisites.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person shall be entitled to take an examination for the purpose of determining whether she or he is qualified to practice in this state as an engineer if the person is of good moral character and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate from an approved engineering curriculum of 4 years or more in a school, college, or university which has been approved by the board and has a record of 4 years of active engineering experience of a character indicating competence to be in responsible charge of engineering;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an approved engineering technology curriculum of 4 years or more in a school, college, or university within the State University System, having been enrolled or having graduated prior to July 1, 1979, and has a record of 4 years of active engineering experience of a character indicating competence to be in responsible charge of engineering; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has, in lieu of such education and experience requirements, 10 years or more of active engineering work of a character indicating that the applicant is competent to be placed in responsible charge of engineering. However, this subparagraph does not apply unless such person notifies the department before July 1, 1984, that she or he was engaged in such work on July 1, 1981.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The board shall adopt rules providing for the review and approval of schools or colleges and the courses of study in engineering in such schools and colleges. The rules shall be based on the educational requirements for engineering as defined in s. 471.005. The board may adopt rules providing for the acceptance of the approval and accreditation of schools and courses of study by a nationally accepted accreditation organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person shall be entitled to take the fundamentals examination for the purpose of determining whether she or he is qualified to practice in this state as an engineer intern if she or he is in the final year of, or is a graduate of, an approved engineering curriculum in a school, college, or university approved by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person shall not be entitled to take the principles and practice examination until that person has successfully completed the fundamentals examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall deem that an applicant who seeks licensure by examination has passed the fundamentals examination when such applicant has received a doctorate degree in engineering from an institution that has an undergraduate engineering program that is accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology, Inc., and has taught engineering full time for at least 3 years, at the baccalaureate level or higher, after receiving that degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every applicant who is qualified to take the fundamentals examination or the principles and practice examination shall be allowed to take either examination three times, notwithstanding the number of times either examination has been previously failed. If an applicant fails either examination three times, the board shall require the applicant to complete additional college-level education courses as a condition of future eligibility to take that examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may refuse to certify an applicant for failure to satisfy the requirement of good moral character only if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a substantial connection between the lack of good moral character of the applicant and the professional responsibilities of a licensed engineer; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The finding by the board of lack of good moral character is supported by clear and convincing evidence.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an applicant is found to be unqualified for a license because of a lack of good moral character, the board shall furnish the applicant a statement containing the findings of the board, a complete record of the evidence upon which the determination was based, and a notice of the rights of the applicant to a rehearing and appeal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 42, ch. 79-243; s. 340, ch. 81-259; ss. 7, 10, ch. 81-302; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 14, 15, ch. 89-30; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 141, ch. 92-149; s. 332, ch. 97-103; s. 20, ch. 2002-299; s. 1, ch. 2003-293; s. 2, ch. 2004-332.</History></Section>