<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0471.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Seals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall prescribe, by rule, one or more forms of seal to be used by licensees. Each licensee shall obtain at least one seal in the form approved by rule of the board and may, in addition, register his or her seal electronically in accordance with ss. 668.001-668.006. All final drawings, specifications, plans, reports, or documents prepared or issued by the licensee and being filed for public record and all final documents provided to the owner or the owner’s representative shall be signed by the licensee, dated, and sealed with said seal. Such signature, date, and seal shall be evidence of the authenticity of that to which they are affixed. Drawings, specifications, plans, reports, final documents, or documents prepared or issued by a licensee may be transmitted electronically and may be signed by the licensee, dated, and sealed electronically with said seal in accordance with ss. 668.001-668.006.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to seal or digitally sign any document with a seal or digital signature after his or her license has expired or been revoked or suspended, unless such license has been reinstated or reissued. When an engineer’s license has been revoked or suspended by the board, the licensee shall, within a period of 30 days after the revocation or suspension has become effective, surrender his or her seal to the executive director of the board and confirm to the executive director the cancellation of the licensee’s digital signature in accordance with ss. 668.001-668.006. In the event the engineer’s license has been suspended for a period of time, his or her seal shall be returned to him or her upon expiration of the suspension period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No licensee shall affix or permit to be affixed his or her seal, name, or digital signature to any plan, specification, drawing, final bid document, or other document that depicts work which he or she is not licensed to perform or which is beyond his or her profession or specialty therein.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 42, ch. 79-243; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 14, 15, ch. 89-30; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 144, ch. 92-149; s. 334, ch. 97-103; s. 4, ch. 97-241; s. 40, ch. 2000-356; s. 32, ch. 2000-372; s. 2, ch. 2001-63; s. 26, ch. 2002-299.</History></Section>