<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0459.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Chapter not applicable to practice of medicine, surgery, chiropractic medicine, etc.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this chapter shall have no application to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duly licensed health care practitioners, other than osteopathic physicians and their physician assistants, acting within their scope of practice authorized by statute.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any physician lawfully licensed in another state or territory or foreign country when meeting duly licensed physicians of this state in consultation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commissioned medical officers of the Armed Forces of the United States and of the Public Health Service of the United States while on active duty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Students practicing under the direct supervision of licensed osteopathic physicians in extern programs approved by any college recognized and approved by the American Osteopathic Association.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, other than a person licensed under this chapter, furnishing medical assistance in case of any emergency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The domestic administration of recognized family remedies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of the religious tenets of any church in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or manufacturer who, without the use of drugs or medicine, mechanically fits or sells lenses, artificial eyes or limbs, or other apparatus or appliances or is engaged in the mechanical examination of eyes for the purpose of constructing or adjusting spectacles, eyeglasses, or lenses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit any service rendered by any person if such service is rendered under the direct supervision and control of a licensed osteopathic physician who must be available when needed, must provide specific direction for any service to be performed, and must give final approval to all services performed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-230; s. 302, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 2, 27, 29, ch. 86-290; s. 6, ch. 91-22; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 269, ch. 98-166.</History></Section>