<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0459.0076" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary certificate for practice in areas of critical need.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate issued pursuant to this section may be cited as the “Rear Admiral LeRoy Collins, Jr., Temporary Certificate for Practice in Areas of Critical Need.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any physician who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is licensed to practice in any jurisdiction in the United States and whose license is currently valid; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has served as a physician in the United States Armed Forces for at least 10 years and received an honorable discharge from the military;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">and who pays an application fee of $300 may be issued a temporary certificate for practice in areas of critical need.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate may be issued to a physician who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Will practice in an area of critical need;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Will be employed by or practice in a county health department; correctional facility; Department of Veterans’ Affairs clinic; community health center funded by s. 329, s. 330, or s. 340 of the United States Public Health Services Act; or other agency or institution that is approved by the State Surgeon General and provides health care to meet the needs of underserved populations in this state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Will practice for a limited time to address critical physician-specialty, demographic, or geographic needs for this state’s physician workforce as determined by the State Surgeon General.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Osteopathic Medicine may issue this temporary certificate with the following restrictions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General shall determine the areas of critical need. Such areas include, but are not limited to, health professional shortage areas designated by the United States Department of Health and Human Services.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recipient of a temporary certificate for practice in areas of critical need may use the certificate to work for any approved entity in any area of critical need or as authorized by the State Surgeon General.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The recipient of a temporary certificate for practice in areas of critical need shall, within 30 days after accepting employment, notify the board of all approved institutions in which the licensee practices and of all approved institutions where practice privileges have been denied.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may administer an abbreviated oral examination to determine the physician’s competency, but a written regular examination is not required. Within 60 days after receipt of an application for a temporary certificate, the board shall review the application and issue the temporary certificate, notify the applicant of denial, or notify the applicant that the board recommends additional assessment, training, education, or other requirements as a condition of certification. If the applicant has not actively practiced during the prior 3 years and the board determines that the applicant may lack clinical competency, possess diminished or inadequate skills, lack necessary medical knowledge, or exhibit patterns of deficits in clinical decisionmaking, the board may:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deny the application;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a temporary certificate having reasonable restrictions that may include, but are not limited to, a requirement for the applicant to practice under the supervision of a physician approved by the board; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a temporary certificate upon receipt of documentation confirming that the applicant has met any reasonable conditions of the board which may include, but are not limited to, completing continuing education or undergoing an assessment of skills and training.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any certificate issued under this section is valid only so long as the State Surgeon General determines that the reason for which it was issued remains a critical need to the state. The Board of Osteopathic Medicine shall review each temporary certificateholder not less than annually to ascertain that the minimum requirements of the Osteopathic Medical Practice Act and its adopted rules are being complied with. If it is determined that such minimum requirements are not being met, the board shall revoke such certificate or shall impose restrictions or conditions, or both, as a condition of continued practice under the certificate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may not issue a temporary certificate for practice in an area of critical need to any physician who is under investigation in any jurisdiction in the United States for an act that would constitute a violation of this chapter until such time as the investigation is complete, at which time the provisions of s. 459.015 apply.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application fee and all licensure fees, including neurological injury compensation assessments, shall be waived for those persons obtaining a temporary certificate to practice in areas of critical need for the purpose of providing volunteer, uncompensated care for low-income residents. The applicant must submit an affidavit from the employing agency or institution stating that the physician will not receive any compensation for any service involving the practice of medicine.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 2010-161; s. 3, ch. 2011-95.</History>
</Section>