<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0459.0055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">General licensure requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided herein, any person desiring to be licensed or certified as an osteopathic physician pursuant to this chapter shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complete an application form and submit the appropriate fee to the department;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be at least 21 years of age;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be of good moral character;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have completed at least 3 years of preprofessional postsecondary education;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have not previously committed any act that would constitute a violation of this chapter, unless the board determines that such act does not adversely affect the applicant’s present ability and fitness to practice osteopathic medicine;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not be under investigation in any jurisdiction for an act that would constitute a violation of this chapter. If, upon completion of such investigation, it is determined that the applicant has committed an act that would constitute a violation of this chapter, the applicant is ineligible for licensure unless the board determines that such act does not adversely affect the applicant’s present ability and fitness to practice osteopathic medicine;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have not had an application for a license to practice osteopathic medicine denied or a license to practice osteopathic medicine revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against by the licensing authority of any jurisdiction unless the board determines that the grounds on which such action was taken do not adversely affect the applicant’s present ability and fitness to practice osteopathic medicine. A licensing authority’s acceptance of a physician’s relinquishment of license, stipulation, consent order, or other settlement, offered in response to or in anticipation of the filing of administrative charges against the osteopathic physician, shall be considered action against the osteopathic physician’s license;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not have received less than a satisfactory evaluation from an internship, residency, or fellowship training program, unless the board determines that such act does not adversely affect the applicant’s present ability and fitness to practice osteopathic medicine. Such evaluation shall be provided by the director of medical education from the medical training facility;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have met the criteria set forth in s. 459.0075, s. 459.0077, or s. 459.021, whichever is applicable;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit to the department a set of fingerprints on a form and under procedures specified by the department, along with a payment in an amount equal to the costs incurred by the Department of Health for the criminal background check of the applicant;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that he or she is a graduate of a medical college recognized and approved by the American Osteopathic Association;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that she or he has successfully completed a resident internship of not less than 12 months in a hospital approved for this purpose by the Board of Trustees of the American Osteopathic Association or any other internship program approved by the board upon a showing of good cause by the applicant. This requirement may be waived for an applicant who matriculated in a college of osteopathic medicine during or before 1948; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate that she or he has obtained a passing score, as established by rule of the board, on all parts of the examination conducted by the National Board of Osteopathic Medical Examiners or other examination approved by the board no more than 5 years before making application in this state or, if holding a valid active license in another state, that the initial licensure in the other state occurred no more than 5 years after the applicant obtained a passing score on the examination conducted by the National Board of Osteopathic Medical Examiners or other substantially similar examination approved by the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant holds a valid active license in another state and it has been more than 2 years since the active practice of osteopathic medicine, or if an applicant does not hold a valid active license to practice osteopathic medicine in another state and it has been more than 2 years since completion of a resident internship, residency, or fellowship, and if the board determines that the interruption in practice has adversely affected the osteopathic physician’s present ability and fitness to practice, the board may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deny the application;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a license having reasonable restrictions or conditions that may include, but are not limited to, a requirement for the applicant to practice under the supervision of a physician approved by the board; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue a license upon receipt of documentation confirming that the applicant has met any reasonable conditions of the board which may include, but are not limited to, completing continuing education or undergoing an assessment of skills and training.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the board shall ensure through an investigative process that an applicant for licensure meets the criteria in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may require a personal appearance of any applicant for licensure or certification under the provisions of this chapter. Any applicant of whom a personal appearance is required must be given adequate notice of the appearance as to time and place of the appearance, as well as a statement of the purpose for the appearance and the reasons requiring such appearance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an applicant has committed an act that would constitute a violation of this chapter or has had an application for a license to practice osteopathic medicine revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against by the licensing authority of any jurisdiction, notwithstanding the board’s determination that the applicant’s present ability and fitness to practice osteopathic medicine have not been adversely affected, the board may certify the application to the department with restrictions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the investigative process is not completed within the time set out in s. 120.60(1) and the department or board has reason to believe that the applicant does not meet the criteria, the State Surgeon General or the State Surgeon General’s designee may issue a 90-day licensure delay which shall be in writing and sufficient to notify the applicant of the reason for the delay. The provisions of this subsection shall control over any conflicting provisions of s. 120.60(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 29, ch. 86-290; s. 30, ch. 88-1; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 219, ch. 96-410; s. 1095, ch. 97-103; s. 136, ch. 97-237; s. 12, ch. 97-273; s. 1, ch. 2007-229; s. 76, ch. 2008-6; s. 1, ch. 2012-163.</History>
</Section>