<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0459.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for disciplinary action; action by the board and department.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to obtain, obtaining, or renewing a license to practice osteopathic medicine or a certificate issued under this chapter by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentations, or through an error of the department or the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license or the authority to practice osteopathic medicine revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of any jurisdiction, including its agencies or subdivisions. The licensing authority’s acceptance of a physician’s relinquishment of license, stipulation, consent order, or other settlement offered in response to or in anticipation of the filing of administrative charges against the physician shall be construed as action against the physician’s license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the practice of osteopathic medicine or to the ability to practice osteopathic medicine. A plea of nolo contendere shall create a rebuttable presumption of guilt to the underlying criminal charges.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">False, deceptive, or misleading advertising.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department or the department’s impaired professional consultant any person who the licensee or certificateholder knows is in violation of this chapter or of the rules of the department or the board. A treatment provider, approved pursuant to s. 456.076, shall provide the department or consultant with information in accordance with the requirements of s. 456.076(3), (4), (5), and (6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, or advising any unlicensed person to practice osteopathic medicine contrary to this chapter or to a rule of the department or the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a licensed osteopathic physician.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Giving false testimony in the course of any legal or administrative proceedings relating to the practice of medicine or the delivery of health care services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing, or inducing another person to do so. Such reports or records shall include only those which are signed in the capacity as a licensed osteopathic physician.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying or receiving any commission, bonus, kickback, or rebate, or engaging in any split-fee arrangement in any form whatsoever with a physician, organization, agency, person, partnership, firm, corporation, or other business entity, for patients referred to providers of health care goods and services, including, but not limited to, hospitals, nursing homes, clinical laboratories, ambulatory surgical centers, or pharmacies. The provisions of this paragraph shall not be construed to prevent an osteopathic physician from receiving a fee for professional consultation services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusing to provide health care based on a patient’s participation in pending or past litigation or participation in any disciplinary action conducted pursuant to this chapter, unless such litigation or disciplinary action directly involves the osteopathic physician requested to provide services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence within a patient-physician relationship for purposes of engaging a patient in sexual activity. A patient shall be presumed to be incapable of giving free, full, and informed consent to sexual activity with his or her physician.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making deceptive, untrue, or fraudulent representations in or related to the practice of osteopathic medicine or employing a trick or scheme in the practice of osteopathic medicine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Soliciting patients, either personally or through an agent, through the use of fraud, intimidation, undue influence, or forms of overreaching or vexatious conduct. A solicitation is any communication which directly or implicitly requests an immediate oral response from the recipient.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to keep legible, as defined by department rule in consultation with the board, medical records that identify the licensed osteopathic physician or the osteopathic physician extender and supervising osteopathic physician by name and professional title who is or are responsible for rendering, ordering, supervising, or billing for each diagnostic or treatment procedure and that justify the course of treatment of the patient, including, but not limited to, patient histories; examination results; test results; records of drugs prescribed, dispensed, or administered; and reports of consultations and hospitalizations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulently altering or destroying records relating to patient care or treatment, including, but not limited to, patient histories, examination results, and test results.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on the patient or client in such a manner as to exploit the patient or client for financial gain of the licensee or of a third party which shall include, but not be limited to, the promotion or sale of services, goods, appliances, or drugs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting or advertising on any prescription form of a community pharmacy, unless the form shall also state “This prescription may be filled at any pharmacy of your choice.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing professional services which have not been duly authorized by the patient or client or his or her legal representative except as provided in s. 743.064, s. 766.103, or s. 768.13.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, giving, mixing, or otherwise preparing a legend drug, including all controlled substances, other than in the course of the osteopathic physician’s professional practice. For the purposes of this paragraph, it shall be legally presumed that prescribing, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, giving, mixing, or otherwise preparing legend drugs, including all controlled substances, inappropriately or in excessive or inappropriate quantities is not in the best interest of the patient and is not in the course of the osteopathic physician’s professional practice, without regard to his or her intent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing or dispensing any medicinal drug appearing on any schedule set forth in chapter 893 by the osteopathic physician for himself or herself or administering any such drug by the osteopathic physician to himself or herself unless such drug is prescribed for the osteopathic physician by another practitioner authorized to prescribe medicinal drugs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, ordering, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, or giving amygdalin (laetrile) to any person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice osteopathic medicine with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness or use of alcohol, drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other type of material or as a result of any mental or physical condition. In enforcing this paragraph, the department shall, upon a finding of the State Surgeon General or the State Surgeon General’s designee that probable cause exists to believe that the licensee is unable to practice medicine because of the reasons stated in this paragraph, have the authority to issue an order to compel a licensee to submit to a mental or physical examination by physicians designated by the department. If the licensee refuses to comply with such order, the department’s order directing such examination may be enforced by filing a petition for enforcement in the circuit court where the licensee resides or does business. The licensee against whom the petition is filed shall not be named or identified by initials in any public court records or documents, and the proceedings shall be closed to the public. The department shall be entitled to the summary procedure provided in s. 51.011. A licensee or certificateholder affected under this paragraph shall at reasonable intervals be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that he or she can resume the competent practice of medicine with reasonable skill and safety to patients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 456.072(2) but as specified in s. 456.50(2):</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing medical malpractice as defined in s. 456.50. The board shall give great weight to the provisions of s. 766.102 when enforcing this paragraph. Medical malpractice shall not be construed to require more than one instance, event, or act.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing gross medical malpractice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing repeated medical malpractice as defined in s. 456.50. A person found by the board to have committed repeated medical malpractice based on s. 456.50 may not be licensed or continue to be licensed by this state to provide health care services as a medical doctor in this state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require that an osteopathic physician be incompetent to practice osteopathic medicine in order to be disciplined pursuant to this paragraph. A recommended order by an administrative law judge or a final order of the board finding a violation under this paragraph shall specify whether the licensee was found to have committed “gross medical malpractice,” “repeated medical malpractice,” or “medical malpractice,” or any combination thereof, and any publication by the board shall so specify.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="y">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing any procedure or prescribing any therapy which, by the prevailing standards of medical practice in the community, would constitute experimentation on human subjects, without first obtaining full, informed, and written consent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="z">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or offering to practice beyond the scope permitted by law or accepting and performing professional responsibilities which the licensee knows or has reason to know that he or she is not competent to perform. The board may establish by rule standards of practice and standards of care for particular practice settings, including, but not limited to, education and training, equipment and supplies, medications including anesthetics, assistance of and delegation to other personnel, transfer agreements, sterilization, records, performance of complex or multiple procedures, informed consent, and policy and procedure manuals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="aa">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating professional responsibilities to a person when the licensee delegating such responsibilities knows or has reason to know that such person is not qualified by training, experience, or licensure to perform them.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="bb">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a lawful order of the board or department previously entered in a disciplinary hearing or failing to comply with a lawfully issued subpoena of the board or department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="cc">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conspiring with another licensee or with any other person to commit an act, or committing an act, which would tend to coerce, intimidate, or preclude another licensee from lawfully advertising his or her services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="dd">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring, or aiding or abetting in the procuring of, an unlawful termination of pregnancy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ee">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Presigning blank prescription forms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ff">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing any medicinal drug appearing on Schedule II in chapter 893 by the osteopathic physician for office use.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="gg">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, ordering, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, or giving any drug which is a Schedule II amphetamine or Schedule II sympathomimetic amine drug or any compound thereof, pursuant to chapter 893, to or for any person except for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The treatment of narcolepsy; hyperkinesis; behavioral syndrome characterized by the developmentally inappropriate symptoms of moderate to severe distractability, short attention span, hyperactivity, emotional lability, and impulsivity; or drug-induced brain dysfunction;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The differential diagnostic psychiatric evaluation of depression or the treatment of depression shown to be refractory to other therapeutic modalities; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The clinical investigation of the effects of such drugs or compounds when an investigative protocol therefor is submitted to, reviewed, and approved by the board before such investigation is begun.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="hh">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to supervise adequately the activities of those physician assistants, paramedics, emergency medical technicians, advanced registered nurse practitioners, anesthesiologist assistants, or other persons acting under the supervision of the osteopathic physician.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ii">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribing, ordering, dispensing, administering, supplying, selling, or giving growth hormones, testosterone or its analogs, human chorionic gonadotropin (HCG), or other hormones for the purpose of muscle building or to enhance athletic performance. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “muscle building” does not include the treatment of injured muscle. A prescription written for the drug products listed above may be dispensed by the pharmacist with the presumption that the prescription is for legitimate medical use.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="jj">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresenting or concealing a material fact at any time during any phase of a licensing or disciplinary process or procedure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="kk">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly interfering with an investigation or with any disciplinary proceeding.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ll">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department any licensee under chapter 458 or under this chapter who the osteopathic physician or physician assistant knows has violated the grounds for disciplinary action set out in the law under which that person is licensed and who provides health care services in a facility licensed under chapter 395, or a health maintenance organization certificated under part I of chapter 641, in which the osteopathic physician or physician assistant also provides services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="mm">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being found by any court in this state to have provided corroborating written medical expert opinion attached to any statutorily required notice of claim or intent or to any statutorily required response rejecting a claim, without reasonable investigation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="nn">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising or holding oneself out as a board-certified specialist in violation of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="oo">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to comply with the requirements of ss. 381.026 and 381.0261 to provide patients with information about their patient rights and how to file a patient complaint.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="pp">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="qq">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing deceptive or fraudulent expert witness testimony related to the practice of osteopathic medicine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="rr">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applicable to a licensee who serves as the designated physician of a pain-management clinic as defined in s. 458.3265 or s. 459.0137:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registering a pain-management clinic through misrepresentation or fraud;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procuring, or attempting to procure, the registration of a pain-management clinic for any other person by making or causing to be made, any false representation;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to comply with any requirement of chapter 499, the Florida Drug and Cosmetic Act; 21 U.S.C. ss. 301-392, the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; 21 U.S.C. ss. 821 et seq., the Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act; or chapter 893, the Florida Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, regardless of adjudication to, a felony or any other crime involving moral turpitude, fraud, dishonesty, or deceit in any jurisdiction of the courts of this state, of any other state, or of the United States;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted of, or disciplined by a regulatory agency of the Federal Government or a regulatory agency of another state for, any offense that would constitute a violation of this chapter;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted of, or entering a plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction of the courts of this state, of any other state, or of the United States which relates to the practice of, or the ability to practice, a licensed health care profession;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted of, or entering a plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction of the courts of this state, of any other state, or of the United States which relates to health care fraud;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dispensing any medicinal drug based upon a communication that purports to be a prescription as defined in s. 465.003(14) or s. 893.02 if the dispensing practitioner knows or has reason to believe that the purported prescription is not based upon a valid practitioner-patient relationship; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to timely notify the board of the date of his or her termination from a pain-management clinic as required by s. 459.0137(2).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ss">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to timely notify the department of the theft of prescription blanks from a pain-management clinic or a breach of other methods for prescribing within 24 hours as required by s. 459.0137(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="tt">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting or advertising through any communication media the use, sale, or dispensing of any controlled substance appearing on any schedule in chapter 893.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="uu">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dispensing a controlled substance listed in Schedule II or Schedule III in violation of s. 465.0276.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1). In determining what action is appropriate, the board must first consider what sanctions are necessary to protect the public or to compensate the patient. Only after those sanctions have been imposed may the disciplining authority consider and include in the order requirements designed to rehabilitate the physician. All costs associated with compliance with orders issued under this subsection are the obligation of the physician.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any administrative action against a physician which does not involve revocation or suspension of license, the division shall have the burden, by the greater weight of the evidence, to establish the existence of grounds for disciplinary action. The division shall establish grounds for revocation or suspension of license by clear and convincing evidence.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall not reinstate the license or certificate of an osteopathic physician, or cause a license or certificate to be issued to a person it has deemed unqualified, until such time as it is satisfied that he or she has complied with all the terms and conditions set forth in the final order and that such person is capable of safely engaging in the practice of osteopathic medicine. However, the board may not issue a license to, or reinstate the license of, any medical doctor found by the board to have committed repeated medical malpractice based on s. 456.50, regardless of the extent to which the licensee or prospective licensee has complied with all terms and conditions set forth in the final order and is capable of safely engaging in the practice of osteopathic medicine.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall, by rule, establish comprehensive guidelines for the disposition of disciplinary cases involving specific types of violations. Such guidelines shall establish offenses and circumstances for which revocation will be presumed to be appropriate, as well as offenses and circumstances for which suspension for particular periods of time will be presumed to be appropriate. The guidelines shall also establish minimum and maximum fines, periods of supervision or probation, or conditions of probation and conditions for reissuance of a license with respect to particular circumstances and offenses. “Gross medical malpractice,” “repeated medical malpractice,” and “medical malpractice,” under paragraph (1)(x) shall each be considered distinct types of violations requiring specific individual guidelines.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the department’s receipt from an insurer or self-insurer of a report of a closed claim against an osteopathic physician pursuant to s. 627.912 or from a health care practitioner of a report pursuant to s. 456.049, or upon the receipt from a claimant of a presuit notice against an osteopathic physician pursuant to s. 766.106, the department shall review each report and determine whether it potentially involved conduct by a licensee that is subject to disciplinary action, in which case the provisions of s. 456.073 shall apply. However, if it is reported that an osteopathic physician has had three or more claims with indemnities exceeding $50,000 each within the previous 5-year period, the department shall investigate the occurrences upon which the claims were based and determine if action by the department against the osteopathic physician is warranted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the department’s receipt from the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to s. 395.0197 of the name of an osteopathic physician whose conduct may constitute grounds for disciplinary action by the department, the department shall investigate the occurrences upon which the report was based and determine if action by the department against the osteopathic physician is warranted.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any osteopathic physician regulated by the Division of Medical Quality Assurance is guilty of such unprofessional conduct, negligence, or mental or physical incapacity or impairment that the division determines that the osteopathic physician is unable to practice with reasonable skill and safety and presents a danger to patients, the division shall be authorized to maintain an action in circuit court enjoining such osteopathic physician from providing medical services to the public until the osteopathic physician demonstrates the ability to practice with reasonable skill and safety and without danger to patients.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an investigation of an osteopathic physician is undertaken, the department shall promptly furnish to the osteopathic physician or his or her attorney a copy of the complaint or document which resulted in the initiation of the investigation. For purposes of this subsection, such documents include, but are not limited to: the pertinent portions of an annual report submitted to the department pursuant to s. 395.0197(6); a report of an adverse incident which is provided to the department pursuant to s. 395.0197; a report of peer review disciplinary action submitted to the department pursuant to s. 395.0193(4) or s. 459.016, provided that the investigations, proceedings, and records relating to such peer review disciplinary action shall continue to retain their privileged status even as to the licensee who is the subject of the investigation, as provided by ss. 395.0193(8) and 459.016(3); a report of a closed claim submitted pursuant to s. 627.912; a presuit notice submitted pursuant to s. 766.106(2); and a petition brought under the Florida Birth-Related Neurological Injury Compensation Plan, pursuant to s. 766.305(2). The osteopathic physician may submit a written response to the information contained in the complaint or document which resulted in the initiation of the investigation within 45 days after service to the osteopathic physician of the complaint or document. The osteopathic physician’s written response shall be considered by the probable cause panel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A probable cause panel convened to consider disciplinary action against a physician assistant alleged to have violated s. 456.072 or this section must include one physician assistant. The physician assistant must hold a valid license to practice as a physician assistant in this state and be appointed to the panel by the Council of Physician Assistants. The physician assistant may hear only cases involving disciplinary actions against a physician assistant. If the appointed physician assistant is not present at the disciplinary hearing, the panel may consider the matter and vote on the case in the absence of the physician assistant. The training requirements set forth in s. 458.307(4) do not apply to the appointed physician assistant. Rules need not be adopted to implement this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to facilitate uniform discipline for those acts made punishable under this section and, to this end, a reference to this section constitutes a general reference under the doctrine of incorporation by reference.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-230; s. 3, ch. 80-354; s. 305, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 19, ch. 83-329; s. 2, ch. 85-6; s. 5, ch. 85-175; ss. 16, 27, 29, ch. 86-290; s. 54, ch. 87-225; s. 35, ch. 88-1; s. 13, ch. 88-277; s. 3, ch. 90-44; s. 27, ch. 90-228; s. 3, ch. 90-254; s. 63, ch. 91-220; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 40, ch. 92-149; s. 2, ch. 92-178; s. 84, ch. 92-289; s. 29, ch. 95-144; s. 221, ch. 96-410; s. 1097, ch. 97-103; s. 107, ch. 97-261; s. 33, ch. 97-264; s. 38, ch. 98-89; s. 52, ch. 98-166; s. 223, ch. 99-8; s. 103, ch. 99-397; s. 111, ch. 2000-160; ss. 25, 77, ch. 2001-277; s. 27, ch. 2003-416; s. 4, ch. 2004-303; s. 4, ch. 2005-240; s. 4, ch. 2005-266; s. 2, ch. 2006-242; s. 77, ch. 2008-6; s. 10, ch. 2010-211; s. 9, ch. 2011-141; s. 5, ch. 2011-233.</History>
</Section>