<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.172" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or a licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The biennial license fee schedule is as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs not more than 2,000 tests annually, the fee is $400.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs not more than 3 categories of procedures with a total annual volume of more than 2,000 but no more than 10,000 tests, the license fee is $965.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs at least 4 categories of procedures with a total annual volume of not more than 10,000 tests, the license fee is $1,294.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs not more than 3 categories of procedures with a total annual volume of more than 10,000 but not more than 25,000 tests, the license fee is $1,592.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs at least 4 categories of procedures with a total annual volume of more than 10,000 but not more than 25,000 tests, the license fee is $2,103.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs a total of more than 25,000 but not more than 50,000 tests annually, the license fee is $2,364.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs a total of more than 50,000 but not more than 75,000 tests annually, the license fee is $2,625.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs a total of more than 75,000 but not more than 100,000 tests annually, the license fee is $2,886.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs a total of more than 100,000 but not more than 500,000 tests annually, the license fee is $3,397.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs a total of more than 500,000 but not more than 1 million tests annually, the license fee is $3,658.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a laboratory performs a total of more than 1 million tests annually, the license fee is $3,919.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall assess a $100 biennial license fee under this section for facilities surveyed by an approved accrediting organization.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 30, ch. 83-276; s. 80, ch. 85-81; s. 14, ch. 91-282; s. 30, ch. 92-58; s. 19, ch. 93-40; ss. 11, 25, ch. 93-178; s. 4, ch. 97-91; s. 68, ch. 2000-158; s. 188, ch. 2007-230; s. 71, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>