<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Clinical laboratories operated by practitioners for exclusive use; licensure and regulation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clinical laboratory operated by one or more practitioners licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, chapter 462, or chapter 466, exclusively in connection with the diagnosis and treatment of their own patients, must be licensed under this part and must comply with the provisions of this part, except that the agency shall adopt rules for staffing, for personnel, including education and training of personnel, for proficiency testing, and for construction standards relating to the licensure and operation of the laboratory based upon and not exceeding the same standards contained in the federal Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments of 1988 and the federal regulations adopted thereunder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) does not apply to a clinical laboratory operated by one or more practitioners who hold the facilities of the laboratory out as available for the performance of diagnostic tests for other practitioners or their patients. All provisions of this part apply to a clinical laboratory that receives any referred work or performs any work for patients referred by another practitioner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this part and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the agency pursuant to this part. A license issued by the agency is required in order to operate a clinical laboratory.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 93-178; s. 2, ch. 97-91; s. 180, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>