<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.245" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rebates prohibited; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to pay or receive any commission, bonus, kickback, or rebate or engage in any split-fee arrangement in any form whatsoever with any dialysis facility, physician, surgeon, organization, agency, or person, either directly or indirectly, for patients referred to a clinical laboratory licensed under this part. A clinical laboratory is prohibited from, directly or indirectly, providing through employees, contractors, an independent staffing company, lease agreement, or otherwise, personnel to perform any functions or duties in a physician’s office, or any part of a physician’s office, for any purpose whatsoever, including for the collection or handling of specimens, unless the laboratory and the physician’s office are wholly owned and operated by the same entity. A clinical laboratory is prohibited from leasing space within any part of a physician’s office for any purpose, including for the purpose of establishing a collection station.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt rules that assess administrative penalties for acts prohibited by subsection (1). In the case of an entity licensed by the agency, such penalties may include any disciplinary action available to the agency under the appropriate licensing laws. In the case of an entity not licensed by the agency, such penalties may include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fine not to exceed $1,000;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If applicable, a recommendation by the agency to the appropriate licensing board that disciplinary action be taken.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall promptly investigate all complaints of noncompliance with subsection (1). The agency shall impose a fine of $5,000 for each separate violation of subsection (1). In addition, the agency shall deny an application for a license or license renewal if the applicant, or any other entity with one or more common controlling interests in the applicant, demonstrates a pattern of violating subsection (1). A pattern may be demonstrated by a showing of at least two such violations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 79-106; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 29, 30, ch. 83-276; s. 19, ch. 93-40; ss. 17, 25, ch. 93-178; s. 60, ch. 2001-277; s. 35, ch. 2012-160.</History></Section>