<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.825" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for disciplinary action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to obtain, obtaining, or renewing a license or registration under this part by bribery, by fraudulent misrepresentation, or through an error of the department or the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in or attempting to engage in, or representing herself or himself as entitled to perform, any clinical laboratory procedure or category of procedures not authorized pursuant to her or his license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrating incompetence or making consistent errors in the performance of clinical laboratory examinations or procedures or erroneous reporting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing a test and rendering a report thereon to a person not authorized by law to receive such services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been convicted or found guilty of, or entered a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the activities of clinical laboratory personnel or involves moral turpitude or fraudulent or dishonest dealing. The record of a conviction certified or authenticated in such form as to be admissible in evidence under the laws of the state shall be admissible as prima facie evidence of such guilt.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been adjudged mentally or physically incompetent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding and abetting in the violation of any provision of this part or the rules adopted hereunder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reporting a test result when no laboratory test was performed on a clinical specimen.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly advertising false services or credentials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against, including the denial of licensure, by the licensing authority of another jurisdiction. The licensing authority’s acceptance of a relinquishment of a license, stipulation, consent order, or other settlement, offered in response to or in anticipation of the filing of administrative charges against the licensee, shall be construed as action against the licensee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the board, in writing, within 30 days that an action under paragraph (e), paragraph (f), or paragraph (j) has been taken against the licensee or one’s license to practice as clinical laboratory personnel in another state, territory, country, or other jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to perform or report clinical laboratory examinations with reasonable skill and safety to patients by reason of illness or use of alcohol, drugs, narcotics, chemicals, or any other type of material or as a result of any mental or physical condition. In enforcing this paragraph, the department shall have, upon a finding of the State Surgeon General or his or her designee that probable cause exists to believe that the licensee is unable to practice because of the reasons stated in this paragraph, the authority to issue an order to compel a licensee to submit to a mental or physical examination by physicians designated by the department. If the licensee refuses to comply with such order, the department’s order directing such examination may be enforced by filing a petition for enforcement in the circuit court where the licensee resides or does business. The department shall be entitled to the summary procedure provided in s. 51.011. A licensee affected under this paragraph shall at reasonable intervals be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that he or she can resume competent practice with reasonable skill and safety to patients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating professional responsibilities to a person when the licensee delegating such responsibilities knows, or has reason to know, that such person is not qualified by training, experience, or licensure to perform them.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating a previous order of the board entered in a disciplinary proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to report to the department a person or other licensee who the licensee knows is in violation of this chapter or the rules of the department or board adopted hereunder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making or filing a report which the licensee knows to be false, intentionally or negligently failing to file a report or record required by state or federal law, willfully impeding or obstructing such filing or inducing another person to do so, including, but not limited to, impeding an agent of the state from obtaining a report or record for investigative purposes. Such reports or records shall include only those generated in the capacity as a licensed clinical laboratory personnel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying or receiving any commission, bonus, kickback, or rebate, or engaging in any split-fee arrangement in any form whatsoever with a physician, organization, agency, or person, either directly or indirectly for patients referred to providers of health care goods and services including, but not limited to, hospitals, nursing homes, clinical laboratories, ambulatory surgical centers, or pharmacies. The provisions of this paragraph shall not be construed to prevent a clinical laboratory professional from receiving a fee for professional consultation services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="r"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercising influence on a patient or client in such a manner as to exploit the patient or client for the financial gain of the licensee or other third party, which shall include, but not be limited to, the promoting, selling, or withholding of services, goods, appliances, referrals, or drugs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="s"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or offering to practice beyond the scope permitted by law or rule, or accepting or performing professional services or responsibilities which the licensee knows or has reason to know that he or she is not competent to perform.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="t"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresenting or concealing a material fact at any time during any phase of the licensing, investigative, or disciplinary process, procedure, or proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="u"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improperly interfering with an investigation or any disciplinary proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="v"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in or attempting to engage in sexual misconduct, causing undue embarrassment or using disparaging language or language of a sexual nature towards a patient, exploiting superior/subordinate, professional/patient, instructor/student relationships for personal gain, sexual gratification, or advantage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="w"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the amount of the fine to be levied for a violation, as provided in subsection (1), the following factors shall be considered:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The severity of the violation, including the probability that death or serious harm to the health or safety of any person will result or has resulted, the severity of the actual or potential harm, and the extent to which the provisions of this part were violated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken by the licensee to correct the violation or to remedy complaints.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous violation by the licensee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial benefit to the licensee of committing or continuing the violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 92-58; s. 445, ch. 97-103; s. 169, ch. 97-264; s. 152, ch. 99-397; s. 46, ch. 2001-277; s. 22, ch. 2005-240; s. 97, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>