<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.901" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Medical physicists; definitions; licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “Florida Medical Physicists Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DECLARATION OF LEGISLATIVE POLICY.<EmDash />The Legislature finds that the practice of medical physics by incompetent persons is a threat to the public health and safety. It is, therefore, the responsibility of this state to protect the public health and safety from the harmful effects of excessive and unnecessary radiation by ensuring that the practice of medical physics is entrusted only to persons who are licensed under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Council” means the Advisory Council of Medical Physicists in the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Diagnostic radiological physics” means the specialty of medical physics which deals with the diagnostic application and safe use of X rays, gamma rays from sealed sources, ultrasonic radiation, radio frequency radiation, or magnetic fields, and the use of equipment associated with the production, use, measurement, and evaluation of the radiation and the quality of the diagnostic image resulting from its production and use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means a certificate issued by the department which authorizes the holder to practice medical physics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensed medical physicist” means a person who holds a license issued under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical health physics” means the specialty of medical physics which deals with the safe use of X rays, gamma rays, electron or other charged particle beams, neutrons, radionuclides, and radiation from sealed sources, for both diagnostic and therapeutic purposes in human beings and the use of equipment required to perform appropriate tests and measurements that do not involve the direct application of radiation to humans for diagnostic or therapeutic procedures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical nuclear radiological physics” means the specialty of medical physics which deals with the therapeutic and diagnostic application and safe use of radionuclides, except those used in sealed sources for therapeutic purposes, and the use of equipment associated with the production, use, measurement, and evaluation of radionuclides.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical physics” means the branch of physics which is associated with the practice of medicine. It includes the fields of diagnostic radiological physics, therapeutic radiological physics, medical nuclear radiological physics, and medical health physics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physician” means a doctor of medicine, osteopathic medicine, podiatric medicine, dentistry, or chiropractic medicine who is licensed in this state and who prescribes a radiological procedure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Practice of medical physics” means the use of principles and accepted protocols of physics to ensure the correct quality, quantity, and placement of radiation during the performance of a radiological procedure prescribed by a physician which will protect the patient and others from harmful excessive radiation. The term includes radiation beam calibration and characterization quality assurance, instrument specification, acceptance testing, shielding design, protection analysis on radiation-emitting equipment and radiopharmaceuticals, and consultation with a physician to ensure accurate radiation dosage to a specific patient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiation” means ionizing or nonionizing radiation above background levels which is used to perform a diagnostic or therapeutic medical or dental radiological procedure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiological procedure” means a test, measurement, calculation, or radiation exposure used in the diagnosis or treatment of diseases or other medical or dental conditions in human beings that includes therapeutic radiation, diagnostic radiation, nuclear magnetic resonance, or nuclear medicine procedures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Therapeutic radiological physics” means that specialty of medical physics which deals with the therapeutic application and safe use of X rays, gamma rays, electron or other charged particle beams, neutrons, or radiation from radionuclide sources, and the use of equipment associated with the production, use, measurement, and evaluation of that radiation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COUNCIL.<EmDash />The Advisory Council of Medical Physicists is created in the Department of Health to advise the department in regulating the practice of medical physics in this state.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall be composed of nine members appointed by the State Surgeon General as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed medical physicist who specializes in diagnostic radiological physics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed medical physicist who specializes in therapeutic radiological physics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed medical physicist who specializes in medical nuclear radiological physics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician who is board certified by the American Board of Radiology or its equivalent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician who is board certified by the American Osteopathic Board of Radiology or its equivalent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A chiropractic physician who practices radiology.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three consumer members who are not, and have never been, licensed as a medical physicist or licensed in any closely related profession.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General shall appoint the medical physicist members of the council from a list of candidates who are licensed to practice medical physics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General shall appoint the physician members of the council from a list of candidates who are licensed to practice medicine in this state and are board certified in diagnostic radiology, therapeutic radiology, or radiation oncology.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General shall appoint the public members of the council.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As the term of each member expires, the State Surgeon General shall appoint the successor for a term of 4 years. A member shall serve until the member’s successor is appointed, unless physically unable to do so.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual is ineligible to serve more than two full consecutive 4-year terms.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a vacancy on the council occurs, the State Surgeon General shall appoint a member to serve for a 4-year term.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A council member must be a United States citizen and must have been a resident of this state for 2 consecutive years immediately before being appointed.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the council who is a medical physicist must have practiced for at least 6 years before being appointed or be board certified for the specialty in which the member practices.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the council who is a physician must be licensed to practice medicine in this state and must have practiced diagnostic radiology or radiation oncology in this state for at least 2 years before being appointed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public members of the council must not have a financial interest in any endeavor related to the practice of medical physics.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A council member may be removed from the council if the member:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Did not have the required qualifications at the time of appointment;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not maintain the required qualifications while serving on the council; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails to attend the regularly scheduled council meetings in a calendar year as required by s. 456.011.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the council may not receive compensation for their services; however, they are entitled to reimbursement, from funds deposited in the Medical Quality Assurance Trust Fund, for necessary travel expenses as specified in s. 112.061 for each day they engage in the business of the council.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the first regularly scheduled meeting of each calendar year, the council shall elect a presiding officer and an assistant presiding officer from among its members. The council shall meet at least once each year and at other times in accordance with department requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide administrative support to the council for all licensing activities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council may conduct its meetings electronically.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">POWERS OF COUNCIL.<EmDash />The council shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend rules to administer this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend practice standards for the practice of medical physics which are consistent with the Guidelines for Ethical Practice for Medical Physicists prepared by the American Association of Physicists in Medicine and disciplinary guidelines adopted under s. 456.079.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and recommend continuing education requirements for licensed medical physicists.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSE REQUIRED.<EmDash />An individual may not engage in the practice of medical physics, including the specialties of diagnostic radiological physics, therapeutic radiological physics, medical nuclear radiological physics, or medical health physics, without a license issued by the department for the appropriate specialty.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules to administer this section which specify license application and renewal fees, continuing education requirements, and standards for practicing medical physics. The council shall recommend to the department continuing education requirements that shall be a condition of license renewal. The department shall require a minimum of 24 hours per biennium of continuing education offered by an organization recommended by the council and approved by the department. The department, upon recommendation of the council, may adopt rules to specify continuing education requirements for persons who hold a license in more than one specialty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to apply for a medical physicist license in one or more specialties, a person must file an individual application for each specialty with the department. The application must be on a form prescribed by the department and must be accompanied by a nonrefundable application fee for each specialty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a license to an eligible applicant if the applicant meets all license requirements. At any time before the department issues a license, the applicant may request in writing that the application be withdrawn. To reapply, the applicant must submit a new application and an additional nonrefundable application fee and must meet all current licensure requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall review each completed application for a license which the department receives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On receipt of an application and fee as specified in this section, the department may issue a license to practice medical physics in this state on or after October 1, 1997, to a person who is board certified in the medical physics specialty in which the applicant applies to practice by the American Board of Radiology for diagnostic radiological physics, therapeutic radiological physics, or medical nuclear radiological physics; by the American Board of Medical Physics for diagnostic radiological physics, therapeutic radiological physics, or medical nuclear radiological physics; or by the American Board of Health Physics or an equivalent certifying body approved by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display the license in a place accessible to the public; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report immediately any change in the licensee’s address or name to the department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for denial of a license or disciplinary action, as specified in s. 456.072(2):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining or attempting to obtain a license by bribery, fraud, knowing misrepresentation, or concealment of material fact or through an error of the department.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a license denied, revoked, suspended, or otherwise acted against in another jurisdiction.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty of, or entering a plea of nolo contendere to, regardless of adjudication, a crime in any jurisdiction which relates to the practice of, or the ability to practice, the profession of medical physics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully failing to file a report or record required for medical physics or willfully impeding or obstructing the filing of a report or record required by this section or inducing another person to do so.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making misleading, deceptive, or fraudulent representations in or related to the practice of medical physics.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully failing to report any known violation of this section or any rule adopted thereunder.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to perform any statutory or legal obligation placed upon a licensee.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, employing, or advising any unlicensed person to practice medical physics contrary to this section or any rule adopted thereunder.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delegating or contracting for the performance of professional responsibilities by a person when the licensee delegating or contracting such responsibilities knows, or has reason to know, such person is not qualified by training, experience, and authorization to perform them.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing or offering to practice beyond the scope permitted by law or accepting and performing professional responsibilities the licensee knows, or has reason to know, the licensee is not competent to perform.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gross or repeated malpractice or the inability to practice medical physics with reasonable skill and safety.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Judicially determined mental incompetency.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being unable to practice medical physics with reasonable skill and safety because of a mental or physical condition or illness or the use of alcohol, controlled substances, or any other substance which impairs one’s ability to practice.</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, upon probable cause, compel a licensee to submit to a mental or physical examination by physicians designated by the department. The cost of an examination shall be borne by the licensee, and the licensee’s failure to submit to such an examination constitutes an admission of the allegations against the licensee, consequent upon which a default and a final order may be entered without the taking of testimony or presentation of evidence, unless the failure was due to circumstances beyond the licensee’s control.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee who is disciplined under this subparagraph shall, at reasonable intervals, be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that the licensee can resume the practice of medical physics with reasonable skill and safety.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any proceeding under this subparagraph, the record of proceedings or the orders entered by the department may not be used against a licensee in any other proceeding.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violating any provision of this chapter or chapter 456, or any rules adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may enter an order denying licensure or imposing any of the penalties in s. 456.072(2) against any applicant for licensure or licensee who is found guilty of violating any provision of subsection (1) of this section or who is found guilty of violating any provision of s. 456.072(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue or reinstate a license to a person it has deemed unqualified until it is satisfied that such person has complied with the terms and conditions of the final order and that the licensee can safely practice medical physics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a complete application and the fee set forth by rule, the department may issue a physicist-in-training certificate to a person qualified to practice medical physics under direct supervision. The department may establish by rule requirements for initial certification and renewal of a physicist-in-training certificate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FEES.<EmDash />The fee for the initial license application shall be $500 and is nonrefundable. The fee for license renewal may not be more than $500. These fees may cover only the costs incurred by the department and the council to administer this section. By July 1 each year, the department shall advise the council if the fees are insufficient to administer this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISPOSITION OF FEES.<EmDash />The department shall deposit all funds received into the Medical Quality Assurance Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PENALTY FOR VIOLATIONS.<EmDash />It is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice or attempt to practice medical physics or hold oneself out to be a licensed medical physicist without holding an active license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice or attempt to practice medical physics under a name other than one’s own.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use or attempt to use a revoked or suspended license or the license of another.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS.<EmDash />This section does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician who is licensed by this state to the extent that the physician practices within the scope of the physician’s training, education, and licensure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is licensed under part IV of chapter 468 to the extent that the person practices within the scope of the person’s training, education, and licensure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who performs beam calibration and characterization, quality assurance, instrument specification, acceptance testing, shielding design, or protection analysis on radiation-emitting equipment or radiopharmaceuticals in connection with procedures that are not involved with the diagnosis or treatment of disease or other medical or dental conditions in humans;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is employed by a federal or state regulatory agency and is performing duties within the scope of the person’s employment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A student or intern who practices medical physics in conjunction with a program at an accredited college or university to the extent that the student or intern is adequately supervised by a licensed medical physicist or licensed physician; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dentist or any person working under the dentist’s supervision pursuant to chapter 466 to the extent that the dentist or the person supervised by the dentist is practicing within the scope of his or her training, education, and licensure.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3, 5, ch. 95-231; s. 446, ch. 97-103; s. 171, ch. 97-264; ss. 137, 218, 247, 286, ch. 98-166; s. 153, ch. 99-397; s. 69, ch. 2000-158; s. 197, ch. 2000-160; s. 60, ch. 2000-318; s. 48, ch. 2001-277; s. 80, ch. 2002-1; s. 23, ch. 2005-240; s. 98, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>