<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Offenses; criminal penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operate, maintain, direct, or engage in the business of operating a clinical laboratory unless she or he has obtained a clinical laboratory license from the agency or is exempt under s. 483.031.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct, maintain, or operate a clinical laboratory, other than an exempt laboratory or a laboratory operated under s. 483.035, unless the clinical laboratory is under the direct and responsible supervision and direction of a person licensed under part III of this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allow any person other than an individual licensed under part III of this chapter to perform clinical laboratory procedures, except in the operation of a laboratory exempt under s. 483.031 or a laboratory operated under s. 483.035.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violate or aid and abet in the violation of any provision of this part or the rules adopted under this part.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The performance of any act specified in paragraph (a) shall be referred by the agency to the local law enforcement agency and constitutes a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Additionally, the agency may issue and deliver a notice to cease and desist from such act and may impose by citation an administrative penalty not to exceed $5,000 per act. Each day that unlicensed activity continues after issuance of a notice to cease and desist constitutes a separate act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any use or attempted use of a forged license under this part or part III of this chapter constitutes the crime of forgery.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 67-248; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 2, ch. 77-48; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 20, 29, 30, ch. 83-276; s. 31, ch. 92-58; s. 19, ch. 93-40; ss. 16, 25, ch. 93-178; s. 438, ch. 97-103; s. 4, ch. 2000-154; s. 34, ch. 2012-160.</History></Section>