<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.314" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Collection and transmittal of specimens.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A center shall forward the specimens collected by it to a clinical laboratory for such analyses as are authorized by the medical director of the center. Multiphasic health testing centers are authorized to conduct dipstick urinalysis and fecal occult blood tests only if such tests are conducted by licensed registered nurses, practical nurses, medical technicians, medical assistants, or clinical laboratory technicians trained to perform and interpret these tests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consumer multiphasic health testing centers shall report the results of an analysis directly to the medical director of the center that requested it and shall forward the results to the person from whom the specimen was collected within 5 days after the date the specimen was collected. When test results deviate significantly from established ranges, indicating the presence of a potential pathological condition, the contract multiphasic health testing center must forward the results to the person from whom the specimen was collected and the person’s designated physician within 5 days after the date the specimen was collected. Complete results of contract multiphasic health testing must be forwarded to the medical director of the contracting employer within 30 days after the date the specimen was collected.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A multiphasic health testing center may not collect specimens from the human body where prudent medical practice requires that such specimens only be collected during the course of a physical examination by a physician. The agency, which may consult with the Board of Medicine and the Board of Osteopathic Medicine, shall develop rules to implement this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A center may not perform or hold itself out to the public as providing for testing for the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) unless it complies with s. 381.004.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-48; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 29, 30, ch. 83-276; ss. 13, 19, ch. 93-40; s. 25, ch. 93-178.</History></Section>