<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.291" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of the agency; rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt rules to implement this part and part II of chapter 408, which rules must include the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSING STANDARDS.<EmDash />The agency shall prescribe standards necessary for licensure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FEES.<EmDash />In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or a licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. The licensure fee must be not less than $600 or more than $2,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STANDARDS OF PERFORMANCE.<EmDash />The agency shall prescribe standards for the performance of health testing procedures.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSTRUCTION OF CENTERS.<EmDash />The agency may adopt rules to ensure that centers comply with all local, county, state, and federal standards for the construction, renovation, maintenance, or repair of centers, which standards must ensure the conduct and operation of the centers in a manner that will protect the public health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SAFETY AND SANITARY CONDITIONS WITHIN THE CENTER AND ITS SURROUNDINGS.<EmDash />The agency shall establish standards relating to safety and sanitary conditions within the center and its surroundings, including water supply; sewage; the handling of specimens; identification, segregation, and separation of biohazardous waste as required by s. 381.0098; storage of chemicals; workspace; firesafety; and general measures, which standards must ensure the protection of the public health. The agency shall determine compliance by a multiphasic health testing center with the requirements of s. 381.0098 by verifying that the center has obtained all required permits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EQUIPMENT.<EmDash />The agency shall establish minimum standards for center equipment essential to the proper conduct and operation of the center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERSONNEL.<EmDash />The agency shall prescribe minimum qualifications for center personnel. A center may employ as a medical assistant a person who has at least one of the following qualifications:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior experience of not less than 6 months as a medical assistant in the office of a licensed medical doctor or osteopathic physician or in a hospital, an ambulatory surgical center, a home health agency, or a health maintenance organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification and registration by the American Medical Technologists Association or other similar professional association approved by the agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior employment as a medical assistant in a licensed center for at least 6 consecutive months at some time during the preceding 2 years.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-48; s. 208, ch. 79-400; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 25, 29, 30, ch. 83-276; ss. 5, 19, ch. 93-40; s. 25, ch. 93-178; s. 55, ch. 97-264; s. 192, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>