<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0483.807" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees; establishment; disposition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board, by rule, shall establish fees to be paid for application, examination, reexamination, licensing and renewal, registration, laboratory training program application, reinstatement, and recordmaking and recordkeeping. The board may also establish, by rule, a delinquency fee. The board shall establish fees that are adequate to ensure the continued operation of the board and to fund the proportionate expenses incurred by the department in carrying out its licensure and other related responsibilities under this part. Fees shall be based on departmental estimates of the revenue required to implement this part and the provisions of law with respect to the regulation of clinical laboratory personnel.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nonrefundable application fee may not exceed $200.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The examination fee shall be in an amount which covers the costs of obtaining and administering the examination and shall be refunded if the applicant is found ineligible to sit for the examination. The combined fees for initial application and examination may not exceed $200 plus the actual per applicant cost to the department for developing, administering, or procuring the licensure examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial license fee may not exceed $100.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for licensure by endorsement may not exceed $100.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The biennial renewal fee may not exceed $150.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee for application for an inactive status license or for reactivation of an inactive status license may not exceed $50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial application fee for registration of a trainee shall not exceed $20.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial application and renewal fee for approval as a laboratory training program may not exceed $300. The fee for late filing of a renewal application shall be $50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fees shall be established, collected, and deposited in accordance with s. 456.025.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 92-58; s. 243, ch. 94-119; s. 136, ch. 98-166; s. 146, ch. 99-397; s. 196, ch. 2000-160; s. 9, ch. 2001-277.</History></Section>