<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0774.205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Claimant proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A civil action alleging an asbestos or silica claim may be brought in the courts of this state if the plaintiff is domiciled in this state or the exposure to asbestos or silica that is a substantial contributing factor to the physical impairment of the plaintiff on which the claim is based occurred in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plaintiff in a civil action alleging an asbestos or silica claim must include with the complaint or other initial pleading a written report and supporting test results constituting prima facie evidence of the exposed person’s asbestos-related or silica-related physical impairment meeting the requirements of s. 774.204(2), (3), (5), or (6). For any asbestos or silica claim pending on the effective date of this act, the plaintiff must file the report and supporting test results at least 30 days before setting a date for trial. The defendant must be afforded a reasonable opportunity to challenge the adequacy of the proffered prima facie evidence of asbestos-related impairment. The claim of the plaintiff shall be dismissed without prejudice upon a finding of failure to make the required prima facie showing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All asbestos claims and silica claims filed in this state on or after the effective date of this act must include, in addition to the written report described in subsection (2) and the information required by s. 774.207(2), a sworn information form containing the following information:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The claimant’s name, address, date of birth, and marital status;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the claimant alleges exposure to asbestos or silica through the testimony of another person or alleges other than direct or bystander exposure to a product, the name, address, date of birth, and marital status for each person by which the claimant alleges exposure, hereinafter the “index person,” and the claimant’s relationship to each such person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific location of each alleged exposure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The beginning and ending dates of each alleged exposure as to each asbestos product or silica product for each location at which exposure allegedly took place for the plaintiff and each index person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The occupation and name of the employer of the exposed person at the time of each alleged exposure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific condition related to asbestos or silica claimed to exist; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any supporting documentation of the condition claimed to exist.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2005-274; s. 107, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>