<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0774.203" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“AMA Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment” means the American Medical Association’s Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Asbestos” includes all minerals defined as “asbestos” in 29 C.F.R. s. 1910, as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Asbestos claim” means a claim for damages or other civil or equitable relief presented in a civil action, arising out of, based on, or related to the health effects of exposure to asbestos, including loss of consortium, wrongful death, and any other derivative claim made by or on behalf of an exposed person or a representative, spouse, parent, child, or other relative of an exposed person. The term does not include claims for benefits under a workers’ compensation law or veterans’ benefits program, or claims brought by a person as a subrogee by virtue of the payment of benefits under a workers’ compensation law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Asbestosis” means bilateral diffuse interstitial fibrosis of the lungs caused by inhalation of asbestos fibers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board certified in internal medicine” means a physician who is certified by the American Board of Internal Medicine or the American Osteopathic Board of Internal Medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board certified in occupational medicine” means a physician who is certified in the subspecialty of occupational medicine by the American Board of Preventive Medicine or the American Osteopathic Board of Preventive Medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board certified in oncology” means a physician who is certified in the subspecialty of medical oncology by the American Board of Internal Medicine or the American Osteopathic Board of Internal Medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board certified in pathology” means a physician who holds primary certification in anatomic pathology or clinical pathology from the American Board of Pathology or the American Osteopathic Board of Internal Medicine and whose professional practice:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is principally in the field of pathology; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Involves regular evaluation of pathology materials obtained from surgical or postmortem specimens.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board certified in pulmonary medicine” means a physician who is certified in the subspecialty of pulmonary medicine by the American Board of Internal Medicine or the American Osteopathic Board of Internal Medicine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bankruptcy proceeding” means a case brought under Title 11 of the United States Code or any related proceeding as provided in 28 U.S.C. s. 157.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certified B-reader” means an individual qualified as a “final” or “B-reader” under 42 C.F.R. s. 37.51(b), as amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Civil action” means all suits or claims of a civil nature in court, whether cognizable as cases at law or in equity or in admiralty. The term does not include an action relating to a workers’ compensation law, or a proceeding for benefits under a veterans’ benefits program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exposed person” means a person whose exposure to asbestos or to asbestos-containing products is the basis for an asbestos claim.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“FEV1” means forced expiratory volume in the first second, which is the maximal volume of air expelled in one second during performance of simple spirometric tests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“FVC” means forced vital capacity, which is the maximal volume of air expired with maximum effort from a position of full inspiration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“ILO Scale” means the system for the classification of chest X rays set forth in the International Labour Office’s Guidelines for the Use of ILO International Classification of Radiographs of Pneumoconioses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lung cancer” means a malignant tumor in which the primary site of origin of the cancer is inside of the lungs, but the term does not include an asbestos claim based upon mesothelioma.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mesothelioma” means a malignant tumor with a primary site in the pleura or the peritoneum, which has been diagnosed by a board-certified pathologist, using standardized and accepted criteria of microscopic morphology or appropriate staining techniques.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonmalignant condition” means any condition that can be caused by asbestos or silica other than a diagnosed cancer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonsmoker” means the exposed person has not smoked cigarettes or used other tobacco products on a consistent and frequent basis within the last 15 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pathological evidence of asbestosis” means a statement by a board-certified pathologist that more than one representative section of lung tissue uninvolved with any other disease process demonstrates a pattern of peribronchiolar or parenchymal scarring in the presence of characteristic asbestos bodies and that there is no other more likely explanation for the presence of the fibrosis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Predicted lower limit of normal” for any test means the fifth percentile of healthy populations based on age, height, and gender, as referenced in the AMA Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified physician” means a medical doctor, who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a board-certified pathologist licensed to practice and actively practices in this country who performed services requested or authorized by a physician who:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has conducted a physical examination of the exposed person or, if the person is deceased, has reviewed all available records relating to the exposed person’s medical condition;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is actually treating or has treated the exposed person, and has or had a doctor-patient relationship with the person; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is licensed to practice and actively practices in this country; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a board-certified oncologist, pulmonary specialist, or specialist in occupational and environmental medicine who:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has conducted a physical examination of the exposed person or, if the person is deceased, has reviewed all available records relating to the exposed person’s medical condition;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is actually treating or has treated the exposed person, and has or had a doctor-patient relationship with the person; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is licensed to practice and actively practices in this country.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiological evidence of asbestosis” means a quality 1 chest X ray under the ILO System of classification (in a death case where no pathology is available, the necessary radiologic findings may be made with a quality 2 film if a quality 1 film is not available) showing small, irregular opacities (s, t, u) graded by a certified B-reader as at least 1/1 on the ILO scale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Radiological evidence of diffuse pleural thickening” means a quality 1 chest X ray under the ILO System of classification (in a death case where no pathology is available, the necessary radiologic findings may be made with a quality 2 film if a quality 1 film is not available) showing bilateral pleural thickening of at least B2 on the ILO scale and blunting of at least one costophrenic angle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Silica” means a respirable crystalline form of silicon dioxide, including, but not limited to, alpha, quartz, cristobalite, and trydmite.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Silica claim” means a claim for damages or other civil or equitable relief presented in a civil action, arising out of, based on, or related to the health effects of exposure to silica, including loss of consortium, wrongful death, and any other derivative claim made by or on behalf of an exposed person or a representative, spouse, parent, child, or other relative of an exposed person. The term does not include claims for benefits under a workers’ compensation law or veterans’ benefits program, or claims brought by a person as a subrogee by virtue of the payment of benefits under a workers’ compensation law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="28"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Silicosis” means nodular interstitial fibrosis of the lungs caused by inhalation of silica.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="29"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Smoker” means a person who has smoked cigarettes or used other tobacco products on a consistent and frequent basis within the last 15 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="30"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Substantial occupational exposure” means employment for an extended period of time in industries and occupations in which, for a substantial portion of a normal work year for that occupation, the exposed person did any of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Handled raw asbestos fibers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fabricated asbestos-containing products so that the person was exposed to raw asbestos fibers in the fabrication process;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Altered, repaired, or otherwise worked with an asbestos-containing product in a manner that exposed the person on a regular basis to asbestos fibers; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Worked in close proximity to other persons engaged in any of the activities described in paragraphs (a)-(c) in a manner that exposed the person on a regular basis to asbestos fibers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="31"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Veterans benefits program” means a program for benefits in connection with military service administered by the Veterans’ Administration under Title 38 of the United States Code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="32"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Workers’ compensation law” means a law respecting a program administered by this state or the United States to provide benefits, funded by a responsible employer or its insurance carrier, for occupational diseases or injuries or for disability or death caused by occupational diseases or injuries. The term includes the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act, 33 U.S.C. ss. 901-944, 948-950, and the Federal Employees Compensation Act, chapter 81 of Title 5, United States Code, but does not include the Act of April 22, 1908, the Federal Employers Liability Act, 45 U.S.C. ss. 51 et seq.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2005-274; s. 105, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>