<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0774.209" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Miscellaneous provisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act does not affect the scope or operation of any workers’ compensation law or veterans’ benefit program, affect the exclusive remedy or subrogation provisions of the law, or authorize any lawsuit which is barred by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this act is intended to, and nothing in this act shall be interpreted to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affect the rights of any party in bankruptcy proceedings; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affect the ability of any person who is able to make a showing that the person satisfies the claim criteria for compensable claims or demands under a trust established under a plan of reorganization under chapter 11 of the United States Bankruptcy Code, 11 U.S.C. chapter 11, to make a claim or demand against that trust.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that this law render the utmost comity and respect to the constitutional prerogatives of the judiciary of this state, and nothing in this act should be construed as any effort to impinge upon those prerogatives. To that end, if the Florida Supreme Court enters a final judgment concluding or declaring that any provision of this act improperly encroaches on the authority of the court to adopt the rules of practice and procedure in the courts of this state, the Legislature intends that any such provision be construed as a request for a rule change under s. 2, Art. V of the State Constitution and not as a mandatory legislative directive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act may not be interpreted to prevent any person from bringing or maintaining an asbestos claim based on nonoccupational exposure where such person would be otherwise able to bring or maintain a claim under this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any provision of this act or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the invalidity does not affect other provisions or application of the act which can be given effect without the invalid provision or application, and to this end the provisions of this act are declared severable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2005-274.</History></Section>