<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0774.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Asbestos claim” means any claim, wherever or whenever made, for damages, losses, indemnification, contribution, or other relief arising out of, based on, or in any way related to asbestos, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health effects of exposure to asbestos, including any claim for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal injury or death;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mental or emotional injury;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Risk of disease or other injury; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs of medical monitoring or surveillance, to the extent these claims are recognized under state law;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any claim made by or on behalf of a person exposed to asbestos, or a representative, spouse, parent, child, or other relative of the person; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any claim for damage or loss caused by the installation, presence, or removal of asbestos.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporation” means a corporation for profit, including a domestic corporation organized under the laws of this state, or a foreign corporation organized under laws other than the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Successor” means a corporation that assumes or incurs, or has assumed or incurred, successor asbestos-related liabilities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Successor asbestos-related liabilities” means any liabilities, whether known or unknown, asserted or unasserted, absolute or contingent, accrued or unaccrued, liquidated or unliquidated, or due or to become due, which are related in any way to asbestos claims and were assumed or incurred by a corporation as a result of or in connection with a merger or consolidation, or the plan of merger or consolidation related to the merger or consolidation, with or into another corporation, or which are related in any way to asbestos claims based on the exercise of control or the ownership of stock of the corporation before the merger or consolidation. The term includes liabilities that, after the time of the merger or consolidation for which the fair market value of total gross assets is determined under s. 774.004 were or are paid or otherwise discharged, or committed to be paid or otherwise discharged, by or on behalf of the corporation, or by a successor of the corporation, or by or on behalf of a transferor, in connection with settlements, judgments, or other discharges in this state or another jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transferor” means a corporation from which successor asbestos-related liabilities are or were assumed or incurred.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-269.</History></Section>