<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0743.064" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency medical care or treatment to minors without parental consent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The absence of parental consent notwithstanding, a physician licensed under chapter 458 or an osteopathic physician licensed under chapter 459 may render emergency medical care or treatment to any minor who has been injured in an accident or who is suffering from an acute illness, disease, or condition if, within a reasonable degree of medical certainty, delay in initiation or provision of emergency medical care or treatment would endanger the health or physical well-being of the minor, and provided such emergency medical care or treatment is administered in a hospital licensed by the state under chapter 395 or in a college health service. Emergency medical care or treatment may also be rendered in the prehospital setting by paramedics, emergency medical technicians, and other emergency medical services personnel, provided such care is rendered consistent with the provisions of chapter 401. These persons shall follow the general guidelines and notification provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall apply only when parental consent cannot be immediately obtained for one of the following reasons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor’s condition has rendered him or her unable to reveal the identity of his or her parents, guardian, or legal custodian, and such information is unknown to any person who accompanied the minor to the hospital.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parents, guardian, or legal custodian cannot be immediately located by telephone at their place of residence or business.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notification shall be accomplished as soon as possible after the emergency medical care or treatment is administered. The hospital records shall reflect the reason such consent was not initially obtained and shall contain a statement by the attending physician that immediate emergency medical care or treatment was necessary for the patient’s health or physical well-being. The hospital records shall be open for inspection by the person legally responsible for the minor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person as delineated in subsection (1), hospital, or college health service shall incur civil liability by reason of having rendered emergency medical care or treatment pursuant to this section, provided such treatment or care was rendered in accordance with acceptable standards of medical practice.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-302; s. 66, ch. 86-220; s. 1, ch. 90-42; s. 1066, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>