<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0743.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Removal of disabilities of minors; artistic or creative services; professional sports contracts; procedure for court approval; appointment of a guardian ad litem.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proceeding for the approval of a contract described by s. 743.08 shall be commenced by verified petition by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Either natural parent of the minor, or other person having custody of the minor;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guardian of person or property of the minor;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any party to the contract sought to be approved; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other interested person.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a guardian of the person or property of the minor has been appointed or qualified in this state, the petition shall be made to the court by which he or she was appointed or in which he or she qualified. If there is no such guardian, the petition shall be made in the circuit court, probate division, or other circuit division having guardianship jurisdiction, in the circuit where the minor resides, or if he or she is not a resident of the state, in any county in which the minor is to be employed under the contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons, other than one who is the petitioner or who joins in the petition, shall be served with the petition by formal notice as provided by the Florida Probate Rules:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor, if over the age of 14 years.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">His or her guardian or guardians, if any, whether or not appointed or qualified in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each party to the contract.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent or parents of the minor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person having the care and custody of the minor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person with whom the minor resides, if other than a parent or guardian.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Formal notice shall be made at least 30 days before the time at which the petition is set to be heard, unless the court shall fix a shorter time upon cause shown.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition shall have annexed a complete copy of the contract or proposed contract and shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name, residence, and date of birth of the minor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and residence of any living parent of the minor, the name and residence of the person who has care and custody of the minor, and the name and residence of the person with whom the minor resides.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the minor is a resident of the state or, if he or she is not a resident, that the petition is for approval of a contract for performance or rendering of services by the minor and the place in the state where the services are to be performed or rendered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brief statement as to the minor’s employment and compensation under the contract or proposed contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the term of the contract during which the minor is to perform or render services or during which a person is employed to render services to the minor can in no event extend for a period of more than 3 years from the date of approval of the contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An enumeration of any other covenants or conditions contained in the contract which extend beyond such 3 years or a statement that the contract contains no such other covenants or conditions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A schedule showing the minor’s estimated gross earnings, estimated outlays, and estimated net earnings as defined in s. 743.095.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interest of the petitioner in the contract or proposed contract or in the minor’s performance under it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other facts known by the petitioner regarding the minor and his or her family and property as show that the contract is reasonable and provident and for the best interests of the minor, including whether the minor has had at any time a guardian appointed by a court of any jurisdiction, and the facts with respect to any previous application for the relief sought or whether similar relief has been sought with respect to the minor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time after the filing of the petition, the court, if it deems it advisable, may appoint a guardian ad litem, pursuant to s. 744.3025, to represent the interests of the minor. The court shall appoint a guardian ad litem as to any contract where the parent or guardian will receive remuneration or financial gain from the performance of the contract or has any other conflict of interest with the minor as defined by s. 744.446. The court, in determining whether a guardian ad litem should be appointed, may consider the following criteria:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The length of time the exclusive services of the minor are required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the gross earnings of the minor under the contract are either contingent or unknown.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the gross earnings of the minor under the contract are in excess of $15,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guardian ad litem shall be entitled to reasonable compensation. The court shall have the power to determine the amount of the reasonable compensation paid to the guardian ad litem and may determine which party shall be responsible for the fee, whether the fee shall be paid from the earnings of the minor pursuant to the contract sought to be approved, or may apportion the fee between the parties to the proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor, unless excused by the court for good cause shown, shall attend personally before the court upon the hearing of the petition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may, by order:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine any issue arising from the pleadings or proof and required to be determined for final disposition of the matter, including issues with respect to the age or emancipation of the minor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve or disapprove the contract or proposed contract.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve the contract upon such conditions, with respect to modification of the terms thereof or otherwise, as it shall determine.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a guardian of the property to hold the earnings of the minor as provided by s. 743.095.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 39, ch. 95-401; s. 149, ch. 2007-5.</History></Section>