<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0743.0645" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Other persons who may consent to medical care or treatment of a minor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Blood testing” includes Early Periodic Screening, Diagnosis, and Treatment (EPSDT) testing and other blood testing deemed necessary by documented history or symptomatology but excludes HIV testing and controlled substance testing or any other testing for which separate court order or informed consent as provided by law is required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical care and treatment” includes ordinary and necessary medical and dental examination and treatment, including blood testing, preventive care including ordinary immunizations, tuberculin testing, and well-child care, but does not include surgery, general anesthesia, provision of psychotropic medications, or other extraordinary procedures for which a separate court order, power of attorney, or informed consent as provided by law is required, except as provided in s. 39.407(3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person who has the power to consent as otherwise provided by law” includes a natural or adoptive parent, legal custodian, or legal guardian.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the following persons, in order of priority listed, may consent to the medical care or treatment of a minor who is not committed to the Department of Children and Family Services or the Department of Juvenile Justice or in their custody under chapter 39, chapter 984, or chapter 985 when, after a reasonable attempt, a person who has the power to consent as otherwise provided by law cannot be contacted by the treatment provider and actual notice to the contrary has not been given to the provider by that person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who possesses a power of attorney to provide medical consent for the minor. A power of attorney executed after July 1, 2001, to provide medical consent for a minor includes the power to consent to medically necessary surgical and general anesthesia services for the minor unless such services are excluded by the individual executing the power of attorney.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The stepparent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grandparent of the minor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adult brother or sister of the minor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adult aunt or uncle of the minor.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">There shall be maintained in the treatment provider’s records of the minor documentation that a reasonable attempt was made to contact the person who has the power to consent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services or the Department of Juvenile Justice caseworker, juvenile probation officer, or person primarily responsible for the case management of the child, the administrator of any facility licensed by the department under s. 393.067, s. 394.875, or s. 409.175, or the administrator of any state-operated or state-contracted delinquency residential treatment facility may consent to the medical care or treatment of any minor committed to it or in its custody under chapter 39, chapter 984, or chapter 985, when the person who has the power to consent as otherwise provided by law cannot be contacted and such person has not expressly objected to such consent. There shall be maintained in the records of the minor documentation that a reasonable attempt was made to contact the person who has the power to consent as otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The medical provider shall notify the parent or other person who has the power to consent as otherwise provided by law as soon as possible after the medical care or treatment is administered pursuant to consent given under this section. The medical records shall reflect the reason consent as otherwise provided by law was not initially obtained and shall be open for inspection by the parent or other person who has the power to consent as otherwise provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person who gives consent; a physician, dentist, nurse, or other health care professional licensed to practice in this state; or a hospital or medical facility, including, but not limited to, county health departments, shall not incur civil liability by reason of the giving of consent, examination, or rendering of treatment, provided that such consent, examination, or treatment was given or rendered as a reasonable prudent person or similar health care professional would give or render it under the same or similar circumstances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services and the Department of Juvenile Justice may adopt rules to implement this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect other statutory provisions of this state that relate to medical consent for minors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 90-42; s. 10, ch. 93-230; s. 155, ch. 97-101; s. 47, ch. 98-280; s. 82, ch. 99-3; s. 23, ch. 2001-53; s. 4, ch. 2005-65.</History></Section>