<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0367.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any utility, by any authorized officer, agent, or employee, knowingly refuses to comply with, or willfully violates, any provision of this chapter or any lawful rule or order of the commission, such utility shall incur a penalty for each such offense of not more than $5,000, to be fixed, imposed, and collected by the commission. However, any penalty assessed by the commission for a violation of s. 367.111(2) shall be reduced by any penalty assessed by any other state agency for the same violation. Each day that such refusal or violation continues constitutes a separate offense. Each penalty shall be a lien upon the real and personal property of the utility, enforceable by the commission as statutory liens under chapter 85. The proceeds from the enforcement of any such lien shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission has the power to impose upon any entity that is subject to its jurisdiction under this chapter and that is found to have refused to comply with, or to have willfully violated, any lawful rule or order of the commission or any provision of this chapter a penalty for each offense of not more than $5,000, which penalty shall be fixed, imposed, and collected by the commission; or the commission may, for any such violation, amend, suspend, or revoke any certificate of authorization issued by it. Each day that such refusal or violation continues constitutes a separate offense. Each penalty shall be a lien upon the real and personal property of the entity, enforceable by the commission as a statutory lien under chapter 85. The collected penalties shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund unallocated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-278; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 21, 25, 26, ch. 80-99; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 8, ch. 84-149; ss. 21, 26, 27, ch. 89-353; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>