<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0367.0817" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reuse projects.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A utility may submit a reuse project plan for commission approval. A reuse project plan shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the project and other effluent disposal options considered by the utility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of the pertinent Department of Environmental Protection and water management district permit applications filed or, in lieu thereof, a statement of the project’s permit status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the reuse project is required or recommended pursuant to s. 403.064 or other relevant authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and identity of the project’s proposed reuse customer(s) and copies of written agreements, if any, between the utility and the customer(s) regarding the project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The projected costs associated with the reuse project. As used in this section, the term “costs” includes, but is not limited to, all capital investments, including a rate of return, any applicable taxes, and all expenses related to or resulting from the reuse project which were not considered in the utility’s last rate proceeding.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The utility’s proposal for recovering the project’s costs through rates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proposed inservice schedule for the project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information the commission may require pursuant to rule.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall review the utility’s reuse project plan and shall determine whether the projected costs are prudent and the proposed rates are reasonable and in the public interest. The commission shall issue a proposed agency action order to approve or disapprove the utility’s reuse project plan. The commission shall enter its vote on the proposed agency action within 5 months of the date of filing. If the commission’s proposed action is protested, the final decision shall be rendered by the commission within 8 months of the date the protest is filed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All prudent costs of a reuse project shall be recovered in rates. The Legislature finds that reuse benefits water, wastewater, and reuse customers. The commission shall allow a utility to recover the costs of a reuse project from the utility’s water, wastewater, or reuse customers or any combination thereof as deemed appropriate by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission’s order approving the reuse project plan shall approve rates based on projected costs and shall provide for the implementation of rates without the need for a subsequent proceeding. The commission shall allow the approved rates to be implemented when the reuse project plan is approved or when the project is placed in service. If the commission allows the rates to be implemented when the plan is approved, the commission may order the utility to escrow the resulting revenues until the project is placed in service. Escrowed revenues shall be used exclusively for the reuse project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the commission allows the rates to be implemented when the plan is approved, the utility may place its proposed rates into effect on a temporary basis, subject to refund, in the event of a protest by a party other than the utility. If the utility has requested rate implementation upon approval of the plan and the commission has exceeded the time allowed in subsection (2), the utility may place its proposed rates into effect on a temporary basis, subject to refund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the reuse project is placed in service, the commission, by petition or on its own motion, may initiate a proceeding to true-up the costs of the reuse project and the resulting rates.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-243.</History></Section>