<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0367.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each utility shall provide service to the area described in its certificate of authorization within a reasonable time. If the commission finds that any utility has failed to provide service to any person reasonably entitled thereto, or finds that extension of service to any such person could be accomplished only at an unreasonable cost and that addition of the deleted area to that of another utility company is economical and feasible, it may amend the certificate of authorization to delete the area not served or not properly served by the utility, or it may rescind the certificate of authorization. If utility service has not been provided to any part of the area which a utility is authorized to serve, whether or not there has been a demand for such service, within 5 years after the date of authorization for service to such part, such authorization may be reviewed and amended or revoked by the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each utility shall provide to each person reasonably entitled thereto such safe, efficient, and sufficient service as is prescribed by part VI of chapter 403 and parts I and II of chapter 373, or rules adopted pursuant thereto; but such service shall not be less safe, less efficient, or less sufficient than is consistent with the approved engineering design of the system and the reasonable and proper operation of the utility in the public interest. If the commission finds that a utility has failed to provide its customers with water or wastewater service that meets the standards promulgated by the Department of Environmental Protection or the water management districts, the commission may reduce the utility’s return on equity until the standards are met.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-278; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 53, ch. 78-95; ss. 1, 2, ch. 79-49; ss. 14, 25, 26, ch. 80-99; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 15, 26, 27, ch. 89-353; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 10, ch. 93-35; s. 185, ch. 94-356.</History></Section>