<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0367.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are not subject to regulation by the commission as a utility nor are they subject to the provisions of this chapter, except as expressly provided:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale, distribution, or furnishing of bottled water.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Systems owned, operated, managed, or controlled by governmental authorities, including water or wastewater facilities operated by private firms under water or wastewater facility privatization contracts as defined in s. 153.91, and nonprofit corporations formed for the purpose of acting on behalf of a political subdivision with respect to a water or wastewater facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufacturers providing service solely in connection with their operations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public lodging establishments providing service solely in connection with service to their guests.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Landlords providing service to their tenants without specific compensation for the service.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Systems with the capacity or proposed capacity to serve 100 or fewer persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonprofit corporations, associations, or cooperatives providing service solely to members who own and control such nonprofit corporations, associations, or cooperatives.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who resells water or wastewater service at a rate or charge which does not exceed the actual purchase price of the water or wastewater.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wastewater treatment plants operated exclusively for disposing of industrial wastewater.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of bulk supplies of desalinated water to a governmental authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person providing only nonpotable water for irrigation or fireflow purposes in a geographic area where potable water service is available from a governmentally or privately owned utility or a private well.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale for resale of bulk supplies of water or the sale or resale of wastewater services to a governmental authority or to a utility regulated pursuant to this chapter either by the commission or the county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-278; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 3, 25, 26, ch. 80-99; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 26, 27, ch. 89-353; s. 1, ch. 90-166; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 96-107; s. 10, ch. 96-202; s. 24, ch. 97-236; s. 4, ch. 99-319; s. 39, ch. 2002-296.</History></Section>