<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0180.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purchase, sale, or privatization of water, sewer, or wastewater reuse utility by municipality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No municipality may purchase or sell a water, sewer, or wastewater reuse utility that provides service to the public for compensation, or enter into a wastewater facility privatization contract for a wastewater facility until the governing body of the municipality has held a public hearing on the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract, and made a determination that the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract is in the public interest. In determining if the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract is in the public interest, the municipality shall consider, at a minimum, the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The most recent available income and expense statement for the utility;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The most recent available balance sheet for the utility, listing assets and liabilities and clearly showing the amount of contributions-in-aid-of-construction and the accumulated depreciation thereon;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the existing rate base of the utility for regulatory purposes;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physical condition of the utility facilities being purchased, sold, or subject to a wastewater facility privatization contract;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasonableness of the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract price and terms;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The impacts of the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract on utility customers, both positive and negative;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional investment required and the ability and willingness of the purchaser or the private firm under a wastewater facility privatization contract to make that investment, whether the purchaser is the municipality or the entity purchasing the utility from the municipality;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a wastewater facility privatization contract, the terms and conditions on which the private firm will provide capital investment and financing or a combination thereof for contemplated capital replacements, additions, expansions, and repairs. The municipality shall give significant weight to this criterion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The alternatives to the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract, and the potential impact on utility customers if the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract is not made; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability of the purchaser or the private firm under a wastewater facility privatization contract to provide and maintain high-quality and cost-effective utility service, whether the purchaser is the municipality or the entity purchasing the utility from the municipality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a wastewater facility privatization contract, the municipality shall give significant weight to the technical expertise and experience of the private firm in carrying out the obligation specified in the wastewater facility privatization contract.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys paid by a private firm to a municipality pursuant to a wastewater facility privatization contract shall be used for the purpose of reducing or offsetting property taxes, wastewater service rates, or debt reduction or making infrastructure improvements or capital asset expenditures or other public purpose; provided, however, nothing herein shall preclude the municipality from using all or part of the moneys for the purpose of the municipality’s qualification for relief from the repayment of federal grant awards associated with the wastewater system as may be required by federal law or regulation.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The municipality shall prepare a statement showing that the purchase, sale, or wastewater facility privatization contract is in the public interest, including a summary of the purchaser’s or private firm’s experience in water, sewer, or wastewater reuse utility operation and a showing of financial ability to provide the service, whether the purchaser is the municipality or the entity purchasing the utility from the municipality.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 84-84; s. 6, ch. 93-51; s. 7, ch. 96-202.</History></Section>