<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0698.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice given by filing for record of chattel mortgages generally, to extend 7 years.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice given to third persons by the filing for record of any mortgage or other security instrument, except mortgages or other instruments given to secure future advances, creating a lien on, or conveying or reserving an interest in, personal property, or agricultural, horticultural, or fruit crops planted, growing or to be planted, grown or raised, shall, unless otherwise provided by law, expire at the end of 7 years from the date of the filing thereof for record.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice given to third persons by the filing for record of any mortgage or other security instrument given to secure future advances, creating a lien on, or conveying or reserving an interest in, personal property or agricultural, horticultural, or fruit crops planted, growing, or to be planted, grown, or raised, shall, unless otherwise provided by law, expire at the end of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seven years from the date of maturity of the debts or obligations last maturing thereunder and secured by such mortgages or other security instruments, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seven years from the last date an advance could validly be made thereunder so as to be secured thereby,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">whichever of said dates is later.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provided, however, that this law shall not apply to any mortgage or other security instrument creating a lien on, or conveying or reserving an interest in, or in respect of property owned by, or sold or leased to, or agreed to be sold or leased to, any railroad corporation, where such mortgage has been or shall be recorded in the county in the state in which the mortgaged property is situated or, in the case of such other instrument, where such other instrument has been or shall be recorded in the office of the Department of State. Provided further, however, that this law shall not apply to any mortgage or other security instrument given to secure any indebtedness to the United States, or any agency or instrumentality thereof, incurred under the Rural Electrification Act of 1939, as amended.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 17112, 1935; CGL 1936 Supp. 5727(7); s. 1, ch. 20921, 1941; s. 1, ch. 26889, 1951; s. 4, ch. 63-212; ss. 10, 35, ch. 69-106.</History></Section>