<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for certificate of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign limited liability company may apply for a certificate of authority to transact business in this state by delivering an application to the Department of State for filing. Such application shall be made on forms prescribed and furnished by the Department of State and shall set forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the foreign limited liability company, which shall satisfy the requirements of s. 608.506.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction under the law of which it is organized.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its date of organization and period of duration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of its principal office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The street address of its registered office in this state and the name of its registered agent at that office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether or not the limited liability company is manager-managed and, if so, the usual business addresses of its managing members or managers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of the business or purposes to be conducted or promoted in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such additional information as may be necessary or appropriate in order to enable the Department of State to determine whether such limited liability company is entitled to file an application for authority to transact business in this state and to determine and assess the fees, penalties, and taxes payable as prescribed in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company shall deliver with the completed application a certificate of existence, or a document of similar import, duly authenticated by the official having custody of records in the jurisdiction under the law of which it is organized, not more than 90 days prior to delivery of the application to the Department of State. A translation of the certificate, under oath of the translator, shall be attached to a certificate which is in a language other than the English language.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A foreign limited liability company shall not be denied authority to transact business in this state by reason of the fact that the laws of the jurisdiction under which such limited liability company is organized governing its organization and internal affairs differ from the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 61, ch. 93-284; s. 1, ch. 99-315.</History></Section>