<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.4225" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">General standards for managers and managing members.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to ss. 608.4226 and 608.423, each manager and managing member shall owe a duty of loyalty and a duty of care to the limited liability company and all of the members of the limited liability company.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to s. 608.4226, the duty of loyalty is limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accounting to the limited liability company and holding as trustee for the limited liability company any property, profit, or benefit derived by such manager or managing member in the conduct or winding up of the limited liability company business or derived from a use by such manager or managing member of limited liability company property, including the appropriation of a limited liability company opportunity.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refraining from dealing with the limited liability company in the conduct or winding up of the limited liability company business as or on behalf of a party having an interest adverse to the limited liability company.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refraining from competing with the limited liability company in the conduct of the limited liability company business before the dissolution of the limited liability company.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duty of care is limited to refraining from engaging in grossly negligent or reckless conduct, intentional misconduct, or a knowing violation of law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manager and managing member shall discharge the duties to the limited liability company and its members under this chapter or under the articles of organization or operating agreement and exercise any rights consistent with the obligation of good faith and fair dealing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager or managing member does not violate a duty or obligation under this chapter or under the articles of organization or operating agreement merely because the manager’s or managing member’s conduct furthers such manager’s or managing member’s own interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager or managing member may lend money to and transact other business with the limited liability company. As to each loan or transaction, the rights and obligations of the manager or managing member are the same as those of a person who is not a member, subject to other applicable law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to a person winding up the limited liability company business as the personal or other legal representative of the last surviving member as if such person were a manager or managing member.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In discharging a manager’s or managing member’s duties, a manager or managing member is entitled to rely on information, opinions, reports, or statements, including financial statements and other financial data, if prepared or presented by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more members or employees of the limited liability company whom the manager or managing member reasonably believes to be reliable and competent in the matters presented;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legal counsel, public accountants, or other persons as to matters the manager or managing member reasonably believes are within the persons’ professional or expert competence; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A committee of managers, members, or managing members of which the affected manager or managing member is not a participant if the manager or managing member reasonably believes the committee merits confidence.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In discharging a manager’s or managing member’s duties, a manager or managing member may consider such factors as the manager or managing member deems relevant, including the long-term prospects and interests of the limited liability company and its members, and the social, economic, legal, or other effects of any action on the employees, suppliers, customers of the limited liability company, the communities and society in which the limited liability company operates, and the economy of the state and the nation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member, manager, or managing member is not acting in good faith if the member, manager, or managing member has knowledge concerning the matter in question that makes reliance otherwise permitted by subsection (2) unwarranted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager or managing member is not liable for any action taken as a manager or managing member, or any failure to take any action, if the manager or managing member performed the duties of the manager’s or managing member’s position in compliance with this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 93-284; s. 51, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 11, ch. 2002-272; s. 5, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>