<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.471" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax exemption on income of certain limited liability companies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited liability company classified as a partnership for federal income tax purposes, or a single member limited liability company which is disregarded as an entity separate from its owner for federal income tax purposes, and organized pursuant to this chapter or qualified to do business in this state as a foreign limited liability company is not an “artificial entity” within the purview of s. 220.02 and is not subject to the tax imposed under chapter 220. If a single member limited liability company is disregarded as an entity separate from its owner for federal income tax purposes, its activities are, for purposes of taxation under chapter 220, treated in the same manner as a sole proprietorship, branch, or division of the owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of taxation under chapter 220, a limited liability company formed in this state or authorized to transact business in this state as a foreign limited liability company shall be classified as a partnership, or a limited liability company which has only one member shall be disregarded as an entity separate from its owner for federal income tax purposes, unless classified otherwise for federal income tax purposes, in which case the limited liability company shall be classified identically to its classification for federal income tax purposes. For purposes of taxation under chapter 220, a member or an assignee of a member of a limited liability company formed in this state or qualified to do business in this state as a foreign limited liability company shall be treated as a resident or nonresident partner unless classified otherwise for federal income tax purposes, in which case the member or assignee of a member shall have the same status as such member or assignee of a member has for federal income tax purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Single-member limited liability companies and other entities that are disregarded for federal income tax purposes must be treated as separate legal entities for all non-income-tax purposes. The Department of Revenue shall adopt rules to take into account that single-member disregarded entities such as limited liability companies and qualified subchapter S corporations may be disregarded as separate entities for federal tax purposes and therefore may report and account for income, employment, and other taxes under the taxpayer identification number of the owner of the single-member entity.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 73, ch. 83-216; s. 58, ch. 93-284; s. 14, ch. 98-101; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 53, ch. 2002-218.</History></Section>