<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.4492" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Receivership or custodianship.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court in a judicial proceeding brought to dissolve a limited liability company may appoint one or more receivers to wind up and liquidate, or one or more custodians to manage, the business and affairs of the limited liability company. The court shall hold a hearing, after notifying all parties to the proceeding and any interested persons designated by the court, before appointing a receiver or custodian. The court appointing a receiver or custodian has exclusive jurisdiction over the limited liability company and all of its property wherever located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may appoint a person authorized to act as a receiver or custodian. The court may require the receiver or custodian to post bond, with or without sureties, in an amount the court directs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall describe the powers and duties of the receiver or custodian in its appointing order, which may be amended from time to time. Among other powers:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The receiver:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May dispose of all or any part of the assets of the limited liability company wherever located, at a public or private sale, if authorized by the court.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May sue and defend in the receiver’s own name as receiver of the limited liability company in all courts of this state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The custodian may exercise all of the powers of the limited liability company, through or in place of its managers or members, to the extent necessary to manage the affairs of the limited liability company in the best interests of its members and creditors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court during a receivership may redesignate the receiver a custodian, and during a custodianship may redesignate the custodian a receiver, if doing so is in the best interests of the limited liability company and its members and creditors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court from time to time during the receivership or custodianship may order compensation paid and expense disbursements or reimbursements made to the receiver or custodian and the receiver’s or custodian’s counsel from the assets of the limited liability company or proceeds from the sale of assets.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court has jurisdiction to appoint an ancillary receiver for the assets and business of a limited liability company. The ancillary receiver shall serve ancillary to a receiver located in any other state, whenever the court deems that circumstances exist requiring the appointment of such a receiver. The court may appoint such an ancillary receiver for a foreign limited liability company even though no receiver has been appointed elsewhere. Such receivership shall be converted into an ancillary receivership when an order entered by a court of competent jurisdiction in the other state provides for a receivership of the limited liability company.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 52, ch. 93-284; s. 62, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-315.</History></Section>