<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.4359" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court costs and counsel fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court in an appraisal proceeding shall determine all costs of the proceeding, including the reasonable compensation and expenses of appraisers appointed by the court. The court shall assess the costs against the limited liability company, except that the court may assess costs against all or some of the members demanding appraisal, in amounts the court finds equitable, to the extent the court finds such members acted arbitrarily, vexatiously, or not in good faith with respect to the rights provided by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court in an appraisal proceeding may also assess the fees and expenses of counsel and experts for the respective parties, in amounts the court finds equitable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Against the limited liability company and in favor of any or all members demanding appraisal if the court finds the limited liability company did not substantially comply with ss. 608.4353 and 608.4356; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Against either the limited liability company or a member demanding appraisal, in favor of any other party, if the court finds that the party against whom the fees and expenses are assessed acted arbitrarily, vexatiously, or not in good faith with respect to the rights provided by this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court in an appraisal proceeding finds that the services of counsel for any member were of substantial benefit to other members similarly situated, and that the fees for those services should not be assessed against the limited liability company, the court may award to such counsel reasonable fees to be paid out of the amounts awarded the members who were benefited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the extent the limited liability company fails to make a required payment pursuant to s. 608.43575, the member may sue directly for the amount owed and, to the extent successful, shall be entitled to recover from the limited liability company all costs and expenses of the suit, including attorney’s fees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>