<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.449" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for judicial dissolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A circuit court may dissolve a limited liability company:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by the Department of Legal Affairs if it is established that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company obtained its articles of organization through fraud; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company has continued to exceed or abuse the authority conferred upon it by law.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enumeration in paragraph (a) of grounds for involuntary dissolution does not exclude actions or special proceedings by the Department of Legal Affairs or any state official for the annulment or dissolution of a limited liability company for other causes as provided in any other law of this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by a manager or member if it is established that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managers, managing members, or members are deadlocked in the management of the limited liability company affairs, the members are unable to break the deadlock, and irreparable injury to the limited liability company is threatened or being suffered; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company’s assets are being misappropriated or wasted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by a creditor if it is established that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The creditor’s claim has been reduced to judgment, the execution on that judgment returned unsatisfied, and the limited liability company is insolvent; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company has admitted in writing that the creditor’s claim is due and owing and the limited liability company is insolvent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by the limited liability company to have its voluntary dissolution continued under court supervision.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 50, ch. 93-284; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 28, ch. 2002-272.</History></Section>