<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.448" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for administrative dissolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may commence a proceeding under s. 608.4481 to administratively dissolve a limited liability company if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company has failed to file its annual report and pay the annual report filing fee by 5 p.m. Eastern Time on the third Friday in September.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company is without a registered agent or registered office in this state for 30 days or more.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company does not notify the Department of State within 30 days that its registered agent or registered office has been changed, that its registered agent has resigned, or that its registered office has been discontinued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company has failed to answer truthfully and fully, within 30 days after mailing or within such additional time as fixed by the Department of State, interrogatories propounded by the Department of State.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company’s period of duration has expired.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The enumeration in subsection (1) of grounds for administrative dissolution shall not exclude actions or special proceedings by the Department of Legal Affairs or any state officials for the annulment or dissolution of a limited liability company for other causes as provided in any other law of this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 46, ch. 93-284; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 13, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>