<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless its articles of organization or operating agreement provide otherwise, each limited liability company organized and existing under this chapter shall have the same powers as an individual to do all things necessary to carry out its business and affairs, including, without limitation, the power to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sue and be sued, and defend, in its name.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase, receive, lease, or otherwise acquire, own, hold, improve, use, and otherwise deal with real or personal property, or any legal or equitable interest in property, wherever located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell, convey, mortgage, grant a security interest in, lease, exchange, and otherwise encumber or dispose of all or any part of its property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase, receive, subscribe for, or otherwise acquire, own, hold, vote, use, sell, mortgage, lend, grant a security interest in, or otherwise dispose of and deal in and with, shares or other interests in or obligations of any other entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make contracts or guarantees, or incur liabilities; borrow money; issue its notes, bonds, or other obligations, which may be convertible into or include the option to purchase other securities of the limited liability company; or make contracts of guaranty and suretyship which are necessary or convenient to the conduct, promotion, or attainment of the business of a corporation the majority of the outstanding stock of which is owned, directly or indirectly, by the contracting limited liability company; a corporation which owns, directly or indirectly, a majority of the outstanding membership interests of the contracting limited liability company; or a corporation the majority of the outstanding stock of which is owned, directly or indirectly, by a corporation which owns, directly or indirectly, the majority of the outstanding membership interests of the contracting limited liability company, which contracts of guaranty and suretyship shall be deemed to be necessary or convenient to the conduct, promotion, or attainment of the business of the contracting limited liability company; or make other contracts of guaranty and suretyship which are necessary or convenient to the conduct, promotion, or attainment of the business of the contracting limited liability company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Lend money, invest or reinvest its funds, and receive and hold real or personal property as security for repayment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct its business, locate offices, and exercise the powers granted by this chapter within or without this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Select managers or managing members and appoint officers, directors, employees, and agents of the limited liability company, define their duties, fix their compensation, and lend them money and credit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make donations for the public welfare or for charitable, scientific, or educational purposes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay pensions and establish pension plans, pension trusts, profit-sharing plans, bonus plans, option plans, and benefit or incentive plans for any or all of its current or former managers, members, officers, agents, and employees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be a promoter, incorporator, shareholder, partner, member, associate, or manager of any corporation, partnership, joint venture, trust, or other entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make payments or donations or do any other act not inconsistent with law that furthers the business of the limited liability company.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 54, ch. 83-216; s. 6, ch. 93-284; s. 47, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 3, ch. 2002-272.</History></Section>