<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.408" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Execution of articles, certificate, or statement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any articles, certificate, or statement required by this chapter to be filed with the Department of State must be executed in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is the articles of organization, a certificate of conversion, or a statement of change of registered agent or registered office, it must be signed by a member or by the authorized representative of a member, and by the new registered agent, if applicable; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is the articles of dissolution or revocation of dissolution, it must be signed by members having the same percentage of membership interests necessary to approve the dissolution or revocation of dissolution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person may sign a certificate through an attorney in fact, but a power of attorney to sign a certificate or statement authorizing the admission of a member must specifically describe the admission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The execution of a certificate constitutes an affirmation by the person executing the certificate, under the penalties of perjury, that the facts stated therein are true.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the articles of organization contain or any other document authorized or required to be filed under this chapter contains a false statement, one who suffers loss by reliance on the statement may recover damages for the loss from a person who signed the record or caused another to sign it on the person’s behalf and knew the statement to be false at the time the record was signed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 56, ch. 83-216; s. 12, ch. 93-284; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 5, ch. 2002-272.</History></Section>