<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.4228" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitation of liability of managers and managing members.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager or a managing member shall not be personally liable for monetary damages to the limited liability company, its members, or any other person for any statement, vote, decision, or failure to act regarding management or policy decisions by a manager or a managing member, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manager or managing member breached or failed to perform the duties as a manager or managing member; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manager’s or managing member’s breach of, or failure to perform, those duties constitutes any of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the criminal law, unless the manager or managing member had a reasonable cause to believe his or her conduct was lawful or had no reasonable cause to believe such conduct was unlawful. A judgment or other final adjudication against a manager or managing member in any criminal proceeding for a violation of the criminal law estops that manager or managing member from contesting the fact that such breach, or failure to perform, constitutes a violation of the criminal law, but does not estop the manager or managing member from establishing that he or she had reasonable cause to believe that his or her conduct was lawful or had no reasonable cause to believe that such conduct was unlawful.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A transaction from which the manager or managing member derived an improper personal benefit, either directly or indirectly.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A distribution in violation of s. 608.426.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by or in the right of the limited liability company to procure a judgment in its favor or by or in the right of a member, conscious disregard of the best interest of the limited liability company, or willful misconduct.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a proceeding by or in the right of someone other than the limited liability company or a member, recklessness or an act or omission which was committed in bad faith or with malicious purpose or in a manner exhibiting wanton and willful disregard of human rights, safety, or property.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “recklessness” means acting, or failing to act, in conscious disregard of a risk known, or so obvious that it should have been known, to the manager or managing member, and known to the manager or managing member, or so obvious that it should have been known, to be so great as to make it highly probable that harm would follow from such action or failure to act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager or managing member is deemed not to have derived an improper personal benefit from any transaction if the transaction and the nature of any personal benefit derived by the manager or managing member are not prohibited by state or federal law or the articles of organization or operating agreement and, without further limitation, the transaction and the nature of any personal benefit derived by a manager or managing member are disclosed or known to the members, and the transaction was authorized, approved, or ratified by the vote of a majority-in-interest of the members other than the managing member, or the transaction was fair and reasonable to the limited liability company at the time it was authorized by the manager or managing member, notwithstanding that a manager or managing member received a personal benefit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circumstances set forth in subsection (3) are not exclusive and do not preclude the existence of other circumstances under which a manager will be deemed not to have derived an improper benefit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 37, ch. 93-284; s. 58, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 14, ch. 2002-272.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 608.4362.</Text></Note></Section>