<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.422" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Management of the limited liability company.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in its articles of organization or the operating agreement, the limited liability company shall be a member-managed company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a member-managed company, unless otherwise provided in its articles of organization or operating agreement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management shall be vested in its members or elected managing members in proportion to the then-current percentage or other interest of members in the profits of the limited liability company owned by all of the members or elected managing members.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3) or in this chapter, the decision of a majority-in-interest of the members or elected managing members shall be controlling.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the articles of organization or the operating agreement provide for the management of the limited liability company by a manager or managers, the management of the limited liability company shall be vested in a manager or managers and the limited liability company shall be a manager-managed company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a manager-managed company, unless otherwise provided in its articles of organization or operating agreement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manager has equal rights in the management and conduct of the limited liability company’s business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3) or in this chapter, any matter relating to the business of the limited liability company may be exclusively decided by the manager or, if there is more than one manager, by a majority of the managers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must be designated, appointed, elected, removed, or replaced by a vote, approval, or consent of a majority-in-interest of the members; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds office until a successor has been elected and qualified, unless the manager sooner resigns or is removed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Action requiring the consent of members or managers under this chapter may be taken without a meeting, subject to the limitations of s. 608.4231.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of organization or operating agreement, a member, managing member, or manager may appoint a proxy to vote or otherwise act for the member, managing member, or manager by signing an appointment instrument, either personally or by the member’s, managing member’s, or manager’s attorney-in-fact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of organization or operating agreement, a member, managing member, or manager may also hold the offices and have such other responsibilities accorded to them by the members and set out in the articles of organization or the operating agreement of the limited liability company.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 22, ch. 93-284; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 10, ch. 2002-272.</History></Section>