<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.426" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Distributions; impairment of capital.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limited liability company may make distributions to its members in accordance with the provisions contained in the operating agreement, except that no distribution may be made if after the distribution the limited liability company would be insolvent. If the operating agreement does not provide for the payment of distributions to members, the distributions shall be made on the basis of the agreed value, as stated in the records of the limited liability company, of the contributions made by each member to the extent they have been received by the limited liability company and have not been returned.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managers or managing members of a limited liability company may base a determination that a distribution is not prohibited under subsection (1) either on financial statements prepared on the basis of accounting practices and principles that are reasonable in the circumstances or on a fair valuation or other method that is reasonable in the circumstances. In the case of any distribution based upon such financial statement or such a valuation, each such distribution shall be identified as a distribution based upon such financial statements or a fair valuation of assets, and the amount distributed shall be disclosed to the receiving members concurrent with their receipt of the distribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager or managing member who votes for or assents to a distribution made in violation of this section, the articles of incorporation, or the operating agreement, is personally liable to the limited liability company for the amount of the distribution that exceeds what could have been distributed without such violation if it is established that the manager or managing member did not perform the manager’s or managing member’s duties in compliance with s. 608.4225. In any proceeding commenced under this section, a manager or managing member has all of the defenses ordinarily available to a manager or managing member.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manager or managing member held liable under subsection (3) for an unlawful distribution is entitled to contribution:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From every other manager or managing member who is also liable under subsection (3) for the unlawful distribution; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From each member to the extent of the amount the member accepted knowing the distribution was made in violation of this section, the articles of incorporation, or the operating agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proceeding under this section is barred unless it is commenced within 2 years after the date on which the distribution was made. In the case of a distribution in the form of indebtedness, each payment of principal or interest is treated as a distribution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 40, ch. 83-215; s. 29, ch. 93-284; s. 52, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-315.</History></Section>