<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.427" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Withdrawal of member and distribution upon withdrawal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member may withdraw from a limited liability company only at the time or upon the occurrence of an event specified in the articles of organization or operating agreement and in accordance with the articles of organization or operating agreement. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary under applicable law, unless the articles of organization or operating agreement provides otherwise, a member may not resign from a limited liability company prior to the dissolution and winding up of the limited liability company. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary under applicable law, the articles of organization or operating agreement may provide that a limited liability company interest may not be assigned prior to the dissolution and winding up of the limited liability company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon withdrawal, a withdrawing member is entitled to receive any distribution to which the withdrawing member is entitled under the articles of organization or operating agreement, and, if not otherwise provided in the articles of organization and operating agreement, the withdrawing member is entitled to receive, within a reasonable time after withdrawal, the fair value of the withdrawing member’s interest in the limited liability company as of the date of resignation based upon the withdrawing member’s right to share in distributions from the limited liability company.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of a statement in the articles of organization or the operating agreement to the contrary or the consent of all members of the limited liability company, a member, irrespective of the nature of the member’s contribution, has only the right to demand and receive cash in return for the member’s contribution to capital.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 31, ch. 93-284; s. 53, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-315.</History></Section>