<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.4235" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agency of members and managers or managing members.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsections (2) and (3):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a member-managed company, each member is an agent of the limited liability company for the purpose of its business, and an act of a member, including the signing of an instrument in the limited liability company’s name, for apparently carrying on in the ordinary course the limited liability company’s business or business of the kind carried on by the company binds the limited liability company, unless the member had no authority to act for the limited liability company in the particular matter and the person with whom the member was dealing knew or had notice that the member lacked authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act of a member which is not apparently for carrying on in the ordinary course the limited liability company’s business or business of the kind carried on by the limited liability company binds the limited liability company only if the act was authorized by appropriate vote of the other members.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to subsection (3), in a manager-managed company:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member is not an agent of the limited liability company for the purpose of its business solely by reason of being a member. Each manager is an agent of the limited liability company for the purpose of its business, and an act of a manager, including the signing of an instrument in the limited liability company’s name, for apparently carrying on in the ordinary course the limited liability company’s business or business of the kind carried on by the company binds the limited liability company, unless the manager had no authority to act for the limited liability company in the particular matter and the person with whom the manager was dealing knew or had notice that the manager lacked authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An act of a manager which is not apparently for carrying on in the ordinary course the limited liability company’s business or business of the kind carried on by the limited liability company binds the limited liability company only if the act was authorized under s. 608.422.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the articles of organization or operating agreement limit the authority of a member, any member of a member-managed company or manager of a manager-managed company may sign and deliver any instrument transferring or affecting the limited liability company’s interest in real property. The instrument is conclusive in favor of a person who gives value without knowledge of the lack of the authority of the person signing and delivering the instrument.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 18, ch. 2002-272.</History></Section>