<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.452" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Fees of the Department of State.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees of the Department of State under this chapter are as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For furnishing a certified copy, $30.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing original articles of organization, articles of revocation of dissolution, or a foreign limited liability company’s application for a certificate of authority to transact business, $100.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing a certificate of merger of limited liability companies or other business entities, $25 per constituent party to the merger, unless a specific fee is required for a party in other applicable law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing an annual report, $50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing an application for reinstatement after an administrative or judicial dissolution or a revocation of authority to transact business, $100.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing a certificate designating a registered agent or changing a registered agent, $25.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing a registered agent’s statement of resignation from an active limited liability company, $85.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing a registered agent’s statement of resignation from a dissolved limited liability company, $25.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing a certificate of conversion of a limited liability company, $25.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filing any other limited liability company document, $25.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For furnishing a certificate of status, $5.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 70, ch. 83-216; s. 65, ch. 90-132; s. 27, ch. 92-319; s. 56, ch. 93-284; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 13, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>