<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.4352" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of members to appraisal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of a domestic limited liability company is entitled to appraisal rights, and to obtain payment of the fair value of that member’s membership interest, in the following events:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consummation of a merger of such limited liability company pursuant to this act and the member possessed the right to vote upon the merger; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consummation of a conversion of such limited liability company pursuant to this act and the member possessed the right to vote upon the conversion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), the availability of appraisal rights shall be limited in accordance with the following provisions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appraisal rights shall not be available for membership interests which are:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Listed on the New York Stock Exchange or the American Stock Exchange or designated as a national market system security on an interdealer quotation system by the National Association of Securities Dealers, Inc.; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not listed or designated as provided in subparagraph 1. but are issued by a limited liability company that has at least 500 members and all membership interests of the limited liability company, including membership interests that are limited to a right to receive distributions, have a market value of at least $10 million, exclusive of the value of any such interests held by its managing members, managers, and other senior executives owning more than 10 percent of the rights to receive distributions from the limited liability company.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicability of paragraph (a) shall be determined as of the date fixed to determine the members entitled to receive notice of, and to vote upon, the appraisal event.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (a) shall not apply, and appraisal rights shall be available pursuant to subsection (1), for any members who are required by the appraisal event to accept for their membership interests anything other than cash or a proprietary interest of an entity that satisfies the standards set forth in paragraph (a) at the time the appraisal event becomes effective.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (a) shall not apply, and appraisal rights shall be available pursuant to subsection (1), for the holders of a membership interest if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the members’ interests in the limited liability company or the limited liability company’s assets are being acquired or converted, whether by merger, conversion, or otherwise, pursuant to the appraisal event by a person, or by an affiliate of a person, who:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is, or at any time in the 1-year period immediately preceding approval of the appraisal event was, the beneficial owner of 20 percent or more of those interests in the limited liability company entitled to vote on the appraisal event, excluding any such interests acquired pursuant to an offer for all interests having such voting rights if such offer was made within 1 year prior to the appraisal event for consideration of the same kind and of a value equal to or less than that paid in connection with the appraisal event; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directly or indirectly has, or at any time in the 1-year period immediately preceding approval of the appraisal event had, the power, contractually or otherwise, to cause the appointment or election of any senior executives; or</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the members’ interests in the limited liability company or the limited liability company’s assets are being acquired or converted, whether by merger, conversion, or otherwise, pursuant to the appraisal event by a person, or by an affiliate of a person, who is, or at any time in the 1-year period immediately preceding approval of the appraisal event was, a senior executive of the limited liability company or a senior executive of any affiliate of the limited liability company, and that senior executive will receive, as a result of the limited liability company action, a financial benefit not generally available to members, other than:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employment, consulting, retirement, or similar benefits established separately and not as part of or in contemplation of the appraisal event;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employment, consulting, retirement, or similar benefits established in contemplation of, or as part of, the appraisal event that are not more favorable than those existing before the appraisal event or, if more favorable, that have been approved by the limited liability company; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a managing member or manager of the limited liability company who will, during or as the result of the appraisal event, become a managing member, manager, general partner, or director of the surviving or converted entity or one of its affiliates, those rights and benefits as a managing member, manager, general partner, or director that are provided on the same basis as those afforded by the surviving or converted entity generally to other managing members, managers, general partners, or directors of the surviving or converted entity or its affiliate.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of sub-subparagraph (d)1.a. only, the term “beneficial owner” means any person who, directly or indirectly, through any contract, arrangement, or understanding, other than a revocable proxy, has or shares the right to vote, or to direct the voting of, an interest in a limited liability company with respect to approval of the appraisal event, provided a member of a national securities exchange shall not be deemed to be a beneficial owner of an interest in a limited liability company held directly or indirectly by it on behalf of another person solely because such member is the recordholder of interests in the limited liability company if the member is precluded by the rules of such exchange from voting without instruction on contested matters or matters that may affect substantially the rights or privileges of the holders of the interests in the limited liability company to be voted. When two or more persons agree to act together for the purpose of voting such interests, each member of the group formed thereby shall be deemed to have acquired beneficial ownership, as of the date of such agreement, of all voting interests in the limited liability company beneficially owned by any member of the group.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member entitled to appraisal rights under this section and ss. 608.4353-608.43595 may not challenge a completed appraisal event unless the appraisal event:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was not effectuated in accordance with the applicable provisions of this section and ss. 608.4353-608.43595, or the limited liability company’s articles of organization or operating agreement; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was procured as a result of fraud or material misrepresentation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited liability company may modify, restrict, or eliminate the appraisal rights provided in this section and ss. 608.4353-608.43595 in its operating agreement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2005-267.</History></Section>