<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.512" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for revocation of authority to transact business.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State may commence a proceeding under s. 608.513 to revoke the certificate of authority of a foreign limited liability company authorized to transact business in this state if:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company has failed to file its annual report with the Department of State by 5 p.m. Eastern Time on the third Friday in September.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company does not pay, within the time required by this chapter, any fees, taxes, or penalties imposed by this chapter or other law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company is without a registered agent or registered office in this state for 30 days or more.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company does not notify the Department of State under s. 608.508 or s. 608.509 that its registered agent has resigned or that its registered office has been discontinued within 30 days after the resignation or discontinuance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company’s period of duration has expired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member, manager, or agent of the foreign limited liability company signed a document the member, manager, or agent knew was false in any material respect with intent that the document be delivered to the Department of State for filing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of State receives a duly authenticated certificate from the other official having custody of records in the jurisdiction under the law of which the foreign limited liability company is incorporated stating that it has been dissolved or disappeared as a result of a merger.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company has failed to answer truthfully and fully, within the time prescribed in s. 608.448, interrogatories propounded by the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreign limited liability company failed to amend its certificate of authority as required by s. 608.504.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 70, ch. 93-284; s. 67, ch. 97-102; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 15, ch. 2009-72.</History></Section>