<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.4431" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of dissolution.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A dissolved limited liability company continues its existence but may not carry on any business except that appropriate to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collecting its assets.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disposing of its properties that will not be distributed in kind to its members.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discharging or making provision for discharging its liabilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distributing its assets in accordance with s. 608.444.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Doing every other act necessary to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dissolution of a limited liability company does not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transfer title to the limited liability company assets.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevent commencement of a proceeding by or against the limited liability company in its name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abate or suspend a proceeding pending by or against the limited liability company on the effective date of dissolution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminate the authority of the registered agent of the limited liability company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the dissolved limited liability company shall not be available for assumption or use by another limited liability company until 120 days after the effective date of dissolution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 42, ch. 93-284.</History></Section>