<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0608.406" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limited liability company name.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limited liability company name:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must contain the words “limited liability company,” the abbreviation “L.L.C.,” or the designation “LLC” as the last words of the name of every limited liability company formed under the provisions of this chapter. The word “limited” may be abbreviated as “Ltd.,” and the word “company” may be abbreviated as “Co.” Omission of the words “limited liability company,” the abbreviation “L.L.C.,” or the designation “LLC” in the use of the name of the limited liability company shall render any person who knowingly participates in the omission, or knowingly acquiesces in the omission, liable for any indebtedness, damage, or liability caused by the omission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not contain language stating or implying that the limited liability company is organized for a purpose other than that permitted in this chapter and its articles of organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not contain language stating or implying that the limited liability company is connected with a state or federal government agency or a corporation or other entity chartered under the laws of the United States.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the limited liability company must be distinguishable on the records of the Division of Corporations of the Department of State, except for fictitious name registrations filed pursuant to s. 865.09 and general partnership registrations filed pursuant to s. 620.8105; however, a limited liability company may register under a name that is not otherwise distinguishable on the records of the Division of Corporations with written consent of the owner entity provided the consent is filed with the Division of Corporations at the time of registration of such name.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the limited liability company shall be filed with the Department of State for public notice only and shall not alone create any presumption of ownership beyond that which is created under the common law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of any limited liability company in existence prior to July 1, 2007, and registered with the Division of Corporations, the requirement in this section that the name of the entity be distinguishable from the names of other entities and filings shall not apply except when the limited liability company files documents on or after July 1, 2007, that would otherwise have affected its name.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 82-177; s. 8, ch. 93-284; s. 11, ch. 98-101; s. 1, ch. 99-315; s. 1, ch. 2007-134.</History></Section>