<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0111.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Testimonials for public officers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Testimonial” means any breakfast, dinner, luncheon, rally, party, reception, or other affair held to honor or raise funds on behalf of any elected public officer, except a campaign fund raiser held pursuant to s. 106.025(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Elected public officer” means any individual holding an elective state, county, municipal, or school or other district office or position.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No testimonial shall be held in honor or on behalf of any person holding public office unless a notice of intent to hold such testimonial has first been filed pursuant to this subsection by the person in charge of such testimonial and a testimonial account has been set up in a depository and a treasurer appointed therefor. No money or donation may be accepted, nor may any payment be made, with respect to such testimonial until the notice of intent has been filed and the testimonial account has been established and a treasurer has been appointed therefor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such notice, in the case of a state or multicounty district officer, shall be filed with the Division of Elections or, in the case of any other public officer, with the supervisor of elections of the county in which such officer resides. Such notice shall state the date and place the testimonial is to be held, the name and address of the person or persons in charge of the testimonial, the name and address of the officer in whose honor or on whose behalf the testimonial is to be held, the purpose for which the testimonial is to be held, and the purpose for which the funds raised are to be used.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All money and donations received, and all payments made, with respect to such testimonial shall be received and made only through the treasurer appointed pursuant to this subsection. The appointed treasurer shall keep detailed accounts of all deposits and all payments made with respect to such account.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the testimonial held pursuant to this subsection remaining after the payment of the expenses therefor shall be disposed of as provided in this paragraph. All proceeds after payment of the expenses for such testimonial shall be donated to a charity stated in the notice of intent; returned pro rata to each person who purchased a ticket, gave money, or made a donation; or given, in the case of a state officer, to the state to be deposited in the General Revenue Fund or, in the case of an officer of a political subdivision, to the political subdivision to be deposited in the general fund thereof. A report of such disposition of funds shall be made by the person in charge of such testimonial within 90 days from the date the testimonial is held and shall be filed with the officer with whom the notice of intent is filed. Each report shall contain the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name and address of each person who purchases one or more tickets or gives any money or donation with respect to such testimonial, together with the amount and date thereof.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The full name and address of each person, charity, or unit of government to whom any payment for expenses or disposition of funds is made with respect to such testimonial, together with the date and amount thereof and the purpose therefor.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or officer who holds a testimonial, or who consents to a testimonial being held, in violation of the provisions of this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person required by the provisions of this subsection to dispose of funds in a testimonial account who fails to dispose of the funds in the manner provided in this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 81-304; s. 30, ch. 83-217.</History></Section>