<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0111.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of judgments or settlements against certain public officers or employees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county, municipality, political subdivision, or agency of the state which has been excluded from participation in the Insurance Risk Management Trust Fund is authorized to expend available funds to pay:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any final judgment, including damages, costs, and attorney’s fees, arising from a complaint for damages or injury suffered as a result of any act or omission of action of any officer, employee, or agent in a civil or civil rights lawsuit described in s. 111.07. If the civil action arises under s. 768.28 as a tort claim, the limitations and provisions of s. 768.28 governing payment shall apply. If the action is a civil rights action arising under 42 U.S.C. s. 1983, or similar federal statutes, payments for the full amount of the judgment may be made unless the officer, employee, or agent has been determined in the final judgment to have caused the harm intentionally.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any compromise or settlement of any claim or litigation as described in paragraph (a), subject to the limitations set forth in that paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any reimbursement required under s. 111.07 for court costs and reasonable attorney’s fees when the county, municipality, political subdivision, or agency of the state has failed to provide an attorney and the defendant prevails.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, a “final judgment” means a judgment upon completion of any appellate proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency of the state” or “state agency,” as used in this section, includes an executive department, a constitutional officer, the Legislature, and the judicial branch.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is not intended to be a waiver of sovereign immunity or a waiver of any other defense or immunity to such lawsuits.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 79-139; ss. 2, 3, ch. 80-271.</History></Section>