<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0170.201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special assessments.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to other lawful authority to levy and collect special assessments, the governing body of a municipality may levy and collect special assessments to fund capital improvements and municipal services, including, but not limited to, fire protection, emergency medical services, garbage disposal, sewer improvement, street improvement, and parking facilities. Without limiting the foregoing, a municipality that has a population of fewer than 100 persons for the previous year’s taxing year may also levy and collect special assessments to fund special security and crime prevention services and facilities, including guard and gatehouse facilities for the current taxing year. However, if prior to the levy of the assessment, the cost of the services and facilities are funded by ad valorem taxes, the taxes shall be abated annually thereafter, in an amount equal to the full amount of the special assessment. The governing body of a municipality may apportion costs of such special assessments based on:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The front or square footage of each parcel of land; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An alternative methodology, so long as the amount of the assessment for each parcel of land is not in excess of the proportional benefits as compared to other assessments on other parcels of land.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property owned or occupied by a religious institution and used as a place of worship or education; by a public or private elementary, middle, or high school; or by a governmentally financed, insured, or subsidized housing facility that is used primarily for persons who are elderly or disabled shall be exempt from any special assessment levied by a municipality to fund any service if the municipality so desires. As used in this subsection, the term “religious institution” means any church, synagogue, or other established physical place for worship at which nonprofit religious services and activities are regularly conducted and carried on and the term “governmentally financed, insured, or subsidized housing facility” means a facility that is financed by a mortgage loan made or insured by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development under s. 8, s. 202, s. 221(d)(3) or (4), s. 232, or s. 236 of the National Housing Act and is owned or operated by an entity that qualifies as an exempt charitable organization under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 96-324; s. 1, ch. 97-110; s. 5, ch. 98-167; s. 14, ch. 99-378; s. 26, ch. 2011-144.</History></Section>