<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0170.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority for providing improvements and levying and collecting special assessments against property benefited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any municipality of this state may, by its governing authority:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the construction, reconstruction, repair, paving, repaving, hard surfacing, rehard surfacing, widening, guttering, and draining of streets, boulevards, and alleys; for grading, regrading, leveling, laying, relaying, paving, repaving, hard surfacing, and rehard surfacing of sidewalks; for constructing or reconstructing permanent pedestrian canopies over public sidewalks; and in connection with any of the foregoing, provide related lighting, landscaping, street furniture, signage, and other amenities as determined by the governing authority of the municipality;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order the construction, reconstruction, repair, renovation, excavation, grading, stabilization, and upgrading of greenbelts, swales, culverts, sanitary sewers, storm sewers, outfalls, canals, primary, secondary, and tertiary drains, water bodies, marshlands, and natural areas, all or part of a comprehensive stormwater management system, including the necessary appurtenances and structures thereto and including, but not limited to, dams, weirs, and pumps;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order the construction or reconstruction of water mains, water laterals, alternative water supply systems, including, but not limited to, reclaimed water, aquifer storage and recovery, and desalination systems, and other water distribution facilities, including the necessary appurtenances thereto;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay for the relocation of utilities, including the placement underground of electrical, telephone, and cable television services, pursuant to voluntary agreement with the utility, but nothing contained in this paragraph shall affect a utility’s right to locate or relocate its facilities on its own initiative at its own expense;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the construction or reconstruction of parks and other public recreational facilities and improvements, including appurtenances thereto;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the construction or reconstruction of seawalls;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the drainage and reclamation of wet, low, or overflowed lands;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for offstreet parking facilities, parking garages, or similar facilities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for mass transportation systems;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for improvements to permit the passage and navigation of watercraft; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the payment of all or any part of the costs of any such improvements by levying and collecting special assessments on the abutting, adjoining, contiguous, or other specially benefited property.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, offstreet parking facilities, parking garages, or other similar facilities and mass transportation systems must be approved by vote of a majority of the affected property owners. Any municipality which is legally obligated for providing capital improvements for water, alternative water supplies, including, but not limited to, reclaimed water, water from aquifer storage and recovery, and desalination systems, or sewer facilities within an unincorporated area of the county may recover the costs of the capital improvements by levying and collecting special assessments for the purposes authorized in this section on the specially benefited property; however, collections of the special assessment shall not take place until the specially benefited property connects to the capital improvement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special assessments may be levied only for the purposes enumerated in this section and shall be levied only on benefited real property at a rate of assessment based on the special benefit accruing to such property from such improvements when the improvements funded by the special assessment provide a benefit which is different in type or degree from benefits provided to the community as a whole.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any municipality, subject to the approval of a majority of the affected property owners, may levy and collect special assessments against property benefited for the purpose of stabilizing and improving:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retail business districts,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wholesale business districts, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nationally recognized historic districts,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">or any combination of such districts, through promotion, management, marketing, and other similar services in such districts of the municipality. This subsection does not authorize a municipality to use bond proceeds to fund ongoing operations of these districts.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 9298, 1923; CGL 3022; s. 1, ch. 59-396; s. 1, ch. 67-552; s. 1, ch. 78-360; s. 32, ch. 79-164; s. 1, ch. 82-198; s. 32, ch. 83-204; s. 1, ch. 83-337; s. 1, ch. 87-103; s. 39, ch. 91-45; s. 1, ch. 92-156; s. 2, ch. 94-344; s. 4, ch. 95-323.</History></Section>