<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0634.424" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Procedure for refusal, suspension, or revocation of license or appointment of sales representatives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any sales representative is convicted by a court of a violation of any provision of this part or an applicable provision of the Florida Insurance Code, the license and appointment of the individual shall thereby be deemed to be immediately revoked without any further procedure relative thereto by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, after an investigation or upon other evidence, the department has reason to believe that there may exist any one or more grounds for the suspension, revocation, or refusal to renew or continue the license or appointment of any sales representative, as such grounds are specified in ss. 634.422 and 634.423, the department may proceed to suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew or continue the license or appointment, as the case may be.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the licensed and appointed sales representative also holds a license to perform professional services of the type covered by the service warranty issued, the department shall file with the regulatory authority that issued the license a recommendation that the license be suspended or revoked. Such regulatory authority shall promptly review the recommendation and take appropriate action in accordance with its laws and rules to suspend or revoke the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever it appears that any licensed or appointed insurance agent has violated the provisions of this part, the department may take action relative thereto as is authorized by the insurance code for a violation of the insurance code by the agent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-255; s. 3, ch. 81-148; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 19, 36, 37, 38, ch. 83-322; s. 64, ch. 91-106; s. 155, ch. 91-108; s. 20, ch. 93-195.</History></Section>