<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0634.425" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Duration of suspension or revocation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, in its order suspending a license or appointment, specify the time period during which the suspension is to be in effect. Such period may not exceed 1 year. The license or appointment shall remain suspended during the period so specified, subject to any rescission or modification of the order by the department before the expiration of the suspension period. A license or appointment which has been suspended may not be reinstated except upon request, but the department may not grant reinstatement if it finds that the circumstances for which the license or appointment was suspended still exist or are likely to recur.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person whose license or appointment has been revoked by the department has the right to apply for another license or appointment within 2 years from the effective date of the revocation or, if judicial review of such revocation is sought, within 2 years from the date of the final court order or decree affirming the revocation. The department, however, may not grant a new license or appointment if it finds that the circumstance or circumstances for which the previous license or appointment was revoked still exist or are likely to recur.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not grant or issue any license or appointment to any individual whose license or appointment has been revoked twice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the period of suspension, or after revocation of the license or appointment, the former licensee or appointee may not engage in or attempt to engage in any transaction or business for which a license or appointment is required under this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-255; s. 3, ch. 81-148; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 20, 36, 37, 38, ch. 83-322; s. 65, ch. 91-106; s. 156, ch. 91-108; s. 20, ch. 93-195.</History></Section>