<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0634.3205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rebating; when allowed.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No sales representative shall rebate any portion of his or her commission except as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rebate shall be available to all consumers in the same actuarial class.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rebate shall be in accordance with a rebating schedule filed with and approved by the home warranty association issuing the home warranty to which the rebate applies. The home warranty association shall maintain a copy of all rebating schedules for a period of 3 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rebating schedule shall be uniformly applied so all consumers who purchase the same home warranty through the sales representative for the same coverage shall receive the same percentage rebate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rebate schedule shall be prominently displayed in public view in the sales representative’s place of business, and a copy shall be made available to consumers on request at no charge.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The age, sex, place of residence, race, nationality, ethnic origin, marital status, or occupation of the consumer shall not be used in determining the percentage of the rebate or whether a rebate is available.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No rebate shall be withheld or limited in amount based on factors which are unfairly discriminatory.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No rebate shall be given which is not reflected on the rebate schedule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No rebate shall be refused or granted based upon the purchase of or failure to purchase collateral business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 40, ch. 2004-374; s. 26, ch. 2010-175.</History>
</Section>