<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0634.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examination of companies.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Motor vehicle service agreement companies licensed under this part may be subject to periodic examination by the office in the same manner and subject to the same terms and conditions as apply to insurers under part II of chapter 624. The office is not required to conduct periodic examinations pursuant to this section, but may examine a service agreement company at its discretion. An examination conducted pursuant to this section may cover a period of only the most recent 5 years. The costs of examinations conducted pursuant to ss. 624.316(2)(e) and 624.3161(3) may not exceed 10 percent of the companies’ reported net income for the prior year. The commission may by rule establish provisions whereby a company may be exempted from examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall determine whether to conduct an examination of a company by considering:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of time that the company has been continuously licensed and operating under the same management and control.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The company’s history of compliance with applicable law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of consumer complaints against the company.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial condition of the company, demonstrated by the financial reports submitted pursuant to s. 634.137.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 59-110; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 17, 32, 33, ch. 82-234; ss. 23, 68, ch. 91-106; s. 20, ch. 93-195; s. 1432, ch. 2003-261; s. 17, ch. 2010-175; s. 3, ch. 2012-77.</History>
</Section>