<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0634.3078" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assets and liabilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ASSETS.<EmDash />In any determination of the financial condition of a home warranty association, there shall be allowed as assets only those assets that are owned by the home warranty association company and which assets consist of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cash in the possession of the home warranty association, or in transit under its control, including the true balance of any deposit in a solvent bank, savings and loan association, or trust company that is domiciled in the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investments, securities, properties, and loans acquired or held in accordance with this part and, in connection therewith, the following items:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest due or accrued on any bond or evidence of indebtedness which is not in default and which is not valued on a basis including accrued interest.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Declared and unpaid dividends on stock and shares, unless the amount of the dividends has otherwise been allowed as an asset.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest due or accrued upon a collateral loan that is not in default in an amount not to exceed 1 year’s interest thereon.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest due or accrued on deposits or certificates of deposit in solvent banks, savings and loan associations, and trust companies domiciled in the United States, and interest due or accrued on other assets, if such interest is in the judgment of the office a collectible asset.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest due or accrued on current mortgage loans, in an amount not exceeding the amount, if any, of the excess of the value of the property less delinquent taxes thereon over the unpaid principal; but interest accrued for a period in excess of 90 days may not be allowed as an asset.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rent due or accrued on real property if such rent is not in arrears for more than 3 months. However, rent accrued for a period in excess of 90 days may not be allowed as an asset.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The unaccrued portion of taxes paid prior to the due date on real property.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furniture, fixtures, furnishings, vehicles, and equipment, if the original cost of each item is at least $200, which cost shall be amortized in full over a period not to exceed 5 calendar years, unless otherwise approved by the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Part inventories maintained for the purpose of servicing products warranted. Part inventories must be listed at cost. Home warranty associations companies are required to maintain records to support valuation of part inventories.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The liquidation value of prepaid expenses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other assets or receivables, not inconsistent with the provisions of this section, deemed by the office to be available for the payment of losses and claims, at values to be determined by the office.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The office, upon determining that a home warranty association’s asset has not been evaluated according to applicable law or that it does not qualify as an asset, shall require the home warranty association to properly reevaluate the asset or replace the asset with an asset suitable to the office within 30 days after written notification by the office of this determination, if the removal of the asset from the organization’s assets would impair the company’s solvency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ASSETS NOT ALLOWED.<EmDash />In addition to assets impliedly excluded by the provisions of subsection (1), the following assets expressly shall not be allowed as assets in any determination of the financial condition of a home warranty association:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Goodwill, agreement holder lists, patents, trade names, agreements not to compete, and other like intangible assets.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any note or account receivable from or advances to officers, directors, or controlling stockholders, whether secured or not, and advances to employees, agents, or other persons on personal security only.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stock of the home warranty association owned by it directly or owned by it through any entity in which the organization owns or controls, directly or indirectly, more than 25 percent of the ownership interest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Leasehold improvements, stationery, and literature, except that leasehold improvements made prior to October 1, 2001, shall be allowed as an asset and shall be amortized over the shortest of the following periods:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The life of the lease.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The useful life of the improvements.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 3-year period following October 1, 2001.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furniture, fixtures, furnishings, vehicles, and equipment, other than those items authorized under paragraph (1)(c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notes or other evidences of indebtedness which are secured by mortgages or deeds of trust which are in default and beyond the express period specified in the instrument for curing the default.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds in default for more than 60 days.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deferred costs other than the liquidation value of prepaid expenses except for those companies that reserve 100 percent of gross written premium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any note, account receivable, advance, or other evidence of indebtedness, or investment in:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The parent of the home warranty association;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity directly or indirectly controlled by the home warranty association’s parent;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affiliate of the parent or the home warranty association; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Officers, directors, shareholders, employees, or salespersons of the home warranty association; however, premium receivables under 45 days old may be considered an admitted asset.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The office may, however, allow all or a portion of such asset, at values to be determined by the office, if deemed by the office to be available for the payment of losses and claims.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LIABILITIES.<EmDash />In any determination of the financial condition of a home warranty association, liabilities to be charged against its assets shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount, in conformity with generally accepted accounting principles, necessary to pay all of its unpaid losses and claims incurred for or on behalf of an agreement holder, on or prior to the end of the reporting period, whether reported or unreported.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taxes, expenses, and other obligations due or accrued at the date of the statement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserve for unearned premiums.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The office, upon determining that the home warranty association has failed to report liabilities that should have been reported, shall require a correct report which reflects the proper liabilities to be submitted by the home warranty association to the office within 10 working days after receipt of written notification.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 2001-281; s. 1459, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>