<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0634.308" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for suspension or revocation of license.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license of any home warranty association may be revoked or suspended, or the office may refuse to renew any such license, if it is determined that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association has violated any lawful rule or order of the commission or office or any provision of this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association has not maintained a funded, unearned premium reserve account as required by s. 634.3077(1).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association has not maintained, at a minimum, net assets as required by s. 634.3077(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license of any home warranty association shall be suspended, revoked, or not renewed if it is determined that such association:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in unsound financial condition or is in such condition or is using such methods and practices in the conduct of its business as to render its further transaction of warranties in this state hazardous or injurious to its warranty holders or to the public.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has refused to be examined or to produce its accounts, records, and files for examination, or if any of its officers have refused to give information with respect to its affairs or have refused to perform any other legal obligation as to such examination, when required by the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to pay any final judgment rendered against it in this state within 60 days after the judgment became final.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has, without just cause, refused to pay proper claims arising under its warranties or, without just cause, has compelled warranty holders to accept less than the amount due them or to employ attorneys, or to bring suit against the association, to secure full payment or settlement of such claims.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is affiliated with, and under the same general management, interlocking directorate, or ownership as, another home warranty association which transacts direct warranties in this state without having a license therefor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has issued warranty contracts which renewal contracts provide that the cost of renewal exceeds the then-current cost for new warranty contracts, unless the increase is supported by the claims history or claims cost data, or impose a fee for inspection of the premises.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, pursuant to s. 120.60, in its discretion and without advance notice or hearing thereon, immediately suspend the license of any home warranty association if it finds that one or more of the following circumstances exist:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The association is insolvent or impaired.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reserve account or net asset ratio requirement of s. 634.3077 is not being maintained.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proceeding for receivership, conservatorship or rehabilitation or any other delinquency proceeding regarding the association has been commenced in any state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial condition or business practices of the association otherwise pose an imminent threat to the public health, safety, or welfare of the residents of this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this part by an insurer is grounds for suspension or revocation of the insurer’s certificate of authority in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-339; s. 2, ch. 78-255; ss. 1, 3, ch. 81-148; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 7, 32, 33, 34, ch. 83-323; s. 1, ch. 84-94; s. 1, ch. 86-75; s. 45, ch. 88-166; s. 34, ch. 91-106; s. 20, ch. 93-195; s. 1460, ch. 2003-261; s. 22, ch. 2010-175.</History>
</Section>