<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0634.436" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices defined.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following methods, acts, or practices are defined as unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISREPRESENTATION AND FALSE ADVERTISING OF INSURANCE POLICIES.<EmDash />Knowingly making, issuing, circulating, or causing to be made, issued, or circulated, any estimate, illustration, circular, statement, sales presentation, omission, or comparison which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresents the benefits, advantages, conditions, or terms of any service warranty contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is misleading or is a misrepresentation as to the financial condition of any person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses any name or title of any contract misrepresenting the true nature thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a misrepresentation for the purpose of inducing, or tending to induce, the lapse, forfeiture, exchange, conversion, or surrender of any service warranty contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE INFORMATION AND ADVERTISING GENERALLY.<EmDash />Knowingly making, publishing, disseminating, circulating, or placing before the public, or causing, directly or indirectly, to be made, published, disseminated, circulated, or placed before the public:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a newspaper, magazine, or other publication;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the form of a notice, circular, pamphlet, letter, or poster;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Over any radio or television station; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any other way,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">an advertisement, announcement, or statement containing any assertion, representation, or statement with respect to the business of service warranty, which assertion, representation, or statement is untrue, deceptive, or misleading.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFAMATION.<EmDash />Knowingly making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating, directly or indirectly, or aiding, abetting, or encouraging the making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating of, any oral or written statement, or any pamphlet, circular, article, or literature, which is false or maliciously critical of, or derogatory to, any person and which is calculated to injure such person.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE STATEMENTS AND ENTRIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing with any supervisory or other public official;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delivering to any person;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing before the public; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Causing, directly or indirectly, to be made, published, disseminated, circulated, delivered to any person, or placed before the public,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">any false statement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly making any false entry of a material fact in any book, report, or statement of any person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNFAIR CLAIM SETTLEMENT PRACTICES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to settle claims on the basis of an application or any other material document which was altered without notice to, or knowledge or consent of, the warranty holder;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a material misrepresentation to the warranty holder for the purpose and with the intent of effecting settlement of such claims, loss, or damage under such contract on less favorable terms than those provided in, and contemplated by, such contract;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing or performing with such frequency as to indicate a general business practice any of the following practices:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure properly to investigate claims;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresentation of pertinent facts or contract provisions relating to coverages at issue;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to acknowledge and act promptly upon communications with respect to claims;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of claims without conducting reasonable investigations based upon available information;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to affirm or deny coverage of claims upon written request of the warranty holder within a reasonable time after proof-of-loss statements have been completed; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to promptly provide a reasonable explanation to the warranty holder of the basis in the contract in relation to the facts or applicable law for denial of a claim or for the offer of a compromise settlement; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denying a claim solely on the basis that the association was not able to confirm that the warranty holder in fact purchased a service warranty because the association did not obtain the name and address as set forth in s. 634.4165(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAILURE TO MAINTAIN PROCEDURES FOR HANDLING COMPLAINTS.<EmDash />Failing to maintain a record of each complaint received for a 3-year period after the date of the receipt of the written complaint.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCRIMINATORY REFUSAL TO ISSUE A CONTRACT.<EmDash />Refusing to issue a contract solely because of an individual’s race, color, creed, marital status, sex, or national origin.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FREE SERVICE WARRANTIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising, offering, or providing a free service warranty as an inducement to the purchase or sale of real or personal property or of services directly or indirectly connected with such real or personal property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection, a “free” service warranty is:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A service warranty for which no identifiable and additional charge is made to the purchaser of such real property, personal property, or services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A service warranty for which an identifiable or additional charge is made in an amount less than the cost of such service warranty as to the seller or other person, other than the service warranty association, providing the same.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A service warranty with respect to which the word “free” or words implying that the provision of the service warranty is without cost are used in connection with the advertising or offering for sale of any kind of goods, merchandise, or services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAILURE TO PROVIDE TERMS AND CONDITIONS PRIOR TO SALE.<EmDash />Failing to provide a consumer with a complete sample copy of the terms and conditions of the service warranty prior to before the time of sale upon a request for the same by the consumer. A service warranty association may comply with this subsection by providing the consumer with a sample copy of the terms and conditions of the warranty contract or by directing the consumer to a website that displays a complete sample of the terms and conditions of the contract.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 28, 38, ch. 83-322; s. 20, ch. 93-195; s. 23, ch. 2001-281; s. 7, ch. 2008-178; s. 37, ch. 2010-175.</History>
</Section>