<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0634.405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Required deposit or bond.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assure the faithful performance of its obligations to its members or subscribers in the event of insolvency, each service warranty association shall, before the issuance of its license by the office and during such time as the association may have premiums in force in this state, deposit and maintain with the department securities of the type eligible for deposit by insurers under s. 625.52. Whenever the market value of the securities deposited with the department is less than 95 percent of the amount required, the association shall deposit additional securities or otherwise increase the deposit to the amount required. Such securities shall have at all times a market value as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Warrantors.</Font><EmDash /></Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any warrantor which:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was licensed under this part before October 1, 1983;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was transacting service warranty business in this state before June 14, 1978;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has continuously transacted service warranty business in this state since June 14, 1978; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not during any year since June 14, 1978, written more than $100,000 of gross written premiums,</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall place and maintain in trust with the department an amount equal to 50 percent of the gross written premiums in force.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A warrantor which has $300,000 or less of gross written premiums in this state and to which the provisions of subparagraph 1. do not apply shall place and maintain in trust with the department an amount not less than $50,000. A new warrantor, before the issuance of its license and before receiving any premiums, shall place and maintain in trust with the department the amount of $50,000.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A warrantor which has more than $300,000 but less than $750,000 of gross written premiums in this state shall place and maintain in trust with the department an amount not less than $75,000.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A warrantor which has $750,000 or more of gross written premiums in this state shall place and maintain in trust with the department an amount equal to $100,000.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All warrantors, upon receipt of written notice from the office, shall have 30 calendar days in which to make additional deposits.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Warranty sellers.</Font><EmDash />A warranty seller shall, before the issuance of its license, place in trust with the department an amount not less than $100,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of any deposit of securities required under subsection (1) and subject to the approval of the office, the service warranty association may file with the office a surety bond issued by an authorized surety insurer. The bond shall be for the same purpose as the deposit in lieu of which it is filed. The office may not approve any bond under the terms of which the protection afforded against insolvency is not equivalent to the protection afforded by those securities provided for in subsection (1). When a bond is deposited in lieu of the required securities, no warranties may be written which provide coverage for a time period beyond the duration of such bond. The bond shall guarantee that the service warranty association will faithfully and truly perform all the conditions of any service warranty contract. No such bond may be canceled or subject to cancellation unless at least 60 days’ advance notice thereof, in writing, is filed with the office. In the event that notice of termination of the bond is filed with the office, the service warranty association insured thereunder shall, within 30 days of the filing of notice of termination, provide the office with a replacement bond meeting the requirements of this part or deposit additional securities as required under subsection (1). The cancellation of a bond will not relieve the obligation of the issuer of the bond for claims arising out of contracts issued before cancellation of the bond unless a replacement bond or securities are filed. In no event may the liability of the issuer under the bond exceed the face amount of the bond. If within 30 days of filing the notice of termination no replacement bond or additional security is provided, the office shall suspend the license of the association until the deposit requirements are satisfied.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Securities and bonds posted by an association pursuant to this section are for the benefit of, and subject to action thereon in the event of insolvency or impairment of any association or insurer by, any person or persons sustaining an actionable injury due to the failure of the association to faithfully perform its obligations to its warranty holders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state is responsible for the safekeeping of all securities deposited with the department under this part. Such securities are not, on account of being in this state, subject to taxation, but shall be held exclusively and solely to guarantee the faithful performance by the association of its obligations to its members or subscribers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The depositing association shall, during its solvency, have the right to exchange or substitute other securities of like quality and value for securities on deposit, to receive the interest and other income accruing to such securities, and to inspect the deposit at all reasonable times.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such deposit or bond shall be maintained unimpaired as long as the association continues in business in this state. Whenever the association ceases to do business in this state and furnishes the office proof satisfactory to the office that it has discharged or otherwise adequately provided for all its obligations to its members or subscribers in this state, the office and department shall release the deposited securities to the parties entitled thereto, on presentation of the receipts of the department for such securities, or shall release any bond filed with it in lieu of such deposit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any business, or its affiliate, whose primary source of income is the sale of goods to the final consumer and derives more than 50 percent of its revenue through such sales and maintains a net worth of $100 million, as evidenced by either filing a form 10-K or other similar statement with the Securities and Exchange Commission or which has an annual financial statement that is audited and certified by an independent public accounting firm, shall be presumed to have complied with this subsection if such forms or statement are filed with the office.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-255; s. 3, ch. 81-148; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 3, 36, 37, 38, ch. 83-322; s. 40, ch. 87-226; s. 49, ch. 91-106; s. 184, ch. 91-108; s. 20, ch. 93-195; s. 5, ch. 96-377; s. 1490, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>