<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0634.282" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices defined.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following methods, acts, or practices are defined as unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISREPRESENTATION AND FALSE ADVERTISING.<EmDash />Knowingly making, issuing, circulating, or causing to be made, issued, or circulated, any estimate, illustration, circular, statement, sales presentation, omission, or comparison which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresents the benefits, advantages, conditions, or terms of any motor vehicle service agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is misleading or is a misrepresentation as to the financial condition of any person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses any name or title of any contract misrepresenting the true nature thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a misrepresentation for the purpose of inducing, or tending to induce, the lapse, forfeiture, exchange, conversion, or surrender of any motor vehicle service agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses any advertisement that would mislead or otherwise cause a reasonable person to believe mistakenly that the state or federal government is responsible for the motor vehicle service agreement sales activity of any person or stands behind any person’s credit or that any person, the state, or the federal government guarantees any returns on motor vehicle service agreements or is a source of payment of any motor vehicle service agreement obligation of or sold by any person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE INFORMATION AND ADVERTISING GENERALLY.<EmDash />Knowingly making, publishing, disseminating, circulating, or placing before the public, or causing, directly or indirectly, to be made, published, disseminated, circulated, or placed before the public:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a newspaper, magazine, or other publication;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the form of a notice, circular, pamphlet, letter, or poster;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Over any radio or television station; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Over the Internet, electronically, or in any other way,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">an advertisement, announcement, or statement containing any assertion, representation, or statement with respect to the business of motor vehicle service agreements, which assertion, representation, or statement is untrue, deceptive, or misleading.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFAMATION.<EmDash />Knowingly making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating, directly or indirectly, or aiding, abetting, or encouraging the making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating of, any oral or written statement, or any pamphlet, circular, article, or literature, that is false or maliciously critical of, or derogatory to, any person and that is calculated to injure such person.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOYCOTT, COERCION, AND INTIMIDATION.<EmDash />Entering into any agreement to commit, or by any concerted action committing, any act of boycott, coercion, or intimidation resulting in, or tending to result in, unreasonable restraint of, or monopoly in, the business of motor vehicle service agreements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE STATEMENTS AND ENTRIES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing with any supervisory or other public official;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making, publishing, disseminating, or circulating;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Delivering to any person;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing before the public; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Causing, directly or indirectly, to be made, published, disseminated, circulated, delivered to any person, or placed before the public,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">any false statement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly making any false entry of a material fact in any book, report, or statement of any person, or knowingly failing to make a true entry of any material fact pertaining to the business of such person in any book, report, or statement of such person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNFAIR DISCRIMINATION.<EmDash />Knowingly making or permitting any unfair discrimination between individuals of the same actuarially supportable class and essentially the same hazard, in the amount of premium, policy fees, or rates charged for any motor vehicle service agreement, in any of the terms or conditions of such agreement, or in any other manner whatsoever.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNLAWFUL REBATES.<EmDash />Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, or in an applicable filing with the office, knowingly:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permitting, or offering to make, or making, any contract or agreement as to such contract other than as plainly expressed in the motor vehicle service agreement issued thereon;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paying, allowing, or giving, or offering to pay, allow, or give, directly or indirectly, as inducement to such motor vehicle service agreement, any unlawful rebate of premiums payable on the agreement, any special favor or advantage in the benefits thereon, or any valuable consideration or inducement not specified in the agreement;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Giving, selling, or purchasing, or offering to give, sell, or purchase, as an inducement to such motor vehicle service agreement or in connection therewith, any stocks, bonds, or other securities of any insurance company, service agreement company, or other corporation, association, or partnership, or any dividends or profits accrued thereon, or anything of value not specified in the motor vehicle service agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">UNFAIR CLAIM SETTLEMENT PRACTICES.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Attempting to settle claims on the basis of an application or any other material document that was altered without notice to, or knowledge or consent of, the service agreement holder;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a material misrepresentation to the service agreement holder for the purpose and with the intent of effecting settlement of such claims, loss, or damage under such contract on less favorable terms than those provided in, and contemplated by, such contract; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing or performing with such frequency as to indicate a general business practice any of the following practices:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to adopt and implement internal standards for the investigation of claims;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresentation of pertinent facts or contract provisions relating to coverages at issue;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to acknowledge and act promptly upon communications with respect to claims;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial of claims without conducting reasonable investigations based upon available information;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to affirm or deny full or partial coverage of claims and, as to partial coverage, the dollar amount or extent of coverage, or failure to provide a written statement that the claim is being investigated, upon written request of the service agreement holder within 30 days after proof-of-loss statements have been completed;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to promptly provide a reasonable explanation to the service agreement holder of the basis in the contract in relation to the facts or applicable law for denial of a claim or for the offer of a compromise settlement;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to promptly notify the service agreement holder of any additional information necessary for the processing of a claim; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to clearly explain the nature of the requested information and the reasons such information is necessary.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAILURE TO MAINTAIN PROCEDURES FOR HANDLING COMPLAINTS.<EmDash />Failing to maintain a complete record of all complaints received since the date of the last examination. For purposes of this paragraph, “complaint” means any written communication primarily expressing a grievance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCRIMINATORY REFUSAL TO ISSUE A CONTRACT.<EmDash />Refusing to issue a contract solely because of an individual’s race, color, creed, marital status, sex, or national origin.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MISREPRESENTATION IN SERVICE AGREEMENT APPLICATIONS.<EmDash />Knowingly making a false or fraudulent written or oral statement or representation on, or relative to, an application or negotiation for a motor vehicle service agreement for the purpose of obtaining a fee, commission, money, or other benefit from any insurer, service agreement company, agent, broker, salesperson, or individual.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FREE SERVICE AGREEMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Advertising, offering, or providing a free motor vehicle service agreement as an inducement to the purchase or sale of real or personal property or of services directly or indirectly connected with such real or personal property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this subsection, a “free” motor vehicle service agreement is:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor vehicle service agreement for which no identifiable and additional charge is made to the purchaser of such real property, personal property, or services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A motor vehicle service agreement for which an identifiable or additional charge is made in an amount less than the cost of such motor vehicle service agreement as to the seller or other person, other than the service agreement company, providing the same.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using the word “free” or words that imply the provision of a motor vehicle service agreement without a cost in connection with the advertising or offering for sale of any kind of goods, merchandise, or services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ILLEGAL DEALINGS IN PREMIUMS; EXCESS OR REDUCED CHARGES FOR MOTOR VEHICLE SERVICE AGREEMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly collecting any sum as a premium or charge for a motor vehicle service agreement, which is not then provided, or is not in due course to be provided, subject to acceptance of the risk by a service agreement company or an insurer, by a motor vehicle service agreement issued by a service agreement company or an insurer as permitted by this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly collecting as a premium or charge for a motor vehicle service agreement any sum in excess of or less than the premium or charge applicable to such motor vehicle service agreement, as specified in the motor vehicle service agreement. However, there is no violation of this subsection if excess premiums or charges are refunded to the service agreement holder within 45 days after receipt of the agreement by the service agreement company or if the licensed sales representative’s commission is reduced by the amount of any premium undercharge.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTERLOCKING OWNERSHIP AND MANAGEMENT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any motor vehicle service agreement company may retain, invest in, or acquire the whole or any part of the capital of any other motor vehicle service agreement company, or have a common management with any other motor vehicle service agreement company, unless such retention, investment, acquisition, or common management is inconsistent with any other provision of this part, or unless by reason thereof the business of such insurers with the public is conducted in a manner that substantially lessens competition generally in the insurance business.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person otherwise qualified may be a director of two or more motor vehicle service agreement companies that are competitors, unless the effect thereof is substantially to lessen competition between motor vehicle service agreement companies generally or materially tend to create a monopoly.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FALSE CLAIMS; OBTAINING OR RETAINING MONEY DISHONESTLY.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any salesperson who causes to be presented to any motor vehicle service agreement company a false claim for payment, knowing the same to be false; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any salesperson who represents any motor vehicle service agreement company or collects or does business without the authority of the motor vehicle service agreement company, secures cash advances by false statements, or fails to turn over when required, or satisfactorily account for, all collections of such motor vehicle service agreement company,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">in addition to the other penalties provided in this act, commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SLIDING.<EmDash />Sliding is the act or practice of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representing to the applicant that a specific ancillary coverage or product is required by law in conjunction with the purchase of a motor vehicle service agreement when such coverage or product is not required;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Representing to the applicant that a specific ancillary coverage or product is included in the motor vehicle service agreement contract applied for without an additional charge when such charge is required; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Charging an applicant for a specific ancillary coverage or product, in addition to the cost of the motor vehicle service agreement coverage applied for, without the informed consent of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FAILURE TO PROVIDE TERMS AND CONDITIONS PRIOR TO SALE.<EmDash />Failing to provide a consumer with a complete sample copy of the terms and conditions of the service agreement prior to the time of sale upon a request for the same by the consumer. A service agreement company may comply with this subsection by providing the consumer with a sample copy of the terms and conditions of the service agreement or by directing the consumer to a website that displays a complete sample of the terms and conditions of the service agreement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">No provision of this section shall be deemed to prohibit a service agreement company or a licensed insurer from giving to service agreement holders, prospective service agreement holders, and others for the purpose of advertising, any article of merchandise having a value of not more than $25.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2001-281; s. 1443, ch. 2003-261; s. 19, ch. 2010-175.</History>
</Section>