<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0634.137" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Financial and statistical reporting requirements.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By March 1 of each year, each service agreement company shall submit to the office annual financial reports on forms prescribed by the commission and furnished by the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any motor vehicle service agreement company engaged in the business of issuing service agreements in this state must transmit the following information, based on Florida data, to the office each year with the annual report of the company:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net assets.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums written.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Premiums earned.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unearned premium reserve.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percent of claim exposure for which contractual liability insurance has been obtained.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incurred claims, not including claims incurred but not reported.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims incurred but not reported.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Loss reserve for all claims except those incurred but not reported.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves for claims incurred but not reported.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number and dollar amount of claims paid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Itemized acquisition costs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net gain or loss from operations before income taxes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net investment income from all reserves.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Net investment income from surplus.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ratio of claims paid to premium earned.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ratio of all claims incurred to premium earned plus investment income from all reserves.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Number of claims resisted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any additional information that the commission requires in order to evaluate the financial condition or trade practices of companies issuing service agreements in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any service agreement company that does not file an annual statement in the form and within the time provided by this section shall forfeit up to $100 for each day during which the default continues, and, upon notice by the office, the authority of the company to do business in this state shall cease while the default continues. The office shall deposit all sums collected under this subsection in the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall provide a summary of the information provided pursuant to subsection (2) in its annual report.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may by rule require each motor vehicle service agreement company to submit to the office, as the commission may designate, all or part of the information contained in the financial reports required by this section in a computer-readable form compatible with the electronic data processing system specified by the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall develop by rule an abbreviated form for motor vehicle manufacturers to use in submitting statistical reporting of sales of service agreements in this state in lieu of the financial reports required in subsections (1) and (2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 16, 33, ch. 82-234; s. 68, ch. 91-106; ss. 10, 20, ch. 93-195; s. 3, ch. 2001-281; s. 1431, ch. 2003-261; s. 4, ch. 2008-178; s. 16, ch. 2010-175.</History>
</Section>