<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0634.320" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for compulsory refusal, suspension, or revocation of license or appointment of sales representatives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deny, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew or continue the license or appointment of any sales representative if it is found that any one or more of the following grounds applicable to the sales representative exist:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Material misstatement, misrepresentation, or fraud in obtaining or attempting to obtain a license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license or appointment is willfully used, or to be used, to circumvent any of the requirements or prohibitions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful misrepresentation of any warranty contract or willful deception with regard to any such contract, done either in person or by any form of dissemination of information or advertising.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the adjustment of claims arising out of warranties, material misrepresentation to a warranty holder or other interested party of the terms and coverage of a contract, with the intent and for the purpose of effecting settlement of such claim on less favorable terms than those provided in and contemplated by the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated lack of fitness or trustworthiness to engage in the business of home warranty.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrated lack of adequate knowledge and technical competence to engage in the transactions authorized by the license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent or dishonest practices in the conduct of business under the license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misappropriation, conversion, or unlawful withholding of moneys belonging to an association, insurer, or warranty holder, or to others, and received in the conduct of business under the license or appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unlawfully rebating, or attempting to unlawfully rebate, or unlawfully dividing, or offering to divide, her or his commission with another.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful failure to comply with, or willful violation of, any proper order or rule of the department or commission or willful violation of any provision of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being found guilty of or pleading guilty or nolo contendere to a felony or a crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of the United States of America or any state thereof or under the law of any other country involving moral turpitude, without regard to whether judgment of conviction has been entered by the court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-339; s. 3, ch. 81-148; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 19, 32, 33, 34, ch. 83-323; s. 1, ch. 84-94; s. 50, ch. 88-166; s. 39, ch. 91-106; s. 145, ch. 91-108; s. 20, ch. 93-195; s. 471, ch. 97-102; s. 1469, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>