<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0634.404" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Qualifications for license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may not issue or allow a service warranty association to maintain a license unless the association:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a warrantor with minimum net assets of $25,000 or a warranty seller with minimum net assets of $300,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnishes the office with evidence satisfactory to it that the management of the association is competent and trustworthy and can successfully manage the affairs of the association in compliance with law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proposes to use and uses in its business a name, together with a trademark or emblem, if any, which is distinctive and not so similar to the name or trademark of any other person already doing business in this state as will tend to mislead or confuse the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Makes the deposit or files the bond required under s. 634.405.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is formed under the laws of this state or another state, district, territory, or possession of the United States, if the association is other than a natural person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of the provisions of subsections (1)-(5) of this section and s. 634.407, a manufacturer or affiliate as defined in this part is eligible for licensure as a service warranty association under the provisions of this part and shall complete an application evidencing its qualifications as set forth in this section. The application for license as a service warranty association from a manufacturer or affiliate shall be made to, and filed with, the office on printed forms as promulgated by the commission to be specifically and exclusively applicable to qualifying manufacturers.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may require that the applicant show:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state of the applicant’s incorporation;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of the applicant’s home office; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and business addresses of the applicant’s board of directors and managing executive officer.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application, when filed, must be accompanied by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the applicant’s articles of incorporation, certified by the public official having custody of the original, and a copy of the applicant’s bylaws, certified by the applicant’s corporate secretary;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence that the applicant has complied with all applicable statutory requirements regarding registering to do business in this state; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license fee in the amount of $500.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon submission of the application for license, the office shall examine the application to determine its compliance with applicable sections of this part. Applicants shall be advised of any inadequate responses or missing information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information as required in this section shall be updated as to changes thereto no less than two times annually, once at the time of the submission of the service warranty association’s submission of its annual report, and the second time, no later than September 30 of each year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-255; s. 3, ch. 81-148; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 83-265; ss. 2, 36, 37, 38, ch. 83-322; s. 44, ch. 90-119; s. 48, ch. 91-106; s. 20, ch. 93-195; s. 39, ch. 95-211; s. 81, ch. 2000-158; s. 1489, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>