<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0800.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lewd or lascivious exhibition in the presence of an employee.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee” means any person employed by or performing contractual services for a public or private entity operating a facility or any person employed by or performing contractual services for the corporation operating the prison industry enhancement programs or the correctional work programs under part II of chapter 946. The term also includes any person who is a parole examiner with the Parole Commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Facility” means a state correctional institution as defined in s. 944.02 or a private correctional facility as defined in s. 944.710.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is detained in a facility may not:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally masturbate;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally expose the genitals in a lewd or lascivious manner; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally commit any other sexual act that does not involve actual physical or sexual contact with the victim, including, but not limited to, sadomasochistic abuse, sexual bestiality, or the simulation of any act involving sexual activity,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">in the presence of a person he or she knows or reasonably should know is an employee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates paragraph (a) commits lewd or lascivious exhibition in the presence of an employee, a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2010-64.</History>
</Section>