<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0800.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Lewd or lascivious offenses committed upon or in the presence of persons less than 16 years of age.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sexual activity” means the oral, anal, or vaginal penetration by, or union with, the sexual organ of another or the anal or vaginal penetration of another by any other object; however, sexual activity does not include an act done for a bona fide medical purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consent” means intelligent, knowing, and voluntary consent, and does not include submission by coercion.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Coercion” means the use of exploitation, bribes, threats of force, or intimidation to gain cooperation or compliance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Victim” means a person upon whom an offense described in this section was committed or attempted or a person who has reported a violation of this section to a law enforcement officer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROHIBITED DEFENSES.<EmDash />Neither the victim’s lack of chastity nor the victim’s consent is a defense to the crimes proscribed by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IGNORANCE OR BELIEF OF VICTIM’S AGE.<EmDash />The perpetrator’s ignorance of the victim’s age, the victim’s misrepresentation of his or her age, or the perpetrator’s bona fide belief of the victim’s age cannot be raised as a defense in a prosecution under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEWD OR LASCIVIOUS BATTERY.<EmDash />A person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engages in sexual activity with a person 12 years of age or older but less than 16 years of age; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encourages, forces, or entices any person less than 16 years of age to engage in sadomasochistic abuse, sexual bestiality, prostitution, or any other act involving sexual activity</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits lewd or lascivious battery, a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEWD OR LASCIVIOUS MOLESTATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who intentionally touches in a lewd or lascivious manner the breasts, genitals, genital area, or buttocks, or the clothing covering them, of a person less than 16 years of age, or forces or entices a person under 16 years of age to so touch the perpetrator, commits lewd or lascivious molestation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender 18 years of age or older who commits lewd or lascivious molestation against a victim less than 12 years of age commits a life felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082(3)(a)4.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender less than 18 years of age who commits lewd or lascivious molestation against a victim less than 12 years of age; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender 18 years of age or older who commits lewd or lascivious molestation against a victim 12 years of age or older but less than 16 years of age</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender less than 18 years of age who commits lewd or lascivious molestation against a victim 12 years of age or older but less than 16 years of age commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEWD OR LASCIVIOUS CONDUCT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally touches a person under 16 years of age in a lewd or lascivious manner; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicits a person under 16 years of age to commit a lewd or lascivious act</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits lewd or lascivious conduct.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender 18 years of age or older who commits lewd or lascivious conduct commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender less than 18 years of age who commits lewd or lascivious conduct commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEWD OR LASCIVIOUS EXHIBITION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally masturbates;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally exposes the genitals in a lewd or lascivious manner; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally commits any other sexual act that does not involve actual physical or sexual contact with the victim, including, but not limited to, sadomasochistic abuse, sexual bestiality, or the simulation of any act involving sexual activity</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">in the presence of a victim who is less than 16 years of age, commits lewd or lascivious exhibition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender 18 years of age or older who commits a lewd or lascivious exhibition commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An offender less than 18 years of age who commits a lewd or lascivious exhibition commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXCEPTION.<EmDash />A mother’s breastfeeding of her baby does not under any circumstance constitute a violation of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 21974, 1943; s. 1, ch. 26580, 1951; s. 780, ch. 71-136; s. 66, ch. 74-383; s. 1, ch. 75-24; s. 40, ch. 75-298; s. 291, ch. 79-400; s. 5, ch. 84-86; s. 1, ch. 90-120; s. 5, ch. 93-4; s. 6, ch. 99-201; s. 1, ch. 2000-246; s. 5, ch. 2005-28; s. 3, ch. 2008-172; s. 3, ch. 2008-182.</History></Section>