<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.280" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Illegal tying arrangements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person authorized to sell grave space may tie the purchase of any grave space to the purchase of a monument from or through the seller of any other designated person or corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Noncemetery licensed persons and firms shall have the right to sell monuments and to perform or provide on cemetery property foundation, preparation, and installation services for monuments. However, a cemetery company or any other entity owning and operating a cemetery may establish reasonable rules regarding the style and size of a monument or its foundation, provided such rules are applicable to all monuments from whatever source obtained and are enforced uniformly as to all monuments. Such rules shall be conspicuously posted and readily accessible to inspection and copy by interested persons.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person who is authorized to sell grave space and no cemetery company or other entity owning and operating a cemetery may:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the payment of a setting or service charge, by whatever name known, from third party installers for the placement of a monument;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refuse to provide care or maintenance for any portion of a gravesite on which a monument has been placed; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require waiver of liability with respect to damage caused by cemetery employees or agents to a monument after installation,</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">where the monument or installation service is not purchased from the person authorized to sell grave space or the cemetery company providing grave space or from or through any other person or corporation designated by the person authorized to sell grave space or the cemetery company providing grave space. No cemetery company may be held liable for the improper installation of a monument where the monument is not installed by the cemetery company or its agents.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No program offering free burial rights may be conditioned by any requirement to purchase additional burial rights, funeral merchandise, or services. Any program offering free burial rights shall comply with s. 817.415.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 19, 32, 40, ch. 80-238; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 12, ch. 85-202; s. 4, ch. 88-227; s. 1, ch. 89-8; ss. 73, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 15, ch. 96-400; s. 61, ch. 2004-301.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 559.409; s. 497.044; s. 497.325.</Text></Note></Section>