<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.151" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Complaints; logs; procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall be applicable to all entities licensed under this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensees shall cause to be maintained on a continuing basis a log of all written complaints received by the licensee regarding any aspect of the licensee’s operations. The log shall show the complainant’s name, the date the complaint was received, and the complainant’s address and phone number if shown in the complaint. Each written complaint received shall be entered into the complaint log within 10 days after receiving such complaint. The licensing authority may by rule establish requirements relating to complaint logs, including whether the log may be electronically maintained or must be kept in writing by pen and ink. Each licensee under this chapter shall retain in its records all written complaints received by the licensee or the licensee’s staff. All complaint logs, and all written complaints and related papers, shall be retained by the licensee until the completion of the next examination by the department of the licensee, which examination covers the period the complaint was received or such other period as the licensing authority may by rule require.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules may be adopted modifying the requirements of this section as applied to different categories of licensees under this chapter, if the board determines that the requirements of this section are impractical as to any category of licensees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the response of a customer recorded by the customer on a customer satisfaction questionnaire or survey form sent to the customer by the licensee, and returned by the customer to the licensee, shall not be deemed to be a complaint.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 2004-301; s. 12, ch. 2005-155.</History></Section>