<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.264" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License not assignable or transferable.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license issued to operate a cemetery pursuant to this chapter is not transferable or assignable, and a licensee may not develop or operate any cemetery authorized by this chapter at any location other than that contained in the application for the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity that seeks to purchase or otherwise acquire control of any cemetery licensed under this chapter shall first apply to the licensing authority and obtain approval of such purchase or change in control.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority may adopt rules establishing forms and procedures for such applications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall state the name and address of the licensed cemetery to which the application relates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For applications by a natural person, the application shall state the applicant’s name, residence address, address of principal office or place of employment, and social security number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For applications by an entity, the application shall state the applicant’s name, address of principal place of business or headquarters offices, the names and titles of all officers of the applicant, the applicant’s state of domicile and date of formation, and the applicant’s federal tax identification number.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall require such historical sketches and audited or unaudited financial statements concerning the applicant and each principal of the applicant as the licensing authority may require by rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must have a net worth of $50,000, as attested to by a sworn statement signed by the applicant if a natural person, otherwise by all officers of the applicant. Such net worth must be continually maintained as a condition of licensure of the cemetery if the application is approved.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall include such description of the development plans the applicant has for the proposed cemetery as the licensing authority may require by rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall be required to make disclosure of the applicant’s criminal records, if any, as required by s. 497.142.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall require the applicant to disclose whether the applicant or any principal of the applicant has ever had a license or the authority to practice a profession or occupation refused, suspended, fined, denied, or otherwise acted against or disciplined by the licensing authority of any jurisdiction. The licensing authority may require by rule additional information to be provided concerning any affirmative answers. A licensing authority’s acceptance of a relinquishment of licensure, stipulation, consent order, or other settlement, offered in response to or in anticipation of the filing of charges against the license, shall be construed as action against the license. The licensing authority may require by rule additional information to be provided concerning any affirmative answers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall submit fingerprints in accordance with s. 497.142.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall demonstrate by clear and convincing evidence that the applicant has the ability, experience, financial stability, and integrity to operate a cemetery, and if the applicant is an entity, that the applicant’s principals are of good character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be signed in accordance with s. 497.141(12).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable application fee of $5,000; provided, the fee shall be $500 if the application is in regard to a change in ownership that will not be accompanied by any change in ultimate control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority may establish by rule requirements for the appearance before the licensing authority of the applicant and the applicant’s principals, to stand for oral interview by the licensing authority at a public licensing authority meeting, before the application shall be deemed complete.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A completed application shall be approved if the requirements of this section are met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 59-363; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 39, 40, ch. 80-238; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 39, ch. 83-215; s. 4, ch. 85-202; s. 1, ch. 89-8; ss. 60, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 46, ch. 2004-301; s. 24, ch. 2005-155.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 559.47; s. 497.007; s. 497.205.</Text></Note></Section>