<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.452" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preneed license required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person, including any cemetery exempt under s. 497.260, may sell, advertise to sell, or make an arrangement for a preneed contract without first having a valid preneed license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person, including any cemetery exempt under s. 497.260, may sell, advertise to sell, or make an arrangement for services, merchandise, or burial rights on a preneed basis unless such person is authorized pursuant to this chapter to provide such services, merchandise, or burial rights on an at-need basis.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may receive any funds for payment on a preneed contract who does not hold a valid preneed license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraph (a) do not apply to a trust company operating pursuant to chapter 660, to a national or state bank holding trust powers, or to a federal or state savings and loan association having trust powers which company, bank, or association receives any money in trust pursuant to the sale of a preneed contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of paragraph (a) do not apply to any Florida corporation existing under chapter 607 acting as a servicing agent hereunder in which the stock of such corporation is held by 100 or more persons licensed pursuant to part III of this chapter, provided no one stockholder holds, owns, votes, or has proxies for more than 5 percent of the issued stock of such corporation; provided the corporation has a blanket fidelity bond, covering all employees handling the funds, in the amount of $50,000 or more issued by a licensed insurance carrier in this state; and provided the corporation processes the funds directly to and from the trustee within the applicable time limits set forth in this chapter. The department may require any person claiming that the provisions of this paragraph exempt it from the provisions of paragraph (a) to demonstrate to the satisfaction of the department that it meets the requirements of this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person may obtain a preneed license under this chapter for the preneed sale of merchandise or services unless such person or its agent, in the case of a corporate entity, holds a license as a funeral establishment, cemetery company, direct disposal establishment, or monument establishment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section do not apply to religious-institution-owned cemeteries exempt under s. 497.260(1)(d), in counties with a population of at least 960,000 persons on July 1, 1996, with respect to the sale to the religious institution’s members and their families of interment rights, mausoleums, crypts, cremation niches, cremation interment containers, vaults, liners, urns, memorials, vases, foundations, memorial bases, floral arrangements, monuments, markers, engraving, and the opening and closing of interment rights, mausoleums, crypts, cremation niches, and cremation interment containers, if such cemeteries have engaged in the sale of preneed contracts prior to October 1, 1993, and maintain a positive net worth at the end of each fiscal year of the cemetery.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 28211, 1953; s. 24, ch. 57-1; s. 5, ch. 65-393; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 77-438; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 31, 32, ch. 83-316; s. 3, ch. 88-139; ss. 92, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 19, ch. 96-400; s. 9, ch. 2000-195; s. 8, ch. 2001-120; s. 101, ch. 2004-301.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 639.09; s. 497.405.</Text></Note></Section>