<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.285" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inactive cemeteries.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee shall be considered inactive upon the acceptance of the surrender of its license by the department or upon the nonreceipt by the department of the license renewal fees required by s. 497.265.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cemetery licensee licensed to engage in preneed sales shall cease all preneed sales to the public upon becoming inactive in regard to its cemetery license. At-need sales to the public shall cease within 30 days after becoming inactive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensee desiring to surrender its license to the department shall first:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File notice with the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit copies of its existing trust agreements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resolve to the department’s satisfaction all findings and violations resulting from the last examination conducted.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay all outstanding fines and invoices due the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit its current license.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of the notice, the department shall review the licensee’s:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trust funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Trust agreements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Care and maintenance of the cemetery grounds.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After a review to the department’s satisfaction, the department shall terminate the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The care and maintenance trust fund of a licensee shall be held intact and in trust after the licensee has become inactive, and funds in that trust fund shall be disbursed to the cemetery on a regular basis for the upkeep of the grounds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The merchandise trust fund of a licensee shall be held intact and in trust after the licensee has become inactive, and the funds in that trust fund shall be disbursed in accordance with the requirements of the written contracts until the fund has been exhausted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 85, ch. 93-399; s. 66, ch. 2004-301.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 497.349.</Text></Note></Section>