<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0497.374" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Funeral directing; licensure as a funeral director by endorsement; licensure of a temporary funeral director.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority shall issue a license by endorsement to practice funeral directing to an applicant who has remitted a fee set by rule of the licensing authority not to exceed $200 and who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form and remitted a nonrefundable application fee set by rule of the licensing authority not to exceed $200.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid license to practice funeral directing in another state of the United States, provided that, when the applicant secured her or his original license, the requirements for licensure were substantially equivalent to or more stringent than those existing in this state; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the qualifications for licensure in s. 497.373 and has successfully completed a state, regional, or national examination in mortuary science or funeral service arts, which, as determined by rule of the licensing authority, is substantially equivalent to or more stringent than the examination given by the licensing authority.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has submitted proof of completion of a licensing authority-approved course on communicable diseases.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made disclosure of the applicant’s criminal records, if any, as required by s. 497.142. The applicant shall submit fingerprints in accordance with s. 497.142. The applicant may not be licensed under this section unless the licensing authority determines the applicant is of good character and has no demonstrated history of lack of trustworthiness or integrity in business or professional matters.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority shall not issue a license by endorsement or a temporary license to any applicant who is under investigation or prosecution in any jurisdiction for acts which would constitute a violation of this chapter until such time as the investigation or prosecution is complete.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State, regional, or national examinations and requirements for licensure in another state shall be presumed to be substantially equivalent to or more stringent than the examination and requirements in this state unless found otherwise by rule of the licensing authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant for licensure by endorsement must pass the examination on local, state, and federal laws and rules relating to the disposition of dead human bodies which is required under s. 497.373 and which shall be given by the licensing authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There may be adopted rules authorizing an applicant who has met the requirements of paragraphs (1)(b) and (c) and who is awaiting an opportunity to take the examination required by subsection (4) to obtain a license as a temporary funeral director. A licensed temporary funeral director may work as a funeral director in a licensed funeral establishment under the general supervision of a funeral director licensed under subsection (1) or s. 497.373. Such license shall expire 60 days after the date of the next available examination required under subsection (4); however, the temporary license may be renewed one time under the same conditions as initial issuance. The fee for initial issuance or renewal of a temporary license under this subsection shall be set by rule of the licensing authority but may not exceed $200. The fee required in this subsection shall be nonrefundable and in addition to the fee required in subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, ch. 79-231; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 89-8; s. 137, ch. 92-149; ss. 10, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 64, ch. 94-119; s. 317, ch. 97-103; s. 79, ch. 2004-301; s. 30, ch. 2005-155; s. 9, ch. 2007-55; s. 18, ch. 2010-125.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 470.011.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>