<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.171" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Identification of human remains.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRIOR TO FINAL DISPOSITION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall apply to licensees under parts III and VI.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee in charge of the final disposition of dead human remains shall, prior to final disposition of such dead human remains, affix to the ankle or wrist of the deceased, and on the casket, alternative container, or cremation container, a tag providing proper identification of the dead human remains. The identification tag shall be encased in or consist of durable and long-lasting material and shall list the name, date of birth, and date of death of the deceased, if available. The board may adopt rules specifying acceptable materials for such identification tag, acceptable locations for the tag on the casket, alternative container, or cremation container, and acceptable methods of affixing the tag.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the dead human remains are cremated, proper identification shall be placed in the container or urn containing the cremated remains.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensee responsible for removal of dead human remains to any establishment, facility, or location shall ensure that the remains are identified by a tag or other means of identification that is affixed to the ankle or wrist of the deceased at the time the remains are removed from the place of death or other location.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTERMENT IN UNLICENSED CEMETERIES.<EmDash />The identification of human remains interred in an unlicensed cemetery shall be the responsibility of the licensed funeral establishment in charge of the funeral arrangements for the deceased person. The licensed funeral establishment in charge of the funeral arrangements for the interment of human remains in an unlicensed cemetery shall place on the outer burial container, cremation interment container, or other container or on the inside of a crypt or niche a tag or permanent identifying mark listing the name of the decedent and the date of death, if available. The materials and locations of the tag or mark shall be more specifically described by rule of the licensing authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTERMENT IN LICENSED CEMETERIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection shall apply to cemetery licensees under part II.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to interments in a licensed cemetery, each licensed cemetery shall place on the outer burial container, cremation interment container, or other container or on the inside of a crypt or niche a tag or permanent identifying marker listing the name of the decedent and the date of death, if available. The materials and the location of the tag or marker shall be more specifically described by rule of the licensing authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensed cemetery may rely entirely on the identity stated on the burial transit permit or on the identification supplied by a person licensed under this chapter to establish the identity of the dead human remains delivered by such person for burial and shall not be liable for any differences between the identity shown on the burial transit permit or identification and the actual identity of the dead human remains delivered by such person and buried in the cemetery.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DIRECT DISPOSAL ESTABLISHMENTS.<EmDash />Direct disposal establishments shall establish a system of identification of human remains received that shall be designed to track the identity of the remains from the time of receipt until delivery of the remains to the authorized persons. This is in addition to the requirements for identification of human remains set forth in subsection (1). A copy of the identification procedures shall be available, upon request, to the department and legally authorized persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RELIANCE ON LEGALLY AUTHORIZED PERSON.<EmDash />Any licensee charged with responsibility under this section may rely on the representation of a legally authorized person to establish the identity of dead human remains.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 2005-155.</History></Section>