<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.454" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Approval of preneed contract and related forms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preneed contract forms and related forms shall be filed with and approved by the licensing authority prior to use, pursuant to procedures specified by rule. The licensing authority may not approve any preneed contract form that does not provide for sequential prenumbering thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A form filed for approval under this section shall be approved unless it is determined that it:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in any respect in violation of, or does not comply with, this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains, or incorporates by reference any inconsistent, ambiguous, or misleading clauses, or exceptions and conditions which deceptively affect the benefits purportedly provided to the customer in the general terms of the contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has any title, heading, or other indication of its contents which is misleading.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is printed or otherwise reproduced in such manner as to render any material provision substantially illegible, or contains variations in print size which de-emphasize provisions which limit or restrict the customer’s rights under the contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains provisions that are unfair or inequitable or contrary to the public policy of this state or that encourage misrepresentation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not provide for the specification in reasonable detail of the type, size, and design of merchandise and the description of service to be delivered or performed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specific disclosure regarding the preneed licensee’s ability to select either trust funding or the financial responsibility alternative as set forth in s. 497.461 in connection with the receipt of preneed contract proceeds is required in the preneed contract.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 32, ch. 83-316; s. 5, ch. 88-139; ss. 94, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 103, ch. 2004-301.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 639.105; s. 497.409.</Text></Note></Section>