<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.164" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Solicitation of goods or services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board is authorized to adopt rules regulating the solicitation of sales of burial rights, merchandise, or services by licensees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall regulate such solicitation to protect the public from solicitation which is intimidating, overreaching, fraudulent, or misleading; which utilizes undue influence; or which takes undue advantage of a person’s ignorance or emotional vulnerability.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall regulate any solicitation which comprises an uninvited invasion of personal privacy. It is the express finding of the Legislature that the public have a high expectation of privacy in their personal residences, and the department by rule shall restrict the hours or otherwise regulate such solicitation in the personal residence of a person unless the solicitation has been previously and expressly requested by the person solicited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict the right of a person to lawfully advertise, use direct mail, or otherwise communicate in a manner not within the definition of solicitation or to solicit the business of anyone responding to such communication or otherwise initiating discussion of goods and services being offered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At-need solicitation of sales of burial rights, merchandise, or services is prohibited. No person may contact the family or next of kin of a deceased person to sell services or merchandise unless the person has been initially called or contacted by the family or next of kin of such person or persons and requested to provide services or merchandise.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 38, ch. 80-238; s. 409, ch. 81-259; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 4, ch. 85-16; s. 1, ch. 89-8; ss. 72, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 34, ch. 2004-301.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 559.408; s. 497.043; s. 497.321.</Text></Note></Section>