<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0497.372" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Funeral directing; conduct constituting practice of funeral directing.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of funeral directing shall be construed to consist of the following functions, which may be performed only by a licensed funeral director:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selling or offering to sell funeral services, embalming, cremation, or other services relating to the final disposition of human remains, including the removal of such remains from the state, on an at-need basis.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Planning or arranging, on an at-need basis, the details of funeral services, embalming, cremation, or other services relating to the final disposition of human remains, including the removal of such remains from the state, with the family or friends of the decedent or any other person responsible for such services; setting the time of the services; establishing the type of services to be rendered; acquiring the services of the clergy; and obtaining vital information for the filing of death certificates and obtaining of burial transit permits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making, negotiating, or completing the financial arrangements for funeral services, embalming, cremation, or other services relating to the final disposition of human remains, including the removal of such remains from the state, on an at-need basis, except that nonlicensed personnel may assist the funeral director in performing such tasks.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directing, being in charge or apparent charge of, or supervising, directly or indirectly, a visitation or viewing. Such functions shall not require that a licensed funeral director be physically present throughout the visitation or viewing, provided that the funeral director is readily available by telephone for consultation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directing, being in charge or apparent charge of, or supervising, directly or indirectly, any funeral service held in a funeral establishment, cemetery, or elsewhere.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directing, being in charge or apparent charge of, or supervising, directly or indirectly, any memorial service held prior to or within 72 hours of the burial or cremation, if such memorial service is sold or arranged by a licensee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using in connection with one’s name or employment the words or terms “funeral director,” “funeral establishment,” “undertaker,” “mortician,” or any other word, term, title, or picture, or combination of any of the above, that when considered in the context in which used would imply that such person is engaged in the practice of funeral directing or that such person is holding herself or himself out to the public as being engaged in the practice of funeral directing; provided, however, that nothing in this paragraph shall prevent using the name of any owner, officer, or corporate director of a funeral establishment, who is not a licensee, in connection with the name of the funeral establishment with which such individual is affiliated, so long as such individual’s affiliation is properly specified.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managing or supervising the operation of a funeral establishment, except for administrative matters such as budgeting, accounting and personnel, maintenance of buildings, equipment and grounds, and routine clerical and recordkeeping functions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A funeral director may not engage in the practice of funeral directing except through affiliation with a funeral establishment licensed under this chapter. The board shall adopt by rule criteria for determining whether such an affiliation exists through the funeral director’s ownership of, employment by, or contractual relationship with, a funeral establishment. This subsection does not prohibit a funeral director from being designated the licensed funeral director in charge of a cineration facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of funeral directing shall not be construed to consist of the following functions:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The phoning-in, faxing, or electronic transmission of obituary notices; ordering of flowers or merchandise; delivery of death certificates to attending physicians; or clerical preparation and processing of death certificates, insurance forms, and any clerical tasks that record the information compiled by the funeral director or that are incidental to any of the functions specified above.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnishing standard printed price lists and other disclosure information to the public by telephone or by providing such lists to persons making inquiry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Removing or transporting human remains from the place of death, or removing or transporting human remains from or to a funeral establishment, centralized embalming facility, refrigeration facility, cemetery, crematory, medical examiner’s office, common carrier, or other locations as authorized and provided by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arranging, coordinating, or employing licensed removal services, licensed refrigeration facilities, or licensed centralized embalming facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any aspect of making preneed funeral arrangements or entering into preneed contracts.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any functions normally performed by cemetery or crematory personnel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 93-399; s. 77, ch. 2004-301; s. 16, ch. 2010-125; s. 40, ch. 2011-4.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 470.0087.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>