<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0497.378" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Renewal of funeral director and embalmer licenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority shall renew a funeral director or embalmer license upon receipt of the renewal application and fee set by the licensing authority, not to exceed $500. The licensing authority may adopt rules for the renewal of a funeral director or embalmer license. The rules may require continuing education of up to 12 classroom hours and may establish criteria for accepting alternative nonclassroom continuing education on an hour-for-hour basis, in addition to a licensing authority-approved course on communicable diseases, for the renewal of a funeral director or embalmer license. The rules may also provide for the waiver of continuing education requirements in circumstances that would justify the waiver, such as hardship, disability, or illness. The continuing education requirement is not required for a licensee who is over the age of 75 years if the licensee does not qualify as the sole person in charge of an establishment or facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority shall adopt rules establishing a procedure for the biennial renewal of licenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority shall adopt rules to establish requirements for the advertising of continuing education courses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, ch. 79-231; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 89-8; ss. 13, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 209, ch. 94-119; s. 2, ch. 96-355; s. 5, ch. 98-298; s. 24, ch. 2000-356; s. 83, ch. 2004-301; s. 32, ch. 2005-155; s. 21, ch. 2010-125.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 470.015.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>