<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.461" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Surety bonding as alternative to trust deposit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of depositing funds into a trust as required by s. 497.458(1) or s. 497.464, a preneed licensee may elect annually, at its discretion, to comply with this section by filing annually a written request with, and receiving annual approval from, the licensing authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No preneed licensee shall utilize this section unless it has filed annually a written request with, and received approval by, the licensing authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preneed licensee receiving approval from the licensing authority to comply with this section shall maintain compliance with this section at all times during the period this election is in effect.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preneed licensee’s request to be governed by this section shall be in the form prescribed by rule by the licensing authority and shall be accompanied by, in addition to other information that the licensing authority may require by rule, the surety bond, the audited financial statements, and proof of the other requirements specified in this section, all as described in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each 12-month period, or any part thereof, in which this section is applicable, the electing preneed licensee shall maintain a bond, issued by a surety company admitted to do business in this state, in an amount at least equal to the sum of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All amounts not currently in trust.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount equal to the total purchase price for all installed preneed contracts where the total purchase price has not been collected, excluding those amounts already in trust.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All amounts the preneed licensee intends to remove from trust if the licensing authority approves the preneed licensee’s request to comply with this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An amount equal to 70 percent of the total purchase price for each preneed contract the preneed licensee expects to sell in the year for which the preneed licensee is electing to comply with this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surety bond shall be conditioned in such a manner to secure the faithful performance of all conditions of any preneed contracts for which the preneed licensee was required to have covered by the amount of the bond, including refunds requested pursuant to ss. 497.459 and 497.460. The surety bond shall also guarantee the financial responsibility of such preneed licensee against its default arising out of any of its preneed contracts. The terms of the surety bond shall cover liabilities arising from all moneys received by the electing preneed licensee from preneed contracts for which the preneed licensee was required to have covered by the amount of the bond during the time the bond is in effect, and the liability of the surety shall continue until the contracts thereunder are fulfilled. The bond shall be in favor of the state for the benefit of any person damaged as a result of purchasing a preneed contract from the preneed licensee. The aggregate liability of the surety to all persons for all breaches of the conditions of the bonds shall in no event exceed the amount of the bond. The per preneed contract liability shall not exceed the amount of the funds received by the preneed licensee per preneed contract during the effective period in which the bond is issued. The bond shall be filed and maintained with the licensing authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of the surety bond shall, upon order of the licensing authority, be increased if, in the licensing authority’s discretion, it finds such increase to be warranted by the volume of preneed contracts handled, or expected to be handled, by the preneed licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surety bond shall be in a form to be approved by the licensing authority, and the licensing authority shall have the right to disapprove any bond which does not provide assurance as provided in, and required by, this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bond shall be maintained unimpaired for as long as the preneed licensee continues in business in this state and continues to utilize this section. Whenever the preneed licensee notifies the licensing authority that it no longer desires to be governed by this section and furnishes to the licensing authority satisfactory proof that it has discharged or otherwise adequately provided for all of its obligations to its preneed contract purchasers covered by the bond, such as by evidence satisfactory to the licensing authority demonstrating that s. 497.458 or s. 497.464 has been complied with, the licensing authority shall release the bond to the entitled parties, provided said parties acknowledge receipt of same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No surety bond used to comply with this section shall be canceled or subject to cancellation unless at least 60 days’ advance notice thereof, in writing, is filed with the licensing authority, by the surety company. The cancellation of the bond shall not relieve the obligation of the surety company for claims arising out of contracts issued or otherwise covered before cancellation of the bond.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that notice of cancellation of the bond is filed with the licensing authority, the preneed licensee insured thereunder shall, within 30 days of the filing of the notice of termination with the licensing authority, provide the licensing authority with a replacement bond or with evidence which is satisfactory to the licensing authority demonstrating that s. 497.458 or s. 497.464 has been fully complied with. If within 30 days of filing of the notice of termination with the licensing authority no replacement bond acceptable to the licensing authority or no evidence satisfactory to the licensing authority demonstrating that s. 497.458 or s. 497.464 has been complied with is filed with the licensing authority, the licensing authority shall suspend the license of the preneed licensee until the preneed licensee files a replacement bond acceptable to the board or demonstrates to the satisfaction of the licensing authority that it has complied with s. 497.458 or s. 497.464.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of the surety bond, the licensing authority may provide by rule for other forms of security or insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every preneed licensee electing to be governed by this section shall have its financial statements, submitted to the department pursuant to s. 497.453, audited by an independent public accountant certified pursuant to chapter 473. The financial statements shall contain, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, for two or more consecutive annual periods, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certified public accountant’s unqualified opinion or, in the case of a qualified opinion, a qualified opinion acceptable to the licensing authority, and:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A balance sheet;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of income and expenses; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of changes in financial position.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notes to the financial statements considered customary or necessary for full disclosure and adequate understanding of the financial statements, financial condition, and operation of the preneed licensee. The notes shall include a schedule, based upon statutory accounting principles, indicating that the preneed licensee which has held a license pursuant to this chapter for less than 10 years has a current ratio of no less than 3 to 1 of current assets to current liabilities and net assets of at least $600,000 or that the preneed licensee which has held a license pursuant to this chapter for 10 years or more has a current ratio of no less than 2 to 1 of current assets to current liabilities and net assets of at least $400,000.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An indication that the preneed licensee has sufficient funds available to perform the obligations under all its preneed contracts.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority may require that the audited financial statements be prepared on a calendar-year basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The electing preneed licensee shall provide the licensing authority interim unaudited financial statements on a quarterly basis demonstrating financial compliance with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of subsections (4)-(14), a preneed licensee with net assets of at least $25,000 may request to comply with this section by providing a written guarantee from a qualified guaranteeing organization. If the preneed licensee so elects, the preneed licensee’s requests to be governed by this section shall be in the form prescribed by rule and shall be accompanied by, in addition to other information the licensing authority may require by rule, a written guarantee approved by the licensing authority as meeting the requirements of this section from a qualified guaranteeing organization, acceptable to the licensing authority, which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is either a preneed licensee or servicing agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a corporation formed under the laws of this state or of another state, district, territory, or possession of the United States.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been in operation for 10 or more years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submits to the licensing authority its annual financial statements audited by an independent public accountant certified pursuant to chapter 473. The financial statements shall contain, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, for two or more consecutive annual periods, the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certified public accountant’s unqualified opinion or, in the case of a qualified opinion, a qualified opinion acceptable to the licensing authority, and:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A balance sheet;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of income and expenses; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of changes in financial position.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notes to the financial statements considered customary or necessary for full disclosure and adequate understanding of the financial statements, financial condition, and operation of the preneed licensee. The notes shall include a schedule, based upon statutory accounting principles, indicating that the guaranteeing organization has a current ratio of no less than 2 to 1 of current assets to current liabilities and net assets of at least $250,000.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has sufficient funds available to perform the obligations under its guarantees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has complied with subsections (5)-(11), except that the bond shall be maintained by the guaranteeing organization in the minimum aggregate principal amount of $1 million.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has principals, including directors, officers, stockholders, employees, and agents that are of good moral character and have reputations for fair dealing in business matters, both as determined by the licensing authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 17, ch. 88-139; ss. 101, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 110, ch. 2004-301; s. 121, ch. 2007-5.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 639.145; s. 497.423.</Text></Note></Section>