<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.368" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Embalmers; licensure as an embalmer by examination; provisional license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed as an embalmer shall apply to the licensing authority to take the licensure examination. The licensing authority shall examine each applicant who has remitted an examination fee set by rule of the licensing authority not to exceed $200 plus the actual per applicant cost to the licensing authority for portions of the examination and who has:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed the application form and remitted a nonrefundable application fee set by the licensing authority not to exceed $200.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted proof satisfactory to the licensing authority that the applicant is at least 18 years of age and is a recipient of a high school degree or equivalent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Made disclosure of the applicant’s criminal records, if any, as required by s. 497.142. The applicant shall submit fingerprints in accordance with s. 497.142. The applicant may not be licensed under this section unless the licensing authority determines the applicant is of good character and has no demonstrated history of lack of trustworthiness or integrity in business or professional matters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completed a course in mortuary science approved by the licensing authority, which course embraces, at least, the following subjects: theory and practice of embalming, restorative art, pathology, anatomy, microbiology, chemistry, hygiene, and public health and sanitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitted proof of completion of a course on communicable diseases approved by the licensing authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority shall license the applicant as an embalmer if the applicant:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Passes an examination on the subjects of the theory and practice of embalming, restorative art, pathology, anatomy, microbiology, chemistry, hygiene, public health and sanitation, and local, state, and federal laws and rules relating to the disposition of dead human bodies; however, there may by rule be approved by the licensing authority the use of a national examination, such as the embalming examination prepared by the Conference of Funeral Service Examining Boards, in lieu of part of this examination requirement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completes a 1-year internship under a licensed embalmer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any applicant who has completed the required 1-year internship and has been approved for examination as an embalmer may qualify for a provisional license to work in a licensed funeral establishment, under the direct supervision of a licensed embalmer for a limited period of 6 months as provided by rule of the licensing authority. The fee for provisional licensure shall be set by rule of the licensing authority, but may not exceed $200, and shall be nonrefundable and in addition to the fee required in subsection (1). This provisional license may be renewed no more than one time.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 5, ch. 79-231; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 19, ch. 88-205; s. 1, ch. 89-8; s. 44, ch. 89-162; s. 17, ch. 91-137; ss. 5, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 60, ch. 94-119; s. 314, ch. 97-103; s. 2, ch. 98-298; s. 73, ch. 2004-301; s. 27, ch. 2005-155.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 470.006.</Text></Note></Section>