<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0497.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensing; general application procedures.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall supplement and implement all provisions of this chapter relating to application for licensure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed shall apply to the licensing authority in writing using such forms and procedures as may be prescribed by rule. The application for licensure shall include the applicant’s social security number if the applicant is a natural person; otherwise, the applicant’s federal tax identification number shall be included. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the department is the sole authority for determining the forms and form contents to be submitted for initial licensure and licensure renewal application. Such forms and the information and materials required by such forms may include, as appropriate, demographics, education, work history, personal background, criminal history, finances, business information, signature notarization, performance periods, reciprocity, local government approvals, supporting documentation, periodic reporting requirements, fingerprint requirements, continuing education requirements, business plans, character references, and ongoing education monitoring. Such forms and the information and materials required by such forms may also include, to the extent such information or materials are not already in the possession of the department or the board, records or information as to complaints, inspections, investigations, discipline, and bonding. The application shall be supplemented as needed to reflect any material change in any circumstance or condition stated in the application that takes place between the initial filing of the application and the final grant or denial of the license and that might affect the decision of the department or the board. After an application by a natural person for licensure under this chapter is approved, the licensing authority may require the successful applicant to provide a photograph of himself or herself for permanent lamination onto the license card to be issued to the applicant, pursuant to rules and fees adopted by the licensing authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall conduct such investigation of the applicant and the application as the department deems necessary or advisable to establish the correctness of matters stated in the application and to determine whether the applicable licensing criteria are met and shall make recommendations in those regards to the board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the issuance of any license, the department shall collect such initial fee as specified by this chapter or, where authorized, by rule of the board. Upon receipt of a completed application and the appropriate fee, and certification by the board that the applicant meets the applicable requirements of law and rules, the department shall issue the license applied for. However, an applicant who is not otherwise qualified for licensure is not entitled to licensure solely based on a passing score on a required examination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority may not issue, and effective July 1, 2011, may not renew, a license under this chapter to an applicant that has a criminal record required to be disclosed under s. 497.142(10) unless the applicant demonstrates that issuance of the license, according to rules adopted by the licensing authority, does not create a danger to the public. A licensee who previously disclosed her or his criminal record upon initial application or renewal of her or his license must disclose only a criminal offense for which the licensee was convicted or entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere since the most recent renewal of her or his license or, if the license has not been renewed, since the licensee’s initial application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may refuse to rule on an initial application for licensure by any applicant who is under investigation or prosecution in any jurisdiction for an action which there is reasonable cause to believe would constitute a violation of this chapter if committed in this state, until such time as such investigation or prosecution is completed and the results of the investigation or prosecution are reviewed by the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any administrative law judge conducts a hearing pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120 with respect to the issuance or denial of a license under this chapter, the administrative law judge shall submit her or his recommended order to the board, which shall thereupon issue a final order. The applicant for a license may appeal the final order in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A privilege against civil liability is hereby granted to any witness for any information furnished by the witness in any proceeding pursuant to this section, unless the witness acted in bad faith or with malice in providing such information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, each applicant for licensure is required to provide her or his social security number in accordance with this section. Disclosure of social security numbers obtained through this requirement shall be limited to the purpose of administration of the Title IV-D program for child support enforcement and use by the department and as otherwise provided by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any provision of this chapter or rules adopted under this chapter require student completion of a specific number of clock hours of classroom instruction for initial licensure purposes, there shall be established by rule the minimal competencies that such students must demonstrate in order to be licensed. The demonstration of such competencies may be substituted for specific classroom clock-hour requirements established in statute or rule which are related to instructional programs for licensure purposes. Student demonstration of the established minimum competencies shall be certified by the educational institution. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply if federal licensure standards are more restrictive or stringent than the standards prescribed in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No license issued under this chapter shall be assignable or transferable except to the extent specifically provided by this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall implement a system for administration of the overall licensing process, including the processing and tracking of applications for licensure, the issuance of licenses approved by the board, the tracking of licenses issued, the administration of the license renewal process, and the collection and processing of fees related to those activities. The system may use staff and facilities of the department or the department may enter into a contract for all or any part of such system, upon such terms and conditions as the department deems advisable, and such contract may be with another government agency or a private business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following licenses may only be applied for and issued to a natural person:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Embalmer apprentice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Embalmer intern.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funeral director intern.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funeral director.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funeral director and embalmer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct disposer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monument establishment sales agent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preneed sales agent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following licenses may be applied for and issued to a natural person, a corporation, a limited liability company, or a partnership:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funeral establishment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Centralized embalming facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refrigeration facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Direct disposal establishment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monument establishment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cinerator facility.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Removal service.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preneed sales business under s. 497.453.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cemetery license may only be applied for and issued to a corporation, partnership, or limited liability company.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No license shall be issued to any applicant that is a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership unless the applicant is organized and in good standing under the laws of this state or another state of the United States and provides written proof thereof issued by the applicable state office or official in the state concerned. Each applicant that is a corporation, limited liability company, or partnership shall file with its application a written statement, signed by the same person who signs the application, identifying by name and business functional title the following persons, as applicable to the type of entity applying: officers, managers, managing members, partners, general partners, limited partners, managing partners, directors, all stockholders controlling more than 10 percent of the voting stock, and all other persons who may exercise control over the applicant. The licensing authority may require the filing of the applicant’s articles of incorporation or other organizational documents and a resume concerning any person identified in this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person regulated under chapter 395, chapter 400, or chapter 429, or any officer, administrator, or board member of such entity if the entity is a firm, corporation, partnership, or association, or any person owning 5 percent or more of such entity to conduct, maintain, manage, own, or operate a licensee under this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph does not apply to a board member of a corporation or organization regulated under chapter 395, chapter 400, or chapter 429, if the board member serves solely in a voluntary capacity, does not regularly take part in the day-to-day operational decisions of the corporation or organization, receives no remuneration for his or her services, and has no financial interest and has no family members with a financial interest in the corporation or organization.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All applications shall be signed by the applicant. Signatures of the applicant shall be as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the applicant is a natural person, the application shall be signed by the applicant.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the applicant is a corporation, the application shall be signed by the corporation’s president.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the applicant is a partnership, the application shall be signed by a partner, who shall provide proof satisfactory to the licensing authority of that partner’s authority to sign on behalf of the partnership.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the applicant is a limited liability company, the application shall be signed by a member of the company, who shall provide proof satisfactory to the licensing authority of that member’s authority to sign on behalf of the company.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority may adopt rules for the implementation of this section, including required procedures and forms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No license regulated under this chapter is assignable or transferable except as provided in this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority may adopt rules that require applicants for any category of licensure under this chapter to apply for the issuance or renewal of their licenses in an online electronic format.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The online electronic format for renewal of a license must not allow submission of an improperly prepared renewal application. Upon an applicant’s submission of her or his renewal application, the online electronic format must allow the applicant to print a receipt of the properly prepared renewal application.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules may allow an applicant to submit a paper form in lieu of the online electronic format and may impose an additional fee not to exceed $25 per form for submitting the paper form.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 2004-301; s. 6, ch. 2005-155; s. 2, ch. 2007-55; s. 5, ch. 2010-125.</History>
</Section>