<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.554" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Monument establishment sales representatives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSE REQUIRED.<EmDash />Each person selling monuments, markers, or related products for a monument establishment must be licensed as a monument establishment sales agent. This requirement shall apply notwithstanding that such person is already registered or licensed in another capacity pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION PROCEDURES.<EmDash />Licensure as a monument establishment sales agent shall be by submission of an application for licensure to the department on a form prescribed by rule.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall require the applicant to state her or his name, residence and business address, business phone number, social security number, and the name and address of the monument establishment for which the applicant will be selling.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall be required to make disclosure of the applicant’s criminal records, if any, as required by s. 497.142. The applicant shall submit fingerprints in accordance with s. 497.142.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall require the applicant to disclose whether the applicant has ever had a license or the authority to practice a profession or occupation revoked, suspended, fined, denied, or otherwise acted against or disciplined by the licensing authority of any jurisdiction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be signed by the applicant and the owner or an officer of the sponsoring monument establishment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The monument establishment sales agent application shall be accompanied by a fee of $50. The licensing authority may from time to time increase the application fee by rule but not to exceed $200.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPROVAL OR DENIAL OF APPLICATION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a properly completed application accompanied by the required application fee indicates the applicant has no criminal or disciplinary record, the requested licensure shall be deemed granted upon receipt of the duly completed application by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the application indicates the applicant has any criminal or disciplinary history, licensure shall be granted unless the licensing authority determines that the licensure of the applicant would pose a substantial threat to the welfare of the public with which the applicant might be dealing as a monument establishment sales agent. Rules may be adopted providing criteria for evaluating criminal and disciplinary records as they may affect applications for licensure under this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RENEWAL; TERMINATION OF AUTHORITY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A monument establishment sales agent license under this section shall be renewed upon payment of a fee determined by rule of the licensing authority but not to exceed $250.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The monument establishment whose officer signed the sales agent application shall terminate that agent’s authority to sell on behalf of that monument establishment, and the monument establishment in writing shall advise the licensing authority of such termination within 30 days after the termination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RESPONSIBILITY FOR AGENTS.<EmDash />The sponsoring monument establishment shall be responsible for the activities of its sales agents concerning their sales activities and shall reasonably supervise such activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AGENT LICENSE REQUIRED.<EmDash />A person selling monuments, markers, and related products on a preneed basis for a monument establishment that has been issued a preneed sales license must also obtain authorization as a preneed sales agent under part IV of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EFFECTIVE DATE.<EmDash />The provisions of this section shall take effect October 1, 2006.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 122, ch. 2004-301; s. 44, ch. 2005-155.</History></Section>