<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.274" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards for grave spaces.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A standard adult grave space shall measure at least 42 inches in width and 96 inches in length, except for preinstalled vaults in designated areas. For interments, except cremated remains, the covering soil shall measure no less than 12 inches from the top of the outer burial container at time of interment, unless such level of soil is not physically possible. In any interment, the family or next of kin may waive the 12-inch coverage minimum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the sale of grave spaces in any undeveloped areas of a licensed cemetery, the cemetery company shall prepare a map documenting the establishment of recoverable internal survey reference markers installed by the cemetery company no more than 100 feet apart in the areas planned for development. The internal reference markers shall be established with reference to survey markers that are no more than 200 feet apart which have been set by a surveyor and mapper licensed under chapter 472 and documented in a certified land survey. Both the map and the certified land survey shall be maintained by the cemetery company and shall be made available upon request to the department or members of the public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The map of the area proposed to be developed shall show:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of grave spaces available for sale.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of each grave space.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number designation assigned to each grave space.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dimensions of a standard adult grave space.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult grave spaces established prior to October 1, 2005, are not required to meet the standards established under this section for the dimensions or separation of grave spaces.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 56, ch. 2004-301.</History></Section>