<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.158" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court enforcement actions; powers; abatement of nuisances.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to or in lieu of other actions authorized by this chapter, the department may petition the courts of this state for injunctive or other relief against any licensed or unlicensed person for the enforcement of this chapter and orders issued under this chapter. The court shall be authorized to impose a fine of up to $5,000 per violation on any licensee under this chapter and up to $10,000 on any person not licensed under this chapter, payable to the department, upon any person determined by the court to have violated this chapter, and may order payment to the department of the department’s attorney’s fees and litigation costs, by any person found to have violated this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to all other means provided by law for the enforcement by a court of a temporary restraining order or an injunction, the circuit court may impound the property of a licensee, including books, papers, documents, and records pertaining thereto, and may appoint a receiver or administrator to prevent further violation of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court-appointed receiver or administrator may take any action to implement the provisions of the court order, to ensure the performance of the order, and to remedy any breach thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nonconforming physical condition in a cemetery or component thereof which is the result of a violation of this chapter or of the rules adopted under this chapter relating to construction, physical operations, or care and maintenance at the cemetery shall be deemed a public nuisance, and the nonconforming physical conditions caused by such violation may be abated as provided in s. 60.05.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 40, ch. 80-238; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 89-8; ss. 89, 122, ch. 93-399; s. 4, ch. 98-268; s. 28, ch. 2004-301; s. 15, ch. 2005-155.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 559.374; s. 497.016; s. 497.229.</Text></Note></Section>