<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0497.281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure of brokers of burial rights.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall receive compensation to act as a third party to the sale or transfer of three or more burial rights in a 12-month period unless the person pays a license fee as determined by licensing authority rule but not to exceed $250 and is licensed with the department as a burial rights broker in accordance with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall be required to make disclosure of the applicant’s criminal records, if any, as required by s. 497.142.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall require the applicant to disclose whether the applicant or any principal of the applicant has ever had a license or the authority to practice a profession or occupation refused, suspended, fined, denied, or otherwise acted against or disciplined by the licensing authority of any jurisdiction. The licensing authority may require by rule additional information to be provided concerning any affirmative answers. A licensing authority’s acceptance of a relinquishment of licensure, stipulation, consent order, or other settlement, offered in response to or in anticipation of the filing of charges against the license, shall be construed as action against the license. The licensing authority may require by rule additional information to be provided concerning any affirmative answers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall submit fingerprints in accordance with s. 497.142. The application shall be signed in accordance with s. 497.141(12).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant shall demonstrate by clear and convincing evidence that the applicant has the ability, experience, and integrity to act as a burial broker and, if the applicant is an entity, that the applicant’s principals are of good character.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of preventing confusion and error by the licensee or by the cemeteries in which the burial rights are located as to the status as sold or unsold, and as to the identity of the owner, of the burial rights and related interment spaces in the cemetery, the licensing authority shall by rule establish requirements for minimum records to be maintained by licensees under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensing authority may by rule require inspections of the records of licensees under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, by rule, shall provide for the biennial renewal of licenses under this section and a renewal fee as determined by licensing authority rule but not to exceed $250.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensure requirements of this section shall not apply to persons otherwise licensed pursuant to this chapter, but such persons, if they engage in activity as burial rights brokers, shall be subject to rules relating to required records and inspections.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 74, ch. 93-399; s. 62, ch. 2004-301; s. 25, ch. 2005-155.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 497.329.</Text></Note></Section>