<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0497.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Other rulemaking provisions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to such other rules as are authorized or required under this chapter, the following additional rules, not inconsistent with this chapter, shall be authorized by the licensing authority.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules by the board defining any technical term used but not defined in this chapter, and defining the terms “at-need” and “preneed” as used in this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules by the board defining and regulating hazardous materials generated in connection with the practice of embalming, funeral directing, or direct disposition.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules by the board governing the operation of cemeteries in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules establishing a fee of up to $100 for issuance of a duplicate license or for a name change on a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules allowing and prescribing procedure and formats for the electronic submission of any applications, documents, filings, or fees required by this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules establishing procedures for investigation, financial examination, and inspection of licensees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to challenges for any invalid exercise of delegated legislative authority, no rule shall be adopted under this chapter, and the administrative law judge upon such a challenge by the department or the board may declare all or part of a rule or proposed rule invalid, if the rule or proposed rule:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not protect the public from any significant and discernible harm or damages;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonably restricts competition or the availability of professional services in the state or in a significant part of the state; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unnecessarily increases the cost of professional services without a corresponding or equivalent public benefit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">However, there shall not be created a presumption of the existence of any of the conditions cited in this subsection in the event that the rule or proposed rule is challenged.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the board shall each have standing under chapter 120 for the purposes of challenging rules or proposed rules under this chapter. This subsection shall not be interpreted to deny standing to a licensee to challenge any rule under this chapter if the licensee would otherwise have standing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, subject to approval by the board, adopt rules that temporarily suspend or modify any provision of this chapter during a state of emergency declared pursuant to s. 252.36. The rules may allow only the suspension or modification of a provision that is necessary or advisable to allow licensees under this chapter to provide essential services to the public under the emergency conditions. The rules may be adopted before any emergency exists, but may not take effect until the Governor issues an executive order or proclamation declaring a state of emergency. The rules may remain in effect after a state of emergency is terminated but only for the limited period necessary to allow for the transition back to normal operations under the nonemergency requirements of this chapter. However, a rule suspending or modifying any provision of this chapter may not remain in effect for more than 12 months after the state of emergency is terminated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 2004-301; s. 17, ch. 2005-155; s. 15, ch. 2007-6; s. 10, ch. 2010-125.</History>
</Section>