<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0796.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Coercion; civil cause of action; evidence; defenses; attorney’s fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person has a cause of action for compensatory and punitive damages against:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who coerced that person into prostitution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who coerces that person to remain in prostitution; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who uses coercion to collect or receive any part of that person’s earnings derived from prostitution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “prostitution” has the same meaning as in s. 796.07.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “coercion” means any practice of domination, restraint, or inducement for the purpose of or with the reasonably foreseeable effect of causing another person to engage in or remain in prostitution or to relinquish earnings derived from prostitution, and includes, but is not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical force or threats of physical force.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical or mental torture.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Kidnapping.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Blackmail.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extortion or claims of indebtedness.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Threat of legal complaint or report of delinquency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Threat to interfere with parental rights or responsibilities, whether by judicial or administrative action or otherwise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promise of legal benefit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promise of greater financial rewards.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promise of marriage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restraint of speech or communication with others.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exploitation of a condition of developmental disability, cognitive limitation, affective disorder, or substance dependency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exploitation of victimization by sexual abuse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exploitation of pornographic performance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exploitation of human needs for food, shelter, safety, or affection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the course of litigation under this section, any transaction about which a plaintiff testifies or produces evidence does not subject such plaintiff to criminal prosecution or any penalty or forfeiture. Further, any testimony or evidence, documentary or otherwise, or information directly or indirectly derived from such testimony or evidence which is given or produced by a plaintiff or a witness for a plaintiff shall not be used against these persons in any other investigation or proceeding. Such testimony or evidence, however, may be used against a plaintiff or a witness for a plaintiff upon any criminal investigation or proceeding for perjury committed while giving such testimony or producing such evidence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It does not constitute a defense to a complaint under this section that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plaintiff was paid or otherwise compensated for acts of prostitution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plaintiff engaged in acts of prostitution prior to any involvement with the defendant; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plaintiff made no attempt to escape, flee, or otherwise terminate contact with the defendant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidence of convictions for prostitution or prostitution-related offenses are inadmissible in a proceeding brought under this section for purposes of attacking the plaintiff’s credibility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action brought under this section, the court, in its discretion, may award prevailing plaintiffs reasonable attorney’s fees and costs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 91-32; s. 20, ch. 93-227.</History></Section>