<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0391.028" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Director of Children’s Medical Services must be a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 who has specialized training and experience in the provision of health care to children and who has recognized skills in leadership and the promotion of children’s health programs. The director shall be the deputy secretary and the Deputy State Health Officer for Children’s Medical Services and is appointed by and reports to the State Surgeon General. The director may appoint such other staff as necessary for the operation of the program subject to the approval of the State Surgeon General.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director shall provide for an operational system using such department staff and contract providers as necessary. The program shall implement the following program activities under physician supervision on a statewide basis:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Case management services for network participants;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management and oversight of local program activities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical and financial eligibility determination for the program in accordance with s. 391.029;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determination of a level of care and medical complexity for long-term care services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorizing services in the program and developing spending plans;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development of treatment plans; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resolution of complaints and grievances from participants and health care providers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each Children’s Medical Services area office shall be directed by a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 who has specialized training and experience in the provision of health care to children. The director of a Children’s Medical Services area office shall be appointed by the director from the active panel of Children’s Medical Services physician consultants.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 78-106; s. 17, ch. 96-403; s. 33, ch. 97-237; s. 7, ch. 98-288; s. 26, ch. 99-397; s. 45, ch. 2008-6; s. 78, ch. 2012-184.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (1) former s. 391.051.</Text></Note></Section>