<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0391.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Statewide Children’s Medical Services Network Advisory Council.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Surgeon General may appoint a Statewide Children’s Medical Services Network Advisory Council for the purpose of acting as an advisory body to the department. Specifically, the duties of the council shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommending standards and credentialing requirements for health care providers rendering health services to Children’s Medical Services network participants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making recommendations to the director of Children’s Medical Services concerning the selection of health care providers for the Children’s Medical Services network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing and making recommendations concerning network health care provider or participant disputes that are brought to the attention of the advisory council.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing input to the Children’s Medical Services program on the policies governing the Children’s Medical Services network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing the financial reports and financial status of the network and making recommendations concerning the methods of payment and cost controls for the network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing and recommending the scope of benefits for the network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reviewing network performance measures and outcomes and making recommendations for improvements to the network and its maintenance and collection of data and information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall be composed of 12 members representing the private health care provider sector, families with children who have special health care needs, the Agency for Health Care Administration, the Chief Financial Officer, the Florida Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics, an academic health center pediatric program, and the health insurance industry. Members shall be appointed for 4-year, staggered terms. In no case shall an employee of the Department of Health serve as a member or as an ex officio member of the advisory council. A vacancy shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. A member may not be appointed to more than two consecutive terms. However, a member may be reappointed after being off the council for at least 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members shall receive no compensation, but shall be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses in accordance with the provisions of s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 98-288; s. 44, ch. 99-397; s. 410, ch. 2003-261; s. 46, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>