<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0391.303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Program requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Developmental evaluation and intervention services shall be established at each hospital that provides Level II or Level III neonatal intensive care services. Program services shall be made available to an infant or toddler identified as being at risk for developmental disabilities, or identified as medically involved, who, along with his or her family, would benefit from program services. Program services shall be made available to infants or toddlers in a Level II or Level III neonatal intensive care unit or in a pediatric intensive care unit, or infants who have a metabolic or genetic disorder or a condition identified through the newborn screening program. The developmental evaluation and intervention programs are subject to the availability of moneys and the limitations established by the General Appropriations Act or chapter 216. Evaluation and referral services and initial developmental assessments services shall be provided to each infant or toddler. Other program services may be provided to an infant or toddler, and the family of the infant or toddler, who do not meet the financial eligibility criteria for the Children’s Medical Services program based on the availability of funding, including insurance and fees.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each developmental evaluation and intervention program shall have a program director, a medical director, and necessary staff to carry out the program. The program director shall establish and coordinate the developmental evaluation and intervention program. The program shall include, but is not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In-hospital evaluation and intervention services, parent support and training, and family support planning and case management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regularly held multidisciplinary team meetings to develop and update the family support plan. In addition to the family, a multidisciplinary team may include a physician, physician assistant, psychologist, psychotherapist, educator, social worker, nurse, physical or occupational therapist, speech pathologist, developmental evaluation and intervention program director, case manager, others who are involved with the in-hospital and posthospital discharge care plan, and anyone the family wishes to include as a member of the team. The family support plan is a written plan that describes the infant or toddler, the services the infant or toddler and his or her family need, and the intended outcomes of the services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discharge planning by the multidisciplinary team, including referral and followup to primary medical care and modification of the family support plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Education and training for neonatal and pediatric intensive care services staff, volunteers, and others, as needed, in order to expand the services provided to high-risk, developmentally disabled, or medically involved infants and toddlers and their families.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Followup intervention services after hospital discharge, to aid the family and the high-risk, developmentally disabled, or medically involved infant’s or toddler’s transition into the community. Support services shall be coordinated at the request of the family and within the context of the family support plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Referral to and coordination of services with community providers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational materials about infant care, infant growth and development, community resources, medical conditions and treatments, and family advocacy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Involvement of the parents and guardians of each identified high-risk, developmentally disabled, or medically involved infant or toddler.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 89-379; s. 25, ch. 91-282; s. 7, ch. 94-140; s. 1040, ch. 95-148; s. 27, ch. 98-288; s. 21, ch. 2004-350.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 383.215(4).</Text></Note></Section>