<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0391.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When used in this act, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Children’s Medical Services network” or “network” means a statewide managed care service system that includes health care providers, as defined in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Children with special health care needs” means those children younger than 21 years of age who have chronic and serious physical, developmental, behavioral, or emotional conditions and who require health care and related services of a type or amount beyond that which is generally required by children.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible individual” means a child with a special health care need or a female with a high-risk pregnancy, who meets the financial and medical eligibility standards established in s. 391.029.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care provider” means a health care professional, health care facility, or entity licensed or certified to provide health services in this state that meets the criteria as established by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health services” includes the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of human disease, pain, injury, deformity, or disabling conditions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Participant” means an eligible individual who is enrolled in the Children’s Medical Services program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Program” means the Children’s Medical Services program established in the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 78-106; s. 695, ch. 95-148; s. 87, ch. 97-101; s. 4, ch. 98-288; s. 43, ch. 99-397; s. 15, ch. 2004-350; s. 75, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>