<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0391.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service delivery systems.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall apply managed care methods to ensure the efficient operation of the Children’s Medical Services network. Such methods include, but are not limited to, capitation payments, utilization management and review, prior authorization, and case management.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The components of the network are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualified primary care physicians who shall serve as the gatekeepers and who shall be responsible for the provision or authorization of health services to an eligible individual who is enrolled in the Children’s Medical Services network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comprehensive specialty care arrangements that meet the requirements of s. 391.035 to provide acute care, specialty care, long-term care, and chronic disease management for eligible individuals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Case management services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Children’s Medical Services network may contract with school districts participating in the certified school match program pursuant to ss. 409.908(21) and 1011.70 for the provision of school-based services, as provided for in s. 409.9071, for Medicaid-eligible children who are enrolled in the Children’s Medical Services network.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a newborn has an abnormal screening result for metabolic or other hereditary and congenital disorders which is identified through the newborn screening program pursuant to s. 383.14, the newborn shall be referred to the Children’s Medical Services program for additional testing, medical management, early intervention services, or medical referral.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 98-288; s. 978, ch. 2002-387; s. 19, ch. 2004-350.</History></Section>