<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Termination of retail installment contract for leasing a motor vehicle by a servicemember.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any servicemember, as defined in s. 250.01, may terminate his or her retail installment contract for leasing a motor vehicle by providing the sales finance company with a written notice of termination, effective on the date specified in the notice, which date shall be at least 30 days after the receipt of the notice by the sales finance company, if any of the following criteria are met:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The servicemember is required, pursuant to a permanent change of station, to move outside the continental United States; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The servicemember receives temporary duty orders, temporary change of station orders, or active duty orders outside the continental United States, provided such orders are for a period exceeding 60 days.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written notice to the sales finance company under subsection (1) must be accompanied by either a copy of the official military orders or a written verification signed by the servicemember’s commanding officer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon termination of a contract under this section, the lessee is liable for the amount due under the contract, prorated to the effective date of the termination, payable at such time as would have otherwise been required by the terms of the contract. The lessee is not liable for any other fees due to the early termination of the contract as provided for in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section may not be waived or modified by the agreement of the parties under any circumstances.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 2003-72.</History></Section>