<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.68" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Persons not required to be licensed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No home improvement finance seller’s or seller’s license shall be required under this act of any person when acting in any capacity or type of transaction set forth in this section:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who performs services for a home improvement finance seller for wages or salary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plumber, electrician, architect, engineer, residential designer, or landscape architect who is required by state or local law to attain standards of competency or experience as a prerequisite to engaging in such craft or profession and who is acting exclusively within the scope of the craft or profession for which he or she is currently licensed pursuant to such other law. The installation of central heating and air-conditioning systems by such a person shall be deemed within the scope of such person’s craft or profession.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who does not engage, in any manner, in two or more home improvements, each of which was for consideration of $500 or more, within a calendar year. This exemption does not apply if the work is divided and contracts for less than $500 are made for the purpose of evasion of this provision or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person engaged in the construction or erection of any building upon land owned by that person or in which such person has a substantial legal or equitable interest, which building the owner does not intend to occupy but intends to sell upon completion thereof or shortly thereafter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person licensed under chapter 527.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retail establishments, including employees thereof, which are licensed under part II of this chapter and which engage in home improvements as an incidental part of their business. However, such retail establishments and their employees shall be governed by all other provisions contained in this act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-44; s. 2, ch. 70-149; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 16, 21, ch. 80-256; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 20, ch. 87-91; ss. 20, 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 693, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>