<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.73" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Home improvement contract; form and content; separate disclosures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every home improvement contract shall be evidenced by a written agreement and shall be signed by the parties. The home improvement contract shall be in the form approved by the office and shall contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and license number of the home improvement finance seller;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names of the home improvement finance seller’s employees who solicited or negotiated the home improvement contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The approximate dates when the work will begin and will be completed; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the work to be done and the materials to be used.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement contract shall also contain:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The “amount financed,” using that term, and a brief description such as “the amount of credit provided to you or on your behalf.” The amount financed is calculated by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining the cash price, and subtracting any down payment;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adding any other amounts that are financed by the creditor and that are not part of the finance charge; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subtracting any prepaid finance charge;</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The “finance charge,” using that term, and a brief description such as “the dollar amount the credit will cost you”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The “total of payments,” using that term, and a descriptive explanation such as “the amount you will have paid when you have made all scheduled payments”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a credit sale, the “total sale price,” using that term, and a descriptive explanation, including the amount of any down payment, such as “the total price of your purchase on credit, including your down payment of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.” The total sale price is the sum of the cash price, the items described in subparagraph (a)2., and the finance charge disclosed under paragraph (b);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of any money provided for debt consolidation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interest charge for the amount advanced for debt consolidation;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total amount due under the home improvement contract, which shall be stated as a sum in dollars, less any down payment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of monthly payments and the amount of each payment; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The description of any collateral security taken or to be taken for the owner’s obligation under the home improvement contract.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Except for the requirements of subsection (1) and the provisions of subsection (3) which provide for a separate written itemization of the amount financed, a contract which complies with the federal Truth in Lending Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1601 et seq., or any accompanying regulations shall be deemed to comply with the provisions of this subsection and subsection (3). However, in any proceeding to enforce the provisions of this section, the burden of alleging and proving compliance with the federal Truth in Lending Act shall be on the party claiming compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement finance seller shall provide a separate written itemization of the amount financed, which itemization shall disclose the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cash price;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of down payment;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The difference between the amounts disclosed under paragraphs (a) and (b);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amounts, if any, included for insurance and other benefits, specifying the types of coverages and benefits; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The official fees, survey charges, or permit charges actually incurred.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The itemization required by this subsection may appear on a disclosure statement separate from all other material, or it may be placed on the same document with the contract or other information so long as it is clearly and conspicuously segregated from everything else on the document.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement contract shall be completed in full without any blank spaces to be filled in after the home improvement contract is signed by the owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement contract shall contain the following notice, in substantially this form, and such other notices required by the public interest and specified by the commission by rule, in 10-point boldfaced type directly above the space provided for the signature of the owner:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">Notice To Owner</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">a. Do not sign this home improvement contract in blank.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">b. You are entitled to a copy of the contract at the time you sign. Keep it to protect your legal rights.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">c. This home improvement contract may contain a mortgage or otherwise create a lien on your property that could be foreclosed on if you do not pay. Be sure you understand all provisions of the contract before you sign.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement contract shall state whether workers’ compensation and public liability insurance are carried by the home improvement finance seller and if they are applicable to the work to be performed under the contract or if the home improvement finance seller is qualified as a self-insurer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-44; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-149; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 142, ch. 71-355; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 77, ch. 79-40; ss. 17, 21, ch. 80-256; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 8, ch. 83-123; s. 96, ch. 85-81; s. 24, ch. 87-91; ss. 24, 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 628, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>