<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.76" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance provisions, procurement, rates.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The premium paid for any group credit life or other insurance shall be included in the home improvement contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement contract shall state which party is to procure insurance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount, if any, included for such insurance shall not exceed the applicable premiums chargeable in accordance with rates filed with the Office of Insurance Regulation of the commission. If any such group credit life or other insurance is canceled, the refund for unearned insurance premiums received or receivable by the holder of the home improvement contract or the excess of the amount included in the contract for insurance over the premiums paid or payable by the holder of the contract together with, in either case, the unearned portion of the finance charge or other interest applicable thereto shall be credited to the final maturing installments of the home improvement contract. However, no such credit need be made if the amount would be less than $1.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the insurance is to be procured by the home improvement finance seller or holder, he or she shall, within 30 days after delivery of the goods and furnishing of the services under the home improvement contract, deliver or mail to the owner at his or her address as specified in the contract a copy of the policy or policies of insurance or a certificate or certificates of the insurance procured.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-44; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 18, 21, ch. 80-256; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 26, 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 695, ch. 97-103; s. 629, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>