<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.83" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cancellation of contract on payment in full.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all home improvement contracts pursuant to which there is a lien, mortgage, or encumbrance upon the goods or real property, upon payment in full by the owner of the time sales price and other amounts lawfully due under a home improvement contract, the holder shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Return to the owner the original instruments evidencing indebtedness under a home improvement contract which were signed by the owner or the owner’s sureties or guarantors in connection with such contract, excepting such instruments as are filed with a public official and retained in the files of such official;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Release all security interest in the goods and real property affected by the contract;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver to the owner such good and sufficient assignments, releases of liens and mortgages on personal and real property, and such other instruments of title as may be necessary to vest the owner with complete evidence of title.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all other home improvement contracts, the holder, upon payment in full by the owner of the time sales price and other amounts lawfully due under the home improvement contract, shall furnish the owner with such instruments as the commission may by rule provide.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-44; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 80-256; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 697, ch. 97-103; s. 631, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>