<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.74" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Provisions expressly prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No home improvement contract shall contain any provision by which:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The buyer agrees not to assert against a home improvement finance seller a claim or defense arising out of the sale or agrees not to assert against an assignee such a claim or defense;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the absence of the buyer’s default in the performance of any of her or his obligations, the holder may arbitrarily and without reasonable cause accelerate the maturity of any part or all of the amount owing thereunder;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The buyer waives any right of action against the home improvement finance seller or holder of the home improvement contract, or other person acting on her or his behalf, for any illegal act committed in the collection of payments under the home improvement contract;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The buyer relieves the home improvement finance seller from liability for any legal remedies which the buyer may have against the home improvement finance seller under the contract or any separate instrument executed in connection therewith;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement finance seller or holder or any person acting on behalf of the home improvement finance seller or holder is authorized to enter upon the premises of the buyer unlawfully;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home improvement finance seller or holder is entitled to liquidated damages in an amount which exceeds 10 percent of the cash price stated in the contract in the event of the buyer’s failure or refusal to accept delivery of the goods or performance of the services covered by the contract;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract requires or entails the execution of any note or series of notes by the buyer which, when separately negotiated, will cut off as to third parties any right of action or defense which the buyer may have against the home improvement finance seller;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any power of attorney to confess judgment or any power of attorney;</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any assignment of or order for the payment of wages, salary, commissions, or other compensation for services, or any part thereof, earned or to be earned.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-44; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 21, ch. 80-256; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 25, ch. 87-91; ss. 25, 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 694, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>