<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.90" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts are prohibited:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abandonment or willful failure to perform, without justification, any home improvement contract or project engaged in or undertaken by a home improvement finance seller or willful deviation from or disregard of plans or specifications in any material respect without the consent of the owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of a home improvement finance seller’s employee to account for or to remit to the home improvement finance seller any payment received in connection with a home improvement sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making any substantial misrepresentation in the procurement of a home improvement contract or making any false promise of a character likely to influence, persuade, or induce.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any fraud in the execution or in the material alteration of any contract, mortgage, promissory note, or other document incident to a home improvement finance transaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preparing or accepting any mortgage, promissory note, or other evidence of indebtedness upon the obligations of a home improvement finance transaction with knowledge that it recites a greater monetary obligation than the consideration for the home improvement work, which consideration may be a time sale price.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directly or indirectly publishing any advertisement relating to home improvements which contains an assertion, representation, or statement of fact which is false, deceptive, or misleading, provided that any advertisement which is subject to and complies with the then-existing rules, regulations, or guides of the Federal Trade Commission shall not be deemed false, deceptive, or misleading; or by any means advertising or purporting to offer the general public any home improvement work with the intent not to accept contracts for the particular work or at the price which is advertised or offered to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful or deliberate disregard and violation of the building laws of this state or of any political subdivision or of the safety, labor, or workers’ compensation insurance laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Doing any home improvement business with or through any person who is subject to the licensing requirements of this act with the knowledge that such person is not licensed as required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresentation of a material fact by an applicant in obtaining a license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful failure to notify the office of any change of control in ownership, management, business name, or location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducting a home improvement business in any name other than the one in which the home improvement finance seller is licensed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful failure to comply with any order, demand, or requirement lawfully made by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly or without the exercise of due care failing to comply with or violating any provision of this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful failure to perform any written agreement with an owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willful misrepresentation or failure to disclose any matter which is required to be stated to or furnished to the owner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-44; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 70-149; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 78, ch. 79-40; s. 21, ch. 80-256; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 26, ch. 87-91; ss. 31, 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 632, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>