<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In this act, unless the context or subject matter otherwise requires:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Branch” means any location, other than a licensee’s principal place of business, at which a licensee operates or conducts business under this act or which a licensee owns or controls for the purpose of conducting business under this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cash price” means the price at which a seller, in the ordinary course of business, offers to sell for cash the property or service that is the subject of the transaction. At the seller’s option, the term “cash price” may include the price of accessories, services related to the sale, service contracts, and taxes and fees for license, title, and registration of the motor vehicle. The term “cash price” does not include any finance charge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commission” means the Financial Services Commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Control person” means an individual, partnership, corporation, trust, or other organization that possesses the power, directly or indirectly, to direct the management or policies of a company, whether through ownership of securities, by contract, or otherwise. A person is presumed to control a company if, with respect to a particular company, that person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a director, general partner, or officer exercising executive responsibility or having similar status or functions;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directly or indirectly may vote 10 percent or more of a class of a voting security or sell or direct the sale of 10 percent or more of a class of voting securities; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a partnership, may receive upon dissolution or has contributed 10 percent or more of the capital.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Down payment” means the amount, including the value of any property used as a trade-in, paid to a seller to reduce the cash price of goods or services purchased in a credit sale transaction. A deferred portion of a down payment may be treated as part of the down payment if it is payable not later than the due date of the second otherwise regularly scheduled payment and is not subject to a finance charge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Finance charge” means the cost of consumer credit as a dollar amount. The term “finance charge” includes any charge payable directly or indirectly by the buyer and imposed directly or indirectly by the seller as an incident to or a condition of the extension of credit. The term “finance charge” does not include any charge of a type payable in a comparable cash transaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Guaranteed asset protection product” means a loan, lease, or retail installment contract term, or modification or addendum to a loan, lease, or retail installment contract, under which a creditor agrees to waive a customer’s liability for payment of some or all of the amount by which the debt exceeds the value of the collateral. Such a product is not insurance for purposes of the Florida Insurance Code. This subsection also applies to all guaranteed asset protection products issued before October 1, 2008.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Holder” of a retail installment contract means the retail seller of a motor vehicle retail installment contract or an assignee of such contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mobile home” means a structure, transportable in one or more sections, which is 8 body feet or more in width and is 32 body feet or more in length, designed to be used as a dwelling with or without a permanent foundation when connected to the required utilities, and includes the plumbing, heating, air-conditioning, and electrical systems contained therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motor vehicle” means any device or vehicle, including automobiles, motorcycles, motor trucks, trailers, mobile homes, and all other vehicles operated over the public highways and streets of this state and propelled by power other than muscular power, but excluding traction engines, road rollers, implements of husbandry and other agricultural equipment, and vehicles which run only upon a track.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motor vehicle retail installment seller” or “seller” means a person engaged in the business of selling motor vehicles to retail buyers in retail installment transactions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Office” means the Office of Financial Regulation of the commission.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Official fees” means fees and charges prescribed by law which actually are or will be paid to public officials for determining the existence of, or for perfecting, releasing, or satisfying, any security related to the credit transaction, or the premium payable for any insurance in lieu of perfecting any security interest otherwise required by the creditor in connection with the transaction, if the premium does not exceed the fees and charges which would otherwise be payable to public officials.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual, partnership, corporation, association, and any other group however organized.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Principal place of business” means the physical location designated on the licensee’s application for licensure, unless otherwise designated as required by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail buyer” or “buyer” means a person who buys a motor vehicle from a seller not principally for the purpose of resale, and who executes a retail installment contract in connection therewith or a person who succeeds to the rights and obligations of such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail installment contract” or “contract” means an agreement, entered into in this state, pursuant to which the title to, or a lien upon the motor vehicle, which is the subject matter of a retail installment transaction, is retained or taken by a seller from a retail buyer as security, in whole or in part, for the buyer’s obligation. The term includes a conditional sales contract and a contract for the bailment or leasing of a motor vehicle by which the bailee or lessee contracts to pay as compensation for its use a sum substantially equivalent to or in excess of its value and by which it is agreed that the bailee or lessee is bound to become, or for no further or a merely nominal consideration, has the option of becoming, the owner of the motor vehicle upon full compliance with the provisions of the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retail installment transaction” means any transaction evidenced by a retail installment contract entered into between a retail buyer and a seller wherein the retail buyer buys a motor vehicle from the seller at a deferred payment price payable in one or more deferred installments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sales finance company” means a person engaged in the business of purchasing retail installment contracts from one or more sellers. The term includes, but is not limited to, a bank or trust company, if so engaged. The term does not include the pledge of an aggregate number of such contracts to secure a bona fide loan thereon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Words in the singular include the plural and vice versa.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 57-799; s. 1, ch. 59-456; s. 1, ch. 61-117; s. 1, ch. 63-101; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 69-370; s. 198, ch. 71-377; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 1, 21, ch. 80-256; s. 1, ch. 81-102; s. 400, ch. 81-259; s. 2, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 83-123; ss. 2, 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 99-164; s. 619, ch. 2003-261; s. 40, ch. 2006-213; s. 1, ch. 2008-75.</History></Section>