<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.996" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Investigations and complaints.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office or its agent may, at intermittent periods, make such investigations and examinations of any licensee or other person as it deems necessary to determine compliance with this chapter. For such purposes, it may examine the books, accounts, records, and other documents or matters of any licensee or other person. It shall have the power to compel the production of all relevant books, records, and other documents and materials relative to an examination or investigation. Such investigations and examinations shall not be made more often than once during any 12-month period unless the office has good and sufficient reason to believe the licensee is not complying with the provisions of this chapter. Such examination fee shall be calculated on an hourly basis and shall be rounded to the nearest hour.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall conduct all examinations at a convenient location in this state unless the office determines that it is more effective or cost-efficient to perform an examination at the licensee’s out-of-state location. For an examination performed at the licensee’s out-of-state location, the licensee shall pay the travel expense and per diem subsistence at the rate provided by law for up to thirty 8-hour days per year for each examiner who participates in such an examination. However, if the examination involves or reveals possible fraudulent conduct of the licensee, the licensee shall pay the travel expenses and per diem subsistence provided by law, without limitation, for each participating examiner.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The examination expenses incurred by the office in each examination shall be paid by the licensee examined. The expenses of the office incurred in each examination of a home improvement finance seller or of an employee representing such home improvement finance seller shall be paid by the home improvement finance seller. Expenses incurred for each examination of a sales finance company shall be paid by it. The examination expenses shall be paid by such licensee examined or such other person obligated to pay such examination expenses within 30 days after demand therefor by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any retail buyer or owner having reason to believe that the provisions of this chapter have been violated may file with the office or the Department of Financial Services a written complaint setting forth the details of such alleged violations and the office upon receipt of such complaint, may inspect the pertinent books, records, letters, and contracts of the licensee and of the seller involved, relating to such specific written complaint.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 34, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 6, ch. 92-9; s. 18, ch. 99-164; s. 635, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>