<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0520.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Finance charge limitation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the finance charge, exclusive of insurance, shall not exceed the following rates:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class 1. Any new motor vehicle designated by the manufacturer by a year model not earlier than the year in which the sale is made<EmDash />$10 per $100 per year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class 2. Any new motor vehicle not in Class 1 and any used motor vehicle designated by the manufacturer by a year model of the same or not more than 2 years prior to the year in which the sale is made<EmDash />$11 per $100 per year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class 3. Any used motor vehicle not in Class 2 and designated by the manufacturer by a year model not more than 4 years prior to the year in which the sale is made<EmDash />$15 per $100 per year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Class 4. Any used motor vehicle not in Class 2 or Class 3 and designated by the manufacturer by a year model more than 4 years prior to the year in which the sale is made<EmDash />$17 per $100 per year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such finance charge shall be computed on the amount financed as determined under s. 520.07(2) on contracts payable in successive monthly payments substantially equal in amount. Such finance charge may be computed on the basis of a full month for any fractional-month period in excess of 10 days. A minimum finance charge of $25 may be charged on any retail installment transaction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a retail installment contract provides for unequal or irregular installment payments, the finance charge may be at a rate which will provide the same yield as is permitted on monthly payment contracts under subsections (1) and (2) having due regard for the schedule of payment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any holder may purchase or acquire or agree to purchase or acquire from any seller any contract on such terms and conditions as may be agreed upon between them. Filing of the assignment, notice to the buyer of the assignment, and any requirement that the holder maintain dominion over the payments or the motor vehicle if repossessed shall not be necessary to the validity of a written assignment of a contract as against creditors, subsequent purchasers, pledgees, mortgagees, and lien claimants of the seller. Unless the buyer has notice of the assignment of her or his contract, payment thereunder made by the buyer to the last known holder of such contract shall be binding upon all subsequent holders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of subsection (1) shall not apply to any retail installment contract for the purchase of a mobile home, titled as a motor vehicle, when such contract is entered into pursuant to a commitment to guarantee issued by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or pursuant to a commitment to insure issued by the Federal Housing Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by chapter 79-592, Laws of Florida, chapter 79-274, Laws of Florida, which amended paragraph (1)(a):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall apply only to loans, advances of credit, or lines of credit made on or subsequent to July 1, 1979, and to loans, advances of credit, or lines of credit made prior to that date if the lender has the legal right to require full payment or to adjust or modify the interest rate, by renewal, assumption, reaffirmation, contract, or otherwise; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall not be construed as diminishing the force and effect of any laws applying to loans, advances of credit, or lines of credit, other than to those mentioned in paragraph (a) of this subsection, completed prior to July 1, 1979.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 57-799; s. 7, ch. 59-456; s. 3, ch. 69-370; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 1, ch. 78-312; ss. 5, 15, ch. 79-274; s. 1, ch. 79-592; s. 21, ch. 80-256; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 35, 36, ch. 90-103; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 29, ch. 93-268; s. 688, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>