<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0556.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notification requirements provided in s. 556.105(1) do not apply to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any excavation or demolition performed by the owner of a single-family residential property, not including property that is subdivided or is to be subdivided into more than one single-family residential property; or for such owner by a member operator or an agent of a member operator when such excavation or demolition is made entirely on such land, and only up to a depth of 10 inches; provided due care is used and there is no encroachment on any member operator’s right-of-way, easement, or permitted use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any excavation or demolition associated with normal agricultural or railroad activities, provided such activities are not performed on any operator’s marked right-of-way, easement, or permitted use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any excavation or demolition that occurs as the result of normal industrial activities, provided such activities are confined to the immediate secured property of the facility and the activities are not performed on any operator’s marked right-of-way, easement, or permitted use. For the purposes of this act, the industrial activities are limited to the following list of Standard Industrial Classifications: Industry Group Numbers 141, 206, 242, 243, and 491, and Major Group Numbers 13, 26, 28, and 29, as published by the United States Office of Management and Budget in 1987.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any excavation of 18 inches or less for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Surveying public or private property by surveyors or mappers as defined in chapter 472 and services performed by a pest control licensee under chapter 482, excluding marked rights-of-way, marked easements, or permitted uses where marked, if mechanized equipment is not used in the process of such surveying or pest control services and the surveying or pest control services are performed in accordance with the practice rules established under s. 472.027 or s. 482.051, respectively;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance activities performed by a state agency and its employees when such activities are within the right-of-way of a public road; however, if a member operator has permanently marked facilities on such right-of-way, mechanized equipment may not be used without first providing notification; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Locating, repairing, connecting, adjusting, or routine maintenance of a private or public underground utility facility by an excavator, if the excavator is performing such work for the current owner or future owner of the underground facility and if mechanized equipment is not used.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any excavation with hand tools by a member operator or an agent of a member operator for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Locating, repairing, connecting, or protecting, or routine maintenance of, the member operator’s underground facilities; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extension of a member operator’s underground facilities onto the property of a person to be served by such facilities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption provided in this subsection is limited to excavations to a depth of 30 inches if the right-of-way has permanently marked facilities of a company other than the member operator or its agents performing the excavation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 93-240; s. 3, ch. 94-132; s. 3, ch. 96-172; s. 2, ch. 97-231; s. 39, ch. 2000-164; s. 8, ch. 2006-138.</History></Section>