<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0556.114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Low-impact marking practices.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An excavator providing notice under s. 556.105(1)(a) shall identify in its notice only the area that will be excavated during the period that the information in such notice is considered valid under s. 556.105(1)(c).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an excavator has not completed an excavation noticed under s. 556.105(1)(a) within the period that the information in the notice is considered valid under s. 556.105(1)(c), the excavator must provide a subsequent notice to the system under s. 556.105(1)(a) to continue with the excavation, and such subsequent notice shall identify only the remaining area to be excavated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When an excavation site cannot be described in information provided under s. 556.105(1)(a) with sufficient particularity to enable the member operator to ascertain the excavation site, and if the excavator and member operator have not mutually agreed otherwise, the excavator shall premark the proposed area of the excavation before a member operator is required to identify the horizontal route of its underground facilities in the proximity of any excavation. However, premarking is not required when the premarking could reasonably interfere with traffic or pedestrian control.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member operator shall identify the horizontal route of its underground facilities as set forth in s. 556.105(5)(a) and (b), and excavators shall premark an excavation site as set forth in subsection (3) using flags or stakes or temporary, nonpermanent paint or other industry-accepted low-impact marking practices.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any horizontal route-identification marker must be in a color identified in the Uniform Color Code for Utilities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sunshine State One-Call of Florida, Inc., shall establish an educational program for the purpose of informing excavators and member operators about low-impact marking practices.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2010-100.</History>
</Section>