<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0586.025" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful acts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Introduce into this state any honeybee pest or an unwanted race of honeybees, except under special permit issued by the department, which shall be the sole issuing agency for such special permits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use the terms “certified honey,” “certified,” “registered,” or “inspected” or any other term to convey or imply to the purchaser that the honey is certified honey, unless the honey has been certified by the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Label, represent, advertise, or offer honey for sale unless it meets the definition provided in this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly sell, offer for sale, or distribute any honeybee, any unwanted race of honeybee, or any regulated article infested or infected with any honeybee pest declared by rule of the department to be a nuisance or threat to the state’s apiary industry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly conceal, or willfully withhold information regarding, honeybees, honeybee pests, unwanted races of honeybees, or regulated articles from the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly receive honeybees, honeybee pests, honeybee products, beekeeping equipment, or other articles for distribution within this state that are not in compliance with this chapter without immediately informing the department and isolating and holding the honeybees, honeybee pests, honeybee products, beekeeping equipment, or other articles unopened or unused until action is taken by the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-62; s. 66, ch. 93-169.</History></Section>