<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0586.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Removal, destruction, or treatment of infested or infected honeybees or beekeeping equipment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds any honeybees, honeybee products, or used beekeeping equipment or other articles infested or infected with honeybee pests or an unwanted race of honeybees, notification shall be given in writing to the owner or person having charge of the apiary to that effect. The owner or person in charge shall, under the supervision of the department and within 48 hours after notice, cause the infested and infected honeybees, honeybee products, or beekeeping equipment or other article to be removed from this state or destroyed if the problem cannot be successfully treated, as determined by the department. If successful treatment is possible, the owner or person in charge shall, under the supervision of the department, follow the treatment as prescribed in the notice of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No damages shall be awarded to the owner for the destruction of unwanted races of honeybees or infested or infected honeybees, honeybee products, or beekeeping equipment or other articles except as provided under the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the owner or person in charge refuses or neglects to comply with the terms of the notice within 10 days after receiving it, the department may treat or destroy or cause to be treated or destroyed the infested or infected honeybees, beekeeping equipment, honeybee products, honeybee pests or unwanted races of honeybees. The expenses shall be assessed, collected, and enforced against the owner by the department.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 61-415; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 10, ch. 86-62; s. 3, ch. 87-17; s. 74, ch. 93-169.</History></Section>