<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0586.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certificate of inspection to accompany interstate shipments; enforcement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All honeybees, except bees in combless packages, and used beekeeping equipment shipped or moved into this state shall be accompanied by a certificate of inspection issued by the state of origin.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate shall certify that the apiaries owned or operated by the beekeeper or his or her agents or representatives have been inspected annually in the state of origin at a time when the bees are actively rearing brood, and that the honeybees meet the entry requirements of the department concerning honeybee pests and unwanted races of honeybees.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certificate described in paragraph (a) shall not be valid to allow honeybees and used beekeeping equipment to be shipped or moved into this state unless the certificate is issued by a state which has standards of inspection which are adequate to ensure the health and safety of Florida honeybees and which are at least equal to the standards established by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bees in combless packages must be accompanied by a certificate of inspection from the state of origin and an affidavit that no honey is used in the feed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be the duty of the sheriffs and officers of the Florida Highway Patrol to enforce the provisions relating to the movement of bees and used beekeeping equipment into the state, as well as such movement within the state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 61-415; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 83-168; s. 8, ch. 86-62; s. 4, ch. 89-56; s. 1, ch. 91-21; s. 72, ch. 93-169; s. 942, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>