<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0388.291" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Source reduction measures; supervision by department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or district may perform source reduction measures in conformity with good engineering practices in any area, provided that the department cooperating with the county or district has approved the operating or construction plan and it has been determined by criteria contained in rule that the area or areas to be controlled would produce arthropods in significant numbers to constitute a health or nuisance problem.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county or district shall manage the detailed business affairs and supervise said work, and the department shall advise the districts as to the best and most effective measures to be used in bringing about better temporary control and the permanent elimination of breeding conditions. The department may at its discretion discontinue any state aid provided hereunder in the event it finds the jointly agreed upon program is not being followed or is not efficiently and effectively administered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property owners in a developed residential area shall maintain their property in a manner that does not create or maintain any standing freshwater condition capable of breeding mosquitoes or other arthropods in significant numbers so as to constitute a public health, welfare, or nuisance problem. This subsection does not authorize the alteration of permitted stormwater management systems or prohibit maintained fish ponds, Florida-friendly landscaping, or other maintained systems of landscaping or vegetation. If such a condition is found to exist, the local arthropod control agency shall serve notice on the property owner to treat, remove, or abate the condition. Such notice is prima facie evidence of maintaining a nuisance, and upon failure of the property owner to treat, remove, or abate the condition, the local arthropod control agency or any affected citizen may proceed pursuant to s. 60.05 to enjoin the nuisance and may recover costs and attorney’s fees if they prevail in the action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 59-195; s. 1, ch. 63-236; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 165, ch. 77-147; s. 11, ch. 86-203; s. 4, ch. 90-90; s. 26, ch. 2009-243.</History></Section>