<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0388.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Arthropod” means those insects of public health or nuisance importance, including all mosquitoes, midges, sand flies, dog flies, yellow flies, and house flies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Board of commissioners” means the governing body of any mosquito control district, and may include boards of county commissioners when context so indicates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“County” means a political subdivision of the state administered by a board of county commissioners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District” means any mosquito control district established in this state by law for the express purpose of controlling arthropods within boundaries of said districts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Integrated arthropod control” means the implementation of arthropod control measures, including, but not limited to, the use of pesticides and biological control agents and source reduction, to control arthropods without an unreasonable adverse effect on the environment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Land management agency” means the agency charged with managing publicly owned lands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local arthropod control agency” means the county, city, or district charged with arthropod control over publicly owned lands.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nuisance” means a condition in which pestiferous arthropods occur in such numbers as to be annoying, obnoxious, or inimical to human comfort.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Source reduction” means the physical land or water management of arthropod breeding areas to reduce the area’s suitability for arthropod breeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unreasonable adverse effects on the environment” means any unreasonable risk to humans or the environment, with due consideration of the economic, social, and environmental costs and benefits of the use of any arthropod control measure.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 59-195; s. 1, ch. 63-236; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 146, ch. 71-377; s. 156, ch. 77-147; s. 2, ch. 86-203; s. 2, ch. 92-203; s. 689, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>