<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0388.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">District boards of commissioners; term of office.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Following the creation of the district, and in the general election each 4 years thereafter, the district board of commissioners shall be elected on a nonpartisan basis by the electors of the district. The three persons receiving the highest number of votes cast in the general election shall serve 4 years and shall take office at the same time as do other county officers, on the first Tuesday after the first Monday in January next after their election, and serve on the same cycle as do other constitutional county officers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district board of commissioners may, by resolution, elect to increase the membership of the board to five commissioners to be elected on a nonpartisan basis in the manner specified by subsection (1) to terms of 4 years each.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district board of commissioners may, by resolution, elect to stagger the terms of office of the members of the board. If the board of commissioners is composed of three members, at the first general election following the resolution the electors of the district shall elect three commissioners, one to a term of office of 2 years and the other two to terms of office of 4 years. If the board of commissioners is composed of five members, the electors of the district shall, at the first general election following the resolution, elect five commissioners, two to terms of office of 2 years and three to terms of office of 4 years. The board of commissioners shall, in their resolution, designate the term of office of each seat on the board for the purposes of the initial election following the resolution. Each commissioner shall hold his or her office until a successor is elected and qualified. Thereafter, each commissioner shall be elected to a 4-year term of office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district board of commissioners, if it resolves to increase the membership of the board or stagger the terms of office of the members of the board, must do so at least 1 month prior to the opening of the qualifying period for the next general election. Resolutions to increase board membership and stagger terms of office may be effective at the same general election.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of county commissioners shall call and provide for said election. Members of the district board of commissioners shall be resident registered electors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 59-195; s. 1, ch. 63-236; s. 10, ch. 80-281; s. 4, ch. 86-203; s. 690, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>