<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0388.281" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of state matching funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds, supplies, and services released to counties and districts hereunder shall be used in accordance with the detailed work plan and certified budget approved by both the department and the county or district. The plan and budget may be amended at any time upon prior approval of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds, supplies, and services released on the dollar-for-dollar matching basis shall be used exclusively for an integrated program that provides a combination of mosquito control, source reduction measures, public education, personnel training and certification, arthropod population surveillance, larvicides, adulticides, equipment, and public alerts as approved by the department. Source reduction measures may include measures to improve management and enhance the ecological integrity of source reduction areas. If source reduction measures require permits, approvals, or agreement by federal, state, regional, or local agencies, such permits, approvals, or agreement shall be obtained prior to commencement of the source reduction project. These measures include sanitary landfills, drainage, diking, filling of arthropod breeding areas, and the purchase, maintenance, and operation of all types of equipment including trucks, dredges, draglines, bulldozers, or any other type of machinery and materials utilized in ditching, ditch lining, ditch construction, diking, filling, hiring personnel, rental of equipment, and payment for contract work awarded to the lowest responsible bidder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any county or district where the arthropod problem has been eliminated, or reduced to such an extent that it does not constitute a health, comfort, or economic problem as determined by the department, the maximum amount of state funds available under this chapter shall be reduced to the amount necessary to meet actual need.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 59-195; s. 1, ch. 63-236; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 164, ch. 77-147; s. 10, ch. 86-203; s. 3, ch. 90-90; s. 10, ch. 92-203; s. 14, ch. 2002-295.</History></Section>