<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0388.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Tax levy.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of commissioners of such district may levy upon all of the real and personal taxable property in said district a special tax not exceeding 10 mills on the dollar during each year as maintenance tax to be used solely for the purposes authorized and prescribed by this chapter. Said board shall by resolution certify to the property appraiser of the county in which the property is situate, timely for the preparation of the tax roll, the tax rate to be applied in determining the amount of the district’s annual maintenance tax. Certified copies of such resolution executed in the name of said board by its chair and secretary and under its corporate seal shall be made and delivered to the property appraiser and the board of county commissioners of the county in which such district is located, and to the Department of Revenue not later than September 30 of such year. The property appraiser of said county shall assess and the tax collector of said county shall collect the amount of taxes so assessed and levied by said board of commissioners of said district upon all of the taxable real and personal property in said district at the rate of taxation adopted by said board for said year and included in said resolution, and said levy shall be included in the warrants of the property appraiser and attached to the assessment roll of taxes for said county each year. The tax collector shall collect such taxes so levied by said board in the same manner as other taxes are collected and shall pay the same within the time and in the manner prescribed by law to the treasurer of said board. The Department of Revenue shall assess and levy on all the railroad lines and railroad property and telegraph and telephone lines and telegraph and telephone property situated in said district in the amount of each such levy as in case of other state and county taxes and shall collect said taxes thereon in the same manner as it is required by law to assess and collect taxes for state and county purposes and remit the same to the treasurer of said board. All such taxes shall be held by said treasurer for the credit of said board and paid out by him or her as ordered by said board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax officers of the county are hereby authorized and directed to perform the duties devolving upon them under this chapter and to receive compensation therefor at such rates or charges as are provided by law with respect to similar services or charges.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 59-195; ss. 21, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 7, ch. 86-203; s. 693, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>