<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0388.45" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Threat to public or animal health; declarations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Health Officer has the authority to declare that a threat to public health exists when the Department of Health discovers in the human or surrogate population the occurrence of an infectious disease that can be transmitted from mosquitoes or other arthropods to humans. The State Health Officer must immediately notify the Commissioner of Agriculture of the declaration of this threat to public health. The Commissioner of Agriculture is authorized to issue a mosquito or other arthropod declaration in those counties needing additional mosquito or other arthropod control measures based on the State Health Officer’s declaration of a threat to the public health. Each declaration must contain the geographical boundaries and the duration of the declaration. The State Health Officer shall order such human medical preventive treatment and the Commissioner of Agriculture shall order such ameliorative mosquito or other arthropod control measures as are necessary to prevent the spread of disease, notwithstanding contrary provisions of this chapter or the rules adopted under this chapter. Within 24 hours after a declaration of a threat to the public health, the State Health Officer must also notify the agency heads of the Department of Environmental Protection and the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission of the declaration. Within 24 hours after a mosquito or other arthropod declaration based on the public health declaration, the Commissioner of Agriculture must notify the agency heads of the Department of Environmental Protection and the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission of the declaration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Agriculture has the authority to declare that a threat to animal health exists when the department discovers the occurrence of an infectious disease in animals that can be transmitted by mosquitoes or other arthropods and is authorized to issue an animal health declaration in those counties needing additional veterinary care or mosquito or other arthropod control measures based on a threat to animal health. Each declaration must contain the geographical boundaries and the duration of the declaration. The Commissioner of Agriculture shall order such veterinary treatment or ameliorative mosquito or other arthropod control measures as are necessary to prevent the spread of disease, notwithstanding contrary provisions of this chapter or the rules adopted under this chapter. The Commissioner of Agriculture shall immediately notify the State Health Officer and the agency heads of the Department of Environmental Protection and the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission upon issuance of an animal health declaration.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 86-203; s. 21, ch. 92-203; s. 354, ch. 94-356; s. 85, ch. 97-101; s. 201, ch. 99-245; s. 16, ch. 2002-295.</History></Section>