<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0435.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for covered employees and employers.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by law, the following requirements apply to covered employees and employers:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every person required by law to be screened pursuant to this chapter must submit a complete set of information necessary to conduct a screening under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For level 1 screening, the employer must submit the information necessary for screening to the Department of Law Enforcement within 5 working days after receiving it. The Department of Law Enforcement shall conduct a search of its records and respond to the employer or agency. The employer must inform the employee whether screening has revealed any disqualifying information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For level 2 screening, the employer or agency must submit the information necessary for screening to the Department of Law Enforcement within 5 working days after receiving it. The Department of Law Enforcement shall perform a criminal history record check of its records and request that the Federal Bureau of Investigation perform a national criminal history record check of its records for each employee for whom the request is made. The Department of Law Enforcement shall respond to the employer or agency, and the employer or agency must inform the employee whether screening has revealed disqualifying information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person whose background is being checked must supply any missing criminal or other necessary information upon request to the requesting employer or agency within 30 days after receiving the request for the information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every employee must attest, subject to penalty of perjury, to meeting the requirements for qualifying for employment pursuant to this chapter and agreeing to inform the employer immediately if arrested for any of the disqualifying offenses while employed by the employer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employer licensed or registered with an agency must conduct level 2 background screening and must submit to the agency annually or at the time of license renewal, under penalty of perjury, a signed affidavit attesting to compliance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 47, ch. 95-228; s. 208, ch. 99-8; s. 46, ch. 2000-349; s. 63, ch. 2001-62; s. 21, ch. 2004-267; s. 67, ch. 2009-223; s. 39, ch. 2010-114.</History>
</Section>