<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1000.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Function, mission, and goals of the Florida K-20 education system.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Florida’s K-20 education system shall be a decentralized system without excess layers of bureaucracy. Florida’s K-20 education system shall maintain a systemwide technology plan based on a common set of data definitions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature shall establish education policy, enact education laws, and appropriate and allocate education resources.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the exception of matters relating to the State University System, the State Board of Education shall oversee the enforcement of all laws and rules, and the timely provision of direction, resources, assistance, intervention when needed, and strong incentives and disincentives to force accountability for results.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors shall oversee the enforcement of all state university laws and rules and regulations and the timely provision of direction, resources, assistance, intervention when needed, and strong incentives and disincentives to force accountability for results.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public education is a cooperative function of the state and local educational authorities. The state retains responsibility for establishing a system of public education through laws, standards, and rules to assure efficient operation of a K-20 system of public education and adequate educational opportunities for all individuals. Local educational authorities have a duty to fully and faithfully comply with state laws, standards, and rules and to efficiently use the resources available to them to assist the state in allowing adequate educational opportunities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mission of Florida’s K-20 education system is to allow its students to increase their proficiency by allowing them the opportunity to expand their knowledge and skills through rigorous and relevant learning opportunities, in accordance with the mission statement and accountability requirements of s. 1008.31.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The priorities of Florida’s K-20 education system include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Learning and completion at all levels, including increased high school graduation rate and readiness for postsecondary education without remediation.</Font><EmDash />All students demonstrate increased learning and completion at all levels, graduate from high school, and are prepared to enter postsecondary education without remediation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Student performance.</Font><EmDash />Students demonstrate that they meet the expected academic standards consistently at all levels of their education.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Alignment of standards and resources.</Font><EmDash />Academic standards for every level of the K-20 education system are aligned, and education financial resources are aligned with student performance expectations at each level of the K-20 education system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Educational leadership.</Font><EmDash />The quality of educational leadership at all levels of K-20 education is improved.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Workforce education.</Font><EmDash />Workforce education is appropriately aligned with the skills required by the new global economy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Parental, student, family, educational institution, and community involvement.</Font><EmDash />Parents, students, families, educational institutions, and communities are collaborative partners in education, and each plays an important role in the success of individual students. Therefore, the State of Florida cannot be the guarantor of each individual student’s success. The goals of Florida’s K-20 education system are not guarantees that each individual student will succeed or that each individual school will perform at the level indicated in the goals.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2002-387; s. 4, ch. 2006-74; s. 65, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>