<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1000.39" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1" />
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">State council; Interstate Compact on Educational Opportunity for Military Children.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to Article VIII of the Interstate Compact on Educational Opportunity for Military Children, the State Council on Interstate Educational Opportunity for Military Children is created.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of the council is to provide advice and recommendations regarding this state’s participation in and compliance with the compact and Interstate Commission on Educational Opportunity for Military Children activities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 3 months after its formation, and whenever requested by the Governor thereafter, the council shall provide the Governor with names of at least three, but no more than five, persons who are recommended by the council to serve as the Military Family Education Liaison.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The council shall consist of the following seven members:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Education or his or her designee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The superintendent, or his or her designee, for the school district with the highest percentage per capita of military children during the previous school year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two members appointed by the Commissioner of Education, one of whom shall represent a military installation located within this state and one of whom shall represent the executive branch and possess experience in assisting military families in obtaining educational services for their children. The term of each member appointed under this paragraph shall be for 4 years, except that, in order to provide for staggered terms, the Commissioner of Education shall initially appoint one member to a term of 2 years and one member to a term of 3 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One member appointed by, and who shall serve at the pleasure of, the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Compact Commissioner and the Military Family Education Liaison designated by the Governor under s. 1000.38, who shall serve as nonvoting, ex officio members of the council.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Council members shall serve without compensation but are entitled to reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution and of chapter 119 and s. 286.011 apply to proceedings and records of the council. Minutes, including a record of all votes cast, must be maintained for all meetings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Education shall provide administrative support to the council.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the council is abolished, its records must be appropriately stored, within 30 days after the effective date of its abolition, by the department or its successor agency. Any property assigned to the council must be reclaimed by the department or its successor agency. The council may not perform any activities after the effective date of its abolition.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 5, ch. 2008-225; ss. 1, 3, ch. 2010-52.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 3, ch. 2010-52, provides that “[s]ections 1000.36, 1000.37, 1000.38, and 1000.39, Florida Statutes, shall stand repealed 3 years after the effective date of this act unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.”</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>