<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0448.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 448.101-448.105, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Appropriate governmental agency” means any agency of government charged with the enforcement of laws, rules, or regulations governing an activity, policy, or practice of an employer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employee” means a person who performs services for and under the control and direction of an employer for wages or other remuneration. The term does not include an independent contractor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employer” means any private individual, firm, partnership, institution, corporation, or association that employs ten or more persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law, rule, or regulation” includes any statute or ordinance or any rule or regulation adopted pursuant to any federal, state, or local statute or ordinance applicable to the employer and pertaining to the business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Retaliatory personnel action” means the discharge, suspension, or demotion by an employer of an employee or any other adverse employment action taken by an employer against an employee in the terms and conditions of employment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supervisor” means any individual within an employer’s organization who has the authority to direct and control the work performance of the affected employee or who has managerial authority to take corrective action regarding the violation of law, rule, or regulation of which the employee complains.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 91-285.</History></Section>