<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0448.109" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notification of the state minimum wage.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the terms:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Employer,” “employee,” and “wage” have the meanings as established under the federal Fair Labor Standards Act and its implementing regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Florida minimum wage” means the wage that an employer must, at a minimum, pay an employee pursuant to s. 24, Art. X of the State Constitution and implementing law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each employer who must pay an employee the Florida minimum wage shall prominently display a poster substantially similar to the one made available pursuant to subsection (3) in a conspicuous and accessible place in each establishment where such employees are employed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each year the Department of Economic Opportunity shall, on or before December 1, create and make available to employers a poster in English and in Spanish which reads substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">NOTICE TO EMPLOYEES</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">The Florida minimum wage is $ <Directions xml:space="preserve">(amount)</Directions> per hour, with a minimum wage of at least $ <Directions xml:space="preserve">(amount)</Directions> per hour for tipped employees, in addition to tips, for January 1, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, through December 31, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">The rate of the minimum wage is recalculated yearly on September 30, based on the Consumer Price Index. Every year on January 1 the new Florida minimum wage takes effect.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">An employer may not retaliate against an employee for exercising his or her right to receive the minimum wage. Rights protected by the State Constitution include the right to:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">1. File a complaint about an employer’s alleged noncompliance with lawful minimum wage requirements.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">2. Inform any person about an employer’s alleged noncompliance with lawful minimum wage requirements.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockIndent">3. Inform any person of his or her potential rights under Section 24, Article X of the State Constitution and to assist him or her in asserting such rights.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">An employee who has not received the lawful minimum wage after notifying his or her employer and giving the employer 15 days to resolve any claims for unpaid wages may bring a civil action in a court of law against an employer to recover back wages plus damages and attorney’s fees.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">An employer found liable for intentionally violating minimum wage requirements is subject to a fine of $1,000 per violation, payable to the state.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">The Attorney General or other official designated by the Legislature may bring a civil action to enforce the minimum wage.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">For details see Section 24, Article X of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The poster must be at least 8.5 inches by 11 inches and in a format easily seen by employees. The text in the poster must be of a conspicuous size. The text in the first line must be larger than the text of any other line, and the text of the first sentence must be in bold type and larger than the text in the remaining lines.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2006-84; s. 398, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>