<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0448.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this part:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Labor pool” means a business entity that operates a labor hall by one or more of the following methods:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contracting with third-party users to supply day laborers to them on a temporary basis.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hiring, employing, recruiting, or contracting with workers to fulfill these temporary labor contracts for day labor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fulfilling any contracts for day labor in accordance with this subsection, even if the entity also conducts other business.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Day labor” means temporary labor or employment that is occasional or irregular for which the worker is employed for not longer than the time period required to complete the temporary assignment for which the individual worker was hired, although an individual may be eligible for additional temporary assignments when available.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Labor hall” means a central location maintained by a labor pool where day laborers assemble and are dispatched to work for a third-party user.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Business entity” means any individual, corporation, business partnership, firm, institution, or association.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Third-party user” means a business entity that uses the services of a day laborer provided by a labor pool.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 95-332.</History></Section>