<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0082.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trial; form of verdict.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IN CASES OF FORCIBLE OR UNLAWFUL ENTRY.<EmDash />In forcible or unlawful entry the form of verdict shall be substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">We, the jury, find that defendant did (or did not), within 3 years next before the filing of the complaint, forcibly (or unlawfully) enter upon the real estate mentioned in the complaint and turn plaintiff out of possession; that defendant did (or did not) continue to hold possession at the date of the complaint; and we assess the damages of plaintiff at <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> dollars.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IN CASES OF UNLAWFUL DETAINER.<EmDash />The form of verdict in unlawful detainer shall be substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">We, the jury, find that the defendant did (or did not), at the time of filing the complaint, wrongfully hold possession of the real estate mentioned in the complaint against the consent of plaintiff that defendant has (or has not) so held possession thereof against the consent of plaintiff, within 3 years next before the filing of the complaint; and that plaintiff has (or has not) the right of possession in the real estate, and we assess the damage of plaintiff at <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> dollars.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">This subsection shall not apply with regard to residential tenancies.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 1630, 1868; RS 1701; GS 2166; RGS 3470; CGL 5323; s. 33, ch. 67-254; s. 13, ch. 73-330; s. 19, ch. 77-104.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 82.15.</Text></Note></Section>