<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0610.114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitation on local authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A municipality or county may not impose additional requirements on a certificateholder, including, but not limited to, financial, operational, and administrative requirements, except as expressly permitted by this chapter. A municipality or county may not impose on activities of a certificateholder a requirement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That particular business offices be located in the municipality or county;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regarding the filing of reports and documents with the municipality or county that are not required by state or federal law and that are not related to the use of the public right-of-way. Reports and documents other than schematics indicating the location of facilities for a specific site that are provided in the normal course of the municipality’s or county’s permitting process, that are authorized by s. 337.401 for communications service providers, or that are otherwise required in the normal course of such permitting process shall not be considered related to the use of the public right-of-way for communications service providers. A municipality or county may not request information concerning the capacity or technical configuration of a certificateholder’s facilities;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the inspection of a certificateholder’s business records; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the approval of transfers of ownership or control of a certificateholder’s business, except that a municipality or county may require a certificateholder to provide notice of a transfer within a reasonable time.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a municipality or county may require the issuance of a permit in accordance with and subject to s. 337.401 to a certificateholder that is placing and maintaining facilities in or on a public right-of-way in the municipality or county. In accordance with s. 337.402, the permit may require the permitholder to be responsible, at the permitholder’s expense, for any damage resulting from the issuance of such permit and for restoring the public right-of-way to its original condition before installation of such facilities. The terms of the permit shall be consistent with construction permits issued to other providers of communications services placing or maintaining communications facilities in a public right-of-way.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2007-29.</History></Section>