<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0610.103" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 610.102-610.117:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cable service” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The one-way transmission to subscribers of video programming or any other programming service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subscriber interaction, if any, that is required for the selection or use of such video programming or other programming service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cable service provider” means a person that provides cable service over a cable system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cable system” means a facility consisting of a set of closed transmission paths and associated signal generation, reception, and control equipment that is designed to provide cable service that includes video programming and that is provided to multiple subscribers within a community, but such term does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that serves only to retransmit the television signals of one or more television broadcast stations;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that serves only subscribers in one or more multiple-unit dwellings under common ownership, control, or management, unless such facility or facilities use any public right-of-way;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that serves subscribers without using any public right-of-way;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility of a common carrier that is subject, in whole or in part, to the provisions of Title II of the federal Communications Act of 1934 except that such facility shall be considered a cable system other than for purposes of 47 U.S.C. s. 541(c) to the extent such facility is used in the transmission of video programming directly to subscribers, unless the extent of such use is solely to provide interactive on-demand services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facilities of any electric utility used solely for operating its electric utility systems; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An open video system that complies with 47 U.S.C. s. 573.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificateholder” means a cable or video service provider that has been issued and holds a certificate of franchise authority from the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of State.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Franchise” means an initial authorization or renewal of an authorization, regardless of whether the authorization is designated as a franchise, permit, license, resolution, contract, certificate, agreement, or otherwise, to construct and operate a cable system or video service provider network facilities in the public right-of-way.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Franchise authority” means any governmental entity empowered by federal, state, or local law to grant a franchise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Incumbent cable service provider” means a cable or video service provider providing cable or video service on July 1, 2007.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public right-of-way” means the area on, below, or above a public roadway, highway, street, sidewalk, alley, or waterway, including, without limitation, a municipal, county, state, district, or other public roadway, highway, street, sidewalk, alley, or waterway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Video programming” means programming provided by, or generally considered comparable to programming provided by, a television broadcast station as set forth in 47 U.S.C. s. 522(20).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Video service” means video programming services, including cable services, provided through wireline facilities located at least in part in the public rights-of-way without regard to delivery technology, including Internet protocol technology. This definition does not include any video programming provided by a commercial mobile service provider as defined in 47 U.S.C. s. 332(d), video programming provided as part of and via a service that enables end users to access content, information, electronic mail, or other services offered over the public Internet.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Video service provider” means an entity providing video service.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2007-29.</History></Section>