<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0560.1092" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examination expenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee examined shall pay to the office the expenses of the examination at the rates adopted by the commission by rule. Such expenses shall include actual travel expenses, reasonable living expense allowance, compensation of the examiner or other person making the examination, and necessary attendant administrative costs of the office directly related to the examination. Travel expense and living expense allowance are limited to those expenses incurred on account of the examination and shall be paid by the examined licensee together with compensation upon presentation by the office to the licensee of a detailed account of the charges and expenses after a detailed statement has been filed by the examiner and approved by the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected from licensees for examinations shall be deposited into the Regulatory Trust Fund, and the office may make deposits into such fund from moneys appropriated for the operation of the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 112.061, the office may pay to the examiner or person making the examination out of the trust fund the actual travel expenses, reasonable living expense allowance, and compensation in accordance with the statement filed with the office by the examiner or other person, as provided in subsection (1) upon approval by the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When not examining a licensee, the travel expenses, per diem, and compensation for the examiners and other persons employed to make examinations, if approved, shall be paid out of moneys budgeted for such purpose as regular employees, and reimbursement for travel expenses and per diem shall be at rates as provided in s. 112.061.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2008-177.</History>
</Section>