<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0560.406" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Worthless checks.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a check is returned to a deferred presentment provider from a payor financial institution due to lack of funds, a closed account, or a stop-payment order, the deferred presentment provider may seek collection pursuant to s. 68.065, except a deferred presentment provider may not collect treble damages. The notice sent by the deferred deposit provider may not include any references to treble damages and must clearly state that the deferred presentment provider is not entitled to recover such damages. Except as otherwise provided in this part, an individual who issues a personal check to a deferred presentment provider under a deferred presentment agreement is not subject to criminal penalty.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a check is returned to a deferred presentment provider from a payor financial institution due to insufficient funds, a closed account, or a stop-payment order, the deferred presentment provider may pursue all legally available civil remedies to collect the check, including, but not limited to, the imposition of all charges imposed on the deferred presentment provider by the financial institution. In its collection practices, a deferred presentment provider must comply with the prohibitions against harassment or abuse, false or misleading representations, and unfair practices that are contained in the Fair Debt Collections Practices Act, 15 U.S.C. ss. 1692d, 1692e, and 1692f. A violation of this act is a deceptive and unfair trade practice and constitutes a violation of the Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act under part II of chapter 501. In addition, a deferred presentment provider must comply with the applicable provisions of the Consumer Collection Practices Act under part VI of chapter 559, including s. 559.77.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A deferred presentment provider may not assess the cost of collection, other than charges for insufficient funds as allowed by law, without a judgment from a court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 2001-119; s. 47, ch. 2008-177; s. 74, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>