<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0560.2085" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authorized vendors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee under this part shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 60 days after an authorized vendor commences business, file with the office such information as prescribed by rule together with the nonrefundable location fee as provided by s. 560.143. This requirement applies to vendors who are also terminated within the 60-day period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into a written contract, signed by the licensee and the authorized vendor, which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sets forth the nature and scope of the relationship between the licensee and the authorized vendor, including the respective rights and responsibilities of the parties; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Includes contract provisions that require the authorized vendor to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report to the licensee, immediately upon discovery, the theft or loss of currency received for a transmission or payment instrument;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Display a notice to the public, in such form as prescribed by rule, that the vendor is the authorized vendor of the licensee;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remit all amounts owed to the licensee for all transmissions accepted and all payment instruments sold in accordance with the contract between the licensee and the authorized vendor;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold in trust all currency or payment instruments received for transmissions or for the purchase of payment instruments from the time of receipt by the licensee or authorized vendor until the time the transmission obligation is completed;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not commingle the money received for transmissions accepted or payment instruments sold on behalf of the licensee with the money or property of the authorized vendor, except for making change in the ordinary course of the vendor’s business, and ensure that the money is accounted for at the end of the business day;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent to examination or investigation by the office;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adhere to the applicable state and federal laws and rules pertaining to a money services business; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide such other information or disclosure as may be required by rule.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and implement written policies and procedures to monitor compliance with applicable state and federal law by its authorized vendors.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 2008-177; s. 4, ch. 2009-185.</History></Section>