<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0560.126" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Required notice by licensee.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee must provide the office with a written notice sent by registered mail within 30 days after the occurrence or knowledge of, whichever period of time is greater, any of the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a petition under the United States Bankruptcy Code for bankruptcy or reorganization by the licensee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commencement of an administrative or judicial license suspension or revocation proceeding, or the denial of a license request or renewal, by any state, the District of Columbia, any United States territory, or any foreign country in which the licensee operates, plans to operate, or is licensed to operate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony indictment relating to a money services business or deferred presentment provider involving the licensee, its authorized vendor, or an affiliated party.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The felony conviction, guilty plea, or plea of nolo contendere, regardless of adjudication, of the licensee, its authorized vendor, or an affiliated party.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interruption of any corporate surety bond required under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any suspected criminal act perpetrated in this state relating to activities regulated under this chapter by an affiliated party against a money services business or authorized vendor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notification by a law enforcement or prosecutorial agency that the licensee or its authorized vendor is under criminal investigation including, but not limited to, subpoenas to produce records or testimony and warrants issued by a court of competent jurisdiction which authorize the search and seizure of any records relating to a business activity regulated under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee must report, on a form adopted by rule, any change in the information contained in an initial license application form, any amendment to such application, or the appointment of an authorized vendor within 30 days after the change is effective.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee must report any change in the partners, officers, members, joint venturers, directors, controlling shareholders, or responsible persons of the licensee or changes in the form of business organization by written amendment in such form and at such time as specified by rule.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person, directly or indirectly or acting by or through one or more persons, proposes to purchase or acquire a controlling interest in a licensee, such person or group must submit an application for licensure as a money services business or deferred presentment provider before such purchase or acquisition at such time and in such form as prescribed by rule. As used in this subsection, the term “controlling interest” means the same as described in s. 560.127.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The addition of a partner, officer, member, joint venturer, director, controlling shareholder, or responsible person of the applicant who does not have a controlling interest and who has not previously complied with the applicable provisions of ss. 560.1401 and 560.141 is subject to such provisions. If the office determines that the licensee does not continue to meet the licensure requirements, the office may bring an administrative action in accordance with s. 560.114 to enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall adopt rules providing for the waiver of the license application required by this subsection if the person or group of persons proposing to purchase or acquire a controlling interest in a licensee has previously complied with the applicable provisions of ss. 560.1401 and 560.141 under the same legal entity or is currently licensed under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee that engages in check cashing must notify the office within 5 business days after the licensee ceases to maintain a federally insured depository account as required by s. 560.309(3) and, before resuming check cashing, must reestablish such an account and notify the office of the account.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-238; s. 1, ch. 94-354; s. 706, ch. 2003-261; s. 56, ch. 2006-213; s. 21, ch. 2008-177; s. 5, ch. 2012-85.</History>
</Section>