<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0560.114" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disciplinary actions; penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following actions by a money services business, authorized vendor, or affiliated party constitute grounds for the issuance of a cease and desist order; the issuance of a removal order; the denial, suspension, or revocation of a license; or taking any other action within the authority of the office pursuant to this chapter:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with any provision of this chapter or related rule or order, or any written agreement entered into with the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraud, misrepresentation, deceit, or gross negligence in any transaction by a money services business, regardless of reliance thereon by, or damage to, a customer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fraudulent misrepresentation, circumvention, or concealment of any matter that must be stated or furnished to a customer pursuant to this chapter, regardless of reliance thereon by, or damage to, such customer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">False, deceptive, or misleading advertising.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to maintain, preserve, keep available for examination, and produce all books, accounts, files, or other documents required by this chapter or related rules or orders, by 31 C.F.R. ss. 103.20, 103.22, 103.23, 103.27, 103.28, 103.29, 103.33, 103.37, 103.41, and 103.125, or by any agreement entered into with the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusing to allow the examination or inspection of books, accounts, files, or other documents by the office pursuant to this chapter, or to comply with a subpoena issued by the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to pay a judgment recovered in any court by a claimant in an action arising out of a money transmission transaction within 30 days after the judgment becomes final.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging in an act prohibited under s. 560.111.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insolvency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by a money services business to remove an affiliated party after the office has issued and served upon the money services business a final order setting forth a finding that the affiliated party has violated a provision of this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a material misstatement, misrepresentation, or omission in an application for licensure, any amendment to such application, or application for the appointment of an authorized vendor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing any act that results in a license or its equivalent, to practice any profession or occupation being denied, suspended, revoked, or otherwise acted against by a licensing authority in any jurisdiction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being the subject of final agency action or its equivalent, issued by an appropriate regulator, for engaging in unlicensed activity as a money services business or deferred presentment provider in any jurisdiction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Committing any act resulting in a license or its equivalent to practice any profession or occupation being denied, suspended, revoked, or otherwise acted against by a licensing authority in any jurisdiction for a violation of 18 U.S.C. s. 1956, 18 U.S.C. s. 1957, 18 U.S.C. s. 1960, 31 U.S.C. s. 5324, or any other law or rule of another state or of the United States relating to a money services business, deferred presentment provider, or usury that may cause the denial, suspension, or revocation of a money services business or deferred presentment provider license or its equivalent in such jurisdiction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been convicted of, or entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, any felony or crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of any state or the United States which involves fraud, moral turpitude, or dishonest dealing, regardless of adjudication.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been convicted of, or entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, a crime under 18 U.S.C. s. 1956 or 31 U.S.C. s. 5324, regardless of adjudication.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having been convicted of, or entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere to, misappropriation, conversion, or unlawful withholding of moneys belonging to others, regardless of adjudication.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to inform the office in writing within 30 days after having pled guilty or nolo contendere to, or being convicted of, any felony or crime punishable by imprisonment of 1 year or more under the law of any state or the United States, or any crime involving fraud, moral turpitude, or dishonest dealing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Aiding, assisting, procuring, advising, or abetting any person in violating a provision of this chapter or any order or rule of the office or commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to pay any fee, charge, or cost imposed or assessed under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to pay a fine assessed by the office within 30 days after the due date as stated in a final order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to pay any judgment entered by any court within 30 days after the judgment becomes final.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engaging or advertising engagement in the business of a money services business or deferred presentment provider without a license, unless exempted from licensure.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment to the office for a license or other fee, charge, cost, or fine with a check or electronic transmission of funds that is dishonored by the applicant’s or licensee’s financial institution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="y">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violations of 31 C.F.R. ss. 103.20, 103.22, 103.23, 103.27, 103.28, 103.29, 103.33, 103.37, 103.41, and 103.125, and United States Treasury Interpretive Release 2004-1.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="z">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any practice or conduct that creates the likelihood of a material loss, insolvency, or dissipation of assets of a money services business or otherwise materially prejudices the interests of its customers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="aa">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of a check casher to maintain a federally insured depository account as required by s. 560.309.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="bb">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of a check casher to deposit into its own federally insured depository account any payment instrument cashed as required by s. 560.309.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may immediately suspend the license of any money services business if the money services business fails to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide to the office, upon written request, any of the records required by s. 560.123, s. 560.1235, s. 560.211, or s. 560.310 or any rule adopted under those sections. The suspension may be rescinded if the licensee submits the requested records to the office.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain a federally insured depository account as required by s. 560.309.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of s. 120.60(6), failure to perform any of the acts specified in this subsection constitutes immediate and serious danger to the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may deny licensure if the applicant or an affiliated party is the subject of a pending criminal prosecution or governmental enforcement action in any jurisdiction until the conclusion of the prosecution or action.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may issue a cease and desist order or removal order, suspend or revoke a license, or take any other action within the authority of the office against a licensee based on any fact or condition that exists and that, if it had existed or been known to exist at the time of license application, would have been grounds for license denial.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A money services business licensed under part II of this chapter is responsible for any act of its authorized vendors if the money services business should have known of the act or had actual knowledge that such act is a violation of this chapter, and the money services business allowed the act to continue. Such responsibility is limited to conduct engaged in by the authorized vendor pursuant to the authority granted to it by the money services business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a license granted under this chapter expires or is surrendered by the licensee during the pendency of an administrative action, the proceeding may continue as if the license is still in effect.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office may, in addition to or in lieu of the denial, suspension, or revocation of a license, impose a fine of at least $1,000 but not more than $10,000 for each violation of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other provision of this chapter, the office may impose a fine of up to $1,000 per day for each day that a person engages in the business of a money services business or deferred presentment provider without being licensed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-238; s. 1, ch. 94-354; s. 3, ch. 97-59; s. 5, ch. 2000-360; s. 3, ch. 2001-119; s. 697, ch. 2003-261; s. 3, ch. 2004-85; s. 54, ch. 2006-213; s. 10, ch. 2008-177; s. 4, ch. 2012-85.</History>
</Section>