<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0560.123" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Control of Money Laundering in Money Services Business Act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Florida Control of Money Laundering in Money Services Business Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to require the maintenance of certain records of transactions involving currency or payment instruments in order to deter the use of a money services business to conceal proceeds from criminal activity and to ensure the availability of such records for criminal, tax, or regulatory investigations or proceedings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A money services business shall keep a record of each financial transaction occurring in this state which it knows to involve currency or other payment instrument, as prescribed by the commission, having a value greater than $10,000; to involve the proceeds of specified unlawful activity; or to be designed to evade the reporting requirements of this section or chapter 896. The money services business must maintain appropriate procedures to ensure compliance with this section and chapter 896.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Multiple financial transactions shall be treated as a single transaction if the money services business has knowledge that they are made by or on behalf of any one person and result in cash in or cash out totaling more than $10,000 during any day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A money services business may keep a record of any financial transaction occurring in this state, regardless of the value, if it suspects that the transaction involves the proceeds of unlawful activity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The money services business must file a report with the office of any records required by this subsection, at such time and containing such information as required by rule. The timely filing of the report required by 31 U.S.C. s. 5313 with the appropriate federal agency shall be deemed compliance with the reporting requirements of this subsection unless the reports are not regularly and comprehensively transmitted by the federal agency to the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A money services business, or officer, employee, or agent thereof, that files a report in good faith pursuant to this section is not liable to any person for loss or damage caused in whole or in part by the making, filing, or governmental use of the report, or any information contained therein.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A money services business must comply with the money laundering, enforcement, and reporting provisions of s. 655.50 relating to reports of transactions involving currency transactions and payment instruments, and of chapter 896 concerning offenses relating to financial transactions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In enforcing this section, the office shall acknowledge and take into consideration the requirements of Title 31, United States Code, in order to reduce the burden of duplicate requirements and to acknowledge the economic advantage of having similar reporting and recordkeeping requirements between state and federal regulatory authorities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office must retain a copy of all reports received under subsection (3) for a minimum of 5 years after receipt of the report. However, if a report or information contained in a report is known by the office to be the subject of an existing criminal proceeding, the report must be retained for a minimum of 10 years after the date of receipt.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other powers conferred upon the office to enforce and administer this chapter, the office may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bring an action in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce or administer this section. In such action, the office may seek award of any civil penalty authorized by law and any other appropriate relief at law or equity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue and serve upon a person an order requiring the person to cease and desist and take corrective action if the office finds that the person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this section or chapter 896; any rule or order adopted under this section or chapter 896; or any written agreement related to this section or chapter 896 which is entered into with the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue and serve upon a person an order suspending or revoking the person’s money services business license if the office finds that the person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this section or chapter 896; any rule or order adopted under this section or chapter 896; or any written agreement related to this section or chapter 896 which is entered into with the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Issue and serve upon any person an order of removal whenever the office finds that the person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this section or chapter 896; any rule or order adopted under this section or chapter 896; or any written agreement related to this section or chapter 896 which is entered into with the office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose and collect an administrative fine against any person found to have violated any provision of this section or chapter 896; any rule or order adopted under this section or chapter 896; or any written agreement related to this section or chapter 896 which is entered into with the office, of up to $10,000 per day for each willful violation or $500 per day for each negligent violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (b), a person who willfully violates any provision of this section commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who willfully violates any provision of this section, if the violation involves:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Currency or payment instruments exceeding $300 but less than $20,000 in any 12-month period, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Currency or payment instruments totaling or exceeding $20,000 but less than $100,000 in any 12-month period, commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Currency or payment instruments totaling or exceeding $100,000 in any 12-month period, commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the penalties authorized by s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, a person who has been convicted of, or entered a plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of adjudication, to having violated paragraph (b) may be sentenced to pay a fine of up to $250,000 or twice the value of the currency or payment instruments, whichever is greater, except that on a second or subsequent conviction for or plea of guilty or nolo contendere, regardless of adjudication, to a violation of paragraph (b), the fine may be up to $500,000 or quintuple the value of the currency or payment instruments, whichever is greater.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates this section is also liable for a civil penalty of not more than the greater of the value of the currency or payment instruments involved or $25,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any prosecution brought pursuant to this section, the common law corpus delicti rule does not apply. The defendant’s confession or admission is admissible during trial without the state having to prove the corpus delicti if the court finds in a hearing conducted outside the presence of the jury that the defendant’s confession or admission is trustworthy. Before the court admits the defendant’s confession or admission, the state must prove by a preponderance of the evidence that there is sufficient corroborating evidence that tends to establish the trustworthiness of the statement by the defendant. Hearsay evidence is admissible during the presentation of evidence at the hearing. In making its determination, the court may consider all relevant corroborating evidence, including the defendant’s statements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 94-238; s. 1, ch. 94-354; s. 8, ch. 2000-360; s. 704, ch. 2003-261; s. 20, ch. 2004-335; s. 17, ch. 2008-177; s. 1, ch. 2009-185.</History></Section>