<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0043.19" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Money paid into court; unclaimed funds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In every case in which the right to withdraw money deposited as hereinbefore provided has been adjudicated or is not in dispute and the money has remained so deposited for 5 years or more unclaimed by the person, firm, or corporation entitled thereto, on or before December 1 of each year the judge, or one of the judges, of the court shall direct that the money be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the State School Fund, to become a part of that fund, subject to the right of the person, firm, or corporation entitled thereto to receive the money as provided in subsection (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The direction that the money be deposited as provided in subsection (1) shall be by written order. A copy of the order shall be filed in the action in which the money was originally deposited. The order shall also be noted in the progress docket in the action, if a docket is maintained by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person, firm or corporation entitled to any of the money may obtain an order directing the payment of the money to the claimant on written petition to the court from which the money was deposited or its successor, and written notice to the state attorney of the circuit wherein the court is situate, whether or not the court is a circuit court, and proof of right thereto, and the money deposited shall constitute and be a permanent appropriation for payments by the Chief Financial Officer of the state in obedience of such orders.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All interest and income that accrue from the money while on deposit with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the State School Fund belong to that fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 15996, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 4355(3); s. 1, ch. 21993, 1943; s. 1, ch. 24351, 1947; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 44, ch. 67-254; s. 33, ch. 81-259; s. 99, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 54.06.</Text></Note></Section>