<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.142" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Color photographic or digital imaged licenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, upon receipt of the required fee, issue to each qualified applicant for a driver’s license a color photographic or digital imaged driver’s license bearing a fullface photograph or digital image of the licensee. Notwithstanding chapter 761 or s. 761.05, the requirement for a fullface photograph or digital image of the licensee may not be waived. A space shall be provided upon which the licensee shall affix his or her usual signature, as required in s. 322.14, in the presence of an authorized agent of the department so as to ensure that such signature becomes a part of the license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall, upon receipt of the required fee, issue to each qualified licensee applying for a renewal license in accordance with s. 322.18 a color photographic or digital imaged license as provided for in subsection (1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may conduct negotiations and enter into contracts with qualified firms possessing the requisite qualifications for the development and production of photographic or digital imaged identification documents to assure efficient and economical processing of such licenses in sufficient quantity and of acceptable quality to meet the requirements and intent of this section, and to ensure adequate service at a sufficient number of locations, at the lowest competitive sealed bid price.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may maintain a film negative or print file. The department shall maintain a record of the digital image and signature of the licensees, together with other data required by the department for identification and retrieval. Reproductions from the file or digital record are exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and shall be made and issued only for departmental administrative purposes; for the issuance of duplicate licenses; in response to law enforcement agency requests; to the Department of Business and Professional Regulation pursuant to an interagency agreement for the purpose of accessing digital images for reproduction of licenses issued by the Department of Business and Professional Regulation; to the Department of State pursuant to an interagency agreement to facilitate determinations of eligibility of voter registration applicants and registered voters in accordance with ss. 98.045 and 98.075; to the Department of Revenue pursuant to an interagency agreement for use in establishing paternity and establishing, modifying, or enforcing support obligations in Title IV-D cases; to the Department of Children and Family Services pursuant to an interagency agreement to conduct protective investigations under part III of chapter 39 and chapter 415; to the Department of Children and Family Services pursuant to an interagency agreement specifying the number of employees in each of that department’s regions to be granted access to the records for use as verification of identity to expedite the determination of eligibility for public assistance and for use in public assistance fraud investigations; to the Department of Financial Services pursuant to an interagency agreement to facilitate the location of owners of unclaimed property, the validation of unclaimed property claims, and the identification of fraudulent or false claims; or to district medical examiners pursuant to an interagency agreement for the purpose of identifying a deceased individual, determining cause of death, and notifying next of kin of any investigations, including autopsies and other laboratory examinations, authorized in <Reference Number="1"/>s. 406.011.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 67-346; ss. 1, 2, ch. 72-279; s. 15, ch. 78-394; s. 8, ch. 85-98; s. 4, ch. 89-90; s. 28, ch. 90-268; s. 406, ch. 95-148; s. 36, ch. 95-333; s. 156, ch. 96-406; s. 4, ch. 98-223; s. 1, ch. 99-306; s. 23, ch. 2001-158; s. 143, ch. 2004-390; s. 14, ch. 2005-39; s. 76, ch. 2005-164; s. 52, ch. 2005-278; s. 17, ch. 2008-245; s. 5, ch. 2010-31; s. 3, ch. 2010-106; s. 1, ch. 2010-207; s. 54, ch. 2012-181.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 406.011 does not exist; the intended reference may be to s. 406.11, which relates to examinations, investigations, and autopsies by medical examiners to determine cause of death of deceased human beings.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>