<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Driver’s license examiners.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall designate persons to serve as driver’s license examiners who, upon accepting such designation, shall conduct examinations hereunder, perform other assigned duties, and make factual reports of findings and recommendations to the department as it may require. In the course of his or her duties, an examiner is authorized to administer oaths or have persons affirm as to the truth of statements filed before him or her.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Those persons serving as driver’s license examiners are not liable for actions taken within the scope of their employment or designation, except as provided by s. 768.28.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall further designate persons to serve as driver’s license examiners to enforce all driver’s license laws; suspension, revocation, and cancellation orders; and laws relating to the registration of motor vehicles entered in compliance with the provisions of this chapter and chapters 320, 324, and 488. Upon designation, certain examiners shall be empowered to issue uniform traffic citations to persons found in violation of such chapters. Any person who fails or refuses to surrender his or her driver’s license, registration certificate, and license plate upon lawful demand of an examiner is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Persons designated as examiners by the department shall not be considered for membership in the state high-risk retirement program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(639); s. 25, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 1, ch. 57-767; s. 13, ch. 78-394; s. 4, ch. 85-98; s. 11, ch. 87-225; s. 42, ch. 91-224; s. 1, ch. 93-10; s. 405, ch. 95-148; s. 47, ch. 96-413.</History></Section>