<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.058" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension of driving privileges due to support delinquency; reinstatement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department receives notice from the Title IV-D agency or depository or the clerk of the court that any person licensed to operate a motor vehicle in the State of Florida under the provisions of this chapter has a delinquent support obligation or has failed to comply with a subpoena, order to appear, order to show cause, or similar order, the department shall suspend the driver’s license of the person named in the notice and the registration of all motor vehicles owned by that person.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department must reinstate the driving privilege and allow registration of a motor vehicle when the Title IV-D agency in IV-D cases or the depository or the clerk of the court in non-IV-D cases provides to the department an affidavit stating that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has paid the delinquency;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has reached a written agreement for payment with the Title IV-D agency or the obligee in non-IV-D cases;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court has entered an order granting relief to the obligor ordering the reinstatement of the license and motor vehicle registration; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has complied with the subpoena, order to appear, order to show cause, or similar order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not be held liable for any license or vehicle registration suspension resulting from the discharge of its duties under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies only to the annual renewal in the owner’s birth month of a motor vehicle registration and does not apply to the transfer of a registration of a motor vehicle sold by a motor vehicle dealer licensed under chapter 320, except for the transfer of registrations which includes the annual renewals. This section does not affect the issuance of the title to a motor vehicle, notwithstanding s. 319.23(8)(b).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 93-208; s. 45, ch. 94-306; s. 929, ch. 95-148; s. 2, ch. 95-222; s. 22, ch. 2001-158; s. 47, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>