<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.0261" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Driver improvement course; requirement to maintain driving privileges; failure to complete; department approval of course.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall screen crash reports received under s. 316.066 or s. 324.051 to identify crashes involving the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A crash involving death or a bodily injury requiring transport to a medical facility;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A second crash by the same operator within the previous 2-year period involving property damage in an apparent amount of at least $500; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A third crash by the same operator within 36 months after the first crash.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an operator convicted of, or who pleaded nolo contendere to, a traffic offense giving rise to a crash identified in paragraph (1)(a) or paragraph (1)(b), the department shall require that the operator, in addition to other applicable penalties, attend a department-approved driver improvement course in order to maintain his or her driving privileges. If the operator fails to complete the course within 90 days after receiving notice from the department, the operator’s driver’s license shall be canceled by the department until the course is successfully completed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to an operator convicted of, or who pleaded nolo contendere to, a traffic offense giving rise to a crash identified in paragraph (1)(c), the department shall require that the operator, in addition to other applicable penalties, attend a department-approved driver improvement course in order to maintain his or her driving privileges. The course must include behind-the-wheel instruction and an assessment of the operator’s ability to safely operate a motor vehicle. Successful completion of a behind-the-wheel examination is required in order to receive completion credit for the course. If the operator fails to complete the course within 90 days after receiving notice from the department, the operator’s driver’s license shall be canceled by the department until the course is successfully completed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall identify any operator convicted of, or who pleaded nolo contendere to, a violation of s. 316.074(1), s. 316.075(1)(c)1., s. 316.172, s. 316.191, or s. 316.192 and shall require that operator, in addition to other applicable penalties, to attend a department-approved driver improvement course in order to maintain driving privileges. The department shall, within 10 days after receiving a notice of judicial disposition, send notice to the operator of the requirement to attend a driver improvement course. If the operator fails to complete the course within 90 days after receiving notice from the department, the operator’s driver license shall be canceled by the department until the course is successfully completed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any operator who receives a traffic citation for a violation of s. 316.074(1), s. 316.075(1)(c)1., s. 316.191, or s. 316.192, for which the court withholds adjudication, is not required to attend a driver improvement course, unless the court finds that the nature or severity of the violation is such that attendance to a driver improvement course is necessary. The department shall, within 10 days after receiving a notice of judicial disposition, send notice to the operator of the requirement to attend a driver improvement course. If the operator fails to complete the course within 90 days after receiving notice from the department, the operator’s driver license shall be canceled by the department until the course is successfully completed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any operator who receives a traffic citation for a violation of s. 316.172, for which the court withholds adjudication, is required to attend a driver improvement course. The department shall, within 10 days after receiving a notice of judicial disposition, send notice to the operator of the requirement to attend a driver improvement course. If the operator fails to complete the course within 90 days after receiving notice from the department, the operator’s driver license shall be canceled by the department until the course is successfully completed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining whether to approve a driver improvement course for the purposes of this section, the department shall consider course content designed to promote safety, driver awareness, crash avoidance techniques, and other factors or criteria to improve driver performance from a safety viewpoint.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 90-119; s. 72, ch. 94-306; s. 280, ch. 99-248; s. 5, ch. 2005-194; s. 3, ch. 2009-138; s. 9, ch. 2009-183; s. 12, ch. 2010-198.</History>
</Section>