<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.282" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Procedure when court revokes or suspends license or driving privilege and orders reinstatement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a court suspends or revokes a person’s license or driving privilege and, in its discretion, orders reinstatement as provided by s. 322.28(2)(d) or former s. 322.261(5):</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall pick up all revoked or suspended driver’s licenses from the person and immediately forward them to the department, together with a record of such conviction. The clerk of such court shall also maintain a list of all revocations or suspensions by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall issue an order of reinstatement, on a form to be furnished by the department, which the person may take to any driver’s license examining office. The department shall issue a temporary driver’s permit to a licensee who presents the court’s order of reinstatement, proof of completion of a department-approved driver training or substance abuse education course, and a written request for a hearing under s. 322.271. The permit shall not be issued if a record check by the department shows that the person has previously been convicted for a violation of s. 316.193, former s. 316.1931, former s. 316.028, former s. 860.01, or a previous conviction outside this state for driving under the influence, driving while intoxicated, driving with an unlawful blood-alcohol level, or any similar alcohol-related or drug-related traffic offense; that the person’s driving privilege has been previously suspended for refusal to submit to a lawful test of breath, blood, or urine; or that the person is otherwise not entitled to issuance of a driver’s license. This paragraph shall not be construed to prevent the reinstatement of a license or driving privilege that is presently suspended for driving with an unlawful blood-alcohol level or a refusal to submit to a breath, urine, or blood test and is also revoked for a conviction for a violation of s. 316.193 or former s. 316.1931, if the suspension and revocation arise out of the same incident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The temporary driver’s permit shall be restricted to either business or employment purposes described in s. 322.271, as determined by the department, and shall not be used for pleasure, recreational, or nonessential driving.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department determines at a later date from its records that the applicant has previously been convicted of an offense referred to in paragraph (a) which would render him or her ineligible for reinstatement, the department shall cancel the temporary driver’s permit and shall issue a revocation or suspension order for the minimum period applicable. A temporary permit issued pursuant to this section shall be valid for 45 days or until canceled as provided in this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The period of time for which a temporary permit issued in accordance with paragraph (a) is valid shall be deemed to be part of the period of revocation imposed by the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 74-384; s. 2, ch. 75-113; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 24, ch. 78-394; s. 24, ch. 83-215; s. 11, ch. 84-359; s. 9, ch. 86-296; s. 4, ch. 89-525; ss. 11, 23, ch. 91-255; s. 417, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>