<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.29" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Surrender and return of license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, upon suspending or revoking a license, shall require that such license be surrendered to the department. At the end of the period of suspension, such license so surrendered shall be returned, or a duplicate license issued, to the licensee after the applicant has successfully passed the vision, sign, and traffic law examinations. In addition, pursuant to s. 322.221, the department may require the licensee to successfully complete a driving examination. The department is prohibited from requiring the surrender of a license except as authorized by this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (1), an examination is not required for the return of a license suspended under s. 318.15 or s. 322.245 unless an examination is otherwise required by this chapter. A person applying for the return of a license suspended under s. 318.15 or s. 322.245 must present to the department certification from the court that he or she has complied with all obligations and penalties imposed pursuant to s. 318.15 or, in the case of a suspension pursuant to s. 322.245, that he or she has complied with all directives of the court and the requirements of s. 322.245 and shall pay to the department a nonrefundable service fee of $60, of which $37.50 shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund and $22.50 shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund. If reinstated by the clerk of the court or tax collector, $37.50 shall be retained and $22.50 shall be remitted to the Department of Revenue for deposit into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund. However, the service fee is not required if the person is required to pay a $45 fee or $75 fee under s. 322.21(8).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 41, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(655); s. 41, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 1, ch. 59-442; s. 9, ch. 72-175; s. 1, ch. 80-308; s. 3, ch. 84-265; s. 23, ch. 84-359; s. 10, ch. 86-296; s. 418, ch. 95-148; s. 6, ch. 2003-410; s. 53, ch. 2005-236; s. 38, ch. 2009-71.</History></Section>