<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.212" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unauthorized possession of, and other unlawful acts in relation to, driver’s license or identification card.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly have in his or her possession or to display any blank, forged, stolen, fictitious, counterfeit, or unlawfully issued driver’s license or identification card or any instrument in the similitude of a driver’s license or identification card unless possession by such person has been duly authorized by the department;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly have in his or her possession any instrument in the similitude of a driver’s license issued by the department or its duly authorized agents or those of any state or jurisdiction issuing licenses recognized in this state for the operation of a motor vehicle;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly have in his or her possession any instrument in the similitude of an identification card issued by the department or its duly authorized agents or those of any state or jurisdiction issuing identification cards recognized in this state for the purpose of indicating a person’s true name and age; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly sell, manufacture, or deliver, or knowingly offer to sell, manufacture, or deliver, a blank, forged, stolen, fictitious, counterfeit, or unlawfully issued driver’s license or identification card, or an instrument in the similitude of a driver’s license or identification card, unless that person is authorized to do so by the department. A violation of this section may be investigated by any law enforcement agency, including the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The term “driver’s license” includes a driver’s license issued by the department or its agents or a driver’s license issued by any state or jurisdiction that issues licenses recognized in this state for the operation of a motor vehicle. The term “identification card” includes any identification card issued by the department or its agents or any identification card issued by any state or jurisdiction that issues identification cards recognized in this state for the purpose of indicating a person’s true name and age. This subsection does not prohibit a person from possessing or displaying another person’s driver’s license or identification card for a lawful purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to barter, trade, sell, or give away any driver’s license or identification card or to perpetrate a conspiracy to barter, trade, sell, or give away any such license or identification card unless such person has been duly authorized to issue the license or identification card by the department as provided in this chapter or in the adopted rules of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any employee of the department to allow or permit the issuance of a driver’s license or identification card when he or she knows that the applicant has not lawfully fulfilled the requirements of this chapter for the issuance of such license or identification card.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to agree to supply or to aid in supplying any person with a driver’s license or identification card by any means whatsoever not in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to use a false or fictitious name in any application for a driver’s license or identification card or knowingly to make a false statement, knowingly conceal a material fact, or otherwise commit a fraud in any such application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to have in his or her possession a driver’s license or identification card upon which the date of birth has been altered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person designated as a sexual predator or sexual offender to have in his or her possession a driver’s license or identification card upon which the sexual predator or sexual offender markings required by s. 322.141 are not displayed or have been altered.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, any person who violates any of the provisions of this section is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. Any person who violates paragraph (5)(a) by giving a false age in any application for a driver’s license or identification card or who violates paragraph (5)(b) by possessing a driver’s license, identification card, or any instrument in the similitude thereof, on which the date of birth has been altered is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Any person who violates paragraph (1)(d) commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalties provided by this section, any person who provides false information when applying for a commercial driver’s license shall be disqualified from operating a commercial motor vehicle for a period of 60 days.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are in addition and supplemental to all other provisions of this chapter and of the laws of this state relating to driver’s licenses and identification cards.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-167; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 212, ch. 71-136; s. 24, ch. 73-334; s. 19, ch. 78-394; s. 1, ch. 84-91; s. 410, ch. 95-148; s. 4, ch. 97-206; s. 1, ch. 2002-178; s. 6, ch. 2002-259; s. 2, ch. 2003-286; s. 82, ch. 2005-164; s. 2, ch. 2007-207.</History></Section>