<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation or suspension of, or delay of eligibility for, driver’s license for persons 18 years of age or older convicted of certain drug offenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 322.28, upon the conviction of a person 18 years of age or older for possession or sale of, trafficking in, or conspiracy to possess, sell, or traffic in a controlled substance, the court shall direct the department to revoke the driver’s license or driving privilege of the person. The period of such revocation shall be 2 years or until the person is evaluated for and, if deemed necessary by the evaluating agency, completes a drug treatment and rehabilitation program approved or regulated by the Department of Children and Family Services. However, the court may, in its sound discretion, direct the department to issue a license for driving privileges restricted to business or employment purposes only, as defined by s. 322.271, if the person is otherwise qualified for such a license. A driver whose license or driving privilege has been suspended or revoked under this section or s. 322.056 may, upon the expiration of 6 months, petition the department for restoration of the driving privilege on a restricted or unrestricted basis depending on length of suspension or revocation. In no case shall a restricted license be available until 6 months of the suspension or revocation period has expired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person 18 years of age or older is convicted for the possession or sale of, trafficking in, or conspiracy to possess, sell, or traffic in a controlled substance and such person is eligible by reason of age for a driver’s license or privilege, the court shall direct the department to withhold issuance of such person’s driver’s license or driving privilege for a period of 2 years after the date the person was convicted or until the person is evaluated for and, if deemed necessary by the evaluating agency, completes a drug treatment and rehabilitation program approved or regulated by the Department of Children and Family Services. However, the court may, in its sound discretion, direct the department to issue a license for driving privileges restricted to business or employment purposes only, as defined by s. 322.271, if the person is otherwise qualified for such a license. A driver whose license or driving privilege has been suspended or revoked under this section or s. 322.056 may, upon the expiration of 6 months, petition the department for restoration of the driving privilege on a restricted or unrestricted basis depending on the length of suspension or revocation. In no case shall a restricted license be available until 6 months of the suspension or revocation period has expired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person 18 years of age or older is convicted for the possession or sale of, trafficking in, or conspiracy to possess, sell, or traffic in a controlled substance and such person’s driver’s license or driving privilege is already under suspension or revocation for any reason, the court shall direct the department to extend the period of such suspension or revocation by an additional period of 2 years or until the person is evaluated for and, if deemed necessary by the evaluating agency, completes a drug treatment and rehabilitation program approved or regulated by the Department of Children and Family Services. However, the court may, in its sound discretion, direct the department to issue a license for driving privileges restricted to business or employment purposes only, as defined by s. 322.271, if the person is otherwise qualified for such a license. A driver whose license or driving privilege has been suspended or revoked under this section or s. 322.056 may, upon the expiration of 6 months, petition the department for restoration of the driving privilege on a restricted or unrestricted basis depending on the length of suspension or revocation. In no case shall a restricted license be available until 6 months of the suspension or revocation period has expired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person 18 years of age or older is convicted for the possession or sale of, trafficking in, or conspiracy to possess, sell, or traffic in a controlled substance and such person is ineligible by reason of age for a driver’s license or driving privilege, the court shall direct the department to withhold issuance of such person’s driver’s license or driving privilege for a period of 2 years after the date that he or she would otherwise have become eligible or until he or she becomes eligible by reason of age for a driver’s license and is evaluated for and, if deemed necessary by the evaluating agency, completes a drug treatment and rehabilitation program approved or regulated by the Department of Children and Family Services. However, the court may, in its sound discretion, direct the department to issue a license for driving privileges restricted to business or employment purposes only, as defined by s. 322.271, if the person is otherwise qualified for such a license. A driver whose license or driving privilege has been suspended or revoked under this section or s. 322.056 may, upon the expiration of 6 months, petition the department for restoration of the driving privilege on a restricted or unrestricted basis depending on the length of suspension or revocation. In no case shall a restricted license be available until 6 months of the suspension or revocation period has expired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each clerk of court shall promptly report to the department each conviction for the possession or sale of, trafficking in, or conspiracy to possess, sell, or traffic in a controlled substance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 87-243; s. 4, ch. 89-281; s. 7, ch. 90-265; s. 74, ch. 94-306; s. 928, ch. 95-148; s. 60, ch. 99-8; s. 281, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>