<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mandatory revocation of license by department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall forthwith revoke the license or driving privilege of any person upon receiving a record of such person’s conviction of any of the following offenses:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Murder resulting from the operation of a motor vehicle, DUI manslaughter where the conviction represents a subsequent DUI-related conviction, or a fourth violation of s. 316.193 or former s. 316.1931. For such cases, the revocation of the driver’s license or driving privilege shall be permanent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manslaughter resulting from the operation of a motor vehicle.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Driving a motor vehicle or being in actual physical control thereof, or entering a plea of nolo contendere, said plea being accepted by the court and said court entering a fine or sentence to a charge of driving, while under the influence of alcoholic beverages or a substance controlled under chapter 893, or being in actual physical control of a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcoholic beverages or a substance controlled under chapter 893. In any case where DUI manslaughter occurs and the person has no prior convictions for DUI-related offenses, the revocation of the license or driving privilege shall be permanent, except as provided for in s. 322.271(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to stop and render aid as required under the laws of this state in the event of a motor vehicle crash resulting in the death or personal injury of another.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perjury or the making of a false affidavit or statement under oath to the department under this law, or under any other law relating to the ownership or operation of motor vehicles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conviction, or forfeiture of bail not vacated, upon three charges of reckless driving committed within a period of 12 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of the law against lewdness, assignation, and prostitution where such violation has been effected through the use of a motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conviction in any court having jurisdiction over offenses committed under this chapter or any other law of this state regulating the operation of a motor vehicle on the highways, upon direction of the court, when the court feels that the seriousness of the offense and the circumstances surrounding the conviction warrant the revocation of the licensee’s driving privilege.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conviction in any court having jurisdiction over offenses committed under s. 817.234(8) or (9) or s. 817.505.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 38, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(652); s. 38, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 1, ch. 21764, 1943; s. 4, ch. 61-457; s. 2, ch. 65-124; s. 20, ch. 73-331; s. 1, ch. 77-119; s. 2, ch. 78-204; s. 46, ch. 89-282; s. 6, ch. 96-330; s. 8, ch. 98-223; s. 290, ch. 99-248; s. 3, ch. 2006-305.</History></Section>