<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.0515" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Department to forward certain information to federal Selective Service System; notification to applicant for certain license; application statement required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require any male United States citizen or immigrant who is at least 18 years of age but less than 26 years of age to comply with federal Selective Service System requirements when applying to receive a driver’s license, a learner’s driver’s license, a commercial driver’s license, an identification card, or the renewal or duplicate card or license as described in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forward to the federal Selective Service System information about applicants for a license or card as described in paragraph (a) in an electronic format to assist in compliance with federal Selective Service System requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide notification to each applicant for a license or card as described in paragraph (a) that an applicant’s submission of the application serves to certify that the applicant either has complied with federal Selective Service System requirements or is authorizing the department to forward to the Selective Service System the information necessary for registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify an applicant for a license or card as described in paragraph (a) who is under 18 years of age that the applicant will be registered upon attaining 18 years of age as required by federal law.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide, by rule, for the following statement to be included on an application for a license or card as described in paragraph (1)(a): “By submitting this application, I am consenting to registration with the federal Selective Service System, if so required. If under 18 years of age, I understand that I will be registered when I attain 18 years of age as required by federal law.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-159.</History></Section>