<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.19" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Change of address or name.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any person, after applying for or receiving a driver’s license, changes his or her legal name, that person must within 10 days thereafter obtain a replacement license that reflects the change.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any person, after applying for or receiving a driver license, changes the legal residence or mailing address in the application or license, the person must, within 10 calendar days after making the change, obtain a replacement license that reflects the change. A written request to the department must include the old and new addresses and the driver license number. Any person who has a valid, current student identification card issued by an educational institution in this state is presumed not to have changed his or her legal residence or mailing address. This subsection does not affect any person required to register a permanent or temporary address change pursuant to s. 775.13, s. 775.21, s. 775.25, or s. 943.0435.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of this section is a nonmoving violation with a penalty as provided in s. 318.18(2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, if a licensee established his or her identity for a driver’s license using an identification document authorized under s. 322.08(2)(c)7. or 8., the licensee may not change his or her name or address except in person and upon submission of an identification document authorized under s. 322.08(2)(c)7. or 8.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(645); s. 31, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 18, ch. 84-359; s. 41, ch. 89-282; s. 409, ch. 95-148; s. 8, ch. 95-326; s. 40, ch. 95-333; s. 5, ch. 2002-259; s. 80, ch. 2005-164; s. 34, ch. 2008-176; s. 55, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>