<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Actual weight” means the weight of a motor vehicle or motor vehicle combination plus the weight of the load carried on it, as determined at a fixed scale operated by the state or as determined by use of a portable scale operated by a law enforcement officer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alcohol” means any substance containing any form of alcohol including, but not limited to, ethanol, methanol, propanol, and isopropanol.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Alcohol concentration” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of grams of alcohol per 100 milliliters of blood;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of grams of alcohol per 210 liters of breath; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of grams of alcohol per 67 milliliters of urine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Authorized emergency vehicle” means a vehicle that is equipped with extraordinary audible and visual warning devices, that is authorized by s. 316.2397 to display red or blue lights, and that is on call to respond to emergencies. The term includes, but is not limited to, ambulances, law enforcement vehicles, fire trucks, and other rescue vehicles. The term does not include wreckers, utility trucks, or other vehicles that are used only incidentally for emergency purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cancellation” means the act of declaring a driver’s license void and terminated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Color photographic driver’s license” means a color photograph of a completed driver’s license form meeting the requirements prescribed in s. 322.14.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial driver’s license” means a Class A, Class B, or Class C driver’s license issued in accordance with the requirements of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commercial motor vehicle” means any motor vehicle or motor vehicle combination used on the streets or highways, which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a gross vehicle weight rating of 26,001 pounds or more;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is designed to transport more than 15 persons, including the driver; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is transporting hazardous materials and is required to be placarded in accordance with Title 49 C.F.R. part 172, subpart F.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A vehicle that occasionally transports personal property to and from a closed-course motorsport facility, as defined in s. 549.09(1)(a), is not a commercial motor vehicle if the use is not for profit and corporate sponsorship is not involved. As used in this subsection, the term “corporate sponsorship” means a payment, donation, gratuity, in-kind service, or other benefit provided to or derived by a person in relation to the underlying activity, other than the display of product or corporate names, logos, or other graphic information on the property being transported.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Controlled substance” means any substance classified as such under 21 U.S.C. s. 802(6), Schedules I-V of Title 21 C.F.R. part 1308, or chapter 893.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Convenience service” means any means whereby an individual conducts a transaction with the department other than in person.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Conviction” means a conviction of an offense relating to the operation of motor vehicles on highways which is a violation of this chapter or any other such law of this state or any other state, including an admission or determination of a noncriminal traffic infraction pursuant to s. 318.14, or a judicial disposition of an offense committed under any federal law substantially conforming to the aforesaid state statutory provisions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the definition of “conviction” provided in 49 C.F.R. part 383.5 applies to offenses committed in a commercial motor vehicle or by a person holding a commercial driver’s license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court” means any tribunal in this state or any other state, or any federal tribunal, which has jurisdiction over any civil, criminal, traffic, or administrative action.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Declared weight” means the maximum loaded weight declared for purposes of registration, pursuant to chapter 320.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles acting directly or through its duly authorized representatives.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Disqualification” means a prohibition, other than an out-of-service order, that precludes a person from driving a commercial motor vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Drive” means to operate or be in actual physical control of a motor vehicle in any place open to the general public for purposes of vehicular traffic.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Driver’s license” means a certificate that, subject to all other requirements of law, authorizes an individual to drive a motor vehicle and denotes an operator’s license as defined in 49 U.S.C. s. 30301.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Endorsement” means a special authorization which permits a driver to drive certain types of vehicles or to transport certain types of property or a certain number of passengers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Farmer” means a person who grows agricultural products, including aquacultural, horticultural, and forestry products, and, except as provided herein, employees of such persons. The term does not include employees whose primary purpose of employment is the operation of motor vehicles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Farm tractor” means a motor vehicle that is:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operated principally on a farm, grove, or orchard in agricultural or horticultural pursuits and that is operated on the roads of this state only incidentally for transportation between the owner’s or operator’s headquarters and the farm, grove, or orchard or between one farm, grove, or orchard and another; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designed and used primarily as a farm implement for drawing plows, mowing machines, and other implements of husbandry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Felony” means any offense under state or federal law that is punishable by death or by a term of imprisonment exceeding 1 year.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign jurisdiction” means any jurisdiction other than a state of the United States.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gross vehicle weight rating” means the value specified by the manufacturer as the maximum loaded weight of a single, combination, or articulated vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hazardous materials” means any material that has been designated as hazardous under 49 U.S.C. s. 5103 and is required to be placarded under subpart F of 49 C.F.R. part 172 or any quantity of a material listed as a select agent or toxin in 42 C.F.R. part 73.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical examiner’s certificate” means a document substantially in accordance with the requirements of Title 49 C.F.R. s. 391.43.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="26">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motorcycle” means a motor vehicle powered by a motor with a displacement of more than 50 cubic centimeters, having a seat or saddle for the use of the rider, and designed to travel on not more than three wheels in contact with the ground, but excluding a tractor, tri-vehicle, or moped.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="27">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motor vehicle” means any self-propelled vehicle, including a motor vehicle combination, not operated upon rails or guideway, excluding vehicles moved solely by human power, motorized wheelchairs, and motorized bicycles as defined in s. 316.003.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="28">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Motor vehicle combination” means a motor vehicle operated in conjunction with one or more other vehicles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="29">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Narcotic drugs” means coca leaves, opium, isonipecaine, cannabis, and every substance neither chemically nor physically distinguishable from them, and any and all derivatives of same, and any other drug to which the narcotics laws of the United States apply, and includes all drugs and derivatives thereof known as barbiturates.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="30">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Out-of-service order” means a prohibition issued by an authorized local, state, or Federal Government official which precludes a person from driving a commercial motor vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="31">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means the person who holds the legal title to a vehicle. However, if a vehicle is the subject of an agreement for the conditional sale or lease thereof with the right of purchase upon performance of the conditions stated in the agreement and with an immediate right of possession vested in the conditional vendee or lessee, or if a mortgagor of a vehicle is entitled to possession, such conditional vendee, lessee, or mortgagor is the owner for the purpose of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="32">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Passenger vehicle” means a motor vehicle designed to transport more than 15 persons, including the driver, or a school bus designed to transport more than 15 persons, including the driver.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="33">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permit” means a document authorizing the temporary operation of a motor vehicle within this state subject to conditions established in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="34">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident” means a person who has his or her principal place of domicile in this state for a period of more than 6 consecutive months, has registered to vote, has made a statement of domicile pursuant to s. 222.17, or has filed for homestead tax exemption on property in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="35">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Restriction” means a prohibition against operating certain types of motor vehicles or a requirement that a driver comply with certain conditions when driving a motor vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="36">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Revocation” means the termination of a licensee’s privilege to drive.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="37">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“School bus” means a motor vehicle that is designed to transport more than 15 persons, including the driver, and that is used to transport students to and from a public or private school or in connection with school activities, but does not include a bus operated by a common carrier in the urban transportation of school children. The term “school” includes all preelementary, elementary, secondary, and postsecondary schools.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="38">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” means a state or possession of the United States, and, for the purposes of this chapter, includes the District of Columbia.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="39">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Street or highway” means the entire width between the boundary lines of a way or place if any part of that way or place is open to public use for purposes of vehicular traffic.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="40">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Suspension” means the temporary withdrawal of a licensee’s privilege to drive a motor vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="41">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tank vehicle” means a vehicle that is designed to transport any liquid or gaseous material within a tank either permanently or temporarily attached to the vehicle, if such tank has a designed capacity of 1,000 gallons or more.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="42">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“United States” means the 50 states and the District of Columbia.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="43">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vehicle” means every device in, upon, or by which any person or property is or may be transported or drawn upon a public highway or operated upon rails or guideway, except a bicycle, motorized wheelchair, or motorized bicycle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="44">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Identification card” means a personal identification card issued by the department which conforms to the definition in 18 U.S.C. s. 1028(d).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="45">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Temporary driver’s license” or “temporary identification card” means a certificate issued by the department which, subject to all other requirements of law, authorizes an individual to drive a motor vehicle and denotes an operator’s license, as defined in 49 U.S.C. s. 30301, or a personal identification card issued by the department which conforms to the definition in 18 U.S.C. s. 1028(d) and denotes that the holder is permitted to stay for a short duration of time, as specified on the temporary identification card, and is not a permanent resident of the United States.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="46">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tri-vehicle” means an enclosed three-wheeled passenger vehicle that:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is designed to operate with three wheels in contact with the ground;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a minimum unladen weight of 900 pounds;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a single, completely enclosed, occupant compartment;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is produced in a minimum quantity of 300 in any calendar year;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is capable of a speed greater than 60 miles per hour on level ground; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is equipped with:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seats that are certified by the vehicle manufacturer to meet the requirements of Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 207, “Seating systems” (49 C.F.R. s. 571.207);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A steering wheel used to maneuver the vehicle;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A propulsion unit located forward or aft of the enclosed occupant compartment;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A seat belt for each vehicle occupant certified to meet the requirements of Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 209, “Seat belt assemblies” (49 C.F.R. s. 571.209);</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A windshield and an appropriate windshield wiper and washer system that are certified by the vehicle manufacturer to meet the requirements of Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 205, “Glazing Materials” (49 C.F.R. s. 571.205) and Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 104, “Windshield Wiping and Washing Systems” (49 C.F.R. s. 571.104); and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A vehicle structure certified by the vehicle manufacturer to meet the requirements of Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 216, “Rollover crush resistance” (49 C.F.R. s. 571.216).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(627); s. 13, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 1, ch. 29721, 1955; s. 1, ch. 61-457; s. 1, ch. 63-156; s. 1, ch. 65-496; s. 1, ch. 67-242; s. 1, ch. 67-304; s. 1, ch. 67-346; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 99, ch. 71-377; s. 5, ch. 76-286; s. 5, ch. 78-353; s. 1, ch. 78-394; s. 1, ch. 81-3; s. 1, ch. 81-188; s. 17, ch. 83-218; s. 8, ch. 85-81; s. 16, ch. 87-161; s. 3, ch. 89-282; s. 3, ch. 90-230; s. 70, ch. 94-306; s. 925, ch. 95-148; s. 11, ch. 95-247; s. 31, ch. 95-333; s. 8, ch. 96-247; s. 67, ch. 2005-164; s. 39, ch. 2006-290; s. 26, ch. 2008-176; s. 3, ch. 2008-179; s. 31, ch. 2010-223; ss. 4, 9, ch. 2011-7; HJR 7103, 2011 Regular Session.</History>
</Section>