<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.202" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Admission of evidence obtained from the Division of Motorist Services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the Division of Motorist Services of the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles is not a law enforcement agency. The Legislature also finds that the division is not an adjunct of any law enforcement agency in that employees have no stake in particular prosecutions. The Legislature further finds that errors in records maintained by the division are not within the collective knowledge of any law enforcement agency. The Legislature also finds that the missions of the division and the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles provide a sufficient incentive to maintain records in a current and correct fashion.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the purpose of the exclusionary rule is to deter misconduct on the part of law enforcement officers and law enforcement agencies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the application of the exclusionary rule to cases where a law enforcement officer effects an arrest based on objectively reasonable reliance on information obtained from the division is repugnant to the purposes of the exclusionary rule and contrary to the decisions of the United States Supreme Court in <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Arizona v. Evans,</Font> 514 U.S. 1 (1995) and <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">United States v. Leon,</Font> 468 U.S. 897 (1984).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case where a law enforcement officer effects an arrest based on objectively reasonable reliance on information obtained from the division, evidence found pursuant to such an arrest shall not be suppressed by application of the exclusionary rule on the grounds that the arrest is subsequently determined to be unlawful due to erroneous information obtained from the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2002-215; s. 25, ch. 2011-66.</History>
</Section>