<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Attendance requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBILITY REQUIREMENTS FOR DRIVING PRIVILEGES.<EmDash />A minor is not eligible for driving privileges unless that minor:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is enrolled in a public school, nonpublic school, or home education program and satisfies relevant attendance requirements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received a high school diploma, a high school equivalency diploma, a special diploma, or a certificate of high school completion;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is enrolled in a study course in preparation for the Test of General Educational Development and satisfies relevant attendance requirements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is enrolled in other educational activities approved by the district school board and satisfies relevant attendance requirements;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been issued a certificate of exemption according to s. 1003.21(3); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received a hardship waiver under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department may not issue a driver’s license or learner’s driver’s license to, or shall suspend the driver’s license or learner’s driver’s license of, any minor concerning whom the department receives notification of noncompliance with the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTIFICATION OF INTENT TO SUSPEND; SUSPENSION; RECORD OF NONCOMPLIANCE.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall notify each minor for whom the department has received notification of noncompliance with the requirements of this section as provided in s. 1003.27, and the minor’s parent or guardian, of the department’s intent to suspend the minor’s driving privileges.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor, or the parent or guardian of the minor, has 15 calendar days after the date of receipt of this notice to provide proof of compliance with the requirements of this section as provided in subsection (4) or to request a hardship waiver hearing under subsection (3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty days after the date of issuance of this notice, the department shall suspend the minor’s operator’s license or learner’s driver’s license or record the legal name, sex, date of birth, and social security number of each minor who does not possess a driver’s license or learner’s driver’s license, unless the minor has provided the department with verification of compliance with the requirements of subsection (1) or the appropriate school official has provided the department with verification of a request for a waiver hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon notification of the outcome of a hardship waiver hearing, the department shall suspend the driver’s license or learner’s driver’s license of a minor who was denied a hardship waiver, or record the legal name, sex, date of birth, and social security number of a minor who does not possess a driver’s license or learner’s driver’s license and who was denied a hardship waiver.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a driver’s license or learner’s driver’s license to any minor for whom it has a record of noncompliance with the requirements of subsection (1) unless the minor submits verification of compliance pursuant to subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HARDSHIP WAIVER AND APPEAL.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A minor, or the parent or guardian of a minor, has 15 calendar days after the date of receipt of the notice of intent to suspend to request a hardship waiver hearing before the public school principal, the principal’s designee, or the designee of the governing body of a private school for the purpose of reviewing the pending suspension of driving privileges. The school official receiving the request shall notify the department of the request for a waiver hearing within 24 hours after receiving the request. Public school officials shall also notify the district school board of the request for a waiver hearing. The hearing must be conducted within 30 calendar days after the public school principal, the principal’s designee, or the designee of the governing body of a private school receives the request.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public school principal, the principal’s designee, or the designee of the governing body of a private school shall waive the requirements of subsection (1) for any minor under the school’s jurisdiction for whom a personal or family hardship requires that the minor have a driver’s license for his or her own, or his or her family’s, employment or medical care. The minor or the minor’s parent or guardian may present other evidence that indicates compliance with the requirements of subsection (1) at the waiver hearing. The public school principal, the principal’s designee, or the designee of the governing body of a private school shall take into consideration the recommendations of teachers, other school officials, guidance counselors, or academic advisers before waiving the requirements of subsection (1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public school principal, the principal’s designee, or the designee of the governing body of a private school shall notify the department of the outcome of a minor’s hardship waiver hearing within 24 hours after conducting the hearing. Public school officials shall also notify the district school board of the outcome of the hearing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person denied a hardship waiver by a public school principal, the principal’s designee, or the designee of the governing body of a private school may appeal the decision to the district school board or the governing body of the private school. The district school board or the governing body of the private school shall notify the department if the hardship waiver is subsequently granted.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">VERIFICATION OF COMPLIANCE AND REINSTATEMENT.<EmDash />A district school board shall provide a minor with written verification that he or she is in compliance with the requirements of subsection (1) if the district determines that he or she has been in compliance for 30 days prior to the request for verification of compliance. Upon receiving written verification that the minor is again in compliance with the requirements of subsection (1), the department shall reinstate the minor’s driving privilege. Thereafter, if the school district determines that the minor is not in compliance with the requirements of subsection (1), the department shall suspend the minor’s driving privilege until the minor is 18 years of age or otherwise satisfies the requirements of subsection (1), whichever occurs first.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORTING AND ACCOUNTABILITY.<EmDash />The department shall report quarterly to each school district the legal name, sex, date of birth, and social security number of each student whose driving privileges have been suspended under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 97-234; s. 968, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>