<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.2715" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Ignition interlock device.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before issuing a permanent or restricted driver’s license under this chapter, the department shall require the placement of a department-approved ignition interlock device for any person convicted of committing an offense of driving under the influence as specified in subsection (3), except that consideration may be given to those individuals having a documented medical condition that would prohibit the device from functioning normally. An interlock device shall be placed on all vehicles that are individually or jointly leased or owned and routinely operated by the convicted person.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, any conviction for a violation of s. 316.193, a previous conviction for a violation of former s. 316.1931, or a conviction outside this state for driving under the influence, driving while intoxicated, driving with an unlawful blood-alcohol level, or any other similar alcohol-related or drug-related traffic offense is a conviction of driving under the influence.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person is convicted of:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A first offense of driving under the influence under s. 316.193 and has an unlawful blood-alcohol level or breath-alcohol level as specified in s. 316.193(4), or if a person is convicted of a violation of s. 316.193 and was at the time of the offense accompanied in the vehicle by a person younger than 18 years of age, the person shall have the ignition interlock device installed for not less than 6 continuous months for the first offense and for not less than 2 continuous years for a second offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A second offense of driving under the influence, the ignition interlock device shall be installed for a period of not less than 1 continuous year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A third offense of driving under the influence which occurs within 10 years after a prior conviction for a violation of s. 316.193, the ignition interlock device shall be installed for a period of not less than 2 continuous years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A third offense of driving under the influence which occurs more than 10 years after the date of a prior conviction, the ignition interlock device shall be installed for a period of not less than 2 continuous years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fourth or subsequent offense of driving under the influence, the ignition interlock device shall be installed for a period of not less than 5 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court fails to order the mandatory placement of the ignition interlock device or fails to order for the applicable period the mandatory placement of an ignition interlock device under s. 316.193 or s. 316.1937 at the time of imposing sentence or within 30 days thereafter, the department shall immediately require that the ignition interlock device be installed as provided in this section, except that consideration may be given to those individuals having a documented medical condition that would prohibit the device from functioning normally. This subsection applies to the reinstatement of the driving privilege following a revocation, suspension, or cancellation that is based upon a conviction for the offense of driving under the influence which occurs on or after July 1, 2005.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any fees authorized by rule for the installation and maintenance of the ignition interlock device, the authorized installer of the device shall collect and remit $12 for each installation to the department, which shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund to be used for the operation of the Ignition Interlock Device Program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-138; s. 36, ch. 2008-176; s. 37, ch. 2009-71; s. 38, ch. 2010-223.</History>
</Section>