<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">High-risk drivers; restricted licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the department shall restrict the driving privilege of any Class E licensee who is age 15 through 17 and who has accumulated six or more points pursuant to s. 318.14, excluding parking violations, within a 12-month period.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determination that any person has accumulated six or more points, the department shall notify the licensee and issue the licensee a restricted license for business purposes only. The licensee must appear before the department within 10 days after notification to have this restriction applied. The period of restriction shall be for a period of no less than 1 year beginning on the date it is applied by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The restriction shall be automatically withdrawn by the department after 1 year if the licensee does not accumulate any additional points. If the licensee accumulates any additional points, then the period of restriction shall be extended 90 days for each point. The restriction shall also be automatically withdrawn upon the licensee’s 18th birthday if no other grounds for restriction exist. The licensee must appear before the department to have the restriction removed and a duplicate license issued.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action taken by the department pursuant to this section shall not be subject to any formal or informal administrative hearing or similar administrative procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules to carry out the purposes of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 96-413; s. 12, ch. 2001-196; s. 77, ch. 2005-164.</History></Section>