<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Persons not to be licensed.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a license:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a person who is under the age of 16 years, except that the department may issue a learner’s driver’s license to a person who is at least 15 years of age and who meets the requirements of ss. 322.091 and 322.1615 and of any other applicable law or rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a person who is at least 16 years of age but is under 18 years of age unless the person meets the requirements of s. 322.091 and holds a valid:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Learner’s driver’s license for at least 12 months, with no moving traffic convictions, before applying for a license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Learner’s driver’s license for at least 12 months and who has a moving traffic conviction but elects to attend a traffic driving school for which adjudication must be withheld pursuant to s. 318.14; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">License that was issued in another state or in a foreign jurisdiction and that would not be subject to suspension or revocation under the laws of this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a person who is at least 16 years of age but who is under 18 years of age, unless the parent, guardian, or other responsible adult meeting the requirements of s. 322.09 certifies that he or she, or another licensed driver 21 years of age or older, has accompanied the applicant for a total of not less than 50 hours’ behind-the-wheel experience, of which not less than 10 hours must be at night. This subsection is not intended to create a private cause of action as a result of the certification. The certification is inadmissible for any purpose in any civil proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided by this subsection, to any person, as a Class A licensee, Class B licensee, or Class C licensee, who is under the age of 18 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person whose license has been suspended, during such suspension, nor to any person whose license has been revoked, until the expiration of the period of revocation imposed under the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person, as a commercial motor vehicle operator, whose privilege to operate a commercial motor vehicle has been disqualified, until the expiration of the period of disqualification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person who is an habitual drunkard, or is an habitual user of narcotic drugs, or is an habitual user of any other drug to a degree which renders him or her incapable of safely driving a motor vehicle.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person who has been adjudged to be afflicted with or suffering from any mental disability or disease and who has not at the time of application been restored to competency by the methods provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person who is required by this chapter to take an examination, unless such person shall have successfully passed such examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person, when the department has good cause to believe that the operation of a motor vehicle on the highways by such person would be detrimental to public safety or welfare. Deafness alone shall not prevent the person afflicted from being issued a Class E driver’s license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any person who is ineligible under s. 322.056.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(631); s. 17, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 2, ch. 21949, 1943; s. 4, ch. 29721, 1955; s. 1, ch. 67-174; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 6, ch. 78-394; ss. 1, 7, ch. 89-112; s. 17, ch. 89-282; s. 6, ch. 90-265; ss. 3, 4, ch. 93-144; s. 396, ch. 95-148; s. 1, ch. 96-414; s. 14, ch. 97-234; s. 3, ch. 2000-239; s. 10, ch. 2001-196; s. 68, ch. 2005-164; s. 40, ch. 2006-290.</History></Section>