<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.126" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Report of disability to department; content; use.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of the reports authorized by this section, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, assisted by the Medical Advisory Board, shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Define mental or physical disabilities affecting the ability of a person to safely operate a motor vehicle.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and keep current coded restrictions to be placed upon drivers’ licenses of persons who are required to wear medical identification bracelets when operating a motor vehicle.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any physician, person, or agency having knowledge of any licensed driver’s or applicant’s mental or physical disability to drive or need to obtain or to wear a medical identification bracelet is authorized to report such knowledge to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles. The report should be made in writing giving the full name, date of birth, address, and a description of the alleged disability of any person over 15 years of age having mental or physical disorders that could affect his or her driving ability.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reports authorized by this section shall be confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and shall be used solely for the purpose of determining the qualifications of any person to operate a motor vehicle on the highways of this state. No civil or criminal action may be brought against any physician, person, or agency who provides the information required herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No report forwarded under the provisions of this section shall be used as evidence in any civil or criminal trial or in any court proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 75-289; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 4, ch. 88-410; s. 2, ch. 89-90; s. 77, ch. 94-306; s. 932, ch. 95-148; s. 155, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>