<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.291" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Driver improvement schools or DUI programs; required in certain suspension and revocation cases.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 322.03(2), any person:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whose driving privilege has been revoked:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon conviction for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Driving, or being in actual physical control of, any vehicle while under the influence of alcoholic beverages, any chemical substance set forth in s. 877.111, or any substance controlled under chapter 893, in violation of s. 316.193;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Driving with an unlawful blood- or breath-alcohol level;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manslaughter resulting from the operation of a motor vehicle;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to stop and render aid as required under the laws of this state in the event of a motor vehicle crash resulting in the death or personal injury of another;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reckless driving; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a habitual offender;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon direction of the court, if the court feels that the seriousness of the offense and the circumstances surrounding the conviction warrant the revocation of the licensee’s driving privilege; or</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whose license was suspended under the point system, was suspended for driving with an unlawful blood-alcohol level of 0.10 percent or higher before January 1, 1994, was suspended for driving with an unlawful blood-alcohol level of 0.08 percent or higher after December 31, 1993, was suspended for a violation of s. 316.193(1), or was suspended for refusing to submit to a lawful breath, blood, or urine test as provided in s. 322.2615</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall, before the driving privilege may be reinstated, present to the department proof of enrollment in a department-approved advanced driver improvement course operating pursuant to s. 318.1451 or a substance abuse education course conducted by a DUI program licensed pursuant to s. 322.292, which shall include a psychosocial evaluation and treatment, if referred. Additionally, for a third or subsequent violation of requirements for installation of an ignition interlock device, a person must complete treatment as determined by a licensed treatment agency following a referral by a DUI program and have the duration of the ignition interlock device requirement extended by at least 1 month up to the time period required to complete treatment. If the person fails to complete such course or evaluation within 90 days after reinstatement, or subsequently fails to complete treatment, if referred, the DUI program shall notify the department of the failure. Upon receipt of the notice, the department shall cancel the offender’s driving privilege, notwithstanding the expiration of the suspension or revocation of the driving privilege. The department may temporarily reinstate the driving privilege upon verification from the DUI program that the offender has completed the education course and evaluation requirement and has reentered and is currently participating in treatment. If the DUI program notifies the department of the second failure to complete treatment, the department shall reinstate the driving privilege only after notice of completion of treatment from the DUI program.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-219; s. 10, ch. 82-155; s. 11, ch. 86-296; s. 6, ch. 91-200; ss. 6, 26, ch. 91-255; ss. 4, 5, ch. 92-195; s. 6, ch. 93-124; s. 10, ch. 95-326; s. 43, ch. 95-333; s. 8, ch. 99-234; s. 293, ch. 99-248; s. 37, ch. 2008-176.</History></Section>