<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.53" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">License required; exemptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2), every person who drives a commercial motor vehicle in this state is required to possess a valid commercial driver’s license issued in accordance with the requirements of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons are exempt from the requirement to obtain a commercial driver license:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drivers of authorized emergency vehicles.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Military personnel driving vehicles operated for military purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Farmers transporting agricultural products, farm supplies, or farm machinery to or from their farms and within 150 miles of their farms, if the vehicle operated under this exemption is not used in the operations of a common or contract motor carrier.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drivers of recreational vehicles, as defined in s. 320.01.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Drivers who operate straight trucks, as defined in s. 316.003, and who are transporting exclusively their own tangible personal property, which is not for sale.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employees of a publicly owned transit system who are limited to moving vehicles for maintenance or parking purposes exclusively within the restricted-access confines of a transit system’s property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding subsection (2), all drivers of for-hire commercial motor vehicles are required to possess a valid commercial driver’s license issued in accordance with the requirements of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resident who is exempt from obtaining a commercial driver’s license pursuant to paragraph (2)(b), paragraph (2)(d), paragraph (2)(e), or paragraph (2)(f) may drive a commercial motor vehicle pursuant to the exemption granted in paragraph (2)(b), paragraph (2)(d), paragraph (2)(e), or paragraph (2)(f) if he or she possesses a valid Class E driver’s license or a military license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules and enter into necessary agreements with other jurisdictions to provide for the operation of commercial vehicles by nonresidents pursuant to the exemption granted in subsection (2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 89-282; s. 23, ch. 94-237; s. 86, ch. 94-306; s. 942, ch. 95-148; s. 27, ch. 96-413; s. 11, ch. 97-280; s. 35, ch. 97-300; s. 88, ch. 2005-164; s. 16, ch. 2012-128; s. 60, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>