<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.283" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Commencement of period of suspension or revocation for incarcerated offenders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the court in a criminal traffic case orders the defendant to serve a term of incarceration or imprisonment and also suspends or revokes the defendant’s driver’s license as a result of the offense, the period of suspension or revocation shall commence upon the defendant’s release from incarceration. For purposes of calculating the defendant’s eligibility for reinstatement of his or her driver’s license or driving privilege under this section, the date of the defendant’s release from incarceration shall be deemed the date the suspension or revocation period was imposed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For defendants convicted of a criminal traffic offense and sentenced to imprisonment with the Department of Corrections, the Department of Corrections shall notify the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles of the date of the defendant’s release from prison or other state correctional facility. For defendants convicted of a criminal traffic offense and sentenced to incarceration within the jurisdictional county jail or other correctional facility operated by the jurisdictional county, the sheriff of the jurisdictional county wherein the defendant is incarcerated shall notify the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles of the date of the defendant’s release from the county jail or other correctional facility. The notification of a defendant’s release from incarceration shall be on a form approved by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles. This subsection applies only to those defendants who have had their driver’s license or driving privilege suspended or revoked as a result of the offense for which they are incarcerated or imprisoned.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 98-223.</History></Section>