<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">License fees; procedure for handling and collecting fees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided herein, the fee for:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An original or renewal commercial driver’s license is $75, which shall include the fee for driver education provided by s. 1003.48. However, if an applicant has completed training and is applying for employment or is currently employed in a public or nonpublic school system that requires the commercial license, the fee is the same as for a Class E driver’s license. A delinquent fee of $15 shall be added for a renewal within 12 months after the license expiration date.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An original Class E driver’s license is $48, which includes the fee for driver’s education provided by s. 1003.48. However, if an applicant has completed training and is applying for employment or is currently employed in a public or nonpublic school system that requires a commercial driver license, the fee is the same as for a Class E license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The renewal or extension of a Class E driver’s license or of a license restricted to motorcycle use only is $48, except that a delinquent fee of $15 shall be added for a renewal or extension made within 12 months after the license expiration date. The fee provided in this paragraph includes the fee for driver’s education provided by s. 1003.48.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An original driver’s license restricted to motorcycle use only is $48, which includes the fee for driver’s education provided by s. 1003.48.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A replacement driver’s license issued pursuant to s. 322.17 is $25. Of this amount $7 shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund and $18 shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund. Beginning July 1, 2015, or upon completion of the transition of driver’s license issuance services, if the replacement driver’s license is issued by the tax collector, the tax collector shall retain the $7 that would otherwise be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund and the remaining revenues shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An original, renewal, or replacement identification card issued pursuant to s. 322.051 is $25. Funds collected from these fees shall be distributed as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For an original identification card issued pursuant to s. 322.051 the fee is $25. This amount shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a renewal identification card issued pursuant to s. 322.051 the fee is $25. Of this amount, $6 shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund and $19 shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a replacement identification card issued pursuant to s. 322.051 the fee is $25. Of this amount, $9 shall be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund and $16 shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund. Beginning July 1, 2015, or upon completion of the transition of the driver’s license issuance services, if the replacement identification card is issued by the tax collector, the tax collector shall retain the $9 that would otherwise be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund and the remaining revenues shall be deposited into the General Revenue Fund.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each endorsement required by s. 322.57 is $7.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hazardous-materials endorsement, as required by s. 322.57(1)(d), shall be set by the department by rule and must reflect the cost of the required criminal history check, including the cost of the state and federal fingerprint check, and the cost to the department of providing and issuing the license. The fee shall not exceed $100. This fee shall be deposited in the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund. The department may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specialty driver license or identification card issued pursuant to s. 322.1415 is $25, which is in addition to other fees required in this section. The fee shall be distributed as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent shall be distributed as provided in s. 320.08058 to the appropriate state or independent university, professional sports team, or branch of the United States Armed Forces.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent shall be distributed to the department for costs directly related to the specialty driver license and identification card program and to defray the costs associated with production enhancements and distribution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the duty of the director of the Division of Motorist Services to set up a division in the department with the necessary personnel to perform the necessary clerical and routine work for the department in issuing and recording applications, licenses, and certificates of eligibility, including the receiving and accounting of all license funds and their payment into the State Treasury, and other incidental clerical work connected with the administration of this chapter. The department may use such electronic, mechanical, or other devices as necessary to accomplish the purposes of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall prepare sufficient forms for certificates of eligibility, applications, notices, and license materials to supply all applicants for driver’s licenses and all renewal licenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department determines from its records or is otherwise satisfied that the holder of a license about to expire is entitled to have it renewed, the department shall mail a renewal notice to the licensee at his or her last known address, within 30 days before the licensee’s birthday. The licensee shall be issued a renewal license, after reexamination, if required, during the 30 days immediately preceding his or her birthday upon presenting a renewal notice, his or her current license, and the fee for renewal to the department at any driver’s license examining office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall collect and transmit all fees received by it under this section to the Chief Financial Officer to be deposited into the General Revenue Fund, and sufficient funds for the necessary expenses of the department shall be included in the appropriations act. The fees shall be used for the maintenance and operation of the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any member of the Armed Forces or his or her spouse, daughter, son, stepdaughter, or stepson, who holds a Florida driver’s license and who presents an affidavit showing that he or she was out of the state due to service in the Armed Forces of the United States at the time of license expiration is exempt from paying the delinquent fee if the application for renewal is made within 15 months after the expiration of his or her license and within 90 days after the date of discharge or transfer to a military or naval establishment in this state as shown in the affidavit. However, such a person is not exempt from any reexamination requirement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any veteran honorably discharged from the Armed Forces who has been issued a valid identification card by the Department of Veterans’ Affairs in accordance with s. 295.17, has been determined by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor to have a 100-percent total and permanent service-connected disability rating for compensation, or has been determined to have a service-connected total and permanent disability rating of 100 percent, is in receipt of disability retirement pay from any branch of the United States Armed Services, and who is qualified to obtain a driver’s license under this chapter is exempt from all fees required by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who applies for reinstatement following the suspension or revocation of the person’s driver’s license must pay a service fee of $45 following a suspension, and $75 following a revocation, which is in addition to the fee for a license. Any person who applies for reinstatement of a commercial driver’s license following the disqualification of the person’s privilege to operate a commercial motor vehicle shall pay a service fee of $75, which is in addition to the fee for a license. The department shall collect all of these fees at the time of reinstatement. The department shall issue proper receipts for such fees and shall promptly transmit all funds received by it as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the $45 fee received from a licensee for reinstatement following a suspension, the department shall deposit $15 in the General Revenue Fund and $30 in the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the $75 fee received from a licensee for reinstatement following a revocation or disqualification, the department shall deposit $35 in the General Revenue Fund and $40 in the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion"><Reference Number="1"/>If the revocation or suspension of the driver’s license was for a violation of s. 316.193, or for refusal to submit to a lawful breath, blood, or urine test, an additional fee of $130 must be charged. However, only one $130 fee may be collected from one person convicted of violations arising out of the same incident. The department shall collect the $130 fee and deposit the fee into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund at the time of reinstatement of the person’s driver’s license, but the fee may not be collected if the suspension or revocation is overturned. If the revocation or suspension of the driver’s license was for a conviction for a violation of s. 817.234(8) or (9) or s. 817.505, an additional fee of $180 is imposed for each offense. The department shall collect and deposit the additional fee into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund at the time of reinstatement of the person’s driver’s license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requesting a review authorized in s. 322.222, s. 322.2615, s. 322.2616, s. 322.27, or s. 322.64 must pay a filing fee of $25 to be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Petitioning the department for a hearing authorized in s. 322.271 must pay a filing fee of $12 to be deposited into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 33, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(647); s. 33, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 1, ch. 22838, s. 7, ch. 22858, 1945; ss. 2, 3, ch. 24346, 1947; s. 51, ch. 26869, 1951; s. 1, ch. 59-314; s. 2, ch. 61-13; s. 3, ch. 67-242; s. 1, ch. 67-306; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 72-211; s. 1, ch. 73-305; s. 4, ch. 75-228; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 202, ch. 81-259; s. 6, ch. 83-71; s. 7, ch. 83-228; s. 3, ch. 84-314; s. 9, ch. 85-81; s. 7, ch. 85-98; s. 15, ch. 87-356; s. 28, ch. 88-290; s. 12, ch. 89-282; ss. 10, 12, ch. 91-243; s. 13, ch. 93-268; s. 80, ch. 94-306; s. 935, ch. 95-148; s. 970, ch. 2002-387; s. 363, ch. 2003-261; s. 4, ch. 2003-410; s. 81, ch. 2005-164; s. 2, ch. 2006-305; s. 35, ch. 2008-176; s. 36, ch. 2009-71; s. 26, ch. 2011-66; s. 56, ch. 2012-181.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph was created as part of subsection (8) by s. 4, ch. 2003-410. Section 36, ch. 2009-71, amended s. 322.21, inserting a new subsection (9) before the paragraph at the end of subsection (8). Subsection (9) relates to payment of filing fees; subsection (8), including this paragraph, relates to reinstatement fees following license suspension or revocation. The editors have restored this paragraph to subsection (8).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>