<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.264" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">“Habitual traffic offender” defined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A “habitual traffic offender” is any person whose record, as maintained by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, shows that such person has accumulated the specified number of convictions for offenses described in subsection (1) or subsection (2) within a 5-year period:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three or more convictions of any one or more of the following offenses arising out of separate acts:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Voluntary or involuntary manslaughter resulting from the operation of a motor vehicle;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of s. 316.193, former s. 316.1931, or former s. 860.01;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is used;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Driving a motor vehicle while his or her license is suspended or revoked;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failing to stop and render aid as required under the laws of this state in the event of a motor vehicle crash resulting in the death or personal injury of another; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Driving a commercial motor vehicle while his or her privilege is disqualified.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifteen convictions for moving traffic offenses for which points may be assessed as set forth in s. 322.27, including those offenses in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any violation of any federal law, any law of another state or country, or any valid ordinance of a municipality or county of another state similar to a statutory prohibition specified in subsection (1) or subsection (2) shall be counted as a violation of such prohibition. In computing the number of convictions, all convictions during the 5 years previous to July 1, 1972, will be used, provided at least one conviction occurs after that date. The fact that previous convictions may have resulted in suspension, revocation, or disqualification under another section does not exempt them from being used for suspension or revocation under this section as a habitual offender.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 72-175; s. 21, ch. 73-331; s. 4, ch. 74-384; s. 8, ch. 84-359; s. 21, ch. 86-296; s. 21, ch. 89-282; ss. 11, 21, ch. 91-255; s. 13, ch. 97-96; s. 291, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>