<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application of minors; responsibility for negligence or misconduct of minor.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of any person under the age of 18 years for a driver’s license must be signed and verified before a person authorized to administer oaths by the father, mother, or guardian; by a secondary guardian if the primary guardian dies before the minor reaches 18 years of age; or, if there is no parent or guardian, by another responsible adult who is willing to assume the obligation imposed under this chapter upon a person signing the application of a minor. This section does not apply to a person under the age of 18 years who is emancipated by marriage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be submitted with each application a certified copy of a United States birth certificate, a valid United States passport, an alien registration receipt card (green card), an employment authorization card issued by the United States Department of Homeland Security, or proof of nonimmigrant classification provided by the United States Department of Homeland Security, for an original license.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any negligence or willful misconduct of a minor under the age of 18 years when driving a motor vehicle upon a highway shall be imputed to the person who has signed the application of such minor for a permit or license, which person shall be jointly and severally liable with such minor for any damages caused by such negligence or willful misconduct.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not issue a driver’s license or learner’s driver’s license to any applicant under the age of 18 years who is not in compliance with the requirements of s. 322.091.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (1) and (2), if a foster parent of a minor who is under the age of 18 years and is in foster care as defined in s. 39.01, an authorized representative of a residential group home at which such a minor resides, or the caseworker at the agency at which the state has placed the minor signs the minor’s application for a learner’s driver’s license, that foster parent, group home representative, or caseworker does not assume any obligation or become liable for any damages caused by the negligence or willful misconduct of the minor by reason of having signed the application. Prior to signing the application, the caseworker shall notify the foster parent or other responsible party of his or her intent to sign and verify the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (1) and (2), a caseworker at the agency at which the state has placed a minor in foster care may sign the minor’s application for a driver’s license pursuant to a court-approved transition plan. Before signing the application, the caseworker shall notify the foster parent or other responsible party of the intent to sign and verify the application. The caseworker does not assume any obligation or become liable for any damages caused by the negligence or willful misconduct of the minor by reason of having signed the application.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 19551, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(635); s. 21, ch. 20451, 1941; s. 1, ch. 29671, 1955; s. 1, ch. 77-373; s. 9, ch. 78-394; ss. 3, 7, ch. 89-112; ss. 3, 4, ch. 93-144; s. 2, ch. 96-414; s. 15, ch. 97-234; s. 75, ch. 99-248; s. 1, ch. 2001-83; s. 29, ch. 2004-5; s. 72, ch. 2005-164; s. 1, ch. 2007-147.</History></Section>