<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0322.251" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of cancellation, suspension, revocation, or disqualification of license.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All orders of cancellation, suspension, revocation, or disqualification issued under the provisions of this chapter, chapter 318, chapter 324, or ss. 627.732-627.734 shall be given either by personal delivery thereof to the licensee whose license is being canceled, suspended, revoked, or disqualified or by deposit in the United States mail in an envelope, first class, postage prepaid, addressed to the licensee at his or her last known mailing address furnished to the department. Such mailing by the department constitutes notification, and any failure by the person to receive the mailed order will not affect or stay the effective date or term of the cancellation, suspension, revocation, or disqualification of the licensee’s driving privilege.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The giving of notice and an order of cancellation, suspension, revocation, or disqualification by mail is complete upon expiration of 20 days after deposit in the United States mail for all notices except those issued under chapter 324 or ss. 627.732–627.734, which are complete 15 days after deposit in the United States mail. Proof of the giving of notice and an order of cancellation, suspension, revocation, or disqualification in either manner shall be made by entry in the records of the department that such notice was given. The entry is admissible in the courts of this state and constitutes sufficient proof that such notice was given.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever the driving privilege is suspended, revoked, or disqualified under the provisions of this chapter, the period of such suspension, revocation, or disqualification shall be indicated on the order of suspension, revocation, or disqualification, and the department shall require the licensee whose driving privilege is suspended, revoked, or disqualified to surrender all licenses then held by him or her to the department. However, should the person fail to surrender such licenses, the suspension, revocation, or disqualification period shall not expire until a period identical to the period for which the driving privilege was suspended, revoked, or disqualified has expired after the date of surrender of the licenses, or the date an affidavit swearing such licenses are lost has been filed with the department. In any instance where the suspension, revocation, or disqualification order is mailed as provided herein, and the license is not surrendered to the department, and such license thereafter expires, the department shall not renew that license until a period of time identical to the period of such suspension, revocation, or disqualification imposed has expired.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose privilege to operate a commercial motor vehicle is temporarily disqualified may, upon surrendering his or her commercial driver’s license, be issued a Class E driver’s license, valid for the length of his or her unexpired commercial driver’s license, at no cost. Such person may, upon the completion of his or her disqualification, be issued a commercial driver’s license, of the type disqualified, for the remainder of his or her unexpired license period. Any such person shall pay the reinstatement fee provided in s. 322.21 before being issued a commercial driver’s license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose privilege to operate a commercial motor vehicle is permanently disqualified may, upon surrendering his or her commercial driver’s license, be issued a Class E driver’s license, if he or she is otherwise qualified to receive such license. Any such person shall be issued a Class E license, valid for the remainder of his or her unexpired license period, at no cost.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a cancellation, suspension, revocation, or disqualification occurs, the department shall enter the cancellation, suspension, revocation, or disqualification order on the licensee’s driver file 20 days after the notice was actually placed in the mail. Any inquiry into the file after the 20-day period shall reveal that the license is canceled, suspended, revoked, or disqualified and whether the license has been received by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person whose driving privilege is suspended or revoked pursuant to s. 832.09 shall be notified, pursuant to this section, and the notification shall direct the person to surrender himself or herself to the sheriff who entered the warrant to satisfy the conditions of the warrant. A person whose driving privilege is suspended or revoked under this subsection shall not have his or her driving privilege reinstated for any reason other than:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full payment of any restitution, court costs, and fees incurred as a result of a warrant or capias being issued pursuant to s. 832.09;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cancellation of the warrant or capias from the Department of Law Enforcement recorded by the entering agency; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment of an additional fee of $10 to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles to be paid into the Highway Safety Operating Trust Fund; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has modified the suspension or revocation of the license pursuant to s. 322.271 restoring the driving privilege solely for business or employment purposes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement shall provide electronic access to the department for the purpose of identifying any person who is the subject of an outstanding warrant or capias for passing worthless bank checks.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 59-278; ss. 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 78-37; s. 1, ch. 80-158; s. 1, ch. 82-20; s. 561, ch. 82-243; s. 1, ch. 84-265; s. 20, ch. 89-282; s. 413, ch. 95-148; s. 3, ch. 98-223; s. 5, ch. 2003-410; s. 84, ch. 2005-164; s. 81, ch. 2010-102; s. 57, ch. 2012-181.</History>
</Section>