<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonresident Violator Compact.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Nonresident Violator Compact, hereinafter called “the compact,” is hereby enacted into law and entered into with all other jurisdictions legally joining therein in the form substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE I</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">FINDINGS, DECLARATION OF POLICY, AND PURPOSE.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) The party jurisdictions find that:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) In most instances, a motorist who is cited for a traffic violation in a jurisdiction other than his or her home jurisdiction must post collateral or bond to secure appearance for trial at a later date or, if unable to post collateral or bond, is taken into custody until the collateral or bond is posted or is taken directly to court for trial to be held. In some instances, the motorist’s driver’s license is deposited as collateral to be returned after he or she has complied with the terms of the citation. The purpose of the practices described is to obviate the difficulty of ensuring compliance with the terms of a traffic citation by the motorist who, if permitted to continue on his or her way after receiving the traffic citation, could return to his or her home jurisdiction and disregard his or her duty under the terms of the traffic citation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) A motorist receiving a traffic citation in his or her home jurisdiction is permitted, except for certain violations, to accept the citation from the officer at the scene of the violation and to immediately continue on his or her way after promising or being instructed to comply with the terms of the citation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The practices described in paragraph (a) cause unnecessary inconvenience and, at times, a hardship for the motorist who is unable at the time to post collateral, furnish a bond, stand trial, or pay the fine and thus is compelled to remain in custody until some arrangement can be made.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) The deposit of a driver’s license as a bail bond, as described in paragraph (a), is viewed with disfavor.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(e) The practices described herein consume an undue amount of law enforcement time.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) It is the policy of the party jurisdictions to:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Seek compliance with the laws, ordinances, and administrative rules and regulations relating to the operation of motor vehicles in each of the jurisdictions.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Allow a motorist to accept a traffic citation for certain violations and to proceed on his or her way without delay whether or not the motorist is a resident of the jurisdiction in which the citation was issued.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) Extend cooperation to its fullest extent among the jurisdictions for obtaining compliance with the terms of a traffic citation issued in one jurisdiction to a resident of another jurisdiction.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(d) Maximize effective utilization of law enforcement personnel and assist court systems in the efficient disposition of traffic violations.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) The purposes of this compact are to:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) Provide a means through which the party jurisdictions may participate in a reciprocal program to effectuate the policies enumerated in subsection (2) in a uniform and orderly manner.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) Provide for the fair and impartial treatment of traffic violators operating within party jurisdictions in recognition of the motorist’s right to due process and the sovereign status of a party jurisdiction.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE II</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">DEFINITIONS.—As used in this compact, the following words have the meanings indicated, unless the context requires otherwise:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) “Jurisdiction” means a state, territory, or possession of the United States; the District of Columbia; the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; or a Canadian province.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) “Citation” means any summons, ticket, or other official document issued by a police officer for a traffic violation, containing an order which requires the motorist to respond.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) “Home jurisdiction” means the jurisdiction which issued the driver’s license of the traffic violator.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) “Driver’s license” means any license or privilege to operate a motor vehicle issued under the laws of the home jurisdiction.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) “Collateral” means any cash or other security deposited to secure an appearance for trial following the issuance by a police officer of a citation for a traffic violation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) “Personal recognizance” means an agreement by a motorist made at the time of the issuance of a traffic citation that he or she will comply with the terms of that traffic citation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(7) “Court” means a court of law or a traffic tribunal.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(8) “Motorist” means a driver of a motor vehicle operating in a party jurisdiction other than the home jurisdiction.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(9) “Issuing jurisdiction” means the jurisdiction in which the traffic citation was issued to the motorist.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(10) “Police officer” means any individual authorized by the party jurisdiction to issue a citation for a traffic violation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(11) “Terms of the citation” means those options expressly stated upon the citation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(12) “Comply with terms of the citation” means to appear in court or pay the fine and costs specified in the citation or to fulfill an obligation arising from any other option expressly stated upon the citation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE III</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">PROCEDURE FOR ISSUING JURISDICTION.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) When issuing a citation for a traffic violation, a police officer shall issue the citation to a motorist who possesses a driver’s license issued by a party jurisdiction and shall not, subject to the exceptions noted in subsection (2) of this Article, require the motorist to post collateral to secure appearance, if the officer receives the motorist’s personal recognizance that he or she will comply with the terms of the citation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) A personal recognizance is acceptable only if not prohibited by law. If a mandatory appearance is required, it should take place immediately following the issuance of the citation.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) Upon the failure of a motorist to comply with the terms of a traffic citation, the appropriate official shall report the failure to comply to the licensing authority of the jurisdiction in which the traffic citation was issued. The report shall be made in accordance with procedures specified by the issuing jurisdiction and shall contain information as specified in the Compact Manual as minimum requirements for effective processing by the home jurisdiction.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) Upon receipt of the report, the licensing authority of the issuing jurisdiction shall transmit to the licensing authority in the home jurisdiction of the motorist the information in a form and content as contained in the Compact Manual.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) The licensing authority of the issuing jurisdiction need not suspend the driving privilege of a motorist for whom a report has been transmitted.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) The licensing authority of the issuing jurisdiction shall not transmit a report on a violation if the date of transmission is more than 6 months after the date on which the traffic citation was issued.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(7) The licensing authority of the issuing jurisdiction shall not transmit a report on a violation if the date of issuance of the citation predates the most recent of the effective dates of entry for the two jurisdictions affected.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE IV</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">PROCEDURE FOR HOME JURISDICTION.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) Upon receipt of a report of a failure to comply from the licensing authority of the issuing jurisdiction, the licensing authority of the home jurisdiction shall notify the motorist and initiate a suspension action, in accordance with the procedures of the home jurisdiction, to suspend the motorist’s driver’s license until satisfactory evidence of compliance with the terms of the traffic citation has been furnished to the licensing authority of the home jurisdiction.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) The licensing authority of the home jurisdiction shall maintain a record of actions taken and make reports to issuing jurisdictions as provided in the Compact Manual.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE V</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">APPLICABILITY OF OTHER LAWS.—Except as expressly required by provisions of this compact, nothing contained herein shall be construed to affect the right of any party jurisdiction to apply any of its other laws relating to licenses to drive to any person or circumstance or to invalidate or prevent any driver license agreement or other cooperative arrangement between a party jurisdiction and a nonparty jurisdiction.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VI</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">COMPACT ADMINISTRATOR PROCEDURES.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) For the purpose of administering the provisions of this compact and to serve as a governing body for the resolution of all matters relating to the operation of this compact, the Board of Compact Administrators is created. The board shall be composed of one representative from each party jurisdiction, to be known as the “compact administrator.” The compact administrator shall be appointed by the executive of the jurisdiction and will serve and be subject to removal in accordance with the laws of the jurisdiction he or she represents. A compact administrator may provide for the discharge of his or her duties and the performance of his or her functions as a board member by an alternate. An alternate may not be entitled to serve unless written notification of his or her identity has been given to the board.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) Each member of the Board of Compact Administrators shall be entitled to one vote. No action of the board shall be binding unless taken at a meeting at which a majority of the total number of votes on the board are cast in favor of such action. Action by the board shall be taken only at a meeting at which a majority of the party jurisdictions are represented.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) The board shall elect annually, from its membership, a chair and a vice chair.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) The board shall adopt bylaws, not inconsistent with the provisions of this compact or the laws of a party jurisdiction, for the conduct of its business and shall have the power to amend and rescind its bylaws.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5) The board may accept for any of its purposes and functions under this compact any and all donations, grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services, conditional or otherwise, from any jurisdiction, the United States, or any other governmental agency and may receive, utilize, and dispose of the same.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) The board may contract with, or accept services or personnel from, any governmental or intergovernmental agency, person, firm, or corporation or any private, nonprofit organization or institution.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(7) The board shall formulate all necessary procedures and develop uniform forms and documents for administering the provisions of this compact. All procedures and forms adopted pursuant to board action shall be contained in the Compact Manual.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">ENTRY INTO COMPACT AND WITHDRAWAL.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) This compact shall become effective when it has been adopted by at least two jurisdictions.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2)(a) Entry into the compact shall be made by a resolution of ratification executed by the authorized officials of the applying jurisdiction and submitted to the chair of the board.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The resolution shall be in a form and content as provided in the Compact Manual and shall include statements that in substance are as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. A citation of the authority by which the jurisdiction is empowered to become a party to this compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. An agreement to comply with the terms and provisions of the compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">3. A statement that compact entry is with all jurisdictions then party to the compact and with any jurisdiction that legally becomes a party to the compact.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) The effective date of entry shall be specified by the applying jurisdiction, but it shall not be less than 60 days after notice has been given by the chair of the Board of Compact Administrators or by the secretariat of the board to each party jurisdiction that the resolution from the applying jurisdiction has been received.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) A party jurisdiction may withdraw from this compact by official written notice to the other party jurisdictions, but a withdrawal shall not take effect until 90 days after notice of withdrawal is given. The notice shall be given to the compact administrator of each member jurisdiction. No withdrawal shall affect the validity of this compact as to the remaining party jurisdictions.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE VIII</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">EXCEPTIONS.—The provisions of this compact shall not apply to parking or standing violations, highway weight limit violations, and violations of law governing the transportation of hazardous materials.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE IX</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">AMENDMENTS TO THE COMPACT.—</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) This compact may be amended from time to time. Amendments shall be presented in resolution form to the chair of the Board of Compact Administrators and may be initiated by one or more party jurisdictions.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) Adoption of an amendment shall require endorsement of all party jurisdictions and shall become effective 30 days after the date of the last endorsement.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) Failure of a party jurisdiction to respond to the compact chair within 120 days after receipt of the proposed amendment shall constitute endorsement.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ARTICLE X</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">CONSTRUCTION AND SEVERABILITY.—This compact shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the purposes stated herein. The provisions of this compact shall be severable; and if any phrase, clause, sentence, or provision of this compact is declared to be contrary to the constitution of any party jurisdiction or of the United States or if the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person, or circumstance is held invalid, the compact shall not be affected thereby. If this compact shall be held contrary to the constitution of any jurisdiction party thereto, the compact shall remain in full force and effect as to the remaining jurisdictions and in full force and effect as to the jurisdiction affected as to all severable matters.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 77-373; s. 2, ch. 81-46; s. 425, ch. 95-148.</History></Section>