<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0322.1615" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Learner’s driver’s license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a learner’s driver’s license to a person who is at least 15 years of age and who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed the written examination for a learner’s driver’s license;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed the vision and hearing examination administered under s. 322.12;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the traffic law and substance abuse education course prescribed in s. 322.095; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets all other requirements set forth in law and by rule of the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When operating a motor vehicle, the holder of a learner’s driver’s license must be accompanied at all times by a driver who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid license to operate the type of vehicle being operated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 21 years of age; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Occupies the closest seat to the right of the driver of the motor vehicle.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who holds a learner’s driver’s license may operate a vehicle only during daylight hours, except that the holder of a learner’s driver’s license may operate a vehicle until 10 p.m. after 3 months following the issuance of the learner’s driver’s license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee who violates subsection (2) or subsection (3) is subject to the civil penalty imposed for a moving violation as set forth in chapter 318.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 96-414; s. 38, ch. 97-300; s. 42, ch. 99-248.</History></Section>