<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0574.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Warehouseman; licenses and fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A warehouseman operating a warehouse for the sale of flue-cured tobacco shall, on or before July 1 of each year, obtain from the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services a state flue-cured tobacco warehouse license for the privilege of operating such warehouse.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant, with an application for license, shall remit a license fee based upon total pounds sold during the previous year on the following scale:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Less than 1,000,000 lbs., $100;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">1,000,000 lbs. and less than 2,000,000 lbs., $200;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">2,000,000 lbs. and less than 3,000,000 lbs., $300;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">3,000,000 lbs. and less than 4,000,000 lbs., $400;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">4,000,000 lbs. and less than 5,000,000 lbs., $500;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">5,000,000 lbs. and less than 6,000,000 lbs., $600;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All in excess of 6,000,000 lbs., $600 and 6 cents per 1,000 lbs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A warehouseman not operating a warehouse the previous year may procure a license by paying the license fee based upon the total estimated pounds that the new warehouseman estimates he or she will market during the complete marketing season.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A new warehouseman operating an old warehouse shall pay license fee based on sales of the preceding year by the previous warehouseman.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fees levied shall be based on official statistical data reported to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services by the United States Department of Agriculture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a prerequisite to the issuance of a license under the provisions of this section, each applicant shall furnish evidence to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services that the applicant has in force a standard fire and extended coverage insurance policy for the full market value of the maximum amount of tobacco contained in his or her sales warehouse at any one time during the marketing season for which the license is sought. The insurance policy shall be written by an insurance company of the warehouseman’s choice authorized to transact business in this state, and such insurance coverage shall be approved in form by the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission, and a copy of the insurance policy shall be filed with the director of the Division of Marketing and Development of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services. The policy shall contain an endorsement requiring notification to the director of the Division of Marketing and Development of the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services by the insurance company at least 10 days prior to cancellation of their intention to cancel the policy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 59-154; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-188; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 4, ch. 83-9; s. 47, ch. 92-291; s. 1, ch. 93-6; s. 906, ch. 97-103; s. 739, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>