<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0177.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Approval of plat by governing bodies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before a plat is offered for recording, it must be approved by the appropriate governing body, and evidence of such approval must be placed on the plat. If not approved, the governing body must return the plat to the professional surveyor and mapper or the legal entity offering the plat for recordation. For the purposes of this part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the plat to be submitted for approval is located wholly within the boundaries of a municipality, the governing body of the municipality has exclusive jurisdiction to approve the plat.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a plat lies wholly within the unincorporated areas of a county, the governing body of the county has exclusive jurisdiction to approve the plat.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a plat lies within the boundaries of more than one governing body, two plats must be prepared and each governing body has exclusive jurisdiction to approve the plat within its boundaries, unless the governing bodies having said jurisdiction agree that one plat is mutually acceptable.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provision in a county charter, or in an ordinance of any charter county or consolidated government chartered under s. 6(e), Art. VIII of the State Constitution, which provision is inconsistent with anything contained in this section shall prevail in such charter county or consolidated government to the extent of any such inconsistency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-339; s. 1, ch. 76-110; s. 1, ch. 77-152; s. 1, ch. 77-278; s. 103, ch. 94-119; s. 1, ch. 95-176; s. 6, ch. 98-20.</History></Section>