<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0177.151" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State plane coordinate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinates may be used to define or designate the position of points on the surface of the earth within the state for land descriptions and subdivision purposes, provided the initial point in the description shall be tied to the nearest government corner or other recorded and well established corner. The state plane coordinates of a point on the earth’s surface, to be used in expressing the position or location of such point in the appropriate projection and zone system, shall consist of two distances, expressed in meters or feet and decimals of the same. One position, to be known as the “Northing,” shall give the position in a north and south direction; the other, to be known as the “Easting,” shall give the position in an east and west direction. These coordinates shall be made to depend upon and conform to the origins and projections on the Florida State Plane Coordinate System and the geodetic control stations of the National Ocean Service within the state, as those origins and projections have been determined by such service. When any tract of land to be defined by a single description extends from one into the other of the above projections or zones, the positions of all points on its boundary may be referred to either of the zones or projections, with the zone and projection being used specifically named in the description.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The position of points on the Florida State Plane Coordinate System shall be as marked on the ground by geodetic control stations established in conformity with standards adopted by the National Ocean Service for first-order and second-order work, the geodetic positions of which have been rigidly adjusted on the North American Datum of 1983, as readjusted in 1990, and the coordinates of which have been computed on the Florida State Plane Coordinate System. Any such station may be used for establishing a survey connection with the Florida State Plane Coordinate System.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 71-339; s. 161, ch. 92-152; s. 106, ch. 94-119; s. 14, ch. 98-20.</History></Section>