<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0747.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Summary procedure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the wife of any person defined as an absentee in s. 747.01(1), or his next of kin if said absentee has no wife, shall wish to sell or transfer any property of the absentee which has a gross value of less than $5,000, or shall require the consent of the absentee in any matter regarding the absentee’s children or in any other matter in which the gross value of the subject matter is less than $5,000, she may apply to the circuit court for an order authorizing said sale, transfer, or consent without opening a full conservatorship proceeding as provided by this chapter. She may make the application without the assistance of an attorney. Said application shall be made by petition on the following form, which form shall be made readily available to the applicant by the clerk of the circuit court:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">In the Circuit Court</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">In re: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Absentee)</Directions>, case number <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">PETITION FOR SUMMARY RELIEF</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Petitioner, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name)</Directions>, whose residence is <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Street &amp; number)</Directions>, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(City or town)</Directions>, and <Directions xml:space="preserve">(County)</Directions>, Florida, and who is the <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Describe relationship to absentee)</Directions> of the absentee, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name)</Directions>, states that the absentee has been <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Imprisoned or missing in action)</Directions> since <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Date)</Directions> when <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Describe details)</Directions>. Petitioner desires to sell/transfer <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Describe property)</Directions> of the value of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Value)</Directions> because <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Give reasons)</Directions>. The terms of sale/transfer are <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Give reasons)</Directions>. Petitioner requires the consent of the absentee for the purpose of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Petitioner)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">State of Florida</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush">County of<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to (or affirmed) and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of person making statement)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public - State of Florida)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Personally Known <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> OR Produced Identification <HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">Type of Identification Produced<HorizontalRule Type="Variable" /></Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall, without hearing or notice, enter an order on said petition if it deems the relief requested in said petition necessary to protect the best interests of the absentee or her or his dependents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such order shall be prima facie evidence of the validity of the proceedings and the authority of the petitioner to make a conveyance or transfer of the property or to give the absentee’s consent in any matter prescribed by subsection (1).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 71-103; s. 32, ch. 73-334; s. 1135, ch. 97-102; s. 19, ch. 98-246.</History></Section>