<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0747.052" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Procedure for order authorizing action by spouse or next of kin.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the spouse, or the next of kin if there is no spouse, of any person defined as an absentee under s. 747.01(1), shall wish to sell, lease, or mortgage specific property having a gross value of $5,000 or more owned by the absentee or in which the absentee had an interest, or take specific action with respect to the absentee’s interest having a gross value of $5,000 or more, he or she may petition the circuit court for an order authorizing the action with respect to such property or interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition shall be sworn to by the petitioner and shall state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names, addresses, and ages of the spouse, children, mother, father, brothers, and sisters, or, if none of these is living, the next of kin, of the absentee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and age of any other person who would have an interest in the property or the estate of the absentee if she or he were deceased;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exact circumstances which cause the person missing to be an absentee under s. 747.01, including the date she or he was first known to be missing, interned, beleaguered, etc.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reasons for the action for which the petition seeks authorization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether or not the person alleged to be an absentee has a will and the whereabouts of said will and contents if known; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of all property constituting an asset of the alleged absentee’s estate or in which she or he has any interest and the approximate value of same.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of the hearing on the petition shall be given to all persons named in the petition by registered mail or certified mail with return receipt requested.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The judge shall hear evidence on the question of whether the person alleged to be missing, interned, beleaguered, etc., is an absentee as defined by s. 747.01 and on the question of whether the action in question should be authorized. Any person interested in such proceedings may intervene with leave of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may in its discretion appoint a guardian ad litem to represent the alleged absentee at the hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, after hearing, the court is satisfied that the person alleged to be an absentee is an absentee as defined in s. 747.01, that the action in question should be authorized, and that there is no necessity for a full conservatorship as provided by s. 747.03, the court shall enter an order appointing the petitioner as conservator for the purposes of the action which is the subject of the petition and authorizing the conservator to take the action requested in the petition. The court shall require the conservator to account for the proceeds of the sale, lease, or other action, but the conservator shall not be required to subject the other property of the absentee to a conservatorship proceeding. The court may retain jurisdiction of the proceeding to make such further orders as it deems proper.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 71-103; s. 1136, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>