<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0747.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petition.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The jurisdiction of the court shall be invoked by the filing of a petition by any person who would have an interest in the property or estate of the absentee were such absentee deceased or any person who is dependent on said absentee for his or her maintenance or support.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition shall be sworn to by the petitioner and shall state:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names, addresses, and ages of the spouse, children, mother, father, brothers, and sisters, or, if none of these is living, the next of kin, of the absentee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and age of any other person who would have an interest in the property or the estate of the absentee if he or she were deceased;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exact circumstances which cause the person missing to be an absentee under s. 747.01 including the date he or she was first known to be missing, interned, beleaguered, etc.;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The necessity for establishing a conservatorship;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether or not the person alleged to be an absentee has a will and the whereabouts of said will; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of all property constituting an asset of the alleged absentee’s estate or in which he or she has any interest and the approximate value of same.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 22888, 1945; s. 5, ch. 71-103; s. 1131, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>