<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0741.0305" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Marriage fee reduction for completion of premarital preparation course.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A man and a woman who intend to apply for a marriage license under s. 741.04 may, together or separately, complete a premarital preparation course of not less than 4 hours. Each individual shall verify completion of the course by filing with the application a valid certificate of completion from the course provider, which certificate shall specify whether the course was completed by personal instruction, videotape instruction, instruction via other electronic medium, or a combination of those methods. All individuals who complete a premarital preparation course pursuant to this section must be issued a certificate of completion at the conclusion of the course by their course provider. Upon furnishing such certificate when applying for a marriage license, the individuals shall have their marriage license fee reduced by $32.50.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The premarital preparation course may include instruction regarding:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conflict management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Communication skills.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children and parenting responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Data compiled from available information relating to problems reported by married couples who seek marital or individual counseling.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All individuals electing to participate in a premarital preparation course shall choose from the following list of qualified instructors:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A psychologist licensed under chapter 490.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A clinical social worker licensed under chapter 491.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A marriage and family therapist licensed under chapter 491.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A mental health counselor licensed under chapter 491.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An official representative of a religious institution which is recognized under s. 496.404(19), if the representative has relevant training.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other provider designated by a judicial circuit, including, but not limited to, school counselors who are certified to offer such courses. Each judicial circuit may establish a roster of area course providers, including those who offer the course on a sliding fee scale or for free.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs of such premarital preparation course shall be paid by the applicant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each premarital preparation course provider shall furnish each participant who completes the course with a certificate of completion specifying the name of the participant and the date of completion and whether the course was conducted by personal instruction, videotape instruction, or instruction via other electronic medium, or by a combination of these methods.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All area course providers shall register with the clerk of the circuit court by filing an affidavit in writing attesting to the provider’s compliance with the premarital preparation course requirements as set forth in this section and including the course instructor’s name and qualifications, including the license number, if any, or, if an official representative of a religious institution, a statement as to relevant training. The affidavit shall also include the addresses where the provider may be contacted.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 98-403; s. 16, ch. 99-307.</History></Section>