<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0741.0306" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of a family law handbook.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based upon their willingness to undertake this project, there shall be created by the Family Law Section of The Florida Bar a handbook explaining those sections of Florida law pertaining to the rights and responsibilities under Florida law of marital partners to each other and to their children, both during a marriage and upon dissolution. The material in the handbook or other suitable electronic media shall be reviewed for accuracy by the Family Court Steering Committee of the Florida Supreme Court prior to publication and distribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such handbooks shall be available from the clerk of the circuit court upon application for a marriage license. The clerks may also make the information in the handbook available on videotape or other electronic media and are encouraged to provide a list of course providers and sites at which marriage and relationship skill-building classes are available.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information contained in the handbook or other electronic media presentation may be reviewed and updated annually, and may include, but need not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prenuptial agreements; as a contract and as an opportunity to structure financial arrangements and other aspects of the marital relationship.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shared parental responsibility for children and the determination of a parenting plan, including a time-sharing schedule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permanent relocation restrictions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Child support for minor children; both parents are obligated for support in accordance with the applicable child support guidelines schedule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property rights, including equitable distribution, premarital property, and nonmarital property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alimony, including temporary, permanent rehabilitative, and lump sum.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Domestic violence and child abuse and neglect, including penalties and other ramifications of false reporting.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Court process for dissolution with or without legal assistance, including who may attend, the recording of proceedings, how to access those records, and the cost of such access.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Parent education course requirements for divorcing parents with children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community resources that are available for separating or divorcing persons and their children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Women’s rights specified in the Battered Women’s Bill of Rights.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The material contained in such a handbook may also be provided through videotape or other suitable electronic media. The information contained in the handbook or other electronic media presentation shall be reviewed and updated annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existing family law handbook shall be reviewed and a report provided to the Legislature by October 1, 2008, or as soon thereafter as practicable, with recommendations for updating the handbook.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 98-403; s. 2, ch. 2008-46; s. 34, ch. 2008-61.</History></Section>