<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0741.405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agency use of designated address.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A program participant may request that state and local agencies or other governmental entities use the address designated by the Attorney General as his or her address. When creating a new public record, state and local agencies or other governmental entities shall accept the address designated by the Attorney General as a program participant’s substitute address, unless the Attorney General has determined that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency or entity has a bona fide statutory or administrative requirement for the use of the address that would otherwise be confidential under ss. 741.401-741.409;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This address will be used only for those statutory and administrative purposes;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency or entity has identified the specific program participant’s record for which the waiver is requested;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency or entity has identified the individuals who will have access to the record; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency or entity has explained how its acceptance of a substitute address will prevent the agency from meeting its obligations under the law and why it cannot meet its statutory or administrative obligation by a change in its internal procedures.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During the review, evaluation, and appeal of an agency’s request, the agency shall accept the use of a program participant’s substitute address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General’s determination to grant or withhold a requested waiver must be based on, but not limited to, an evaluation of information provided under subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Attorney General determines that an agency or entity has a bona fide statutory or administrative need for the actual address and that the information will be used only for that purpose, the Attorney General may issue the actual address to the agency or entity. When granting a waiver, the Attorney General shall notify and require the agency or entity to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain the confidentiality of a program participant’s address information;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limit the use of and access to that address;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designate an address disposition date after which the agency or entity may no longer maintain the record of the address; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with any other provisions and qualifications determined appropriate by the Attorney General.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General’s denial of an agency’s or entity’s waiver request must be made in writing and include a statement of specific reasons for denial. Acceptance or denial of an agency’s or entity’s waiver request shall constitute final agency action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to chapter 120, an agency or entity may appeal the denial of its request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A program participant may use the address designated by the Attorney General as his or her work address.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of the Attorney General shall forward all first class mail to the appropriate program participants at no charge.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 98-404.</History></Section>