<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0741.403" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Address confidentiality program; application; certification.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adult person, a parent or guardian acting on behalf of a minor, or a guardian acting on behalf of a person adjudicated incapacitated under chapter 744 may apply to the Attorney General to have an address designated by the Attorney General serve as the person’s address or the address of the minor or incapacitated person. To the extent possible within funds appropriated for this purpose, the Attorney General shall approve an application if it is filed in the manner and on the form prescribed by the Attorney General and if it contains all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sworn statement by the applicant that the applicant has good reason to believe that the applicant, or the minor or incapacitated person on whose behalf the application is made, is a victim of domestic violence, and that the applicant fears for his or her safety or his or her children’s safety or the safety of the minor or incapacitated person on whose behalf the application is made.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A designation of the Attorney General as agent for purposes of service of process and for the purpose of receipt of mail.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mailing address where the applicant can be contacted by the Attorney General, and the phone number or numbers where the applicant can be called by the Attorney General.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the new address or addresses that the applicant requests must not be disclosed for the reason that disclosure will increase the risk of domestic violence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The signature of the applicant and of any individual or representative of any office designated in writing under s. 741.408 who assisted in the preparation of the application, and the date on which the applicant signed the application.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applications must be filed with the Office of the Attorney General. An application fee may not be charged.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon filing a properly completed application, the Attorney General shall certify the applicant as a program participant. Applicants shall be certified for 4 years following the date of filing unless the certification is withdrawn or invalidated before that date. The Attorney General shall by rule establish a renewal procedure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who falsely attests in an application that disclosure of the applicant’s address would endanger the applicant’s safety or the safety of the applicant’s children or the minor or incapacitated person on whose behalf the application is made, or who knowingly provides false or incorrect information upon making an application, commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who attempts to gain access to a program participant’s actual address through fraud commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly enters the address confidentiality program to evade prosecution of criminal laws or civil liability commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 98-404.</History></Section>