<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0741.2902" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Domestic violence; legislative intent with respect to judiciary’s role.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature, with respect to domestic violence cases, that at the first appearance the court shall consider the safety of the victim, the victim’s children, and any other person who may be in danger if the defendant is released, and exercise caution in releasing defendants.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature, with respect to injunctions for protection against domestic violence, issued pursuant to s. 741.30, that the court shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that the petitioner’s safety may require immediate removal of the respondent from their joint residence and that there can be inherent danger in permitting the respondent partial or periodic access to the residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the parties have a clear understanding of the terms of the injunction, the penalties for failure to comply, and that the parties cannot amend the injunction verbally, in writing, or by invitation to the residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the parties have knowledge of legal rights and remedies including, but not limited to, visitation, child support, retrieving property, counseling, and enforcement or modification of the injunction.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider temporary child support when the pleadings raise the issue and in the absence of other support orders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider supervised visitation, withholding visitation, or other arrangements for visitation that will best protect the child and petitioner from harm.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce, through a civil or criminal contempt proceeding, a violation of an injunction for protection against domestic violence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider requiring the perpetrator to complete a batterers’ intervention program. It is preferred that such program meet the requirements specified in s. 741.325.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 91-210; s. 4, ch. 94-134; s. 4, ch. 94-135; s. 13, ch. 94-170; s. 4, ch. 95-195; s. 11, ch. 2002-55; s. 9, ch. 2012-147.</History>
</Section>