<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0741.29" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Domestic violence; investigation of incidents; notice to victims of legal rights and remedies; reporting.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any law enforcement officer who investigates an alleged incident of domestic violence shall assist the victim to obtain medical treatment if such is required as a result of the alleged incident to which the officer responds. Any law enforcement officer who investigates an alleged incident of domestic violence shall advise the victim of such violence that there is a domestic violence center from which the victim may receive services. The law enforcement officer shall give the victim immediate notice of the legal rights and remedies available on a standard form developed and distributed by the department. As necessary, the department shall revise the Legal Rights and Remedies Notice to Victims to include a general summary of s. 741.30 using simple English as well as Spanish, and shall distribute the notice as a model form to be used by all law enforcement agencies throughout the state. The notice shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resource listing, including telephone number, for the area domestic violence center designated by the Department of Children and Family Services; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the following statement: “IF YOU ARE THE VICTIM OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE, you may ask the state attorney to file a criminal complaint. You also have the right to go to court and file a petition requesting an injunction for protection from domestic violence which may include, but need not be limited to, provisions which restrain the abuser from further acts of abuse; direct the abuser to leave your household; prevent the abuser from entering your residence, school, business, or place of employment; award you custody of your minor child or children; and direct the abuser to pay support to you and the minor children if the abuser has a legal obligation to do so.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a law enforcement officer investigates an allegation that an incident of domestic violence has occurred, the officer shall handle the incident pursuant to the arrest policy provided in s. 901.15(7), and as developed in accordance with subsections (3), (4), and (5). Whether or not an arrest is made, the officer shall make a written police report that is complete and clearly indicates the alleged offense was an incident of domestic violence. Such report shall be given to the officer’s supervisor and filed with the law enforcement agency in a manner that will permit data on domestic violence cases to be compiled. Such report must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of physical injuries observed, if any.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a law enforcement officer decides not to make an arrest or decides to arrest two or more parties, the officer shall include in the report the grounds for not arresting anyone or for arresting two or more parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement which indicates that a copy of the legal rights and remedies notice was given to the victim.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Whenever possible, the law enforcement officer shall obtain a written statement from the victim and witnesses concerning the alleged domestic violence. The officer shall submit the report to the supervisor or other person to whom the employer’s rules or policies require reports of similar allegations of criminal activity to be made. The law enforcement agency shall, without charge, send a copy of the initial police report, as well as any subsequent, supplemental, or related report, which excludes victim/witness statements or other materials that are part of an active criminal investigation and are exempt from disclosure under chapter 119, to the nearest locally certified domestic violence center within 24 hours after the agency’s receipt of the report. The report furnished to the domestic violence center must include a narrative description of the domestic violence incident.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a law enforcement officer determines upon probable cause that an act of domestic violence has been committed within the jurisdiction the officer may arrest the person or persons suspected of its commission and charge such person or persons with the appropriate crime. The decision to arrest and charge shall not require consent of the victim or consideration of the relationship of the parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When complaints are received from two or more parties, the officers shall evaluate each complaint separately to determine whether there is probable cause for arrest.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a law enforcement officer has probable cause to believe that two or more persons have committed a misdemeanor or felony, or if two or more persons make complaints to the officer, the officer shall try to determine who was the primary aggressor. Arrest is the preferred response only with respect to the primary aggressor and not the preferred response with respect to a person who acts in a reasonable manner to protect or defend oneself or another family or household member from domestic violence.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No law enforcement officer shall be held liable, in any civil action, for an arrest based on probable cause, enforcement in good faith of a court order, or service of process in good faith under this chapter arising from an alleged incident of domestic violence brought by any party to the incident.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who willfully violates a condition of pretrial release provided in s. 903.047, when the original arrest was for an act of domestic violence as defined in s. 741.28, commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, and shall be held in custody until his or her first appearance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 84-343; s. 3, ch. 91-210; s. 5, ch. 94-90; s. 2, ch. 94-134; s. 2, ch. 94-135; s. 2, ch. 95-195; s. 1, ch. 97-298; s. 279, ch. 99-8; s. 7, ch. 2000-155.</History></Section>