<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0832.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requiring credit card information for check or draft acceptance prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall require, as a condition of acceptance of a check or share draft or as a means of identification, that the person presenting the check or draft provide a credit card number or credit card expiration date.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recording a credit card number or expiration date in connection with the sale of goods or services in which the purchaser pays by check or share draft, or in connection with the acceptance of a check or share draft, is a noncriminal violation as defined pursuant to s. 775.08 punishable by a fine of $250 for the first violation and $1,000 for the second or subsequent violation in accordance with the provisions of s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not prohibit a person from requesting a purchaser to display a credit card as indicia of credit worthiness and financial responsibility or as additional identification, but the only information concerning a credit card which may be recorded is the type of credit card so displayed and the issuer of the credit card. This section does not require acceptance of a check or share draft whether or not a credit card is presented.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit a person from requesting or receiving a credit card number or expiration date and recording the number or date, or both, in lieu of a deposit to secure payment in the event of default, loss, damage, or other occurrence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit a credit card issuer or a subsidiary of the issuer of a credit card from requesting or receiving a credit card number or expiration date and recording the number or date, or both, for the purpose of establishing identity pursuant to s. 832.07(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit a person from recording a credit card number or expiration date as a condition for cashing a check where that person has agreed with the card issuer to cash checks as a service to the card issuer’s cardholders and the card issuer has agreed to guarantee cardholder checks cashed by that person.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 90-212.</History></Section>