<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0832.06" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prosecution for worthless checks given tax collector for licenses or taxes; refunds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever any person, firm, or corporation violates the provisions of s. 832.05 by drawing, making, uttering, issuing, or delivering to any county tax collector any check, draft, or other written order on any bank or depository for the payment of money or its equivalent for any tag, title, lien, tax (except ad valorem taxes), penalty, or fee relative to a boat, airplane, motor vehicle, driver license, or identification card; any occupational license, beverage license, or sales or use tax; or any hunting or fishing license, the county tax collector, after the exercise of due diligence to locate the person, firm, or corporation which drew, made, uttered, issued, or delivered the check, draft, or other written order for the payment of money, or to collect the same by the exercise of due diligence and prudence, shall swear out a complaint in the proper court against the person, firm, or corporation for the issuance of the worthless check or draft. If the state attorney cannot sign the information due to lack of proof, as determined by the state attorney in good faith, for a prima facie case in court, he or she shall issue a certificate so stating to the tax collector. If payment of the dishonored check, draft, or other written order, together with court costs expended, is not received in full by the county tax collector within 30 days after service of the warrant, 30 days after conviction, or 60 days after the collector swears out the complaint or receives the certificate of the state attorney, whichever is first, the county tax collector shall make a written report to this effect to the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles relative to motor vehicles and vessels, to the Department of Revenue relative to occupational licenses and the sales and use tax, to the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation relative to beverage licenses, or to the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission relative to hunting and fishing licenses, containing a statement of the amount remaining unpaid on the worthless check or draft. If the information is not signed, the certificate of the state attorney is issued, and the written report of the amount remaining unpaid is made, the county tax collector may request the sum be forthwith refunded by the appropriate governmental entity, agency, or department. If a warrant has been issued and served, he or she shall certify to that effect, together with the court costs and amount remaining unpaid on the check. The county tax collector may request that the sum of money certified by him or her be forthwith refunded by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Revenue, the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, or the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission to the county tax collector. Within 30 days after receipt of the request, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Revenue, the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, or the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, upon being satisfied as to the correctness of the certificate of the tax collector, or the report, shall refund to the county tax collector the sums of money so certified or reported. If any officer of any court issuing the warrant is unable to serve it within 60 days after the issuance and delivery of it to the officer for service, the officer shall make a written return to the county tax collector to this effect. Thereafter, the county tax collector may certify that the warrant has been issued and that service has not been had upon the defendant and further certify the amount of the worthless check or draft and the amount of court costs expended by the county tax collector, and the county tax collector may file the certificate with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles relative to motor vehicles and vessels, with the Department of Revenue relative to occupational licenses and the sales and use tax, with the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation relative to beverage licenses, or with the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission relative to hunting and fishing licenses, together with a request that the sums of money so certified be forthwith refunded by the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Revenue, the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, or the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission to the county tax collector, and within 30 days after receipt of the request, the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles, the Department of Revenue, the Division of Alcoholic Beverages and Tobacco of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, or the Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, upon being satisfied as to the correctness of the certificate, shall refund the sums of money so certified to the county tax collector.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this act shall be liberally construed in order to effectively carry out the purposes of this act in the interest of the public.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 63-343; s. 6, ch. 65-190; s. 1, ch. 69-77; ss. 16, 21, 24, 25, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 74-348; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 34, ch. 79-11; s. 250, ch. 94-218; s. 474, ch. 94-356; s. 1304, ch. 97-102; s. 231, ch. 99-245; s. 68, ch. 99-248; s. 30, ch. 2000-197.</History></Section>