<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0197.4155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delinquent personal property taxes; payment program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county tax collector may implement a payment program for the payment of delinquent personal property taxes. If implemented, the tax collector shall require each taxpayer who requests to participate in the program to submit an application on a form prescribed by the tax collector which, at a minimum, must include the name, address, a description of the property subject to personal property taxes, and the amount of the personal property taxes owed by the taxpayer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 days after a taxpayer who owes delinquent personal property taxes submits the required application, the tax collector may prescribe a payment plan for the full payment of the delinquent taxes, including any delinquency charges, interest, and costs allowed by this chapter. The plan must be in writing and must be delivered to the taxpayer after it is prescribed. When the plan is developed, the tax collector may consider a taxpayer’s current and anticipated future ability to pay over the time period of a potential payment plan. The plan must provide that if the taxpayer does not follow the payment terms or fails to timely file returns or pay current obligations after the date of the payment plan, the taxpayer is delinquent, and any unpaid balance of tax, penalty, or interest scheduled in the payment plan will be due and payable immediately. The plan must also provide that unpaid tax amounts bear interest as provided by law. In prescribing a payment plan, the tax collector may exercise flexibility as to the dates, amounts, and number of payments required to collect all delinquent personal property taxes owed, except that the plan must provide for the full satisfaction of all amounts owed by the taxpayer within 3 years after the due date of the first payment under the plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a tax warrant is issued under s. 197.413 against a delinquent taxpayer who is participating in an installment payment plan under this section, the tax warrant is unenforceable as long as the taxpayer is neither delinquent under the terms of the installment payment plan nor attempting to remove or dispose of the personal property that is subject to the tax warrant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the amounts due under the installment payment plan are not paid in full in accordance with the terms of the plan, the tax collector may use all enforcement methods available under the law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 98-167; s. 36, ch. 2011-151.</History>
</Section>