<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1011.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">School depositories; payments into and withdrawals from depositories.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SCHOOL FUNDS TO BE PAID INTO DEPOSITORIES.<EmDash />The tax collector, the clerk of the circuit court, the superintendent, and all other persons having, receiving, or collecting any money payable to the school district shall promptly pay the same to the bank or banks selected by the district school board to receive funds for that purpose. No bank shall be so selected unless it is qualified as an approved depository as provided by law. Each bank receiving any school money as provided herein shall make a receipt for same.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INVESTMENT OF FUNDS DUE.<EmDash />The district school board shall have the authority to designate that funds due it be placed for investment for its account with the State Board of Administration rather than be deposited, and the district school board may direct those persons having moneys due it or due any state school fund to pay out such funds to the State Board of Administration to make authorized investments for its account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FUNDS ON DEPOSIT WITH EACH DEPOSITORY; OVERDRAWING ACCOUNTS PROHIBITED.<EmDash />The district school board shall require an accurate and complete set of accounts to be maintained in the books and records for each fund on deposit in each district school depository. Each such account shall show the amount subject to withdrawal, the amount deposited, the amount expended, and the balance of the account. In compliance with the provisions of this subsection, a district school board may maintain a separate checking account for each such fund or may utilize a single checking account for the deposit and withdrawal of moneys from all funds and segregate the various funds on the books and records only. No check or warrant shall be drawn in excess of the balance to the credit of the appropriate fund. The funds awaiting clearing may be invested in an approved county depository in instruments earning interest, such as repurchase agreements, savings accounts, etc. If repurchase agreements are involved, United States Treasury securities or GNMA’s must be pledged as collateral for an amount to exceed the principal, interest, and a reasonable safety margin for protection against date-to-date price fluctuation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HOW FUNDS DRAWN FROM DEPOSITORIES.<EmDash />All money drawn from any district school depository holding same as prescribed herein shall be upon a check or warrant drawn on authority of the district school board as prescribed by law. Each check or warrant shall be signed by the chair or, in his or her absence, the vice chair of the district school board and countersigned by the district school superintendent, with corporate seal of the school board affixed. However, as a matter of convenience, the corporate seal of the district school board may be printed upon the warrant and a proper record of such warrant shall be maintained. The district school board may by resolution, a copy of which must be delivered to the depository, provide for internal funds to be withdrawn from any district depository by a check duly signed by at least two bonded school employees designated by the board to be responsible for administering such funds. However, the district school superintendent or his or her designee, after having been by resolution specifically authorized by the district school board, may transfer funds from one depository to another, within a depository, to another institution, or from another institution to a depository for investment purposes and may transfer funds to pay expenses, expenditures, or other disbursements that must be evidenced by an invoice or other appropriate documentation in a similar manner. Such transfer may be made by electronic, telephonic, or other medium; and each transfer shall be confirmed in writing and signed by the district school superintendent or his or her designee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FORM OF WARRANTS; DIRECT DEPOSIT OF FUNDS.<EmDash />The district school board is authorized to establish the form or forms of warrants, which are to be signed by the chair or, in his or her absence, the vice chair of the district school board and countersigned by the district school superintendent, for payment or disbursement of moneys out of the school depository and to change the form thereof from time to time as the district school board deems appropriate. If authorized in writing by the payee, such district school board warrants may provide for the direct deposit of funds to the account of the payee in any financial institution that is designated in writing by the payee and that has lawful authority to accept such deposits. The written authorization of the payee must be filed with the district school board. Direct deposit of funds may be by any electronic or other medium approved by the district school board for such purpose. The State Board of Education shall adopt rules prescribing minimum security measures that must be implemented by any district school board before establishing the system authorized in this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTION FOR SELF-INSURANCE PROGRAMS AND THIRD-PARTY ADMINISTERED EMPLOYEES’ FRINGE BENEFIT PROGRAMS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board is authorized to contract with an approved service organization to provide self-insurance services, including, but not limited to, the evaluation, settlement, and payment of self-insurance claims on behalf of the district school board. Pursuant to such contract, the district school board may advance money to the service organization to be deposited in a special checking account for paying claims against the district school board under its self-insurance program. The special checking account shall be maintained in a designated district school depository. The district school board may replenish such account as often as necessary upon the presentation by the service organization of documentation for claims paid equal to the amount of the requested reimbursement. Such replenishment shall be made by a warrant signed by the chair of the district school board and countersigned by the district school superintendent. Such replenishment may be made by electronic, telephonic, or other medium, and each transfer shall be confirmed in writing and signed by the superintendent or his or her designee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board may contract with an insurance company or professional administrator who holds a valid certificate of authority issued by the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission to provide any services that a third-party administrator is authorized by law to perform. Pursuant to such contract, the district school board may advance or remit money to the administrator to be deposited in a designated special checking account for paying claims against the district school board under its self-insurance programs, and remitting premiums to the providers of insured benefits on behalf of the district school board and the participants in such programs, and otherwise fulfilling the obligations imposed upon the administrator by law and the contractual agreements between the district school board and the administrator. The special checking account shall be maintained in a designated district school depository. The district school board may replenish such account as often as necessary upon the presentation by the service organization of documentation for claims or premiums due paid equal to the amount of the requested reimbursement. Such replenishment shall be made by a warrant signed by the chair of the district school board and countersigned by the district school superintendent. Such replenishment may be made by electronic, telephonic, or other medium, and each transfer shall be confirmed in writing and signed by the district school superintendent or his or her designee. The provisions of strict accountability of all funds and an annual audit by an independent certified public accountant as provided in s. 1001.42(12)(k) apply to this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 621, ch. 2002-387; s. 1971, ch. 2003-261; s. 24, ch. 2008-108; s. 26, ch. 2009-59.</History></Section>