<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1011.40" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Budgets for universities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE BUDGET REQUEST.<EmDash />The Board of Governors shall provide instructions, guidelines, and standard formats to be used by each university that will provide to the Board of Governors and the Legislature adequate information to support and justify the legislative budget requests submitted pursuant to ss. 216.023, 1011.90, and 1013.60 for each university.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OPERATING BUDGET.<EmDash />Each university board of trustees shall adopt an operating budget for the operation of the university as prescribed by law and rules of the Board of Governors. Each university president shall prepare and implement the operating budget of the university as prescribed by law, rules of the Board of Governors, policies of the university board of trustees, and provisions of the General Appropriations Act. The proposed expenditures, plus transfers, and balances shall not exceed the estimated income, transfers, and balances. The budget and each part thereof shall balance. If at any time the unencumbered balance in the education and general fund of the university board of trustees approved operating budget goes below 5 percent, the president shall provide written notification to the Board of Governors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXPENDITURES.<EmDash />Expenditures from any source of funds by any university shall not exceed the funds available. Expenditures shall not exceed the amount budgeted under each classification of accounts for each fund and the total amount of the budget, as amended as prescribed by rules of the Board of Governors. No expenditure of funds, contract, or agreement of any nature shall be made that requires additional appropriation of funds by the Legislature unless specifically authorized in advance by law or the General Appropriations Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISTRIBUTION OF APPROPRIATION.<EmDash />Funds appropriated in the General Appropriations Act for the operation of state universities shall be distributed to the universities twice monthly. The Executive Office of the Governor may modify this schedule if required to meet specific needs of a university.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 633, ch. 2002-387; s. 151, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>