<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1011.57" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind; board of trustees; management flexibility.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of ss. 216.031, 216.181, and 216.262 to the contrary and pursuant to the provisions of s. 216.351, but subject to any guidelines imposed in the General Appropriations Act, funds for the operation of the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind shall be requested and appropriated within budget entities, program components, program categories, lump sums, or special categories. Funds appropriated to the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind for each program category, lump sum, or special category may be transferred to traditional categories for expenditure by the board of trustees of the school. The board of trustees shall develop an annual operating budget that allocates funds by program component and traditional expenditure category.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 216.181 and pursuant to the provisions of s. 216.351, but subject to any requirements imposed in the General Appropriations Act, no lump-sum plan is required to implement the special categories, program categories, or lump-sum appropriations. Upon release of the special categories, program categories, or lump-sum appropriations to the board of trustees, the Chief Financial Officer, upon the request of the board of trustees, shall transfer or reallocate funds to or among accounts established for disbursement purposes. The board of trustees shall maintain records to account for the original appropriation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of ss. 216.031, 216.181, 216.251, and 216.262 to the contrary and pursuant to the provisions of s. 216.351, but subject to any requirements imposed in the General Appropriations Act, the board of trustees shall establish the authorized positions and may amend such positions, within the total funds authorized annually in the appropriations act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 216.301 to the contrary, all unexpended funds appropriated for the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind shall be carried forward and included as the balance forward for that fund in the approved operating budget for the following year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees and administration of the Florida School for the Deaf and the Blind shall not authorize fee waivers for out-of-state students.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 651, ch. 2002-387; s. 1973, ch. 2003-261; s. 7, ch. 2004-271; s. 43, ch. 2006-122.</History></Section>