<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1011.60" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimum requirements of the Florida Education Finance Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district which participates in the state appropriations for the Florida Education Finance Program shall provide evidence of its effort to maintain an adequate school program throughout the district and shall meet at least the following requirements:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCOUNTS AND REPORTS.<EmDash />Maintain adequate and accurate records, including a system of internal accounts for individual schools, and file with the Department of Education, in correct and proper form on or before the date due as fixed by law or rule, each annual or periodic report that is required by rules of the State Board of Education.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM TERM.<EmDash />Operate all schools for a term of 180 actual teaching days or the equivalent on an hourly basis as specified by rules of the State Board of Education each school year. The State Board of Education may prescribe procedures for altering, and, upon written application, may alter, this requirement during a national, state, or local emergency as it may apply to an individual school or schools in any district or districts if, in the opinion of the board, it is not feasible to make up lost days or hours, and the apportionment may, at the discretion of the Commissioner of Education and if the board determines that the reduction of school days or hours is caused by the existence of a bona fide emergency, be reduced for such district or districts in proportion to the decrease in the length of term in any such school or schools. A strike, as defined in s. 447.203(6), by employees of the school district may not be considered an emergency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EMPLOYMENT POLICIES.<EmDash />Adopt rules relating to the appointment, promotion, transfer, suspension, and dismissal of personnel.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such rules must conform to applicable law and rules of the State Board of Education and must include the duties and responsibilities of the district school superintendent and school board pertaining to these and other personnel matters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All personnel shall be paid in accordance with payroll period schedules adopted by the school board and included in the official salary schedule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No salary payment shall be paid to any employee in advance of service being rendered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">District school boards may authorize a maximum of six paid legal holidays which shall apply to the total annual number of required days of service adopted by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such rules may include reasonable time for vacation and absences for further professional studies for personnel employed on a 12-month basis.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such rules must not require more than 10 calendar months of service for principals, other school site administrators, and instructional staff, as prescribed by rules of the State Board of Education, excluding Sundays and other holidays. Principals, other school site administrators, and instructional staff may serve more than 10 calendar months of service if specifically approved by the district school board. Contracts for 12 months of service may include reasonable allowance for vacation or further study as prescribed by the school board in accordance with rules of the State Board of Education.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SALARY SCHEDULES.<EmDash />Expend funds for salaries in accordance with a salary schedule or schedules adopted by the school board in accordance with the provisions of law and rules of the State Board of Education. Expenditures for salaries of instructional personnel must include compensation based on employee performance demonstrated under s. 1012.34.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BUDGETS.<EmDash />Observe fully at all times all requirements of law and rules of the State Board of Education relating to the preparation, adoption, and execution of budgets for district school boards.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM FINANCIAL EFFORT REQUIRED.<EmDash />Make the minimum financial effort required for the support of the Florida Education Finance Program as prescribed in the current year’s General Appropriations Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISTRICT EDUCATIONAL PLANNING.<EmDash />Maintain a system of planning and evaluation as required by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MINIMUM CLASSROOM EXPENDITURE REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash />Comply with the minimum classroom expenditure requirements and associated reporting pursuant to s. 1011.64.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 653, ch. 2002-387; s. 169, ch. 2004-5; s. 67, ch. 2004-41; s. 27, ch. 2009-59.</History></Section>