<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1011.801" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Workforce Development Capitalization Incentive Grant Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that the need for school districts and Florida College System institutions to be able to respond to emerging local or statewide economic development needs is critical to the workforce development system. The Workforce Development Capitalization Incentive Grant Program is created to provide grants to school districts and Florida College System institutions on a competitive basis to fund some or all of the costs associated with the creation or expansion of workforce development programs that serve specific employment workforce needs.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds awarded for a workforce development capitalization incentive grant may be used for instructional equipment, laboratory equipment, supplies, personnel, student services, or other expenses associated with the creation or expansion of a workforce development program. Expansion of a program may include either the expansion of enrollments in a program or expansion into new areas of specialization within a program. No grant funds may be used for recurring instructional costs or for institutions’ indirect costs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall accept applications from school districts or Florida College System institutions for workforce development capitalization incentive grants. Applications from school districts or Florida College System institutions shall contain projected enrollments and projected costs for the new or expanded workforce development program. The State Board of Education, in consultation with the Workforce Florida, Inc., shall review and rank each application for a grant according to subsection (3) and shall submit to the Legislature a list in priority order of applications recommended for a grant award.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall give highest priority to programs that train people to enter high-skill, high-wage occupations identified by the Workforce Estimating Conference and other programs approved by Workforce Florida, Inc.; programs that train people to enter occupations under the welfare transition program; or programs that train for the workforce adults who are eligible for public assistance, economically disadvantaged, disabled, not proficient in English, or dislocated workers. The State Board of Education shall consider the statewide geographic dispersion of grant funds in ranking the applications and shall give priority to applications from education agencies that are making maximum use of their workforce development funding by offering high-performing, high-demand programs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 674, ch. 2002-387; s. 175, ch. 2011-5.</History>
</Section>