<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1011.69" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Equity in School-Level Funding Act.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section may be cited as the “Equity in School-Level Funding Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in the 2003-2004 fiscal year, district school boards shall allocate to schools within the district an average of 90 percent of the funds generated by all schools and guarantee that each school receives at least 80 percent of the funds generated by that school based upon the Florida Education Finance Program as provided in s. 1011.62 and the General Appropriations Act, including gross state and local funds, discretionary lottery funds, and funds from the school district’s current operating discretionary millage levy. Total funding for each school shall be recalculated during the year to reflect the revised calculations under the Florida Education Finance Program by the state and the actual weighted full-time equivalent students reported by the school during the full-time equivalent student survey periods designated by the Commissioner of Education. If the district school board is providing programs or services to students funded by federal funds, any eligible students enrolled in the schools in the district shall be provided federal funds.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds allocated to a school pursuant to this section that are unused at the end of the fiscal year shall not revert to the district, but shall remain with the school. These carryforward funds may be used for any purpose provided by law at the discretion of the principal of the school.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following funds are excluded from the school-level allocation under this section: Funds appropriated in the General Appropriations Act for supplemental academic instruction to be used for the purposes described in s. 1011.62(1)(f).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 661, ch. 2002-387; s. 16, ch. 2003-391; s. 32, ch. 2009-59; s. 27, ch. 2010-70.</History>
</Section>