<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1011.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Obligations to eliminate major emergency conditions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board of any district experiencing a major emergency condition in an existing school plant that demands immediate correction in order to prevent further damage to the building or equipment or to eliminate a safety hazard that constitutes an immediate danger to the students and other occupants is authorized to create an obligation for a period of 1 year by way of anticipation of revenues for capital outlay purposes accruing on a current basis without pledging the credit of the district. Such obligation may be extended from year to year with the consent of the lender for a period not to exceed 4 years, or for a total of 5 years including the initial year of the loan. Obligations occurring under this section may be repaid from funds to be received from taxes authorized by s. 1011.71(2) and from any other funds available to the district school board for the purpose under the following conditions:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISTRICT SCHOOL BOARD TO ADOPT PROPOSAL.<EmDash />When the district school board proposes to incur obligations of the nature authorized in this section, it shall adopt and spread upon its minutes a resolution fully describing the emergency condition outlined above, giving the nature of the obligations to be incurred, stating the plan of payment, and providing that such funds will be budgeted during the period of the loan from the current revenue to retire the obligations maturing during the year. This plan of payment shall not extend over a period longer than 1 year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTEREST-BEARING NOTES AUTHORIZED.<EmDash />Each district school board which has authorized the incurring of the obligations as provided in this section shall issue interest-bearing notes for the obligations. The notes shall provide the terms of payment and shall not bear interest in excess of the rate authorized in s. 1010.59.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 618, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>