<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1011.905" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Performance funding for state universities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the 2012-2013 and 2013-2014 fiscal years, the Board of Governors shall review and rank each state university that applies for performance funding based on the following formula:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent of a state university’s score shall be based on the percentage of employed graduates who have earned degrees in the following programs:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Computer and information science;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Computer engineering;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information systems technology;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information technology; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management information systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Twenty-five percent of a state university’s score shall be based on the percentage of graduates who have earned baccalaureate degrees in the programs in paragraph (a) and who have earned industry certifications in a related field from a Florida College System institution or state university prior to graduation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent of a state university’s score shall be based on factors determined by the Board of Governors which relate to increasing the probability that graduates who have earned degrees in the programs described in paragraph (a) will be employed in high-skill, high-wage, and high-demand employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The submission from a state university that has the highest score shall be ranked first, with each remaining submission from a state university ranked sequentially by score.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each year, the Board of Governors shall award up to $15 million to the highest-ranked state universities from funds appropriated for the purposes in this section and as specified in the General Appropriations Act. The award per state university shall be a minimum of 25 percent of the total amount appropriated pursuant to this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds shall be awarded to the department of the state university which offers the degrees described in paragraph (1)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The funds may not be used to supplant funding for the degree programs described in paragraph (1)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By December 31 of each year funds are appropriated for performance funding, the Board of Governors shall submit a report containing the rankings and award distributions to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 2012-195.</History>
</Section>