<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="1011.4106" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trust fund dissolution and local account appropriations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of ss. 215.3206(2) and 215.3208(2), and pursuant to s. 216.351, all unexpended balances as of June 30, 2002, in the following State University System trust funds are hereby appropriated to the appropriate accounts of each university based upon the original source of the trust fund revenue and any accrued interest: the Education/General Student and Other Fees Trust Fund, the Experiment Station Federal Grant Trust Fund, the Experiment Station Incidental Trust Fund, the Extension Service Federal Grant Trust Fund, the Extension Service Incidental Trust Fund, the Incidental Trust Fund, the UF Health Center Operations and Maintenance Trust Fund, the Operations and Maintenance Trust Fund, and all other trust funds in the State Treasury for universities. Expenditure of these funds by each university must be based on the laws, rules, grant agreements, or other legal controlling factors associated with all trust fund balances which are appropriated to local accounts pursuant to this section, and included in each university board of trustees approved operating budget. Each university shall be responsible for the payment of outstanding debts or obligations associated with these funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any appropriations provided in the General Appropriations Act from the Education/General Student and Other Fees Trust Fund are the only budget authority for the fiscal year to the named universities to expend tuition and out-of-state fees that are collected during the fiscal year and carried forward from the prior fiscal year. The expenditure of tuition and fee revenues from local accounts by each university shall not exceed the authority provided in the General Appropriations Act unless approved pursuant to the provisions of chapter 216. If a court of competent jurisdiction finds that the restriction in this subsection is invalid, the moneys described in this section shall be deposited in the State Treasury.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 636, ch. 2002-387; s. 153, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>