<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1011.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Budget system established.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall prepare and submit a coordinated K-20 education annual legislative budget request to the Governor and the Legislature on or before the date provided by the Governor and the Legislature. The board’s legislative budget request must clearly define the needs of school districts, Florida College System institutions, universities, other institutions, organizations, programs, and activities under the supervision of the board and that are assigned by law or the General Appropriations Act to the Department of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be established in each school district and Florida College System institution a budget system as prescribed by law and rules of the State Board of Education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be established in each state university a budget system as prescribed by law and rules of the Board of Governors.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each district school board and each Florida College System institution board of trustees shall prepare, adopt, and submit to the Commissioner of Education an annual operating budget. Operating budgets shall be prepared and submitted in accordance with the provisions of law, rules of the State Board of Education, the General Appropriations Act, and for district school boards in accordance with the provisions of ss. 200.065 and 1011.64.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state university board of trustees shall prepare, adopt, and submit to the Chancellor of the State University System for review an annual operating budget in accordance with provisions of law, rules of the Board of Governors, and the General Appropriations Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education shall coordinate with the Board of Governors to facilitate the budget system requirements of this section. The Board of Governors exclusively retains the review and approval powers of this section for state universities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 601, ch. 2002-387; s. 149, ch. 2007-217; s. 164, ch. 2011-5; s. 30, ch. 2011-175.</History>
</Section>