<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="1011.32" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida College System Institution Facility Enhancement Challenge Grant Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that the Florida College System institutions do not have sufficient physical facilities to meet the current demands of their instructional and community programs. It further recognizes that, to strengthen and enhance Florida College System institutions, it is necessary to provide facilities in addition to those currently available from existing revenue sources. It further recognizes that there are sources of private support that, if matched with state support, can assist in constructing much needed facilities and strengthen the commitment of citizens and organizations in promoting excellence at each Florida College System institution. Therefore, it is the intent of the Legislature to establish a program to provide the opportunity for each Florida College System institution through its direct-support organization to receive and match challenge grants for instructional and community-related capital facilities within the Florida College System institution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established the Florida College System Institution Facility Enhancement Challenge Grant Program for the purpose of assisting the Florida College System institutions in building high priority instructional and community-related capital facilities consistent with s. 1004.65, including common areas connecting such facilities. The direct-support organizations that serve the Florida College System institutions shall solicit gifts from private sources to provide matching funds for capital facilities. For the purposes of this section, private sources of funds shall not include any federal or state government funds that a Florida College System institution may receive.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida College System Institution Capital Facilities Matching Program shall provide funds to match private contributions for the development of high priority instructional and community-related capital facilities, including common areas connecting such facilities, within the Florida College System institutions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within the direct-support organization of each Florida College System institution there must be established a separate capital facilities matching account for the purpose of providing matching funds from the direct-support organization’s unrestricted donations or other private contributions for the development of high priority instructional and community-related capital facilities, including common areas connecting such facilities. The Legislature shall appropriate funds for distribution to a Florida College System institution after matching funds are certified by the direct-support organization and Florida College System institution. The Public Education Capital Outlay and Debt Service Trust Fund shall not be used as the source of the state match for private contributions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A project may not be initiated unless all private funds for planning, construction, and equipping the facility have been received and deposited in the direct-support organization’s matching account for this purpose. However, this requirement does not preclude the Florida College System institution or direct-support organization from expending available funds from private sources to develop a prospectus, including preliminary architectural schematics or models, for use in its efforts to raise private funds for a facility and for site preparation, planning, and construction. The Legislature may appropriate the state’s matching funds in one or more fiscal years for the planning, construction, and equipping of an eligible facility. Each Florida College System institution shall notify all donors of private funds of a substantial delay in the availability of state matching funds for this program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible to participate in the Florida College System Institution Facility Enhancement Challenge Grant Program, a Florida College System institution, through its direct-support organization, shall raise a contribution equal to one-half of the total cost of a facilities construction project from private sources which shall be matched by a state appropriation equal to the amount raised for a facilities construction project, subject to the General Appropriations Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the state’s share of the required match is insufficient to meet the requirements of subsection (6), the Florida College System institution shall renegotiate the terms of the contribution with the donors. If the project is terminated, each private donation, plus accrued interest, reverts to the direct-support organization for remittance to the donor.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By October 15 of each year, the State Board of Education shall transmit to the Governor and the Legislature a list of projects that meet all eligibility requirements to participate in the Florida College System Institution Facility Enhancement Challenge Grant Program and a budget request that includes the recommended schedule necessary to complete each project.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order for a project to be eligible under this program, it must be survey recommended under the provisions of s. 1013.31 and included in the Florida College System institution’s 5-year capital improvement plan, and it must receive approval from the State Board of Education or the Legislature.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A Florida College System institution project may not be removed from the approved 3-year PECO priority list because of its successful participation in this program until approved by the Legislature and provided for in the General Appropriations Act. When such a project is completed and removed from the list, all other projects shall move up on the 3-year PECO priority list.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any private matching funds for a project which are unexpended after the project is completed shall revert to the Florida College System institution’s direct-support organization capital facilities matching account. The balance of any unexpended state matching funds shall be returned to the fund from which those funds were appropriated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surveys, architectural plans, facility, and equipment shall be the property of the participating Florida College System institution. A facility constructed under this section may be named in honor of a donor at the option of the Florida College System institution district board of trustees. A facility may not be named after a living person without prior approval by the State Board of Education.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 2011, state matching funds are temporarily suspended for donations received for the program on or after June 30, 2011. Existing eligible donations remain eligible for future matching funds. The program may be restarted after $200 million of the backlog for programs under this section and ss. 1011.85, 1011.94, and 1013.79 have been matched.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 631, ch. 2002-387; s. 1, ch. 2007-61; s. 29, ch. 2009-60; s. 179, ch. 2010-102; s. 23, ch. 2010-155; s. 169, ch. 2011-5; s. 33, ch. 2011-63.</History>
</Section>