<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.85" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Residents’ bill of rights.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resident of an adult family-care home may not be deprived of any civil or legal rights, benefits, or privileges guaranteed by law, the State Constitution, or the Constitution of the United States solely by reason of status as a resident of the home. Each resident has the right to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Live in a safe and decent living environment, free from abuse and neglect.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be treated with consideration and respect and with due recognition of personal dignity, individuality, and privacy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Keep and use the resident’s own clothes and other personal property in the resident’s immediate living quarters, so as to maintain individuality and personal dignity, except when the provider can demonstrate that to do so would be unsafe or an infringement upon the rights of other residents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have unrestricted private communication, including receiving and sending unopened correspondence, having access to a telephone, and visiting with any person of his or her choice, at any time between the hours of 9 a.m. and 9 p.m. at a minimum.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be free to participate in and benefit from community services and activities and to achieve the highest possible level of independence, autonomy, and interaction within the community.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manage the resident’s own financial affairs unless the resident or the resident’s guardian authorizes the provider to provide safekeeping for funds in accordance with procedures equivalent to those provided in s. 429.27.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Share a room with the resident’s spouse if both are residents of the home.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have reasonable opportunity for regular exercise several times a week and to be outdoors at regular and frequent intervals.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise civil and religious liberties, including the right to independent personal decisions. Religious beliefs or practices and attendance at religious services may not be imposed upon a resident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have access to adequate and appropriate health care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be free from chemical and physical restraints.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have at least 30 days’ notice of relocation or termination of residency from the home unless, for medical reasons, the resident is certified by a physician to require an emergency relocation to a facility providing a more skilled level of care or the resident engages in a pattern of conduct that is harmful or offensive to other residents. If a resident has been adjudicated mentally incompetent, the resident’s guardian must be given at least 30 days’ notice, except in an emergency, of the relocation of a resident or of the termination of a residency. The reasons for relocating a resident must be set forth in writing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Present grievances and recommend changes to the provider, to staff, or to any other person without restraint, interference, coercion, discrimination, or reprisal. This right includes the right to have access to ombudsman volunteers and advocates and the right to be a member of, to be active in, and to associate with advocacy or special interest groups.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provider shall ensure that residents and their legal representatives are made aware of the rights, obligations, and prohibitions set forth in this part. Residents must also be given the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of the local ombudsman council and the central abuse hotline where they may lodge complaints.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adult family-care home may not hamper or prevent residents from exercising the rights specified in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider or staff of an adult family-care home may not serve notice upon a resident to leave the premises or take any other retaliatory action against any person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercises any right set forth in this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appears as a witness in any hearing, in or out of the adult family-care home.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Files a civil action alleging a violation of this part or notifies a state attorney or the Attorney General of a possible violation of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any adult family-care home that terminates the residency of an individual who has participated in activities specified in subsection (4) must show good cause for the termination in a court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who reports a complaint concerning a suspected violation of this part or the services and conditions in an adult family-care home, or who testifies in any administrative or judicial proceeding arising from such a complaint, is immune from any civil or criminal liability therefor, unless the person acted in bad faith or with malicious purpose or the court finds that there was a complete absence of a justiciable issue of either law or fact raised by the losing party.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 93-209; s. 790, ch. 95-148; s. 6, ch. 97-82; s. 12, ch. 98-338; ss. 84, 148, ch. 2000-349; s. 68, ch. 2000-367; ss. 3, 67, ch. 2006-197.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.628.</Text></Note></Section>