<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.256" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assistance with self-administration of medication.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Informed consent” means advising the resident, or the resident’s surrogate, guardian, or attorney in fact, that an assisted living facility is not required to have a licensed nurse on staff, that the resident may be receiving assistance with self-administration of medication from an unlicensed person, and that such assistance, if provided by an unlicensed person, will or will not be overseen by a licensed nurse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Unlicensed person” means an individual not currently licensed to practice nursing or medicine who is employed by or under contract to an assisted living facility and who has received training with respect to assisting with the self-administration of medication in an assisted living facility as provided under s. 429.52 prior to providing such assistance as described in this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residents who are capable of self-administering their own medications without assistance shall be encouraged and allowed to do so. However, an unlicensed person may, consistent with a dispensed prescription’s label or the package directions of an over-the-counter medication, assist a resident whose condition is medically stable with the self-administration of routine, regularly scheduled medications that are intended to be self-administered. Assistance with self-medication by an unlicensed person may occur only upon a documented request by, and the written informed consent of, a resident or the resident’s surrogate, guardian, or attorney in fact. For the purposes of this section, self-administered medications include both legend and over-the-counter oral dosage forms, topical dosage forms and topical ophthalmic, otic, and nasal dosage forms including solutions, suspensions, sprays, and inhalers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assistance with self-administration of medication includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taking the medication, in its previously dispensed, properly labeled container, from where it is stored, and bringing it to the resident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the presence of the resident, reading the label, opening the container, removing a prescribed amount of medication from the container, and closing the container.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Placing an oral dosage in the resident’s hand or placing the dosage in another container and helping the resident by lifting the container to his or her mouth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applying topical medications.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Returning the medication container to proper storage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Keeping a record of when a resident receives assistance with self-administration under this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assistance with self-administration does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mixing, compounding, converting, or calculating medication doses, except for measuring a prescribed amount of liquid medication or breaking a scored tablet or crushing a tablet as prescribed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preparation of syringes for injection or the administration of medications by any injectable route.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration of medications through intermittent positive pressure breathing machines or a nebulizer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration of medications by way of a tube inserted in a cavity of the body.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration of parenteral preparations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Irrigations or debriding agents used in the treatment of a skin condition.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rectal, urethral, or vaginal preparations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medications ordered by the physician or health care professional with prescriptive authority to be given “as needed,” unless the order is written with specific parameters that preclude independent judgment on the part of the unlicensed person, and at the request of a competent resident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medications for which the time of administration, the amount, the strength of dosage, the method of administration, or the reason for administration requires judgment or discretion on the part of the unlicensed person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assistance with the self-administration of medication by an unlicensed person as described in this section shall not be considered administration as defined in s. 465.003.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may by rule establish facility procedures and interpret terms as necessary to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 98-80; s. 214, ch. 99-13; ss. 2, 48, ch. 2006-197.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.4256.</Text></Note></Section>