<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0429.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administrative penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of part II of chapter 408, the agency may deny, revoke, and suspend any license issued under this part and impose an administrative fine in the manner provided in chapter 120 against a licensee for a violation of any provision of this part, part II of chapter 408, or applicable rules, or for any of the following actions by a licensee, for the actions of any person subject to level 2 background screening under s. 408.809, or for the actions of any facility employee:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intentional or negligent act seriously affecting the health, safety, or welfare of a resident of the facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The determination by the agency that the owner lacks the financial ability to provide continuing adequate care to residents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misappropriation or conversion of the property of a resident of the facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to follow the criteria and procedures provided under part I of chapter 394 relating to the transportation, voluntary admission, and involuntary examination of a facility resident.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A citation of any of the following deficiencies as specified in s. 429.19:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more cited class I deficiencies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three or more cited class II deficiencies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five or more cited class III deficiencies that have been cited on a single survey and have not been corrected within the times specified.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with the background screening standards of this part, s. 408.809(1), or chapter 435.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of a moratorium.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the license applicant, the licensee during relicensure, or a licensee that holds a provisional license to meet the minimum license requirements of this part, or related rules, at the time of license application or renewal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intentional or negligent life-threatening act in violation of the uniform firesafety standards for assisted living facilities or other firesafety standards that threatens the health, safety, or welfare of a resident of a facility, as communicated to the agency by the local authority having jurisdiction or the State Fire Marshal.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly operating any unlicensed facility or providing without a license any service that must be licensed under this chapter or chapter 400.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any act constituting a ground upon which application for a license may be denied.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon notification by the local authority having jurisdiction or by the State Fire Marshal, the agency may deny or revoke the license of an assisted living facility that fails to correct cited fire code violations that affect or threaten the health, safety, or welfare of a resident of a facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may deny a license to any applicant or controlling interest as defined in part II of chapter 408 which has or had a 25-percent or greater financial or ownership interest in any other facility licensed under this part, or in any entity licensed by this state or another state to provide health or residential care, which facility or entity during the 5 years prior to the application for a license closed due to financial inability to operate; had a receiver appointed or a license denied, suspended, or revoked; was subject to a moratorium; or had an injunctive proceeding initiated against it.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall deny or revoke the license of an assisted living facility that has two or more class I violations that are similar or identical to violations identified by the agency during a survey, inspection, monitoring visit, or complaint investigation occurring within the previous 2 years.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action taken by the agency to suspend, deny, or revoke a facility’s license under this part or part II of chapter 408, in which the agency claims that the facility owner or an employee of the facility has threatened the health, safety, or welfare of a resident of the <Reference Number="1" />facility be heard by the Division of Administrative Hearings of the Department of Management Services within 120 days after receipt of the facility’s request for a hearing, unless that time limitation is waived by both parties. The administrative law judge must render a decision within 30 days after receipt of a proposed recommended order.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall provide to the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, on a monthly basis, a list of those assisted living facilities that have had their licenses denied, suspended, or revoked or that are involved in an appellate proceeding pursuant to s. 120.60 related to the denial, suspension, or revocation of a license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agency notification of a license suspension or revocation, or denial of a license renewal, shall be posted and visible to the public at the facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 75-233; ss. 12, 18, ch. 80-198; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 46, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 8, ch. 87-371; s. 13, ch. 89-294; s. 30, ch. 91-71; s. 46, ch. 92-58; ss. 8, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 50, ch. 94-218; s. 39, ch. 95-228; s. 7, ch. 95-418; s. 38, ch. 96-169; s. 126, ch. 96-410; s. 7, ch. 98-80; s. 43, ch. 98-171; s. 73, ch. 2000-349; s. 34, ch. 2001-45; s. 19, ch. 2003-57; s. 13, ch. 2004-267; ss. 2, 36, ch. 2006-197; s. 144, ch. 2007-230; s. 61, ch. 2009-223; s. 28, ch. 2010-114.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The words “facility be heard” are as enacted by s. 43, ch. 98-171.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.414.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>