<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0429.67" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this part and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to this part. A license issued by the agency is required in order to operate an adult family-care home in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who intends to be an adult family-care home provider must own or rent the adult family-care home that is to be licensed and reside therein.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. The amount of the fee shall be $200 per biennium.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"> The agency shall require level 2 background screening for personnel as required in s. 408.809(1)(e), including the adult family-care home provider, the designated relief person, and all adult household members, pursuant to chapter 435 and s. 408.809.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the adult family-care home is a community residential home subject to chapter 419, the applicant must provide documentation, signed by the appropriate governmental official, that the home has met local zoning requirements for the location for which the license is sought.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of s. 408.811, access to a licensed adult family-care home must be provided at reasonable times for the appropriate officials of the department, the Department of Health, the Department of Children and Family Services, the agency, and the State Fire Marshal, who are responsible for the development and maintenance of fire, health, sanitary, and safety standards, to inspect the facility to assure compliance with these standards. In addition, access to a licensed adult family-care home must be provided at reasonable times for the local long-term care ombudsman council.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensed maximum capacity of each adult family-care home is based on the service needs of the residents and the capability of the provider to meet the needs of the residents. Any relative who lives in the adult family-care home and who is a disabled adult or frail elder must be included in that limitation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each adult family-care home must designate at least one licensed space for a resident receiving optional state supplementation. The Department of Children and Family Services shall specify by rule the procedures to be followed for referring residents who receive optional state supplementation to adult family-care homes. Those homes licensed as adult foster homes or assisted living facilities prior to January 1, 1994, that convert to adult family-care homes, are exempt from this requirement.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the license categories available in s. 408.808, the agency may issue a conditional license to a provider for the purpose of bringing the adult family-care home into compliance with licensure requirements. A conditional license must be limited to a specific period, not exceeding 6 months. The department shall, by rule, establish criteria for issuing conditional licenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules to establish procedures, identify forms, specify documentation, and clarify terms, as necessary, to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may adopt rules to administer the requirements of part II of chapter 408.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-195; s. 38, ch. 87-225; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 93-209; s. 23, ch. 95-210; ss. 62, 130, ch. 95-418; s. 8, ch. 98-148; ss. 57, 71, ch. 98-171; s. 4, ch. 98-338; s. 147, ch. 2000-349; s. 67, ch. 2000-367; s. 25, ch. 2001-53; s. 2, ch. 2001-67; s. 148, ch. 2001-277; s. 28, ch. 2003-57; s. 25, ch. 2004-267; s. 8, ch. 2004-298; s. 3, ch. 2006-197; s. 160, ch. 2007-230; s. 30, ch. 2010-114.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.619.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>