<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.63" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative intent; purpose.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature encourages the provision of care for disabled adults and frail elders in family-type living arrangements in private homes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult family-care homes provide housing and personal care for disabled adults and frail elders who choose to live with an individual or family in a private home. The adult family-care home provider must live in the home. The purpose of this part is to provide for the health, safety, and welfare of residents of adult family-care homes in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that adult family-care homes are an important part of the continuum of long-term care. The personal care available in these homes, which may be provided directly or through contract or agreement, is intended to help residents remain as independent as possible in order to delay or avoid placement in a nursing home or other institution. Regulations governing adult family-care homes must be sufficiently flexible to allow residents to age in place if resources are available to meet their needs and accommodate their preferences.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature further finds and declares that licensure under this part is a public trust and a privilege, and not an entitlement. This principle must guide the finder of fact or trier of law at any administrative proceeding or circuit court action initiated by the department to enforce this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rules of the department relating to adult family-care homes shall be as minimal and flexible as possible to ensure the protection of residents while minimizing the obstacles that could inhibit the establishment of adult family-care homes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-195; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-209; s. 2, ch. 98-338; s. 3, ch. 2006-197.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.617.</Text></Note></Section>