<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.52" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Staff training and educational programs; core educational requirement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrators and other assisted living facility staff must meet minimum training and education requirements established by the Department of Elderly Affairs by rule. This training and education is intended to assist facilities to appropriately respond to the needs of residents, to maintain resident care and facility standards, and to meet licensure requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a competency test and a minimum required score to indicate successful completion of the training and educational requirements. The competency test must be developed by the department in conjunction with the agency and providers. The required training and education must cover at least the following topics:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State law and rules relating to assisted living facilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resident rights and identifying and reporting abuse, neglect, and exploitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special needs of elderly persons, persons with mental illness, and persons with developmental disabilities and how to meet those needs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nutrition and food service, including acceptable sanitation practices for preparing, storing, and serving food.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medication management, recordkeeping, and proper techniques for assisting residents with self-administered medication.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Firesafety requirements, including fire evacuation drill procedures and other emergency procedures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Care of persons with Alzheimer’s disease and related disorders.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective January 1, 2004, a new facility administrator must complete the required training and education, including the competency test, within a reasonable time after being employed as an administrator, as determined by the department. Failure to do so is a violation of this part and subjects the violator to an administrative fine as prescribed in s. 429.19. Administrators licensed in accordance with part II of chapter 468 are exempt from this requirement. Other licensed professionals may be exempted, as determined by the department by rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrators are required to participate in continuing education for a minimum of 12 contact hours every 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Staff involved with the management of medications and assisting with the self-administration of medications under s. 429.256 must complete a minimum of 4 additional hours of training provided by a registered nurse, licensed pharmacist, or department staff. The department shall establish by rule the minimum requirements of this additional training.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other facility staff shall participate in training relevant to their job duties as specified by rule of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department or the agency determines that there are problems in a facility that could be reduced through specific staff training or education beyond that already required under this section, the department or the agency may require, and provide, or cause to be provided, the training or education of any personal care staff in the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules related to these training requirements, the competency test, necessary procedures, and competency test fees and shall adopt or contract with another entity to develop a curriculum, which shall be used as the minimum core training requirements. The department shall consult with representatives of stakeholder associations and agencies in the development of the curriculum.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The training required by this section shall be conducted by persons registered with the department as having the requisite experience and credentials to conduct the training. A person seeking to register as a trainer must provide the department with proof of completion of the minimum core training education requirements, successful passage of the competency test established under this section, and proof of compliance with the continuing education requirement in subsection (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person seeking to register as a trainer must also:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide proof of completion of a 4-year degree from an accredited college or university and must have worked in a management position in an assisted living facility for 3 years after being core certified;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have worked in a management position in an assisted living facility for 5 years after being core certified and have 1 year of teaching experience as an educator or staff trainer for persons who work in assisted living facilities or other long-term care settings;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have been previously employed as a core trainer for the department; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meet other qualification criteria as defined in rule, which the department is authorized to adopt.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules to establish trainer registration requirements.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 34, ch. 80-198; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 60, 75, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 53, ch. 83-218; s. 3, ch. 85-251; s. 21, ch. 89-294; s. 27, ch. 91-263; ss. 33, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 19, ch. 95-210; ss. 15, 26, 53, ch. 95-418; s. 16, ch. 97-82; s. 29, ch. 97-100; s. 19, ch. 98-80; s. 25, ch. 2003-57; s. 3, ch. 2003-405; ss. 2, 59, ch. 2006-197; s. 1, ch. 2007-219.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.452.</Text></Note></Section>