<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Facilities to be licensed; exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the administration of this part, facilities to be licensed by the agency shall include all assisted living facilities as defined in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from licensure under this part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility, institution, or other place operated by the Federal Government or any agency of the Federal Government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility or part of a facility licensed under chapter 393 or chapter 394.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility licensed as an adult family-care home under part II.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who provides housing, meals, and one or more personal services on a 24-hour basis in the person’s own home to not more than two adults who do not receive optional state supplementation. The person who provides the housing, meals, and personal services must own or rent the home and reside therein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any home or facility approved by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs as a residential care home wherein care is provided exclusively to three or fewer veterans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility that has been incorporated in this state for 50 years or more on or before July 1, 1983, and the board of directors of which is nominated or elected by the residents, until the facility is sold or its ownership is transferred; or any facility, with improvements or additions thereto, which has existed and operated continuously in this state for 60 years or more on or before July 1, 1989, is directly or indirectly owned and operated by a nationally recognized fraternal organization, is not open to the public, and accepts only its own members and their spouses as residents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility certified under chapter 651, or a retirement community, may provide services authorized under this part or part III of chapter 400 to its residents who live in single-family homes, duplexes, quadruplexes, or apartments located on the campus without obtaining a license to operate an assisted living facility if residential units within such buildings are used by residents who do not require staff supervision for that portion of the day when personal services are not being delivered and the owner obtains a home health license to provide such services. However, any building or distinct part of a building on the campus that is designated for persons who receive personal services and require supervision beyond that which is available while such services are being rendered must be licensed in accordance with this part. If a facility provides personal services to residents who do not otherwise require supervision and the owner is not licensed as a home health agency, the buildings or distinct parts of buildings where such services are rendered must be licensed under this part. A resident of a facility that obtains a home health license may contract with a home health agency of his or her choice, provided that the home health agency provides liability insurance and workers’ compensation coverage for its employees. Facilities covered by this exemption may establish policies that give residents the option of contracting for services and care beyond that which is provided by the facility to enable them to age in place. For purposes of this section, a retirement community consists of a facility licensed under this part or under part II of chapter 400, and apartments designed for independent living located on the same campus.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any residential unit for independent living which is located within a facility certified under chapter 651, or any residential unit which is colocated with a nursing home licensed under part II of chapter 400 or colocated with a facility licensed under this part in which services are provided through an outpatient clinic or a nursing home on an outpatient basis.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 5, ch. 75-233; ss. 12, 15, ch. 80-198; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 42, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 4, ch. 87-371; s. 4, ch. 91-263; ss. 3, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 19, ch. 93-268; s. 2, ch. 94-206; s. 1055, ch. 95-148; s. 8, ch. 95-210; s. 2, ch. 98-80; s. 1, ch. 98-148; ss. 2, 30, ch. 2006-197.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.404.</Text></Note></Section>