<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Internal risk management and quality assurance program; adverse incidents and reporting requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every facility licensed under this part may, as part of its administrative functions, voluntarily establish a risk management and quality assurance program, the purpose of which is to assess resident care practices, facility incident reports, deficiencies cited by the agency, adverse incident reports, and resident grievances and develop plans of action to correct and respond quickly to identify quality differences.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every facility licensed under this part is required to maintain adverse incident reports. For purposes of this section, the term, “adverse incident” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An event over which facility personnel could exercise control rather than as a result of the resident’s condition and results in:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Death;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Brain or spinal damage;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permanent disfigurement;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fracture or dislocation of bones or joints;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any condition that required medical attention to which the resident has not given his or her consent, including failure to honor advanced directives;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any condition that requires the transfer of the resident from the facility to a unit providing more acute care due to the incident rather than the resident’s condition before the incident; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An event that is reported to law enforcement or its personnel for investigation; or</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resident elopement, if the elopement places the resident at risk of harm or injury.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed facilities shall provide within 1 business day after the occurrence of an adverse incident, by electronic mail, facsimile, or United States mail, a preliminary report to the agency on all adverse incidents specified under this section. The report must include information regarding the identity of the affected resident, the type of adverse incident, and the status of the facility’s investigation of the incident.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed facilities shall provide within 15 days, by electronic mail, facsimile, or United States mail, a full report to the agency on all adverse incidents specified in this section. The report must include the results of the facility’s investigation into the adverse incident.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each facility shall report monthly to the agency any liability claim filed against it. The report must include the name of the resident, the dates of the incident leading to the claim, if applicable, and the type of injury or violation of rights alleged to have occurred. This report is not discoverable in any civil or administrative action, except in such actions brought by the agency to enforce the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abuse, neglect, or exploitation must be reported to the Department of Children and Family Services as required under chapter 415.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information reported to the agency pursuant to subsection (3) which relates to persons licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 461, chapter 464, or chapter 465 shall be reviewed by the agency. The agency shall determine whether any of the incidents potentially involved conduct by a health care professional who is subject to disciplinary action, in which case the provisions of s. 456.073 apply. The agency may investigate, as it deems appropriate, any such incident and prescribe measures that must or may be taken in response to the incident. The agency shall review each incident and determine whether it potentially involved conduct by a health care professional who is subject to disciplinary action, in which case the provisions of s. 456.073 apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the agency, through its receipt of the adverse incident reports prescribed in this part or through any investigation, has reasonable belief that conduct by a staff member or employee of a licensed facility is grounds for disciplinary action by the appropriate board, the agency shall report this fact to such regulatory board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The adverse incident reports and preliminary adverse incident reports required under this section are confidential as provided by law and are not discoverable or admissible in any civil or administrative action, except in disciplinary proceedings by the agency or appropriate regulatory board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs may adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 2001-45; s. 2, ch. 2006-197; s. 63, ch. 2009-223.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.423.</Text></Note></Section>