<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appropriateness of placements; examinations of residents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The owner or administrator of a facility is responsible for determining the appropriateness of admission of an individual to the facility and for determining the continued appropriateness of residence of an individual in the facility. A determination shall be based upon an assessment of the strengths, needs, and preferences of the resident, the care and services offered or arranged for by the facility in accordance with facility policy, and any limitations in law or rule related to admission criteria or continued residency for the type of license held by the facility under this part. A resident may not be moved from one facility to another without consultation with and agreement from the resident or, if applicable, the resident’s representative or designee or the resident’s family, guardian, surrogate, or attorney in fact. In the case of a resident who has been placed by the department or the Department of Children and Family Services, the administrator must notify the appropriate contact person in the applicable department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician, physician assistant, or nurse practitioner who is employed by an assisted living facility to provide an initial examination for admission purposes may not have financial interest in the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons licensed under part I of chapter 464 who are employed by or under contract with a facility shall, on a routine basis or at least monthly, perform a nursing assessment of the residents for whom they are providing nursing services ordered by a physician, except administration of medication, and shall document such assessment, including any substantial changes in a resident’s status which may necessitate relocation to a nursing home, hospital, or specialized health care facility. Such records shall be maintained in the facility for inspection by the agency and shall be forwarded to the resident’s case manager, if applicable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If possible, each resident shall have been examined by a licensed physician, a licensed physician assistant, or a licensed nurse practitioner within 60 days before admission to the facility. The signed and completed medical examination report shall be submitted to the owner or administrator of the facility who shall use the information contained therein to assist in the determination of the appropriateness of the resident’s admission and continued stay in the facility. The medical examination report shall become a permanent part of the record of the resident at the facility and shall be made available to the agency during inspection or upon request. An assessment that has been completed through the Comprehensive Assessment and Review for Long-Term Care Services (CARES) Program fulfills the requirements for a medical examination under this subsection and s. 429.07(3)(b)6.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 429.07, if a medical examination has not been completed within 60 days before the admission of the resident to the facility, a licensed physician, licensed physician assistant, or licensed nurse practitioner shall examine the resident and complete a medical examination form provided by the agency within 30 days following the admission to the facility to enable the facility owner or administrator to determine the appropriateness of the admission. The medical examination form shall become a permanent part of the record of the resident at the facility and shall be made available to the agency during inspection by the agency or upon request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident accepted in a facility and placed by the department or the Department of Children and Family Services shall have been examined by medical personnel within 30 days before placement in the facility. The examination shall include an assessment of the appropriateness of placement in a facility. The findings of this examination shall be recorded on the examination form provided by the agency. The completed form shall accompany the resident and shall be submitted to the facility owner or administrator. Additionally, in the case of a mental health resident, the Department of Children and Family Services must provide documentation that the individual has been assessed by a psychiatrist, clinical psychologist, clinical social worker, or psychiatric nurse, or an individual who is supervised by one of these professionals, and determined to be appropriate to reside in an assisted living facility. The documentation must be in the facility within 30 days after the mental health resident has been admitted to the facility. An evaluation completed upon discharge from a state mental hospital meets the requirements of this subsection related to appropriateness for placement as a mental health resident providing it was completed within 90 days prior to admission to the facility. The applicable department shall provide to the facility administrator any information about the resident that would help the administrator meet his or her responsibilities under subsection (1). Further, department personnel shall explain to the facility operator any special needs of the resident and advise the operator whom to call should problems arise. The applicable department shall advise and assist the facility administrator where the special needs of residents who are recipients of optional state supplementation require such assistance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facility must notify a licensed physician when a resident exhibits signs of dementia or cognitive impairment or has a change of condition in order to rule out the presence of an underlying physiological condition that may be contributing to such dementia or impairment. The notification must occur within 30 days after the acknowledgment of such signs by facility staff. If an underlying condition is determined to exist, the facility shall arrange, with the appropriate health care provider, the necessary care and services to treat the condition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services may require an examination for supplemental security income and optional state supplementation recipients residing in facilities at any time and shall provide the examination whenever a resident’s condition requires it. Any facility administrator; personnel of the agency, the department, or the Department of Children and Family Services; or long-term care ombudsman council member who believes a resident needs to be evaluated shall notify the resident’s case manager, who shall take appropriate action. A report of the examination findings shall be provided to the resident’s case manager and the facility administrator to help the administrator meet his or her responsibilities under subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A terminally ill resident who no longer meets the criteria for continued residency may remain in the facility if the arrangement is mutually agreeable to the resident and the facility; additional care is rendered through a licensed hospice, and the resident is under the care of a physician who agrees that the physical needs of the resident are being met.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities licensed to provide extended congregate care services shall promote aging in place by determining appropriateness of continued residency based on a comprehensive review of the resident’s physical and functional status; the ability of the facility, family members, friends, or any other pertinent individuals or agencies to provide the care and services required; and documentation that a written service plan consistent with facility policy has been developed and implemented to ensure that the resident’s needs and preferences are addressed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No resident who requires 24-hour nursing supervision, except for a resident who is an enrolled hospice patient pursuant to part IV of chapter 400, shall be retained in a facility licensed under this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12, 30, ch. 80-198; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 53, 75, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 53, ch. 83-218; s. 6, ch. 85-145; s. 11, ch. 87-371; s. 19, ch. 89-294; s. 17, ch. 91-263; ss. 21, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 776, ch. 95-148; s. 15, ch. 95-210; ss. 25, 49, ch. 95-418; s. 39, ch. 96-169; s. 5, ch. 97-82; s. 215, ch. 99-13; s. 101, ch. 2000-318; s. 75, ch. 2000-349; s. 37, ch. 2001-45; s. 61, ch. 2002-1; ss. 2, 49, ch. 2006-197; s. 153, ch. 2007-230; s. 64, ch. 2009-223.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.426.</Text></Note></Section>