<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.42" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Pharmacy and dietary services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any assisted living facility in which the agency has documented a class I or class II deficiency or uncorrected class III deficiencies regarding medicinal drugs or over-the-counter preparations, including their storage, use, delivery, or administration, or dietary services, or both, during a biennial survey or a monitoring visit or an investigation in response to a complaint, shall, in addition to or as an alternative to any penalties imposed under s. 429.19, be required to employ the consultant services of a licensed pharmacist, a licensed registered nurse, or a registered or licensed dietitian, as applicable. The consultant shall, at a minimum, provide onsite quarterly consultation until the inspection team from the agency determines that such consultation services are no longer required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A corrective action plan for deficiencies related to assistance with the self-administration of medication or the administration of medication must be developed and implemented by the facility within 48 hours after notification of such deficiency, or sooner if the deficiency is determined by the agency to be life-threatening.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall employ at least two pharmacists licensed pursuant to chapter 465 among its personnel who biennially inspect assisted living facilities licensed under this part, to participate in biennial inspections or consult with the agency regarding deficiencies relating to medicinal drugs or over-the-counter preparations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may by rule establish procedures and specify documentation as necessary to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 89-218; s. 1, ch. 90-192; s. 23, ch. 91-263; ss. 29, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 17, ch. 95-210; s. 18, ch. 98-80; s. 6, ch. 98-148; ss. 2, 56, ch. 2006-197.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.442.</Text></Note></Section>