<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.65" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Activities of daily living” means functions and tasks for self-care, including eating, bathing, grooming, dressing, ambulating, and other similar tasks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Adult family-care home” means a full-time, family-type living arrangement, in a private home, under which a person who owns or rents the home provides room, board, and personal care, on a 24-hour basis, for no more than five disabled adults or frail elders who are not relatives. The following family-type living arrangements are not required to be licensed as an adult family-care home:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An arrangement whereby the person who owns or rents the home provides room, board, and personal services for not more than two adults who do not receive optional state supplementation under s. 409.212. The person who provides the housing, meals, and personal <Reference Number="1" />care must own or rent the home and reside therein.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An arrangement whereby the person who owns or rents the home provides room, board, and personal services only to his or her relatives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An establishment that is licensed as an assisted living facility under this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Aging in place” means remaining in a noninstitutional living environment despite the physical or mental changes that may occur in a person who is aging. For aging in place to occur, needed services are added, increased, or adjusted to compensate for a person’s physical or mental changes.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Appropriate placement” means that the resident’s needs can be met by the adult family-care home or can be met by services arranged by the adult family-care home or the resident.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Chemical restraint” means a pharmacologic drug that physically limits, restricts, or deprives an individual of movement or mobility, and is used for discipline or convenience and not required for the treatment of medical symptoms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Elderly Affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Disabled adult” means any person between 18 and 59 years of age, inclusive, who is a resident of the state and who has one or more permanent physical or mental limitations that restrict the person’s ability to perform the normal activities of daily living.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Frail elder” means a functionally impaired elderly person who is 60 years of age or older and who has physical or mental limitations that restrict the person’s ability to perform the normal activities of daily living and that impede the person’s capacity to live independently.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal services” or “personal care” includes individual assistance with or supervision of the activities of daily living and the self-administration of medication, and other similar services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Provider” means a person who is licensed to operate an adult family-care home.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Relative” means an individual who is the father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister, grandfather, grandmother, great-grandfather, great-grandmother, uncle, aunt, first cousin, nephew, niece, husband, wife, father-in-law, mother-in-law, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, brother-in-law, sister-in-law, stepfather, stepmother, stepson, stepdaughter, stepbrother, stepsister, half brother, or half sister of a provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Relief person” means an adult designated by the provider to supervise the residents during the provider’s absence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident” means a person receiving room, board, and personal care in an adult family-care home.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, ch. 85-195; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 4, ch. 93-209; s. 22, ch. 95-210; s. 61, ch. 95-418; s. 21, ch. 98-80; s. 3, ch. 98-338; s. 220, ch. 99-13; ss. 3, 66, ch. 2006-197.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 3, ch. 98-338. Section 21, ch. 98-80, substituted the word “services” for the word “care.”</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.618.</Text></Note></Section>