<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Activities of daily living” means functions and tasks for self-care, including ambulation, bathing, dressing, eating, grooming, and toileting, and other similar tasks.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrator” means an individual at least 21 years of age who is responsible for the operation and maintenance of an assisted living facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Aging in place” or “age in place” means the process of providing increased or adjusted services to a person to compensate for the physical or mental decline that may occur with the aging process, in order to maximize the person’s dignity and independence and permit them to remain in a familiar, noninstitutional, residential environment for as long as possible. Such services may be provided by facility staff, volunteers, family, or friends, or through contractual arrangements with a third party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assisted living facility” means any building or buildings, section or distinct part of a building, private home, boarding home, home for the aged, or other residential facility, whether operated for profit or not, which undertakes through its ownership or management to provide housing, meals, and one or more personal services for a period exceeding 24 hours to one or more adults who are not relatives of the owner or administrator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Chemical restraint” means a pharmacologic drug that physically limits, restricts, or deprives an individual of movement or mobility, and is used for discipline or convenience and not required for the treatment of medical symptoms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community living support plan” means a written document prepared by a mental health resident and the resident’s mental health case manager in consultation with the administrator of an assisted living facility with a limited mental health license or the administrator’s designee. A copy must be provided to the administrator. The plan must include information about the supports, services, and special needs of the resident which enable the resident to live in the assisted living facility and a method by which facility staff can recognize and respond to the signs and symptoms particular to that resident which indicate the need for professional services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cooperative agreement” means a written statement of understanding between a mental health care provider and the administrator of the assisted living facility with a limited mental health license in which a mental health resident is living. The agreement must specify directions for accessing emergency and after-hours care for the mental health resident. A single cooperative agreement may service all mental health residents who are clients of the same mental health care provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Elderly Affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Emergency” means a situation, physical condition, or method of operation which presents imminent danger of death or serious physical or mental harm to facility residents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Extended congregate care” means acts beyond those authorized in subsection (16) that may be performed pursuant to part I of chapter 464 by persons licensed thereunder while carrying out their professional duties, and other supportive services which may be specified by rule. The purpose of such services is to enable residents to age in place in a residential environment despite mental or physical limitations that might otherwise disqualify them from residency in a facility licensed under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Guardian” means a person to whom the law has entrusted the custody and control of the person or property, or both, of a person who has been legally adjudged incapacitated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited nursing services” means acts that may be performed pursuant to part I of chapter 464 by persons licensed thereunder while carrying out their professional duties but limited to those acts which the department specifies by rule. Acts which may be specified by rule as allowable limited nursing services shall be for persons who meet the admission criteria established by the department for assisted living facilities and shall not be complex enough to require 24-hour nursing supervision and may include such services as the application and care of routine dressings, and care of casts, braces, and splints.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Managed risk” means the process by which the facility staff discuss the service plan and the needs of the resident with the resident and, if applicable, the resident’s representative or designee or the resident’s surrogate, guardian, or attorney in fact, in such a way that the consequences of a decision, including any inherent risk, are explained to all parties and reviewed periodically in conjunction with the service plan, taking into account changes in the resident’s status and the ability of the facility to respond accordingly.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mental health resident” means an individual who receives social security disability income due to a mental disorder as determined by the Social Security Administration or receives supplemental security income due to a mental disorder as determined by the Social Security Administration and receives optional state supplementation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal services” means direct physical assistance with or supervision of the activities of daily living and the self-administration of medication and other similar services which the department may define by rule. “Personal services” shall not be construed to mean the provision of medical, nursing, dental, or mental health services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Physical restraint” means a device which physically limits, restricts, or deprives an individual of movement or mobility, including, but not limited to, a half-bed rail, a full-bed rail, a geriatric chair, and a posey restraint. The term “physical restraint” shall also include any device which was not specifically manufactured as a restraint but which has been altered, arranged, or otherwise used for this purpose. The term shall not include bandage material used for the purpose of binding a wound or injury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Relative” means an individual who is the father, mother, stepfather, stepmother, son, daughter, brother, sister, grandmother, grandfather, great-grandmother, great-grandfather, grandson, granddaughter, uncle, aunt, first cousin, nephew, niece, husband, wife, father-in-law, mother-in-law, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, brother-in-law, sister-in-law, stepson, stepdaughter, stepbrother, stepsister, half brother, or half sister of an owner or administrator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident” means a person 18 years of age or older, residing in and receiving care from a facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident’s representative or designee” means a person other than the owner, or an agent or employee of the facility, designated in writing by the resident, if legally competent, to receive notice of changes in the contract executed pursuant to s. 429.24; to receive notice of and to participate in meetings between the resident and the facility owner, administrator, or staff concerning the rights of the resident; to assist the resident in contacting the ombudsman council if the resident has a complaint against the facility; or to bring legal action on behalf of the resident pursuant to s. 429.29.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Service plan” means a written plan, developed and agreed upon by the resident and, if applicable, the resident’s representative or designee or the resident’s surrogate, guardian, or attorney in fact, if any, and the administrator or designee representing the facility, which addresses the unique physical and psychosocial needs, abilities, and personal preferences of each resident receiving extended congregate care services. The plan shall include a brief written description, in easily understood language, of what services shall be provided, who shall provide the services, when the services shall be rendered, and the purposes and benefits of the services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Shared responsibility” means exploring the options available to a resident within a facility and the risks involved with each option when making decisions pertaining to the resident’s abilities, preferences, and service needs, thereby enabling the resident and, if applicable, the resident’s representative or designee, or the resident’s surrogate, guardian, or attorney in fact, and the facility to develop a service plan which best meets the resident’s needs and seeks to improve the resident’s quality of life.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supervision” means reminding residents to engage in activities of daily living and the self-administration of medication, and, when necessary, observing or providing verbal cuing to residents while they perform these activities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supplemental security income,” Title XVI of the Social Security Act, means a program through which the Federal Government guarantees a minimum monthly income to every person who is age 65 or older, or disabled, or blind and meets the income and asset requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supportive services” means services designed to encourage and assist aged persons or adults with disabilities to remain in the least restrictive living environment and to maintain their independence as long as possible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Twenty-four-hour nursing supervision” means services that are ordered by a physician for a resident whose condition requires the supervision of a physician and continued monitoring of vital signs and physical status. Such services shall be: medically complex enough to require constant supervision, assessment, planning, or intervention by a nurse; required to be performed by or under the direct supervision of licensed nursing personnel or other professional personnel for safe and effective performance; required on a daily basis; and consistent with the nature and severity of the resident’s condition or the disease state or stage.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 75-233; ss. 12, 14, ch. 80-198; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 19, ch. 82-148; ss. 41, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 4, ch. 85-145; s. 3, ch. 87-371; s. 10, ch. 89-294; s. 3, ch. 91-263; s. 1, ch. 93-209; ss. 2, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 7, ch. 95-210; ss. 1, 22, 47, ch. 95-418; s. 2, ch. 97-82; s. 1, ch. 98-80; s. 98, ch. 2000-318; ss. 2, 29, ch. 2006-197; s. 138, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.402.</Text></Note></Section>