<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.297" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Punitive damages; pleading; burden of proof.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any action for damages brought under this part, no claim for punitive damages shall be permitted unless there is a reasonable showing by evidence in the record or proffered by the claimant which would provide a reasonable basis for recovery of such damages. The claimant may move to amend her or his complaint to assert a claim for punitive damages as allowed by the rules of civil procedure. The rules of civil procedure shall be liberally construed so as to allow the claimant discovery of evidence which appears reasonably calculated to lead to admissible evidence on the issue of punitive damages. No discovery of financial worth shall proceed until after the pleading concerning punitive damages is permitted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A defendant may be held liable for punitive damages only if the trier of fact, based on clear and convincing evidence, finds that the defendant was personally guilty of intentional misconduct or gross negligence. As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intentional misconduct” means that the defendant had actual knowledge of the wrongfulness of the conduct and the high probability that injury or damage to the claimant would result and, despite that knowledge, intentionally pursued that course of conduct, resulting in injury or damage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gross negligence” means that the defendant’s conduct was so reckless or wanting in care that it constituted a conscious disregard or indifference to the life, safety, or rights of persons exposed to such conduct.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of an employer, principal, corporation, or other legal entity, punitive damages may be imposed for the conduct of an employee or agent only if the conduct of the employee or agent meets the criteria specified in subsection (2) and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer, principal, corporation, or other legal entity actively and knowingly participated in such conduct;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The officers, directors, or managers of the employer, principal, corporation, or other legal entity condoned, ratified, or consented to such conduct; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The employer, principal, corporation, or other legal entity engaged in conduct that constituted gross negligence and that contributed to the loss, damages, or injury suffered by the claimant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plaintiff must establish at trial, by clear and convincing evidence, its entitlement to an award of punitive damages. The “greater weight of the evidence” burden of proof applies to a determination of the amount of damages.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section is remedial in nature and shall take effect upon becoming a law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 44, ch. 2001-45; s. 2, ch. 2006-197.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.4297.</Text></Note></Section>