<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Closing of facility; notice; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of part II of chapter 408, the facility shall inform each resident or the next of kin, legal representative, or agency acting on each resident’s behalf, of the fact and the proposed time of discontinuance of operation, following the notification requirements provided in s. 429.28(1)(k). In the event a resident has no person to represent him or her, the facility shall be responsible for referral to an appropriate social service agency for placement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Immediately upon the notice by the agency of the voluntary or involuntary termination of such operation, the agency shall monitor the transfer of residents to other facilities and ensure that residents’ rights are being protected. The department, in consultation with the Department of Children and Family Services, shall specify procedures for ensuring that all residents who receive services are appropriately relocated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All charges shall be prorated as of the date on which the facility discontinues operation, and if any payments have been made in advance, the payments for services not received shall be refunded to the resident or the resident’s guardian within 10 working days of voluntary or involuntary closure of the facility, whether or not such refund is requested by the resident or guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may levy a fine in an amount no greater than $5,000 upon each person or business entity that owns any interest in a facility that terminates operation without providing notice to the agency and the residents of the facility at least 30 days before operation ceases. This fine shall not be levied against any facility involuntarily closed at the initiation of the agency. The agency shall use the proceeds of the fines to operate the facility until all residents of the facility are relocated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 75-233; ss. 12, 25, ch. 80-198; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 57, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 20, ch. 91-263; ss. 25, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 780, ch. 95-148; s. 50, ch. 95-418; s. 123, ch. 99-8; ss. 2, 54, ch. 2006-197; s. 154, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.431.</Text></Note></Section>