<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0429.929" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rules establishing standards.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in consultation with the department, may adopt rules to administer the requirements of part II of chapter 408. The Department of Elderly Affairs, in conjunction with the agency, shall adopt rules to implement the provisions of this part. The rules must include reasonable and fair standards. Any conflict between these standards and those that may be set forth in local, county, or municipal ordinances shall be resolved in favor of those having statewide effect. Such standards must relate to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintenance of adult day care centers with respect to plumbing, heating, lighting, ventilation, and other building conditions, including adequate meeting space, to ensure the health, safety, and comfort of participants and protection from fire hazard. Such standards may not conflict with chapter 553 and must be based upon the size of the structure and the number of participants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and qualifications of all personnel employed by adult day care centers who have responsibilities for the care of participants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All sanitary conditions within adult day care centers and their surroundings, including water supply, sewage disposal, food handling, and general hygiene, and maintenance of sanitary conditions, to ensure the health and comfort of participants.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Basic services provided by adult day care centers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supportive and optional services provided by adult day care centers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Data and information relative to participants and programs of adult day care centers, including, but not limited to, the physical and mental capabilities and needs of the participants, the availability, frequency, and intensity of basic services and of supportive and optional services provided, the frequency of participation, the distances traveled by participants, the hours of operation, the number of referrals to other centers or elsewhere, and the incidence of illness.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Components of a comprehensive emergency management plan, developed in consultation with the Department of Health, the Agency for Health Care Administration, and the Division of Emergency Management.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to this part, s. 408.811, and applicable rules, the agency may conduct an abbreviated biennial inspection of key quality-of-care standards, in lieu of a full inspection, of a center that has a record of good performance. However, the agency must conduct a full inspection of a center that has had one or more confirmed complaints within the licensure period immediately preceding the inspection or which has a serious problem identified during the abbreviated inspection. The agency shall develop the key quality-of-care standards, taking into consideration the comments and recommendations of the Department of Elderly Affairs and of provider groups. These standards shall be included in rules adopted by the Department of Elderly Affairs.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 13, 18, ch. 78-336; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 79, 83, ch. 83-181; ss. 14, 17, ch. 93-215; s. 56, ch. 95-418; s. 61, ch. 2001-45; s. 4, ch. 2006-197; s. 176, ch. 2007-230; s. 345, ch. 2011-142.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.562.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>