<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0429.47" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts; penalties for violation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">While a facility is under construction, the owner may advertise to the public prior to obtaining a license. Facilities that are certified under chapter 651 shall comply with the advertising provisions of s. 651.095 rather than those provided for in this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A freestanding facility shall not advertise or imply that any part of it is a nursing home. For the purpose of this subsection, “freestanding facility” means a facility that is not operated in conjunction with a nursing home to which residents of the facility are given priority when nursing care is required. A person who violates this subsection is subject to fine as specified in s. 429.19.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility which is affiliated with any religious organization or which has a name implying religious affiliation shall include in its advertising whether or not it is affiliated with any religious organization and, if so, which organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility licensed under this part which is not part of a facility authorized under chapter 651 shall include the facility’s license number as given by the agency in all advertising. A company or person owning more than one facility shall include at least one license number per advertisement. All advertising shall include the term “assisted living facility” before the license number.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 75-233; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 14, ch. 87-371; s. 25, ch. 91-263; ss. 32, 38, 39, ch. 93-216; s. 18, ch. 95-210; s. 217, ch. 99-13; ss. 2, 58, ch. 2006-197; s. 158, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.447.</Text></Note></Section>