<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.292" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Misrepresenting food or food product; penalty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An operator may not knowingly and willfully misrepresent the identity of any food or food product to any of the patrons of such establishment. The identity of food or a food product is misrepresented if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The description of the food or food product is false or misleading in any particular;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The food or food product is served, sold, or distributed under the name of another food or food product; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The food or food product purports to be or is represented as a food or food product that does not conform to a definition of identity and standard of quality if such definition of identity and standard of quality has been established by custom and usage.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the food or food product is a fruit or fruit juice, its identity is misrepresented if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The description of the fruit or fruit juice is false or misleading in any particular;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fruit or fruit juice is served, sold, or distributed under the name of another fruit or fruit juice; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A synthetic or flavored drink is sold purporting to be fruit juice.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The term “fresh juice” refers to a juice without additives and prepared from the original fruit within 12 hours or less of sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 57-412; s. 482, ch. 71-136; s. 7, ch. 71-157; s. 22, ch. 73-325; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 25, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 33, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>