<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0509.211" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Safety regulations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each bedroom or apartment in each public lodging establishment shall be equipped with an approved locking device on each door opening to the outside, to an adjoining room or apartment, or to a hallway.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to use within any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment any fuel-burning wick-type equipment for space heating unless such equipment is vented so as to prevent the accumulation of toxic or injurious gases or liquids.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates the provisions of paragraph (a) commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public lodging establishment that is three or more stories in height must have safe and secure railings on all balconies, platforms, and stairways, and all such railings must be properly maintained and repaired. The division may impose administrative sanctions for violations of this subsection pursuant to s. 509.261.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every enclosed space or room that contains a boiler regulated under chapter 554 which is fired by the direct application of energy from the combustion of fuels and that is located in any portion of a public lodging establishment that also contains sleeping rooms shall be equipped with one or more carbon monoxide sensor devices that bear the label of a nationally recognized testing laboratory and have been tested and listed as complying with the most recent Underwriters Laboratories, Inc., Standard 2034, or its equivalent, unless it is determined that carbon monoxide hazards have otherwise been adequately mitigated as determined by the Division of State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services. Such devices shall be integrated with the public lodging establishment’s fire detection system. Any such installation or determination shall be made in accordance with rules adopted by the Division of State Fire Marshal.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 1999, 1874; RS 874; GS 1232; ss. 17-23, ch. 6952, 1915; RGS 2137-2143, 2356; s. 7, ch. 9264, 1923; CGL 3366-3372, 3760; ss. 19-25, 41, ch. 16042, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 3366-3372; ss. 3-5, ch. 23930, 1947; s. 10, ch. 26484, 1951; s. 3, ch. 28129, 1953; s. 4, ch. 29821, 1955; s. 7, ch. 57-389; s. 1, ch. 63-67; s. 1, ch. 63-312; s. 1, ch. 63-426; s. 7, ch. 65-421; s. 1, ch. 65-150; ss. 1, 2, ch. 67-232; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-281; s. 478, ch. 71-136; ss. 2, 4, 13, ch. 71-157; s. 191, ch. 71-377; s. 17, ch. 73-325; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 6, ch. 76-252; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 9, ch. 78-95; ss. 16, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 12, ch. 83-145; s. 6, ch. 86-174; s. 2, ch. 90-242; ss. 20, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 6, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 2007-181; s. 5, ch. 2008-55; s. 39, ch. 2010-106.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 510.05, 511.18-511.24.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>