<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.242" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public lodging establishments; classifications.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public lodging establishment shall be classified as a hotel, motel, nontransient apartment, transient apartment, bed and breakfast inn, or vacation rental if the establishment satisfies the following criteria:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Hotel.</Font><EmDash />A hotel is any public lodging establishment containing sleeping room accommodations for 25 or more guests and providing the services generally provided by a hotel and recognized as a hotel in the community in which it is situated or by the industry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Motel.</Font><EmDash />A motel is any public lodging establishment which offers rental units with an exit to the outside of each rental unit, daily or weekly rates, offstreet parking for each unit, a central office on the property with specified hours of operation, a bathroom or connecting bathroom for each rental unit, and at least six rental units, and which is recognized as a motel in the community in which it is situated or by the industry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Vacation rental.</Font><EmDash />A vacation rental is any unit or group of units in a condominium, cooperative, or timeshare plan or any individually or collectively owned single-family, two-family, three-family, or four-family house or dwelling unit that is also a transient public lodging establishment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Nontransient apartment.</Font><EmDash />A nontransient apartment is a building or complex of buildings in which 75 percent or more of the units are available for rent to nontransient tenants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Transient apartment.</Font><EmDash />A transient apartment is a building or complex of buildings in which more than 25 percent of the units are advertised or held out to the public as available for transient occupancy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Bed and breakfast inn.</Font><EmDash />A bed and breakfast inn is a family home structure, with no more than 15 sleeping rooms, which has been modified to serve as a transient public lodging establishment, which provides the accommodation and meal services generally offered by a bed and breakfast inn, and which is recognized as a bed and breakfast inn in the community in which it is situated or by the hospitality industry.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If 25 percent or more of the units in any public lodging establishment fall within a classification different from the classification under which the establishment is licensed, such establishment shall obtain a separate license for the classification representing the 25 percent or more units which differ from the classification under which the establishment is licensed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public lodging establishment may advertise or display signs which advertise a specific classification, if it has received a license which is applicable to the specific classification and it fulfills the requirements of that classification.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 57-824; s. 2, ch. 61-81; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 19, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 26, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 11, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 9, ch. 93-53; s. 12, ch. 96-384; s. 7, ch. 2008-55; s. 5, ch. 2011-119; s. 2, ch. 2012-165.</History></Section>