<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0509.261" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revocation or suspension of licenses; fines; procedure.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment that has operated or is operating in violation of this chapter or the rules of the division, operating without a license, or operating with a suspended or revoked license may be subject by the division to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fines not to exceed $1,000 per offense;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mandatory completion, at personal expense, of a remedial educational program administered by a food safety training program provider approved by the division, as provided in s. 509.049; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The suspension, revocation, or refusal of a license issued pursuant to this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the division may regard as a separate offense each day or portion of a day on which an establishment is operated in violation of a “critical law or rule,” as that term is defined by rule.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall post a prominent closed-for-operation sign on any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment, the license of which has been suspended or revoked. The division shall also post such sign on any establishment judicially or administratively determined to be operating without a license. It is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for any person to deface or remove such closed-for-operation sign or for any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment to open for operation without a license or to open for operation while its license is suspended or revoked. The division may impose administrative sanctions for violations of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds received by the division as satisfaction for administrative fines shall be paid into the State Treasury to the credit of the Hotel and Restaurant Trust Fund and may not subsequently be used for payment to any entity performing required inspections under contract with the division. Administrative fines may be used to support division programs pursuant to s. 509.302(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license may not be suspended under this section for a period of more than 12 months. At the end of such period of suspension, the establishment may apply for reinstatement or renewal of the license. A public lodging establishment or public food service establishment, the license of which is revoked, may not apply for another license for that location prior to the date on which the revoked license would have expired.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may fine, suspend, or revoke the license of any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment if the operator knowingly lets, leases, or gives space for unlawful gambling purposes or permits unlawful gambling in such establishment or in or upon any premises which are used in connection with, and are under the same charge, control, or management as, such establishment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may fine, suspend, or revoke the license of any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment when:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person with a direct financial interest in the licensed establishment, within the preceding 5 years in this state, any other state, or the United States, has been adjudicated guilty of or forfeited a bond when charged with soliciting for prostitution, pandering, letting premises for prostitution, keeping a disorderly place, illegally dealing in controlled substances as defined in chapter 893, or any other crime reflecting on professional character.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such establishment has been deemed an imminent danger to the public health and safety by the division or local health authority for failure to meet sanitation standards or the premises have been determined by the division or local authority to be unsafe or unfit for human occupancy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person is not entitled to the issuance of a license for any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment except in the discretion of the director when the division has notified the current licenseholder for such premises that administrative proceedings have been or will be brought against such current licensee for violation of any provision of this chapter or rule of the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may fine, suspend, or revoke the license of any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment when the establishment is not in compliance with the requirements of a final order or other administrative action issued against the licensee by the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may refuse to issue or renew the license of any public lodging establishment or public food service establishment until all outstanding fines are paid in full to the division as required by all final orders or other administrative action issued against the licensee by the division.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 48, ch. 16042, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 3355(2); s. 1, ch. 21660, 1943; s. 2, ch. 23930, 1947; ss. 1-5, ch. 26939, 1951; s. 1, ch. 28224, 1953; s. 1, ch. 29823, 1955; s. 10, ch. 57-389; s. 40, ch. 63-512; s. 1, ch. 63-69; s. 1, ch. 63-68; s. 1, ch. 63-70; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 192, ch. 71-377; s. 20, ch. 73-325; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 188, ch. 77-104; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 9, ch. 78-95; ss. 21, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 4, ch. 82-84; ss. 28, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 11, ch. 93-53; s. 48, ch. 95-144; s. 4, ch. 2007-237; s. 8, ch. 2008-55; s. 7, ch. 2011-119.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 511.05, 511.051.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>