<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Immediate closure due to severe public health threat.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall, upon proper finding, immediately issue an order to close an establishment licensed under this chapter in the instance of a severe and immediate public health or safety or welfare threat as follows:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director shall declare a public health threat upon a proper finding by the State Health Officer that the continued operation of a licensed establishment presents a severe and immediate threat to the public health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director shall declare a threat to the public safety or welfare upon a proper finding by the director that the continued operation of a licensed establishment presents a severe and immediate threat to the public safety or welfare.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon such determination, the division shall issue a notice to show cause and an emergency order of suspension. Such order shall be served upon the establishment by the division or its agent, and the establishment shall be closed. An operator who resists such closure is subject to further administrative action by the division and is punishable as provided in s. 509.281. The division shall provide an inspection within 24 hours following such closure and shall review all relevant information to determine whether the facility has met the requirements to resume operations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may attach a sign which states “Closed to Protect Public Health and Safety” to such an establishment and may require the licensee to immediately stop service until notification to the contrary is provided by the director.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may further adopt rules for issuing emergency orders after business hours and on weekends and holidays in order to ensure the timely closure of an establishment under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 3, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 3, ch. 93-53.</History></Section>