<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Firesafety.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Public lodging establishment, as defined in this chapter, which is of three stories or more and for which the construction contract has been let after September 30, 1983, with interior corridors which do not have direct access from the guest area to exterior means of egress, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Building over 75 feet in height that has direct access from the guest area to exterior means of egress and for which the construction contract has been let after September 30, 1983,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">shall be equipped with an automatic sprinkler system installed in compliance with the provisions prescribed in the National Fire Protection Association publication NFPA No. 13 “Standards for the Installation of Sprinkler Systems.” The sprinkler installation may be omitted in closets which are not over 24 square feet in area and in bathrooms which are not over 55 square feet in area, which closets and bathrooms are located in guest rooms. Each guest room shall be equipped with an approved listed single-station smoke detector meeting the minimum requirements of NFPA-74 “Standards for the Installation, Maintenance and Use of Household Fire Warning Equipment,” powered from the building electrical service, notwithstanding the number of stories in the structure or type or means of egress, if the contract for construction is let after September 30, 1983. Single-station smoke detection is not required when guest rooms contain smoke detectors connected to a central alarm system which also alarms locally.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any public lodging establishment, as defined in this chapter, which is of three stories or more and for which the construction contract was let before October 1, 1983, shall be equipped with:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A system which complies with subsection (1); or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An approved sprinkler system for all interior corridors, public areas, storage rooms, closets, kitchen areas, and laundry rooms, less individual guest rooms, if the following conditions are met:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a minimum 1-hour separation between each guest room and between each guest room and a corridor.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The building is constructed of noncombustible materials.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The egress conditions meet the requirements of s. 5-3 of the Life Safety Code, NFPA 101.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The building has a complete automatic fire detection system which meets the requirements of NFPA-72A and NFPA-72E, including smoke detectors in each guest room individually annunciating to a panel at a supervised location.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, this section applies only to those public lodging establishments in a building wherein more than 50 percent of the units in the building are advertised or held out to the public as available for transient occupancy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Special exception to the provisions of this section shall be made for a public lodging establishment structure that is individually listed in the National Register of Historic Places pursuant to the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, as amended; or is a contributing property to a National Register-listed district; or is designated as a historic property, or as a contributing property to a historic district under the terms of a local preservation ordinance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For such structures, provisions shall be made for a system of fire protection and lifesafety support that would meet the intent of the NFPA standards and be acceptable to, and approved by, a task force composed of the director of the Division of Hotels and Restaurants, the director of the Division of State Fire Marshal, and the State Historic Preservation Officer. When recommending alternative systems, the task force shall consider systems which would not disturb, destroy, or alter the integrity of such historic structures. The director of the Division of State Fire Marshal shall be designated chairperson of the task force and shall record the minutes of each task force meeting, which shall be called in a timely manner to review requests for special provision considerations under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of State Fire Marshal shall adopt, in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120, any rules necessary for the implementation and enforcement of this section. The Division of State Fire Marshal shall enforce this section in accordance with the provisions of chapter 633, and any establishment licensed under this chapter in violation of this section may be subject to administrative sanctions by the division pursuant to s. 509.261.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specialized smoke detectors for the deaf and hearing impaired shall be available upon request by guests in public lodging establishments at a rate of at least one such smoke detector per 50 dwelling units or portions thereof, not to exceed five such smoke detectors per public lodging facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The National Fire Protection Association publications referenced in this section are the ones most recently adopted by rule of the Division of State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 3, 4, ch. 83-194; s. 91, ch. 85-81; s. 7, ch. 86-174; s. 32, ch. 88-90; s. 1, ch. 88-209; ss. 22, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 8, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 11, ch. 96-384; s. 59, ch. 99-5; s. 7, ch. 2000-208; s. 567, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>