<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.013" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Operator” means the owner, licensee, proprietor, lessee, manager, assistant manager, or appointed agent of a public lodging establishment or public food service establishment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Guest” means any patron, customer, tenant, lodger, boarder, or occupant of a public lodging establishment or public food service establishment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public lodging establishment” includes a transient public lodging establishment as defined in subparagraph 1. and a nontransient public lodging establishment as defined in subparagraph 2.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transient public lodging establishment” means any unit, group of units, dwelling, building, or group of buildings within a single complex of buildings which is rented to guests more than three times in a calendar year for periods of less than 30 days or 1 calendar month, whichever is less, or which is advertised or held out to the public as a place regularly rented to guests.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nontransient public lodging establishment” means any unit, group of units, dwelling, building, or group of buildings within a single complex of buildings which is rented to guests for periods of at least 30 days or 1 calendar month, whichever is less, or which is advertised or held out to the public as a place regularly rented to guests for periods of at least 30 days or 1 calendar month.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">License classifications of public lodging establishments, and the definitions therefor, are set out in s. 509.242. For the purpose of licensure, the term does not include condominium common elements as defined in s. 718.103.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are excluded from the definitions in paragraph (a):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any dormitory or other living or sleeping facility maintained by a public or private school, college, or university for the use of students, faculty, or visitors.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any facility certified or licensed and regulated by the Agency for Health Care Administration or the Department of Children and Family Services or other similar place regulated under s. 381.0072.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any place renting four rental units or less, unless the rental units are advertised or held out to the public to be places that are regularly rented to transients.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any unit or group of units in a condominium, cooperative, or timeshare plan and any individually or collectively owned one-family, two-family, three-family, or four-family dwelling house or dwelling unit that is rented for periods of at least 30 days or 1 calendar month, whichever is less, and that is not advertised or held out to the public as a place regularly rented for periods of less than 1 calendar month, provided that no more than four rental units within a single complex of buildings are available for rent.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any migrant labor camp or residential migrant housing permitted by the Department of Health under ss. 381.008-381.00895.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any establishment inspected by the Department of Health and regulated by chapter 513.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nonprofit organization that operates a facility providing housing only to patients, patients’ families, and patients’ caregivers and not to the general public.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any apartment building inspected by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development or other entity acting on the department’s behalf that is designated primarily as housing for persons at least 62 years of age. The division may require the operator of the apartment building to attest in writing that such building meets the criteria provided in this subparagraph. The division may adopt rules to implement this requirement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any roominghouse, boardinghouse, or other living or sleeping facility that may not be classified as a hotel, motel, vacation rental, nontransient apartment, bed and breakfast inn, or transient apartment under s. 509.242.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public food service establishment” means any building, vehicle, place, or structure, or any room or division in a building, vehicle, place, or structure where food is prepared, served, or sold for immediate consumption on or in the vicinity of the premises; called for or taken out by customers; or prepared prior to being delivered to another location for consumption.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are excluded from the definition in paragraph (a):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any place maintained and operated by a public or private school, college, or university:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the use of students and faculty; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Temporarily to serve such events as fairs, carnivals, and athletic contests.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any eating place maintained and operated by a church or a religious, nonprofit fraternal, or nonprofit civic organization:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the use of members and associates; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Temporarily to serve such events as fairs, carnivals, or athletic contests.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any eating place located on an airplane, train, bus, or watercraft which is a common carrier.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any eating place maintained by a facility certified or licensed and regulated by the Agency for Health Care Administration or the Department of Children and Family Services or other similar place that is regulated under s. 381.0072.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any place of business issued a permit or inspected by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services under s. 500.12.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any place of business where the food available for consumption is limited to ice, beverages with or without garnishment, popcorn, or prepackaged items sold without additions or preparation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any theater, if the primary use is as a theater and if patron service is limited to food items customarily served to the admittees of theaters.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vending machine that dispenses any food or beverages other than potentially hazardous foods, as defined by division rule.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vending machine that dispenses potentially hazardous food and which is located in a facility regulated under s. 381.0072.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any research and development test kitchen limited to the use of employees and which is not open to the general public.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Director” means the Director of the Division of Hotels and Restaurants of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Single complex of buildings” means all buildings or structures that are owned, managed, controlled, or operated under one business name and are situated on the same tract or plot of land that is not separated by a public street or highway.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Temporary food service event” means any event of 30 days or less in duration where food is prepared, served, or sold to the general public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Theme park or entertainment complex” means a complex comprised of at least 25 contiguous acres owned and controlled by the same business entity and which contains permanent exhibitions and a variety of recreational activities and has a minimum of 1 million visitors annually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Third-party provider” means, for purposes of s. 509.049, any provider of an approved food safety training program that provides training or such a training program to a public food service establishment that is not under common ownership or control with the provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transient establishment” means any public lodging establishment that is rented or leased to guests by an operator whose intention is that such guests’ occupancy will be temporary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transient occupancy” means occupancy when it is the intention of the parties that the occupancy will be temporary. There is a rebuttable presumption that, when the dwelling unit occupied is not the sole residence of the guest, the occupancy is transient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transient” means a guest in transient occupancy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nontransient establishment” means any public lodging establishment that is rented or leased to guests by an operator whose intention is that the dwelling unit occupied will be the sole residence of the guest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nontransient occupancy” means occupancy when it is the intention of the parties that the occupancy will not be temporary. There is a rebuttable presumption that, when the dwelling unit occupied is the sole residence of the guest, the occupancy is nontransient.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nontransient” means a guest in nontransient occupancy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 73-325; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 1, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 2, ch. 83-241; s. 3, ch. 87-117; s. 31, ch. 88-90; s. 2, ch. 88-275; ss. 2, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 1, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 21, ch. 92-180; s. 1, ch. 93-53; s. 14, ch. 93-133; s. 36, ch. 94-180; s. 202, ch. 94-218; s. 42, ch. 95-210; s. 3, ch. 95-314; s. 2, ch. 96-384; s. 245, ch. 99-8; s. 7, ch. 2004-292; s. 1, ch. 2008-55; s. 25, ch. 2010-161; s. 1, ch. 2011-119; s. 1, ch. 2012-165.</History></Section>