<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.508" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prize and gift promotional offers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “prize and gift promotional offer” means any advertising material wherein a prospective purchaser may receive goods or services other than the membership camping plan itself, either free of charge or at a discount, including, but not limited to, the use of any prize, gift, award, premium, or lodging or vacation certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A game promotion, contest of chance, or sweepstakes in which the elements of chance and prize are present may not be used by an offeror in connection with the offering for sale of membership camping plans.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a prospective purchaser meets all eligibility requirements stated in a prize and gift promotional offer, a prize, gift, or other item offered pursuant to a prize and gift promotional offer must be delivered to the prospective purchaser on the day she or he appears to claim it, whether or not the prospective purchaser executes a membership camping contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offeror shall maintain among its records for the period of 1 year following the completion of each prize and gift promotional offer the following information with regard to each prize and gift promotional offer:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of all advertising material used in connection with the prize and gift promotional offer;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number, including area code, of the supplier or manufacturer from whom each type or variety of prize, gift, or other item is obtained;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer’s model number or other description of such item; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information on which the developer relies in determining the verifiable retail value of the prize or gift.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 88-157; s. 675, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>