<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.506" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Trust accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds or other properties received from or on behalf of a purchaser in connection with the execution of the membership camping contract shall be deposited by the offeror within 3 days after receipt by the offeror or a salesperson into a trust account with a financial institution located in this state, established by a trustee solely for the purpose of refunds. The funds or other properties shall be maintained in the trust account until 5 days after the purchaser’s cancellation period has expired. If the purchaser delivers a written cancellation of the purchaser’s contract to the trustee within the time period described in s. 509.504(1)(a), the purchaser’s funds or other properties shall be refunded by the trustee pursuant to s. 509.504(1)(b). If the purchaser does not timely cancel the contract in the required manner, all funds or other properties received from the purchaser may be released by the trustee to the offeror on the 6th day after the expiration of the cancellation period. If the trustee receives conflicting demands for any funds or other properties held in the trust account, the trustee shall immediately either submit the matter to arbitration with the consent of the parties or, by interpleader or otherwise, seek an adjudication of the matter by a court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All trustees shall be independent of the offeror, and neither the offeror nor any officer, director, affiliate, subsidiary, or employee of the offeror may serve as trustee; however, an attorney who represents an offeror but who is not an officer, director, or employee of the offeror may serve as trustee for the offeror.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The moneys held in trust pursuant to subsection (1) may be invested only in securities of the United States Government or any agency thereof or in savings or time deposits in institutions insured by an agency of the United States Government. The interest generated by the investments, if any, shall be paid to the party to whom the escrowed moneys are paid unless otherwise specified in the contract.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any offeror, trustee, or other person who intentionally fails to comply with the provisions of this section concerning the establishment of a trust account and the deposit and disbursement of funds and other properties received from a purchaser is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. The proof of failure to establish a trust account or to deposit funds therein as required by this section constitutes prima facie proof of the intent required by this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 88-157.</History></Section>