<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cancellation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A purchaser has the right to cancel her or his contract within the time period and in the manner described in paragraph (a) and to receive a refund of all sums paid to the offeror within the time period and in the manner described in paragraph (b). Any attempt by an offeror, tour generator, or salesperson to misrepresent this absolute right to cancel to a purchaser is a violation of this act.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following capitalized language must appear in at least 10-point type in close proximity to the purchaser’s signature line on the contract: “YOU MAY CANCEL THIS CONTRACT WITHOUT ANY PENALTY OR OBLIGATION UNTIL MIDNIGHT OF THE 5TH DAY AFTER THE DATE YOU SIGN THIS CONTRACT, UNLESS THE 5TH DAY FALLS ON A SUNDAY OR NATIONAL HOLIDAY, IN WHICH EVENT, YOU MAY CANCEL THIS CONTRACT WITHOUT PENALTY OR OBLIGATION UNTIL MIDNIGHT ON THE FIRST BUSINESS DAY FOLLOWING SUCH SUNDAY OR NATIONAL HOLIDAY. IF YOU DECIDE TO CANCEL THIS CONTRACT, YOU MUST NOTIFY THE TRUSTEE IN WRITING OF YOUR CANCELLATION. YOUR CANCELLATION SHALL BE EFFECTIVE UPON THE DATE POSTMARKED AND SHALL BE MAILED TO <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of Trustee)</Directions> AT <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Address of Trustee)</Directions>. ANY ATTEMPT TO MISREPRESENT YOUR ABSOLUTE CANCELLATION RIGHT IS UNLAWFUL.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contract shall also include the following statement: “Within 20 days after the trustee receives your written cancellation, the trustee shall refund to you the total amount of all payments which you have made under the contract, provided that such refunds may be made either by check or, if you used a credit card, by credit to your credit card account.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following capitalized language must appear in at least 10-point type in close proximity to the purchaser’s signature line on the contract: “YOU MAY ALSO CANCEL THIS CONTRACT AT ANY TIME AFTER THE CAMPGROUNDS OR FACILITIES ARE NO LONGER AVAILABLE AS PROVIDED IN THIS CONTRACT.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offeror shall maintain among its business records a copy of each executed contract for a period of at least 3 years after the date of entering into the contract.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 88-157; s. 674, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>