<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.405" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Complaint; requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To obtain an order authorizing the issuance of a writ of distress upon final judgment, the operator must first file with the clerk of the court a complaint reciting and showing the following information:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to the amount of the guest’s account at the public lodging establishment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the plaintiff is the operator of the public lodging establishment in which the guest has an outstanding account. If the operator’s interest in such account is based on written documents, a copy of such documents shall be attached to the complaint.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the operator has reasonably attempted to obtain payment from the guest for an outstanding account, either by confronting the guest or by a lockout pursuant to s. 509.401, and that the guest has failed to make any payment or that the guest has vacated the premises without paying the outstanding account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the account is outstanding and unpaid by the guest; a statement of the services provided to the guest for which the outstanding account was accumulated; and the cause of such nonpayment according to the best knowledge, information, and belief of the operator.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to what property the operator is requesting levy against, including the inventory conducted as prescribed by s. 509.402 if the operator has recovered the premises, and the authority under which the operator has a lien against such property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement, to the best of the operator’s knowledge, that the claimed property has not been taken for a tax, assessment, or fine pursuant to law or taken under an execution or attachment by order of any court.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 77-249; ss. 31, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 39, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>