<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.502" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Advertising” means any written, oral, printed, or visual communication by an offeror made in connection with the promotion of a membership camping plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Business day” means a calendar day other than a Saturday, Sunday, or national holiday.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Campground” means any real property which is a part of a membership camping plan. This term does not include a mobile home, lodging, or recreational vehicle park or recreational camp as defined in chapter 513 so long as no membership camping plan is offered for sale, sold, or otherwise promoted with regard to such park.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Camping site” means any portion of a campground designed or promoted for the purpose of camping, including any trailer, tent, tent trailer, pickup camper, cabin, or other similar device or accommodation used for camping and located upon such site.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dues payment” means the mandatory annual or periodic fee paid by a purchaser, other than the purchase price, as set forth in the membership camping contract. This term does not include optional user fees charged for specific goods or services such as campground recreation or rental fees, equipment or accommodation rentals, or meals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Facilities” means all amenities offered in connection with a campground, including, but not limited to, camping sites, available rental trailers or cabins, if any, swimming pools, sport courts, recreation buildings, and trading posts or grocery stores.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Membership camping contract” means an agreement evidencing a purchaser’s right to use campgrounds and facilities pursuant to a membership camping plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Membership camping plan” means any arrangement or other device, membership agreement, rental agreement, license, right-to-use agreement, or other agreement under which a purchaser, in exchange for consideration, receives the right to use campgrounds and facilities. This term does not include any arrangement or other device, membership agreement, rental agreement, license, right-to-use agreement, or other agreement under which a purchaser has the one-time right to use a specific, identified camping site and related facilities for a specific, identified, nonrecurring period of time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Offer” means any solicitation, advertisement, inducement, or other method or attempt to encourage any person to become a purchaser.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Offeror” means the person who creates a membership camping plan and offers membership camping contracts for sale to the public in the ordinary course of business in connection with the membership camping plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ordinary course of business” means the transaction of business by a person in the business of selling or reselling membership camping plans.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Purchase price” means the total price of a membership camping contract, including finance charges and related closing costs, if any, and excluding all dues payments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Purchaser” means a person who purchases a membership camping contract and obtains the right to use the campgrounds and facilities of a membership camping plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Salesperson” means a person who is engaged in promoting, offering for sale, or selling a membership camping plan as the employee, independent contractor, agent, officer, director, shareholder, partner, or principal of an offeror. This term does not include an offeror or a tour generator and does not include a purchaser who refers names of prospective purchasers to an offeror, provided that such purchaser is not in the business of making such referrals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tour generator” means a person who is engaged in the referral of prospective purchasers of a membership camping plan to a salesperson or to an offeror. This term does not include an offeror and does not include a purchaser who refers names of prospective purchasers to an offeror, provided that such purchaser is not in the business of making such referrals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trust account” means an account created and used for the purposes required in this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trustee” includes only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A savings and loan association, bank, trust company, or other financial lending institution having a net worth in excess of $5 million which is either located in this state or which has submitted to the jurisdiction of the Circuit Court of Leon County, Florida, and is otherwise acceptable; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An attorney who is a member in good standing of The Florida Bar and who has posted a fidelity bond in the amount of $50,000 issued by a company authorized and licensed to do business in this state as surety.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 88-157; s. 28, ch. 93-150.</History></Section>