<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0509.221" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sanitary regulations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public lodging establishment shall be supplied with potable water and shall provide adequate sanitary facilities for the accommodation of its employees and guests. Such facilities may include, but are not limited to, showers, handwash basins, toilets, and bidets. Such sanitary facilities shall be connected to approved plumbing. Such plumbing shall be sized, installed, and maintained in accordance with the Florida Building Code as approved by the local building authority. Wastewater or sewage shall be properly treated onsite or discharged into an approved sewage collection and treatment system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public food service establishment shall be supplied with potable water and shall provide adequate sanitary facilities for the accommodation of its employees. Such facilities may include, but are not limited to, showers, handwash basins, toilets, and bidets. Such sanitary facilities shall be connected to approved plumbing. Such plumbing shall be sized, installed, and maintained in accordance with the Florida Building Code as approved by the local building authority. Wastewater or sewage shall be properly treated onsite or discharged into an approved sewage collection and treatment system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each public lodging establishment and each public food service establishment shall maintain public bathroom facilities in accordance with the Florida Building Code as approved by the local building authority. The division shall establish by rule categories of establishments not subject to the bathroom requirement of this paragraph. Such rules may not alter the exemption provided for theme parks in paragraph (b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within a theme park or entertainment complex as defined in s. 509.013(9), the bathrooms are not required to be in the same building as the public food service establishment, so long as they are reasonably accessible.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each transient establishment that does not provide private or connecting bathrooms shall maintain one public bathroom on each floor for every 15 guests, or major fraction of that number, rooming on that floor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each establishment licensed under this chapter shall be properly lighted, heated, cooled, and ventilated and shall be operated with strict regard to the health, comfort, and safety of the guests. Such proper lighting shall be construed to apply to both daylight and artificial illumination.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each bedroom in a public lodging establishment shall have an opening to the outside of the building, air shafts, or courts sufficient to provide adequate ventilation. Where ventilation is provided mechanically, the system shall be capable of providing at least two air changes per hour in all areas served. Where ventilation is provided by windows, each room shall have at least one window opening directly to the outside.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each transient public lodging establishment shall provide in the main public bathroom soap and clean towels or other approved hand-drying devices and each public lodging establishment shall furnish each guest with two clean individual towels so that two guests will not be required to use the same towel unless it has first been laundered. Each public food service establishment shall provide in the employee bathroom and any public bathroom soap and clean towels or other approved hand-drying devices.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each transient establishment shall provide each bed, bunk, cot, or other sleeping place for the use of guests with clean pillowslips and under and top sheets. Sheets and pillowslips shall be laundered before they are used by another guest, a clean set being furnished each succeeding guest. All bedding, including mattresses, quilts, blankets, pillows, sheets, and comforters, shall be thoroughly aired, disinfected, and kept clean. Bedding, including mattresses, quilts, blankets, pillows, sheets, or comforters, may not be used if they are worn out or unfit for further use.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator of any establishment licensed under this chapter shall take effective measures to protect the establishment against the entrance and the breeding on the premises of all vermin. Any room in such establishment infested with such vermin shall be fumigated, disinfected, renovated, or other corrective action taken until the vermin are exterminated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person, while suffering from any contagious or communicable disease, while a carrier of such disease, or while afflicted with boils or infected wounds or sores, may not be employed by any establishment licensed under this chapter, in any capacity whereby there is a likelihood such disease could be transmitted to other individuals. An operator that has reason to believe that an employee may present a public health risk shall immediately notify the proper health authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (2), (5), and (6) do not apply to any facility or unit classified as a vacation rental or nontransient apartment as described in s. 509.242(1)(c) and (d).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 12-16, 24-26, 32, ch. 6952, ss. 1-5, ch. 6953, 1915; RGS 2132-2136, 2144-2146, 2152-2156, 5642; ss. 5, 6, 10, ch. 9264, 1923; ss. 3, 4, ch. 12053, 1927; CGL 3361-3365, 3373-3375, 3381-3385, 7836; ss. 14-18, 26-28, 34-37, ch. 16042, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 3361-3365, 3373-3375, 3381, 3382, 3384, 3385; s. 8, ch. 57-389; s. 1, ch. 59-152; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 71-157; s. 18, ch. 73-325; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 17, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; s. 388, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 4, ch. 82-84; ss. 3, 4, ch. 83-241; ss. 23, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 9, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 8, ch. 93-53; s. 7, ch. 96-384; s. 48, ch. 2000-141; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372; s. 6, ch. 2008-55; s. 3, ch. 2011-119.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 511.13-511.17, 511.25-511.27, 511.35-511.37, 511.42.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>