<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.036" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public food service inspector standardization.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person performing required inspections of licensed public food service establishments for the division or its agent must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be standardized by a food service evaluation officer certified by the federal Food and Drug Administration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pass an approved food protection practices test as prescribed by s. 509.039; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pass a written examination to demonstrate knowledge of the laws and rules which regulate public food service establishments.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division or its agent shall provide a minimum of 20 hours of continuing education annually for each public food service inspector. This continuing education shall include instruction in techniques to prevent food-borne illness, sanitation, and a review of relevant laws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division and its agent shall adopt rules in accordance with the provisions of chapter 120 to provide for disciplinary action in cases of inspector negligence. An inspector may be subject to suspension or dismissal for cause as set forth in s. 110.227.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any costs incurred as a direct result of the requirements of subsection (1) shall be funded from the Hotel and Restaurant Trust Fund from the amounts deposited from public food service establishment license fees.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 90-339; s. 15, ch. 91-201; s. 56, ch. 91-297; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 23, ch. 92-180; s. 15, ch. 93-53; s. 31, ch. 2002-299.</History></Section>