<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0509.101" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Establishment rules; posting of notice; food service inspection report; maintenance of guest register; mobile food dispensing vehicle registry.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any operator of a public lodging establishment or a public food service establishment may establish reasonable rules and regulations for the management of the establishment and its guests and employees; and each guest or employee staying, sojourning, eating, or employed in the establishment shall conform to and abide by such rules and regulations so long as the guest or employee remains in or at the establishment. Such rules and regulations shall be deemed to be a special contract between the operator and each guest or employee using the services or facilities of the operator. Such rules and regulations shall control the liabilities, responsibilities, and obligations of all parties. Any rules or regulations established pursuant to this section shall be printed in the English language and posted in a prominent place within such public lodging establishment or public food service establishment. In addition, any operator of a public food service establishment shall maintain the latest food service inspection report or a duplicate copy on premises and shall make it available to the public upon request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the duty of each operator of a transient establishment to maintain at all times a register, signed by or for guests who occupy rental units within the establishment, showing the dates upon which the rental units were occupied by such guests and the rates charged for their occupancy. This register shall be maintained in chronological order and available for inspection by the division at any time. Operators need not make available registers which are more than 2 years old.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the duty of each operator of a public food service establishment that provides commissary services to maintain a daily registry verifying that each mobile food dispensing vehicle that receives such services is properly licensed by the division. In order that such licensure may be readily verified, each mobile food dispensing vehicle operator shall permanently affix in a prominent place on the side of the vehicle, in figures at least 2 inches high and in contrasting colors from the background, the operator’s public food service establishment license number. Prior to providing commissary services, each public food service establishment must verify that the license number displayed on the vehicle matches the number on the vehicle operator’s public food service establishment license.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 1999, 1874; RS 871; GS 1229; RGS 2353; CGL 3757; s. 38, ch. 16042, 1933; s. 5, ch. 57-389; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 5, ch. 73-325; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 7, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 10, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 4, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 5, ch. 93-53; s. 6, ch. 96-384; s. 4, ch. 2008-55.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 510.02.</Text></Note></Section>