<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0509.241" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licenses required; exceptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LICENSES; ANNUAL RENEWALS.<EmDash />Each public lodging establishment and public food service establishment shall obtain a license from the division. Such license may not be transferred from one place or individual to another. It shall be a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, for such an establishment to operate without a license. Local law enforcement shall provide immediate assistance in pursuing an illegally operating establishment. The division may refuse a license, or a renewal thereof, to any establishment that is not constructed and maintained in accordance with law and with the rules of the division. The division may refuse to issue a license, or a renewal thereof, to any establishment an operator of which, within the preceding 5 years, has been adjudicated guilty of, or has forfeited a bond when charged with, any crime reflecting on professional character, including soliciting for prostitution, pandering, letting premises for prostitution, keeping a disorderly place, or illegally dealing in controlled substances as defined in chapter 893, whether in this state or in any other jurisdiction within the United States, or has had a license denied, revoked, or suspended pursuant to s. 429.14. Licenses shall be renewed annually, and the division shall adopt a rule establishing a staggered schedule for license renewals. If any license expires while administrative charges are pending against the license, the proceedings against the license shall continue to conclusion as if the license were still in effect.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICATION FOR LICENSE.<EmDash />Each person who plans to open a public lodging establishment or a public food service establishment shall apply for and receive a license from the division prior to the commencement of operation. A condominium association, as defined in s. 718.103, which does not own any units classified as vacation rentals under s. 509.242(1)(c) is not required to apply for or receive a public lodging establishment license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISPLAY OF LICENSE.<EmDash />Any license issued by the division shall be conspicuously displayed in the office or lobby of the licensed establishment. Public food service establishments which offer catering services shall display their license number on all advertising for catering services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 3-5, 8, ch. 6952, 1915; RGS 2124-2126, 2129; ss. 3, 4, ch. 9264, 1923; s. 6, ch. 12053, 1927; CGL 3353-3355, 3358; s. 1, ch. 13659, 1929; ss. 6-8, 13, ch. 16042, 1933; CGL 1936 Supp. 3353, 3354; s. 1, ch. 23930, 1947; ss. 5, 6, ch. 29821, 1955; s. 1, ch. 29820, 1955; s. 9, ch. 57-389; s. 1, ch. 57-824; s. 1, ch. 61-81; s. 1, ch. 67-507; ss. 16, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 4, ch. 70-281; s. 480, ch. 71-136; s. 6, ch. 71-157; s. 19, ch. 73-325; s. 20, ch. 75-233; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 17, ch. 78-336; s. 1, ch. 78-343; ss. 18, 20, 39, 42, ch. 79-240; ss. 3, 4, ch. 81-161; s. 389, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 4, ch. 86-174; s. 23, ch. 89-294; ss. 25, 51, 52, ch. 90-339; s. 10, ch. 91-40; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 97, ch. 2006-197; s. 4, ch. 2011-119.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former ss. 511.01-511.03, 511.10.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>