<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0588.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition of impounded livestock.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the impounding of any livestock by the sheriff or his or her deputies or designees, or any other law enforcement officers of the county, the county animal control center, or state highway patrol officers, the sheriff shall forthwith serve written notice upon the owner, advising such owner of the location or place where the livestock is being held and impounded, of the amount due by reason of such impounding, and that unless such livestock be redeemed within 3 days from date thereof that the same shall be offered for sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the owner of such livestock is unknown or cannot be found, service upon the owner shall be obtained by once publishing a notice in a newspaper of general circulation where the livestock is impounded (Sundays and holidays excluded). If there be no such newspaper then by posting of the notice at the courthouse door and at two other conspicuous places within said county.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Such notice shall be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">“To Whom It May Concern:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">You are hereby notified that the following described livestock <Directions xml:space="preserve">(giving full and accurate description of same, including marks and brands)</Directions> is now impounded at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(giving location where livestock is impounded)</Directions> and the amount due by reason of such impounding is <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> dollars. The above described livestock will, unless redeemed within 3 days from date hereof, be offered for sale at public auction to the highest and best bidder for cash.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Date)</Directions><FlushRight /><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Sheriff)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceBelow="true">of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the impounded livestock is redeemed within 3 days from date of notice, the sheriff shall forthwith give notice of sale thereof which shall be held not less than 5 days nor more than 10 days (excluding Sundays and holidays) from the first publication of the notice of sale. Said notice of sale shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the said county (excluding Sundays and holidays) and by posting a copy of such notice at the courthouse door. If there be no such newspaper then by posting such copy at the courthouse door and at two other conspicuous places in said county.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Such notice of sale shall be in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">“<Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of owner, if known, otherwise ‘To Whom It May Concern’)</Directions> you are hereby notified that I will offer for sale and sell at public sale to the highest and best bidder for cash the following described livestock <Directions xml:space="preserve">(giving full and accurate description of each head of livestock)</Directions> at <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> o’clock, <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> m. (the hour of sale to be between 11 a.m. and 2 p.m. Eastern Standard Time) on the <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> day of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> at the following place <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> (which place shall be where the livestock is impounded or at the place provided by the county commissioners for the taking up and keeping of such livestock) to satisfy a claim in the sum of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> for fees, expenses for feeding and care and costs hereof.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Date)</Directions><FlushRight /><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Sheriff)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight">of <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 25236, 1949; s. 3, ch. 77-200; s. 945, ch. 97-103; s. 34, ch. 99-391.</History></Section>