<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0616.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Permit from Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services required.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual public fair may not be conducted by a fair association without a permit issued by the department. The association shall present to the department an application for a permit, signed by an officer of the association, at least 3 months before holding the annual public fair. The application shall be accompanied by a fee in an amount to be determined by the department for processing the application and making any required investigation. The application fee must be at least $183 and may not exceed $366. Fees collected under this subsection shall be deposited in the General Inspection Trust Fund of the State Treasury in a special account to be known as the “Agricultural and Livestock Fair Account.” A copy of the application must be sent to each fair association located within 50 miles of the site of the proposed annual public fair at the same time the application is sent to the department. The department may issue a permit if the applicant provides:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The opening and closing dates of the proposed annual public fair.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the owner of the central amusement attraction that will operate during the annual public fair.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An affidavit properly executed by the president or chief executive officer of the applicant association certifying the existence of a binding contract entered into by the association and the owner of the central amusement attraction covering the period for which the permit from the department is applied. The contract between the parties shall be available for inspection by duly authorized agents of the department in administering this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written statement that the main purpose of the association is to conduct and operate a public fair and exposition, including the annual fair, for the benefit and development of the educational, agricultural, horticultural, livestock, charitable, historical, civic, cultural, scientific, and other resources of the geographical area the fair association represents and serves. The statement must be subscribed and acknowledged by an officer of the association before an officer authorized to take acknowledgments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A premium list of the current annual public fair to be conducted or a copy of the previous year’s premium list showing all premiums and awards to be offered to exhibitors in various departments of the annual public fair, which may include, but are not limited to, art exhibition, beef cattle, county exhibits, dairy cattle, horticulture, swine, women’s department, 4-H Club activities, Future Farmers of America activities, Future Homemakers of America activities, poultry and egg exhibits, and community exhibits. The premium list, which may be submitted separately from the application, must be submitted at least 60 days before the annual public fair begins operation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of liability insurance insuring the association against liability for injury to persons, in an amount of not less than $300,000 per occurrence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the most recent review.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of all current members of the board of directors of the association and their contact information, including home address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department shall issue the permit within 10 days after it receives all the information and the applicant qualifies pursuant to this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall administer and enforce the provisions of this chapter except as to the regulation of games, which shall be regulated by local law enforcement agencies. The department shall adopt rules to administer this chapter, including rules governing the form and contents of the application for the permit and any reports that it may deem necessary in enforcing the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any fair association meeting the requirements set forth in subsection (1), the department may order a full investigation to determine if the fair association meets the requirements of s. 616.01, and may withhold a permit from, deny a permit to, or withdraw a permit once issued to the association. The department shall also consider whether any proposed annual public fair, as set forth in an application for a permit, will compete with another annual public fair within 50 miles of the proposed annual public fair with respect to name, dates of operation, or market. The department may deny, withhold, or withdraw a permit from a fair association if the department determines that such fair association will compete with another association. The department shall give preference to existing fair associations with established dates, locations, and names. The determination by the department is final.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 57-796; s. 6, ch. 59-166; s. 2, ch. 61-119; s. 4, ch. 67-491; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 81-297; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 14, 25, 26, ch. 83-239; s. 15, ch. 92-4; ss. 20, 44, ch. 93-168; s. 2, ch. 94-297; s. 21, ch. 99-391; s. 12, ch. 2000-272; s. 14, ch. 2012-204.</History>
</Section>