<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0616.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Association authorized to contract with municipality, county, or state for use of land; admission fees; state, counties, and municipalities authorized to make contributions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any fair association may enter into any contract, lease, or agreement with any municipality or county in the state or with the state or agency or subdivision of the state for the donation to or the use and occupation by the association of any land owned, leased, or held by the county or municipality or the state or agency or subdivision of the state during a time and on the terms approved by the county or municipality or the state or agency or subdivision, with the right of the association to use the property for public exposition purposes. The state, the Department of Transportation and any other agency or subdivision of the state, the board of county commissioners of any county within which the fair or exhibition is held, and the mayor and city council of any municipality within the county may also make contributions of money, property, or services to fair associations to assist in carrying out the purposes of the associations under this chapter. The state or any agency or subdivision of the state, boards of county commissioners of the various counties of the state, and the mayor and city council of any municipality within the county may expend such sums of money as they deem necessary for the best interests of their counties and in aiding the development of the educational, agricultural, horticultural, livestock, charitable, historical, civic, cultural, scientific, and any other resources of their counties at and in connection with public fairs and expositions, including the offering and paying of premiums for the exhibitions of resources of the state, county, or municipality.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 7388, 1917; RGS 4527; CGL 6526; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 25, 26, ch. 83-239; ss. 15, 44, ch. 93-168; s. 10, ch. 2012-204.</History>
</Section>