<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0616.001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Annual public fair” means a community, county, district, regional, or state fair that is held and conducted by a fair association and permitted by the department pursuant to s. 616.15.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Authority” means the Florida State Fair Authority.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community fair” means an annual public fair that serves an area of less than an entire county, has exhibits that are in accordance with s. 616.17, and gives premiums or awards to exhibitors. Agricultural products shall be produced in the community the exhibit represents. The majority of the board of directors of the fair shall reside, be employed, or operate a business in the community the fair represents.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Concession” means use by a fair association, or a grant, lease, or license to a third party, of a portion of the land under the ownership, custody, or control of a fair association for specific uses, or the right to enter upon the land for specific purposes, such as providing rides, games, food, beverage, merchandise for sale, exhibits, projects, activities, events, programs, or other uses authorized in this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“County fair” means an annual public fair that serves an entire county and provides exhibitors with premiums or awards for exhibits that are in accordance with s. 616.17. Agricultural products must be typical of those produced in the county the exhibit represents. The majority of the board of directors of the fair shall reside, be employed, or operate a business in the county that the fair association represents.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District fair” means an annual public fair that serves at least five counties and has exhibits that meet the requirements of s. 616.17. A district fair shall pay at least $25,000 in cash premiums or awards to exhibitors. Agricultural products must be typical of those produced in the counties the exhibit represents. Livestock may originate from outside the district, but must be registered in the exhibitor’s name at least 30 days before the opening day of the fair. Each county is encouraged to have proportionate exhibits, typical of its respective natural resources. Each county shall have exhibits representing basic resources in agriculture and industry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Entry” means one item entered for competition or show. An entry may constitute an exhibit, depending upon the regulations stated in the premium book.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exhibit” means one or more entries entered for exhibition and constituting a unit. An exhibit may consist of one or more entries, depending upon the regulations stated in the premium book. The term includes parades and displays of articles or a collection of articles, whether static, interactive, or dynamic, by a fair association or a third party contracting with a fair association, such as exhibits of animals, art, housewares, or motor vehicles.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exhibitor” means an individual, group of individuals, or business, including a fair association or third party contracting with a fair association, which has an exhibit.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fair association” or “association” means an association not for profit incorporated under this chapter for the purpose of conducting and operating public fairs or expositions.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public fair or exposition” means a project, activity, event, or program, and use by a fair association, including, but not limited to, the annual public fair, which serves the purposes specified in s. 616.08 and benefits and develops the educational, agricultural, horticultural, livestock, charitable, historical, civic, cultural, scientific, and other resources of this state, or any county, municipality, or other community in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Regional fair” or “interstate fair” means an annual public fair of this state and other states in which fair exhibits meet the requirements of s. 616.17. Agricultural products must be typical of those produced in the area the exhibit represents.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Specialized show” means a show or exhibition exhibiting and emphasizing livestock or poultry, or a fruit or vegetable festival, and must meet the minimum exhibit requirements specified in s. 616.17. A specialized show may qualify under one of the definitions in subsections (3), (5), (7), and (15).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State fair” means an annual public fair that serves the entire state. Exhibits must comply with s. 616.17, and cash premiums or awards may be given to exhibitors.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 63-247; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 1, 25, 26, ch. 83-239; s. 6, ch. 87-226; s. 94, ch. 92-291; ss. 1, 44, ch. 93-168; s. 25, ch. 96-231; s. 11, ch. 2000-272; s. 1, ch. 2012-204.</History>
</Section>