<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0616.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of application; approval and record of charter.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A notice of intention to apply to the circuit court for the charter of a fair association must specify the date that application will be made, shall be sent to the department for approval, and shall be published in a newspaper in the county where the principal office of the association will be located once each week for 4 consecutive weeks. The notice must briefly summarize the charter and objectives of the proposed association. The proposed charter shall be submitted to and approved by the board of county commissioners of the county in which the principal office of the association will be located. After approval by the department and the board of county commissioners, the proposed charter and proof of approval and publication shall be submitted to the circuit judge on the date specified in the notice. If no cause is shown to the contrary and the judge finds that the proposed charter is in proper form and will serve the primary objective of public service, the judge shall approve the charter and issue an order incorporating the subscribers under the charter for the objectives and purposes specified in the charter. The charter and order of incorporation shall be recorded in the office of the clerk of the circuit court in the county where the principal office of the association will be located and provided to the department. After the order is recorded, the subscribers and their associates are incorporated with the objectives and powers established in the charter and under the name given in the charter. During the publication period, the proposed charter shall be on file in the office of the clerk of the circuit court. This section does not preclude a fair association from also filing its duly approved charter with the Department of State pursuant to chapter 617 for notice purposes.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 7388, 1917; s. 1, ch. 17806, 1937; RGS 4519; CGL 6518; s. 1, ch. 63-247; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 25, 26, ch. 83-239; ss. 4, 44, ch. 93-168; s. 4, ch. 2012-204.</History>
</Section>