<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0616.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Members not personally liable; property of association held in trust; exempt from taxation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member, officer, director, or trustee of a fair association is not personally liable for any of the debts of the association, and money or property of a fair association may not be distributed as profits or dividends among its members, officers, directors, or trustees.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All money and property of the association, except that necessary for the payment of its just debts and liabilities, are public property, shall be administered by the association as trustee, and shall be used exclusively for the legitimate purpose of the association. So long as they are used for that purpose, all money and property of the association are exempt from all forms of taxation, including special assessments, and any projects, activities, events, programs, and uses authorized by this part serve an essential governmental purpose and, therefore, are not taxable and are not subject to assessments. This subsection does not apply to chapter 212.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon order of the circuit judge, any public funds or property remaining in a fair association when the association is dissolved shall be distributed by resolution of the board of directors to any county or any municipality within the county. The board may designate in the distribution resolution the public project that will benefit from the funds or the manner in which the property will be used. If property has been contributed by a municipality or county, the property shall be reconveyed to the municipality or county that gave the property to the association.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 7388, 1917; RGS 4523; CGL 6522; s. 2, ch. 29914, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-745; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 25, 26, ch. 83-239; ss. 9, 44, ch. 93-168; s. 18, ch. 99-391; s. 7, ch. 2012-204.</History>
</Section>