<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0616.256" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall have power to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have a seal and alter the same at its pleasure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire, hold, lease, and dispose of real and personal property for authorized purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Own, operate, maintain, repair, and improve its facilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire in its own name by purchase, grant, gift, or lease, on such terms and conditions and in such manner as it may deem proper, real and personal property, and acquire, construct, reconstruct, improve, alter, repair, maintain, operate, sell, convey, lease, and dispose of any building, structure, or facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ the executive director appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture at the compensation set by the commissioner. Employ other managers, consulting engineers, architects, accountants, inspectors, attorneys, and such other employees as may be deemed necessary and prescribe their powers and duties and fix their compensation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accept loans or grants of money, property, or personal services from any agency, corporation, or person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make and enter into all contracts or agreements, as the authority may determine, which are necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties or the execution of its powers under this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Borrow money for any of its authorized purposes and for expenses incidental thereto, including expenses incurred during the period of organization and construction prior to the operation of the Florida State Fair, and incur obligations with respect to such borrowings, including notes, secured or unsecured, and negotiable revenue bonds, as hereinafter provided, payable solely from revenues accruing from the operation of the Florida State Fair or any part or parts thereof and from authorized activities incidental thereto; pay interest with respect to such borrowings not exceeding the maximum allowable by law; provide for the payment of such borrowings and interest as hereinafter provided; fix rates and make collections for the use of the facilities and services of the authority; and execute mortgages, trust indentures, or other instruments, as may be required for the financing of the authorized activities of the authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage in any lawful business or activity deemed by it to be necessary, convenient, appropriate, or useful in the full exercise of its powers to establish, finance, and operate the Florida State Fair under the provisions of this part, including the leasing for revenue of any land, improved real estate, or personal property directly related to, or appropriate in connection with, the financing or conduct of the Florida State Fair or reserved for its future use or expansion. Within the meaning of this part, any use of the property of the authority, real or personal, shall be deemed necessary, convenient, appropriate, or useful which stimulates, assists, fosters, and promotes all phases of the economy of the state, including agricultural, industrial, commercial, cultural, and recreational pursuits, or which provides revenue to the authority from the property, pending its future use for any of the purposes of the state fair.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement provisions of law conferring duties upon it.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that the authority, when contracting for the acquisition of personal property or services pursuant to this section, give consideration to increasing the number of contractors that are minority businesses.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 74-322; s. 4, ch. 81-81; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 25, 26, ch. 83-239; ss. 31, 44, ch. 93-168; s. 6, ch. 95-220; s. 15, ch. 95-317; s. 29, ch. 96-231; s. 197, ch. 98-200.</History></Section>