<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0599.003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State Viticulture Plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commissioner of Agriculture, in consultation with the Viticulture Advisory Council, shall develop and coordinate the implementation of the State Viticulture Plan, which shall identify problems and constraints of the viticulture industry, propose possible solutions to those problems, and develop planning mechanisms for the orderly growth of the industry, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Criteria for viticultural research, service, and management priorities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additional proposed legislation that may be required.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plans and goals to improve research and service capabilities at Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University and the University of Florida in their efforts to address current and future needs of the industry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The potential for viticulture products in terms of market and needs for development.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation of wine policy alternatives, including, but not limited to, continued improvement in wine quality, blending considerations, promotion and advertising, labeling and vineyard designations, and development of production and marketing strategies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation of production and fresh fruit policy alternatives, including, but not limited to, setting minimum grades and standards, promotion and advertising, development of production and marketing strategies, and setting minimum standards on types and quality of nursery plants.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation of policy alternatives for nonwine processed products, including, but not limited to, setting minimum quality standards and development of production and marketing strategies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Research and service priorities for further development of the viticulture industry.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identification of state agencies and public and private institutions concerned with research, education, extension, services, planning, promotion, and marketing functions related to viticultural development and the delineation of contributions and responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business planning, investment potential, financial risks, and economics of production and utilization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A revision and update of the State Viticulture Plan shall be submitted biennially to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the chairs of appropriate committees of the Senate and House of Representatives, and a progress report and budget request shall be submitted annually.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 4, 6, ch. 84-295; s. 2, ch. 85-111; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 4, ch. 94-296.</History></Section>