<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0406.075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Grounds for discipline; disciplinary proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A medical examiner may be reprimanded, placed on a period of probation, removed, or suspended by the Medical Examiners Commission for any of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with the provisions of this chapter or with the rules of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misuse or misappropriation of public funds or property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Being convicted or found guilty, regardless of adjudication, of a crime in any jurisdiction which directly relates to the duties of the district medical examiner or the ability to perform the duties of the medical examiner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disciplinary action against him or her by any state board licensing him or her as a physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Having a financial interest in any funeral or direct disposal establishment or transportation service which does business, directly or indirectly, with the office of the district medical examiner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A material misrepresentation of his or her education, training, experience, or expertise while in his or her capacity as a medical examiner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A material misrepresentation of data upon which an opinion or conclusion as a medical examiner is based.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of s. 406.11(2)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Negligence or the failure to perform the duties required of a medical examiner with that level of care or skill which is recognized by reasonably prudent medical examiners as being acceptable under similar conditions and circumstances.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall cause to be investigated any complaint which is filed before it if the complaint is in writing, signed by the complainant, and legally sufficient. A complaint is legally sufficient if it contains ultimate facts which show a violation of this chapter or of any rule promulgated by the commission. The commission may investigate and take action on a complaint even though the complainant withdraws the complaint. The commission may investigate a complaint from a confidential informant if the complaint is substantial, if the alleged violation is substantial, if the complaint is legally sufficient, and if the commission has reason to believe, after inquiry, that the allegations are true. When an investigation of any district medical examiner or associate medical examiner is commenced, the commission shall notify the person against whom the complaint was made of the substance of the investigation, unless the commission chair agrees in writing that such notification would be detrimental to the investigation. The commission may conduct an investigation without notification to any person if the act under investigation is a criminal offense. The commission chair shall direct the commission staff to perform an expeditious investigation into the facts of the case, with the assistance of the Department of Law Enforcement, if needed. The staff report shall contain investigative findings and recommendations as to probable cause.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission chair shall appoint a probable cause panel of three members from among the commission membership, one of whom shall be a medical examiner. The probable cause panel may request staff to perform additional investigations as it sees fit.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The determination as to whether or not probable cause exists shall be made by a majority vote of the probable cause panel within 30 working days of its receipt of staff investigative findings and recommendations. The commission chair may grant 30-day extensions of the 30 working day time limit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All proceedings and findings of the probable cause panel are exempt from the provisions of s. 286.011 until probable cause has been found or until the subject of the investigation waives confidentiality. The complaint, all investigative findings, and the recommendations of the probable cause panel are exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) until 10 days after probable cause has been found or until the subject of the investigation waives confidentiality. The commission may provide such information at any time to any law enforcement agency or to any regulatory agency.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the probable cause panel finds that probable cause exists, it shall direct the commission to file a formal complaint against the subject of the investigation. The commission shall file a formal complaint pursuant to the provisions of chapter 120. The probable cause panel may also direct the commission to suspend a district medical examiner from office immediately, under the provisions of s. 120.60(6), if a danger to public health, safety, or welfare so requires.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A formal hearing before an administrative law judge from the Division of Administrative Hearings of the Department of Management Services shall be held pursuant to chapter 120 unless all parties agree in writing that there is no disputed issue of material fact. The administrative law judge shall issue a recommended order pursuant to chapter 120. If any party raises an issue of disputed fact during an informal hearing, the hearing shall be terminated and a formal hearing pursuant to chapter 120 shall be held.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission, with those members of the probable cause panel who reviewed the case being excused from voting, shall determine and issue the final order in each disciplinary case, and such order shall constitute final agency action. Any consent order or agreed settlement shall be subject to the approval of the commission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall periodically notify the person who filed the complaint of the status of the investigation, whether probable cause has been found, and the status of any civil action or administrative proceeding or appeal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A privilege against civil liability is hereby granted to any complainant or any witness with regard to information furnished during any investigation or proceeding pursuant to this section, unless the complainant or witness acted in bad faith or with malice in providing such information.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 87-359; s. 2, ch. 88-303; s. 9, ch. 90-344; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 128, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 246, ch. 96-406; s. 189, ch. 96-410; s. 1015, ch. 97-103; s. 2, ch. 98-253.</History></Section>