<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0406.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of fees, salaries, and expenses; transportation costs; facilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees, salaries, and expenses may be paid from the general funds or any other funds under the control of the board of county commissioners. The district medical examiner shall submit an annual budget to the board of county commissioners.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event that an examination or autopsy is performed by the district medical examiner or his or her associate upon a body when the death occurred outside the district, the governmental body requesting the examination or autopsy shall pay the fee for such services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a body is transported to the district medical examiner or his or her associate, transportation costs, if any, shall be borne by the county in which the death occurred. Nothing within this chapter shall preclude payment for services to the district medical examiner by the state, either in part or on a matching basis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, if an examination, investigation, or autopsy is performed by the district medical examiner or his or her associate upon the body of a person who died while in the custody of a facility or institution operated by a state agency, that state agency shall pay for such services and for any costs of transporting the body to the district medical examiner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Autopsy and laboratory facilities utilized by the district medical examiner or his or her associates may be provided on a permanent or contractual basis by the counties within the district.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 70-232; s. 144, ch. 77-104; s. 3, ch. 81-89; s. 1, ch. 85-268; s. 4, ch. 87-359; s. 28, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>