<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0406.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Examinations, investigations, and autopsies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any of the following circumstances involving the death of a human being, the medical examiner of the district in which the death occurred or the body was found shall determine the cause of death and shall, for that purpose, make or have performed such examinations, investigations, and autopsies as he or she shall deem necessary or as shall be requested by the state attorney:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any person dies in the state:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of criminal violence.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By accident.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By suicide.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suddenly, when in apparent good health.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unattended by a practicing physician or other recognized practitioner.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any prison or penal institution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In police custody.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any suspicious or unusual circumstance.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By criminal abortion.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By poison.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By disease constituting a threat to public health.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By disease, injury, or toxic agent resulting from employment.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a dead body is brought into the state without proper medical certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a body is to be cremated, dissected, or buried at sea.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district medical examiner shall have the authority in any case coming under subsection (1) to perform, or have performed, whatever autopsies or laboratory examinations he or she deems necessary and in the public interest to determine the identification of or cause or manner of death of the deceased or to obtain evidence necessary for forensic examination.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Medical Examiners Commission shall adopt rules, pursuant to chapter 120, providing for the notification of the next of kin that an investigation by the medical examiner’s office is being conducted. A medical examiner may not retain or furnish any body part of the deceased for research or any other purpose which is not in conjunction with a determination of the identification of or cause or manner of death of the deceased or the presence of disease or which is not otherwise authorized by this chapter, part V of chapter 765, or chapter 873, without notification of and approval by the next of kin.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Medical Examiners Commission may adopt rules incorporating by reference parameters or guidelines of practice or standards of conduct relating to examinations, investigations, or autopsies performed by medical examiners.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 70-232; s. 26, ch. 73-334; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 87-166; s. 29, ch. 97-103; s. 3, ch. 98-253; s. 48, ch. 2006-1.</History></Section>