<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0668.704" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Remedies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following persons may bring a civil action against a person who violates this part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person engaged in the business of providing Internet access service to the public who is adversely affected by the violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financial institution as defined in s. 655.005(1) that is adversely affected by the violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner of a web page, trademark, or service mark who is adversely affected by the violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Attorney General.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person bringing an action under this section may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek injunctive relief to restrain the violator from continuing the violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recover damages in an amount equal to the greater of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actual damages arising from the violation; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sum of $5,000 for each violation of the same nature.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may increase an award of actual damages in an action brought under this section to an amount not to exceed three times the actual damages sustained if the court finds that the violations have occurred with a frequency as to constitute a pattern or practice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, violations are of the same nature if the violations consist of the same course of conduct or action, regardless of the number of times the conduct or action occurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plaintiff who prevails in an action filed under this section is entitled to recover reasonable attorney’s fees and court costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By committing a violation under this part, the violator submits personally to the jurisdiction of the courts of this state. This section does not preclude other methods of obtaining jurisdiction over a person who commits a violation under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action under this part may be brought in any court of competent jurisdiction to enforce such rights and to recover damages as stated in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The venue for a civil action brought under this section shall be the county in which the plaintiff resides or in any county in which any part of the alleged violation under this part took place, regardless of whether the defendant was ever actually present in that county. A civil action filed under this section must be brought within 3 years after the violation occurred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remedies available under this section are in addition to remedies otherwise available for the same conduct under federal or state law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any moneys received by the Attorney General for attorney’s fees and costs of investigation or litigation in proceedings brought under this section shall be deposited as received into the Legal Affairs Revolving Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any moneys received by the Attorney General which are not for attorney’s fees and costs of investigation or litigation or used for reimbursing persons found under this part to be damaged shall accrue to the state and be deposited as received into the Legal Affairs Revolving Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Legal Affairs may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-232.</History></Section>