<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0668.003" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this act:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate” means a computer-based record which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identifies the certification authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identifies the subscriber.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contains the subscriber’s public key.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is digitally signed by the certification authority.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certification authority” means a person who issues a certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Digital signature” means a type of electronic signature that transforms a message using an asymmetric cryptosystem such that a person having the initial message and the signer’s public key can accurately determine:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the transformation was created using the private key that corresponds to the signer’s public key.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the initial message has been altered since the transformation was made.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A “key pair” is a private key and its corresponding public key in an asymmetric cryptosystem, under which the public key verifies a digital signature the private key creates. An “asymmetric cryptosystem” is an algorithm or series of algorithms which provide a secure key pair.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electronic signature” means any letters, characters, or symbols, manifested by electronic or similar means, executed or adopted by a party with an intent to authenticate a writing. A writing is electronically signed if an electronic signature is logically associated with such writing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 96-224.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 282.72.</Text></Note></Section>