<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0502.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Milk and milk products which may be sold.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only Grade “A” pasteurized milk and milk products, pasteurized manufactured milk products, ice cream, and frozen desserts, and cheese made from pasteurized milk shall be sold at retail to the final consumer or to food service establishments as defined in chapter 381, food establishments as defined in chapter 500, or public food service establishments as defined in chapter 509. Cheese made from raw milk may also be sold at retail to the final consumer or to food service establishments as defined in chapter 381, food establishments as defined in chapter 500, or public food service establishments as defined in chapter 509 if the cheese is aged more than 60 days at a temperature above 35° F.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an emergency, however, the department may authorize the sale of reconstituted pasteurized milk products, or pasteurized milk and milk products that have not been graded or the grade of which is unknown, in which case such milk and milk products shall be appropriately labeled, as determined by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department determines that milk is fit for human consumption even though it is less than Grade “A” because the producer failed to comply with the sanitation or bacterial standards defined in this chapter, or if any specific shipment of milk fails to comply with standards of the Grade “A” pasteurized milk ordinance, the department may issue a permit allowing the milk to be used in ungraded products, such as frozen desserts, which are being processed by such milk plant. During processing of such milk, it shall be pasteurized at a temperature of at least 175° F. for at least 15 seconds or at least 160° F. for at least 30 minutes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Milk that is in final package form for beverage use shall have been pasteurized and shall contain at least 8.25 percent milk solids-not-fat and at least 3.25 percent milkfat.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 67-263; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 75-14; s. 4, ch. 80-83; s. 17, ch. 92-180; s. 5, ch. 93-68; ss. 9, 15, ch. 94-92; s. 15, ch. 2001-279; s. 9, ch. 2005-210; s. 8, ch. 2007-67; s. 24, ch. 2011-206.</History></Section>