<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.505" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proposals; application process; minimum requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or counties which desire to receive state funding under ss. 154.501-154.506 shall submit an application to the department. The department shall develop an application process for the Primary Care for Children and Families Challenge Grant Program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Applications shall be competitively reviewed by an independent panel appointed by the State Surgeon General. This panel shall determine the relative weight for scoring and evaluating each of the following elements to be used in the evaluation process:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The target population to be served.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The health benefits to be provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed service network, including specific health care providers and health care facilities that will participate in the service network on a paid or voluntary basis.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The methods that will be used to measure cost-effectiveness.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">How patient and provider satisfaction will be measured.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed internal quality assurance process.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Projected health status outcomes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The way in which data to measure the cost-effectiveness, outcomes, and overall performance of the program will be collected, including a description of the proposed information system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All local resources, including cash, in-kind, voluntary, or other resources, that will be dedicated to the proposal.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preference shall be given to proposals which:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exceed the minimum local contribution requirements specified in s. 154.506.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate broad-based local support for the project, including, but not limited to, agreements to participate in the service network, letters of endorsement, or other forms of support.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate a high degree of participation by health care providers on a free or volunteer basis, or through financial contributions. This may include participation by publicly or privately funded health care providers, such as hospitals, county health departments, community health centers, or rural health clinics, in the service network.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are submitted by counties with a high proportion of children and families living in poverty and with poor health status indicators.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate coordinated service delivery with existing publicly financed health care programs, including those programs specified in s. 154.503(2)(e).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in ss. 154.501-154.506 shall prevent a county or group of counties from contracting for the provision of health care services. A service network may include, but need not be limited to, special health care districts, county health departments, federally qualified health centers, community health centers, and rural health clinics.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 97-263; s. 12, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>