<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.05" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation and agreements between counties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Counties may establish cooperative arrangements for shared county health departments in the following ways:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Two or more counties may combine in the establishment and maintenance of a single full-time county health department for the counties which combine for that purpose; and, pursuant to such combination or agreement, such counties may cooperate with one another and the Department of Health and contribute to a joint fund in carrying out the purpose and intent of this chapter. The duration and nature of such agreement shall be evidenced by resolutions of the boards of county commissioners of such counties and shall be submitted to and approved by the department. In the event of any such agreement, a full-time county health department shall be established and maintained by the department in and for the benefit of the counties which have entered into such an agreement; and, in such case, the funds raised by taxation pursuant to this chapter by each such county shall be paid to the Chief Financial Officer for the account of the department and shall be known as the full-time county health department trust fund of the counties so cooperating. Such trust funds shall be used and expended by the department for the purposes specified in this chapter in each county which has entered into such agreement. In case such an agreement is entered into between two or more counties, the work contemplated by this chapter shall be done by a single full-time county health department in the counties so cooperating; and the nature, extent, and location of such work shall be under the control and direction of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operations of two or more county health departments may be combined when the parties agree to the specific roles and responsibilities of each county and county health department. Such an agreement shall specify the roles and responsibilities of each county and county health department, including the method of governance and executive direction; the manner by which each county’s public health needs will be addressed; an inventory of necessary facilities, equipment, and personnel; and any other needed infrastructure.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 14906, 1931; CGL 1936 Supp. 2934(26); s. 2, ch. 61-119; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 33, ch. 77-147; s. 8, ch. 83-177; s. 21, ch. 97-101; s. 152, ch. 2003-261; s. 3, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>