<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of board of trustees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of trustees of each public health trust shall be deemed to exercise a public and essential governmental function of both the state and the county and in furtherance thereof it shall, subject to limitation by the governing body of the county in which such board is located, have all of the powers necessary or convenient to carry out the operation and governance of designated health care facilities, including, but without limiting the generality of, the foregoing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and be sued; however, this provision shall not be construed to affect in any way the laws relating to governmental immunity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have a seal and alter the same.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make and adopt bylaws and rules and regulations for the board’s guidance and for the operation, governance, and maintenance of designated facilities not inconsistent with ordinances of the county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary to exercise the powers of the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To acquire by purchase or otherwise, and to hold title to, any property, real or personal, useful to the purposes of the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To lease, either as lessee or lessor, or rent for any number of years and upon any terms and conditions real property, except that the board shall not lease or rent, as lessor, any real property except in accordance with the requirements of s. 125.35 [F. S. 1973].</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To appoint a chief executive officer of the trust and to remove such an appointee.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish rates and charges for those using the facilities of, or receiving care or assistance from, the board and to collect money pursuant thereto.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To accept gifts of money, services, or real or personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To appoint, remove, or suspend employees or agents of the board, fix their compensation, and adopt personnel and management policies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide for employee benefits, including, but not limited to, the benefits required by s. 154.10(5) and those benefits provided by s. 154.12(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To cooperate with and contract with any governmental agency or instrumentality, federal, state, municipal, or county.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To adopt and amend rules and regulations for the management and use of any properties under its control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To appoint originally the staff of physicians to practice in any designated facility owned or operated by the board and to approve the bylaws and rules to be adopted by the medical staff of any designated facility owned and operated by the board, such governing regulations to be in accordance with the standards of the Joint Commission on the Accreditation of Hospitals which provide, among other things, for the method of appointing additional staff members and for the removal of staff members.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To employ certified public accountants to audit and analyze the records of the board and to prepare financial or revenue statements of the board; however, this paragraph shall not in any way affect any responsibility of the Auditor General pursuant to s. 11.45.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To employ legal counsel.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public health trust shall have no power to impose any tax or issue bonds of any nature, nor shall it have the power to require the imposition of a tax or the issuance of any bond by the governing body of the county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 5, 6, ch. 73-102; s. 39, ch. 2001-266.</History></Section>