<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Eligibility and benefits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county or counties may apply for a primary care for children and families challenge grant to provide primary health care services to children and families with incomes of up to 150 percent of the federal poverty level. Participants shall pay no monthly premium for participation, but shall be required to pay a copayment at the time a service is provided. Copayments may be paid from sources other than the participant, including, but not limited to, the child’s or parent’s employer, or other private sources. Providers may enter into contracts pursuant to s. 766.1115, provided copayments may not be considered and may not be used as compensation for services to health care providers, and all funds generated from copayments shall be used by the governmental contractor and all other provisions in s. 766.1115 are met.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall prevent counties with populations less than 100,000, based on the annual estimates produced by the Population Program of the University of Florida Bureau of Economic and Business Research, from submitting a multicounty application for a primary care for children and families challenge grant to jointly administer and operate a coordinated multicounty primary care for children and families program under ss. 154.501-154.506. However, when such counties submit a joint application, the application shall clearly identify one lead county with respect to program accountability and administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county or group of counties submitting an application to participate in the Primary Care for Children and Families Challenge Grant Program shall develop a schedule of benefits and services appropriate for the population to be served. However, at a minimum, such benefits must cover preventive and primary care services and include a coordination mechanism for limited inpatient hospital care.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 97-263; s. 13, ch. 98-191; s. 5, ch. 99-397.</History></Section>