<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.219" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revenue bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority is authorized from time to time to issue its negotiable revenue bonds for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of any project or projects for which a certificate of need has been obtained, or pursuant to subsections (12) and (13) of s. 154.209 for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of acquiring existing or completed health facilities projects. In anticipation of the sale of such revenue bonds, the authority may issue negotiable bond anticipation notes and may renew the same from time to time, but the maximum maturity of any such note, including renewals thereof, shall not exceed 5 years from the date of issue of the original note. Such notes shall be paid from any revenues of the authority available therefor and not otherwise pledged or from the proceeds of sale of the revenue bonds of the authority in anticipation of which they were issued. The notes shall be issued in the same manner as the revenue bonds. Such notes and the resolution or resolutions authorizing the same may contain any provisions, conditions, or limitation which a bond resolution of the authority may contain.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The revenue bonds and notes of every issue shall be payable solely out of revenues derived by the authority from the sale, operation, or leasing of any project or projects, subject only to any agreements with the holders of particular revenue bonds or notes pledging any particular revenues. Notwithstanding that revenue bonds and notes may be payable from a special fund, they shall be, and be deemed to be, for all purposes, negotiable instruments, subject only to the provisions of the revenue bonds and notes for registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The revenue bonds may be issued as serial bonds or as term bonds, or the authority, in its discretion, may issue bonds of both types. The revenue bonds shall be authorized by resolution of the members of the authority and shall bear such date or dates; mature at such time or times, not exceeding 50 years from their respective dates; bear interest at such rate or rates; be payable at such time or times; be in such denominations; be in such form, either coupon or registered, or both; carry such registration privileges; be executed in such manner; be payable in lawful money of the United States at such place or places; and be subject to such terms of redemption, including redemption prior to maturity, as such resolution or resolutions may provide. The authority shall determine the form and manner of execution of the bonds, including any interest coupons to be attached thereto, and shall fix the denomination or denominations of the bonds and the place or places of payment of principal and interest, which may be at any bank or trust company within or without the state. In case any officer whose signature, or a facsimile of whose signature, shall appear on any bonds or coupons shall cease to be such officer before the delivery of such bonds, such signature or facsimile shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes the same as if the person had remained in office until such delivery. The authority shall also provide for the authentication of the bonds by a trustee or fiscal agent. The revenue bonds or notes may be sold at public or private sale for such price or prices as the authority shall determine. Pending preparation of the definitive bonds, the authority may issue interim receipts or certificates which shall be exchanged for such definitive bonds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resolution or resolutions authorizing any revenue bonds or any issue of revenue bonds may contain provisions which shall be a part of the contract with the holders of the revenue bonds to be authorized, as to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pledging of all or any part of the revenues of a project to secure the payment of the revenue bonds or of any particular issue of revenue bonds, subject to such agreements with bondholders as may then exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rentals, fees, and other charges to be charged, the amounts to be raised in each year thereby, and the use and disposition of the revenues.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The setting aside of reserves or sinking funds and the regulation and disposition thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the right of the authority to restrict and regulate the use of the project.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the purpose to which the proceeds of sale of any issue of revenue bonds then or thereafter to be issued may be applied and pledging such proceeds to secure the payment of the revenue bonds or any issue of the revenue bonds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the issuance of additional bonds, the terms upon which additional bonds may be issued and secured, and the refunding of outstanding bonds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The procedure, if any, by which the terms of any contract with bondholders may be amended or abrogated, the amount of bonds the holders of which must consent thereto, and the manner in which such consent may be given.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Defining the acts or omissions to act which shall constitute a default in the duties of the authority to holders of its obligations and providing the rights and remedies of such holders in the event of a default.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The mortgaging of a project and the site thereof for the purpose of securing the bondholders.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the members of the authority nor any person executing the revenue bonds or notes shall be liable personally on the revenue bonds or notes or be subject to any personal liability or accountability by reason of the issuance thereof.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 74-323; s. 872, ch. 95-147.</History></Section>