<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Primary Care for Children and Families Challenge Grant Program; creation; administration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effective July 1, 1997, there is created the Primary Care for Children and Families Challenge Grant Program to be administered by the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publicize the availability of funds and the method by which a county or counties may submit a primary care for children and families challenge grant application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a quality assurance process to monitor the quality of health services provided under ss. 154.501-154.506.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide technical assistance, as requested, to primary care for children and families challenge grant recipients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop uniform data reporting requirements for primary care for children and families challenge grant recipients for the purpose of evaluating the performance of the projects.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordinate with the primary care program developed pursuant to s. 154.011, the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation program created in s. 624.91, the school health services program created in ss. 381.0056 and 381.0057, and the volunteer health care provider program developed pursuant to s. 766.1115.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A primary care for children and families challenge grant shall be in effect for 1 year and may be renewed for additional years upon application to and approval by the department, subject to meeting quality standards and outcomes and subject to the availability of funds.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 97-263; s. 59, ch. 99-2; s. 41, ch. 2012-116; s. 117, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>