<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Personnel of county health departments; duties; compensation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personnel of a minimum county health department shall consist of a county health department director or administrator and a full-time public health nurse, a public health environmental specialist, and a clerk. All such personnel shall be selected from those especially trained in public health administration and practice, so far as the same shall relate to the duties of their respective positions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The county health department director shall be a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 who is trained in public health administration and shall be appointed by the State Surgeon General after the concurrence of the boards of county commissioners of the respective counties. A county health department administrator trained in public health administration may be appointed by the State Surgeon General after the concurrence of the boards of county commissioners of the respective counties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A registered nurse or licensed physician assistant working in a county health department is authorized to assess a patient and order medications, provided that:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No licensed physician is on the premises;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The patient is assessed and medication ordered in accordance with rules promulgated by the department and pursuant to a protocol approved by a physician who supervises the patient care activities of the registered nurse or licensed physician assistant;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The patient is being assessed by the registered nurse or licensed physician assistant as a part of a program approved by the department; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The medication ordered appears on a formulary approved by the department and is prepackaged and prelabeled with dosage instructions and distributed from a source authorized under chapter 499 to repackage and distribute drugs, which source is under the supervision of a consultant pharmacist employed by the department.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county health department shall adopt written protocols which provide for supervision of the registered nurse or licensed physician assistant by a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459 and for the procedures by which patients may be assessed, and medications ordered and delivered, by the registered nurse or licensed physician assistant. Such protocols shall be signed by the supervising physician, the director of the county health department, and the registered nurse or licensed physician assistant.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each county health department shall maintain and have available for inspection by representatives of the Department of Health all medical records and patient care protocols, including records of medications delivered to patients, in accordance with rules of the department.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall adopt rules which establish the conditions under which a registered nurse or licensed physician assistant may assess patients and order and deliver medications, based upon written protocols of supervision by a physician licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459, and which establish the formulary from which medications may be ordered.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall require that a consultant pharmacist conduct a periodic inspection of each county health department in meeting the requirements of this paragraph.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county health department may establish or contract with peer review committees or organizations to review the quality of communicable disease control and primary care services provided by the county health department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personnel of the county health department shall be employed by the Department of Health. The compensation of such personnel shall be determined under the rules of the Department of Management Services. Such employees shall engage in the prevention of disease and the promotion of health under the supervision of the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 14906, 1931; CGL 1936 Supp. 2934(25); ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 72-139; s. 2, ch. 72-323; s. 3, ch. 72-345; s. 14, ch. 75-48; s. 32, ch. 77-147; s. 7, ch. 83-177; s. 8, ch. 85-68; ss. 1, 2, ch. 86-83; s. 3, ch. 86-220; s. 4, ch. 88-294; s. 1, ch. 88-361; s. 2, ch. 89-311; ss. 2, 3, ch. 90-232; ss. 2, 3, ch. 90-295; s. 4, ch. 91-22; s. 76, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 8, ch. 94-218; s. 15, ch. 96-403; s. 10, ch. 97-237; s. 2, ch. 98-49; s. 4, ch. 98-279; s. 11, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>