<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Relationship with board of county commissioners.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At such time as the governing body of a county shall declare the need for a public health trust to function in such county, appoint a board of trustees, and designate health care facilities pursuant to the provisions of this part, said governing body shall be authorized to transfer to the public health trust any or all of the ownership, operation, governance, or maintenance of such designated facilities. The county governing body shall, by ordinance, by contract or lease with the public health trust, or by a combination of the foregoing, provide for each of the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method whereby the public health trust shall account to the county governing body for all receipts and expenditures of money.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method whereby the public health trust shall request, and the county governing body may approve, the appropriation and payment of county funds to support the lawful purposes of the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method whereby the public health trust shall request, and said county governing body may effectuate, the issuance of bonds or the borrowing of money, pursuant to authority vested in said governing body of the county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance by the public health trust with policies for countywide health care delivery as established by the county governing body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preservation and continuation of the benefits of county employees who became employees of the public health trust, including, but not limited to, participation by such employees in the State and County Officers and Employees’ Retirement System and the Florida Retirement System. The trust may provide social security for its employees pursuant to the provisions of chapter 650 and may bring its employees under the provisions of the Florida Retirement System as authorized by chapter 121.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An appellate process to be available to employees against whom disciplinary or other official action has been taken.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A procedure whereby the county governing body may approve or disapprove of contracts between the board of trustees and labor unions.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A method whereby the county governing body may declassify facilities as “designated facilities” and provide for the county to assume the ownership, operation, governance, or maintenance of such facilities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 73-102.</History></Section>