<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0154.213" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agreements of lease.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In undertaking any project pursuant to this part, the authority shall first obtain a valid certificate of need evidencing need for the project and a statement that the project serves a public purpose by advancing the commerce, welfare, and prosperity of the local agency and its people. No project financed under the provisions of this part shall be operated by the authority or any other governmental agency; however, the authority may temporarily operate or cause to be operated all or any part of a project to protect its interest therein pending any leasing of such project in accordance with the provisions of this part. The authority may lease a project or projects to a health facility for operation and maintenance in such manner as to effectuate the purposes of this part under an agreement of lease in form and substance not inconsistent herewith.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such agreement of lease may provide, among other provisions, that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lessee shall at its own expense operate, repair, and maintain the project or projects leased thereunder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rent payable under the lease shall in the aggregate be not less than an amount sufficient to pay all of the interest, principal, and redemption premiums, if any, on the bonds that shall be issued by the authority to pay the cost of the project or projects leased thereunder.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lessee shall pay all costs incurred by the authority in connection with the acquisition, financing, construction, and administration of the project or projects leased, except as may be paid out of the proceeds of bonds or otherwise, including, but without being limited to: Insurance costs, the cost of administering the bond resolution authorizing such bonds and any trust agreement securing the bonds, and the fees and expenses of trustees, paying agents, attorneys, consultants, and others.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms of the lease shall terminate not earlier than the date on which all such bonds and all other obligations incurred by the authority in connection with the project or projects leased thereunder shall be paid in full, including interest, principal, and redemption premiums, if any, or adequate funds for such payment shall be deposited in trust.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lessee’s obligation to pay rent shall not be subject to cancellation, termination, or abatement by the lessee until such payment of the bonds or provision for such payment shall be made.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such lease agreement may contain such additional provisions as in the determination of the authority are necessary or convenient to effectuate the purposes of this part, including provisions for extensions of the term and renewals of the lease and vesting in the lessee an option to purchase the project leased thereunder pursuant to such terms and conditions consistent with this part as shall be prescribed in the lease. Except as may otherwise be expressly stated in the agreement of lease, to provide for any contingencies involving the damaging, destruction, or condemnation of the project leased or any substantial portion thereof, such option to purchase may not be exercised unless all bonds issued for such project, including all principal, interest, and redemption premiums, if any, and all other obligations incurred by the authority in connection with such project, shall have been paid in full or sufficient funds shall have been deposited in trust for such payment. The purchase price of such project shall not be less than an amount sufficient to pay in full all of the bonds, including all principal, interest, and redemption premiums, if any, issued for the project then outstanding and all other obligations incurred by the authority in connection with such project.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 74-323.</History></Section>