<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.261" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Continuance of municipal housing authorities when municipality abolished; counties in excess of 400,000.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a municipality in any county having a population in excess of 400,000 according to the most recent official census has been or hereafter shall be abolished, wherein at the time of such abolishment a housing authority of such municipality was or is in existence, such housing authority shall continue to function in all respects; provided, however, that the name of such housing authority shall thenceforth be such as may be determined by the county commissioners of the county wherein it functions. Each such housing authority and the commissioners thereof, within the area of operation of such housing authority as hereinafter defined, shall have the same functions, rights, powers, duties, immunities and privileges provided for housing authorities created for cities. Each such housing authority shall continue to operate and prosecute all projects operated or initiated by it prior to the abolishment of the municipality, and shall be entitled to all benefits and privileges thereafter conferred upon housing authorities for cities. The commissioners of each such housing authority shall continue in office after the abolishment of the particular municipality for the remainder of their respective terms. Their successors shall be appointed by resolution of the commissioners of the county. As used in the Housing Authorities Law, the terms “mayor” and “governing body” shall be construed as meaning “county commissioners,” the term “city” as used therein shall be construed as meaning “county,” and the term “clerk” as used therein shall be construed as meaning “clerk of the circuit court of the county,” unless different meanings clearly appear from the contents. The area of operation of any such housing authority shall continue to be the same as that before the abolishment of the municipality, unless extended by resolution of the county commissioners, provided that no such extension shall include any territory lying within a city as defined in the Housing Authorities Law.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 28305, 1953.</History></Section>