<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Operation not for profit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the policy of this state that each housing authority shall manage and operate its housing projects in an efficient manner so as to enable it to fix the rentals for dwelling accommodations at the lowest possible rates consistent with its providing decent, safe, and sanitary dwelling accommodations, and that a housing authority may not construct or operate any such project for profit, or as a source of revenue to the city. To this end an authority may not fix the rentals for dwellings in its project at a higher rate than it finds necessary in order to produce revenues that, together with all other available moneys, revenue, income, and receipts of the authority from whatever sources derived, will be sufficient:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To pay, as they become due, the principal and interest on the debentures of the authority;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To meet the cost of, and to provide for, maintaining and operating the projects, including the cost of any insurance and the administrative expenses of the authority; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To create, during not less than the 6 years immediately succeeding its issuance of any debentures, a reserve sufficient to meet the largest principal and interest payments that will be due on such debentures in any one year thereafter, and to maintain such reserve.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit or restrict the activities or operations of a business entity created under s. 421.08(8).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 17981, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 7100(3-i); s. 4, ch. 2005-54.</History></Section>