<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Validation of debentures and proceedings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A housing authority shall have the right, if it deems it expedient, to determine its authority to issue any debentures, and the legality of all proceedings had or taken in connection therewith, in the same manner and to the same extent, except as otherwise provided in this section, as provided in chapter 75 for the determination by a county, municipality, taxing district, or other political district or subdivision of its authority to incur bonded debt or to issue certificates of indebtedness and of the legality of all proceedings had or taken in connection therewith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition to validate such debentures, and the proceedings had or taken in connection therewith, shall be filed by the housing authority in the circuit court for the county in which is located the city for which said housing authority was created, except that whenever it appears that a housing authority is empowered to function in more than one county the circuit court of any county in the whole or any part of which the housing authority is empowered to function shall have jurisdiction of the cause in the same manner as provided in said chapter whenever a municipality, taxing district or other political district or subdivision shall extend into more than one county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice required by s. 75.06 shall be addressed to the taxpayers and citizens of the city for which such housing authority has been created and of the county, or counties, in the event such housing authority is empowered to function in more than one county, in the whole or any part of which the housing authority is empowered to function; and by the publication of such notice as required by said chapter 75 all taxpayers and citizens of such city and such county or counties, as the case may be, shall be considered as parties defendant to such proceedings, and the circuit court in which the proceeding is brought shall have jurisdiction of all of the same as if they were named defendants in the petition filed pursuant to said chapter and personally served with process.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event no appeal is taken within the time prescribed by said chapter, or if taken, and the decree validating said debentures is affirmed by the Supreme Court, the decree of the circuit court validating and confirming the issuance of the debentures of the housing authority shall be forever conclusive as to the validity of said debentures against the housing authority and against all taxpayers and citizens of the city for which said housing authority was created and of the county or counties in the whole or part of which the housing authority is empowered to function; and the validity of said debentures shall never be called in question in any court in this state. Debentures of a housing authority, when issued under the provisions of said chapter, shall have stamped or written thereon by the proper officers of the housing authority issuing the same, the words: “Validated and Confirmed by Decree of the Circuit Court,” specifying the date when such decree was rendered and the court in which it was rendered, which shall be signed by the clerk of the circuit court in which the decree was rendered, which entry shall be original evidence of said decree in any court in this state.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 17981, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 7100(3-bb).</History></Section>