<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Debentures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authority may issue debentures from time to time in its discretion, for any of its corporate purposes. An authority may also issue refunding debentures for the purpose of paying or retiring debentures previously issued by it. An authority may issue such types of debentures as it may determine, including debentures on which the principal and interest are payable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exclusively from the income and revenues of the housing project financed with the proceeds of such debentures, or with such proceeds together with a grant from the federal government in aid of such project;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exclusively from the income and revenues of certain designated housing projects whether or not they were financed in whole or in part with the proceeds of such debentures; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">From its revenues generally.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Any of such debentures may be additionally secured by a pledge of any revenues of any housing project, projects or other property of the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the commissioners of an authority nor any person executing the debentures shall be liable personally on the debentures by reason of the issuance thereof. The debentures and other obligations of an authority, and such debentures and obligations shall so state on their face, shall not be a debt of the city, the county, the state or any political subdivision thereof, and neither the city or the county, nor the state or any political subdivision thereof shall be liable thereon, nor in any event shall such debentures or obligations be payable out of any funds or properties other than those of said authority. The debentures shall not constitute an indebtedness within the meaning of any constitutional or statutory debt or bond limitation or restriction.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 17981, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 7100(3-y).</History></Section>