<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Creation of housing authorities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In each city, as herein defined, there is hereby created a public body corporate and politic to be known as the “Housing Authority” of the city; provided, however, that such authority shall not transact any business or exercise its powers hereunder until or unless the governing body of the city by proper resolution shall declare that there is need for an authority to function in such city. The determination as to whether there is such need for an authority to function:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May be made by the governing body on its own motion; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shall be made by the governing body upon the filing of a petition signed by 25 residents of the city asserting that there is need for an authority to function in such city and requesting that the governing body so declare.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body may adopt a resolution declaring that there is need for a housing authority in the city if it shall find that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insanitary or unsafe inhabited dwelling accommodations exist in such city; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a shortage of safe or sanitary dwelling accommodations in such city available to persons of low income at rentals they can afford. In determining whether dwelling accommodations are unsafe or insanitary said governing body may take into consideration the degree of overcrowding, the percentage of land coverage, the light, air, space and access available to the inhabitants of such dwelling accommodations, the size and arrangement of the rooms, the sanitary facilities, and the extent to which conditions exist in such buildings which endanger life or property by fire or other causes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any suit, action or proceeding involving the validity or enforcement of or relating to any contract of the authority, the authority shall be conclusively deemed to have become established and authorized to transact business and exercise its powers hereunder upon proof of the adoption of a resolution by the governing body declaring the need for the authority. Such resolution or resolutions shall be sufficient if it declares that there is such need for an authority and finds in substantially the foregoing terms, no further detail being necessary, that either or both of the above enumerated conditions exist in the city. A copy of such resolution duly certified by the clerk shall be admissible in evidence in any suit, action or proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 17981, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 7100(3-d).</History></Section>