<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cooperation of authorities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any two or more housing authorities may join or cooperate with one another in the exercise, either jointly or otherwise, of any or all of their powers for the purpose of financing, including the issuance of bonds, debentures, notes or other obligations and giving security therefor; planning; undertaking; owning; constructing; operating; or contracting with respect to a housing project or projects located within the area of operation of any one or more of said authorities. For such purpose, an authority may by resolution prescribe and authorize any other housing authority or authorities, so joining or cooperating with it, to act on its behalf with respect to any or all such powers. Any authorities joining or cooperating with one another may by resolutions appoint from among the commissioners of such authorities an executive committee with full power to act on behalf of such authorities with respect to any or all of their powers, as prescribed by resolutions of such authorities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any county housing authority may enter into an interlocal agreement with one or more local governing bodies pursuant to the provisions of s. 163.01, the Florida Interlocal Cooperation Act of 1969, with respect to projects or programs located within the county or an adjacent county, and any city housing authority may enter into such agreement with respect to projects or programs located within the county, provided that no power granted an authority under s. 421.08 may be reserved to or exercised by a local governing body under such agreement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 17981, 1937; CGL 1940 Supp. 7100(3-k); s. 1, ch. 21699, 1943; s. 4, ch. 78-165; s. 38, ch. 86-192.</History></Section>