<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.55" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Relocation of displaced persons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to authorize the state and its departments, agencies, political subdivisions, and legislatively established port and airport authorities to comply with the provisions and requirements of the Surface Transportation and Uniform Relocation Assistance Act of 1987, Pub. L. No. 100-17, in those public projects or programs for which federal or federal-aid funds are available and are used.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” means the State of Florida, any department, agency or political subdivision thereof, or any port or airport authority established by the Legislature.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public Law No. 100-17” means the Surface Transportation and Uniform Relocation Assistance Act of 1987 adopted by the United States Congress.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Displaced person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association that is required to move from any real property on or after March 20, 1972, as a result of the acquisition of such real property for public purposes, or who, as the result of the acquisition for public purposes of real property on which such person is conducting a business or farm operation as defined in Pub. L. No. 100-17, is required to move said business or farm operation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state is authorized and empowered, in acquiring real property for use in any public project or program in which federal or federal-aid funds are used, to make all such relocation and other payments to or for displaced persons as are required under the provisions of Pub. L. No. 100-17, and to provide such displaced persons with relocation services and make available to them replacement dwellings, as required by Pub. L. No. 100-17.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state is authorized and empowered, in acquiring real property for use in any public project or program in which federal or federal-aid funds are used, to follow and conform with the land acquisition policies set forth in Pub. L. No. 100-17, and to pay or reimburse owners of property so acquired in the manner specified in Pub. L. No. 100-17. This authority shall include, as to federal-aid highways and airports, as a last resort, the use of eminent domain powers to acquire real property for replacement housing as required by Pub. L. No. 100-17.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, ch. 72-71; s. 2, ch. 89-209.</History></Section>