<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0421.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Decreasing area of operation of regional authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The area of operation of a regional housing authority shall be decreased from time to time to exclude one or more counties from such area if the governing body of each of the counties in such area and the commissioners of the regional housing authority each adopt a resolution declaring that there is a need for excluding such county or counties from such area; provided, that no action may be taken pursuant to this section if the regional housing authority has outstanding any bonds, debentures or notes unless first, all holders of such bonds, debentures or notes consent in writing to such action; and provided, that if such action decreases the area of operation of the regional housing authority to only one county, such authority shall thereupon constitute and become a housing authority for such county, in the same manner as though such authority were created by and authorized to transact business and exercise its powers pursuant to s. 421.04 or s. 421.27, and the commissioners of such authority shall be thereupon appointed as provided for the appointment of commissioners of a housing authority created for a county. The governing body of each of the counties in the area of operation of the regional housing authority and the commissioners of the regional housing authority shall adopt a resolution declaring that there is a need for excluding a county or counties from such area only if each such governing body and the commissioners of the regional housing authority find that, because of facts arising or determined subsequent to the time when such area first included the county or counties to be excluded, the regional housing authority would be a more efficient or economical administrative unit if such county or counties were excluded from such area.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of a county shall not adopt any resolution authorized by this section unless a public hearing has first been held in accordance with the provisions of the Housing Authorities Law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A certificate of the appointment of any commissioner of a regional housing authority shall be filed with the county clerk of the county from which the commissioner is appointed, and such certificate shall be conclusive evidence of the due and proper appointment of such commissioner. The commissioners of a regional housing authority shall be appointed for terms of 4 years, except that all vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired terms. Each commissioner shall hold office until a successor has been appointed and has qualified, except as otherwise provided herein. The Governor shall thereafter appoint the successor of each commissioner of a regional housing authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioners appointed as aforesaid shall constitute the regional housing authority, and the powers of such authority shall be vested in such commissioners in office from time to time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioners of a regional housing authority shall elect a chair from among the commissioners and shall have power to select or employ such other officers and employees as the regional housing authority may require. A majority of the commissioners of a regional housing authority shall constitute a quorum of such authority for the purpose of conducting its business and exercising its powers and for all other purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 21699, 1943; s. 90, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>