<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0056.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Execution sales; notice.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice of all sales under execution shall be given by advertisement once each week for 4 successive weeks in a newspaper published in the county in which the sale is to take place. The time of such notice may be shortened in the discretion of the court from which the execution issued, upon affidavit that the property to be sold is subject to decay and will not sell for its full value if held until date of sale. On or before the date of the first publication or posting of the notice of sale, a copy of the notice of sale shall be furnished by the sheriff by certified mail to the attorney of record of the judgment debtor, or to the judgment debtor at the judgment debtor’s last known address if the judgment debtor does not have an attorney of record. Such copy of the notice of sale shall be mailed even though a default judgment was entered. When levying upon real or personal property, a notice of such levy and execution sale and a copy of the affidavit required by s. 56.27(4) shall be sent by the sheriff to the attorneys of record of all judgment creditors and other lienholders, or to all judgment creditors and other lienholders who do not have an attorney of record, who have acquired a lien as provided in s. 55.10(1) and (2), s. 55.202, s. 55.204(3), or s. 695.01, and whose liens have not lapsed at the time of levy, at the address listed in the judgment lien certificate or other recorded liens, or, if amended, in any amendment thereto, and to all secured creditors who have filed financing statements as provided in part V of chapter 679 in the name of the judgment debtor reflecting a security interest in property of the kind to be sold at the execution sale at the address listed in the financing statement, or, if amended, in any amendment to the financing statement. Such notice shall be made in the same manner as notice is made to any judgment debtor under this section. When levying upon real property, notice of such levy and execution sale and affidavit required by s. 56.27(4) shall be made to the property owner of record in the same manner as notice is made to any judgment debtor pursuant to this section, and shall be made to each other person holding a mortgage or other lien against the real property as disclosed by the affidavit. When selling real or personal property, the sale date shall not be earlier than 30 days after the date of the first advertisement.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, Feb. 17, 1833; RS 1202; GS 1631; RGS 2835; CGL 4522; s. 11, ch. 67-254; s. 2, ch. 77-462; s. 4, ch. 82-118; s. 10, ch. 94-170; s. 18, ch. 2000-258; s. 12, ch. 2001-154; s. 10, ch. 2005-241; s. 5, ch. 2009-215.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 55.44.</Text></Note></Section>