<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0534.083" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Livestock hauler’s permit; display of permit on vehicle; bill of lading.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall engage in the business of transporting or hauling for hire livestock on any street or highway, as defined in s. 316.003(53), without first having applied for and obtained from the department a permit which shall expire on December 31 of each year. The information supplied by the applicant on the application for permit shall be certified under oath. Cost of the permit shall be $5 for each year or fraction thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a metal tag or plate to every person or company required to obtain a permit to transport or haul for hire livestock, which shall bear the serial number of the permit. Such a tag or plate shall be issued for each vehicle used by the hauler.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The metal tag or plate required under this section shall be attached to each vehicle used for transporting or hauling livestock in a conspicuous place in an upright position on the rear of the vehicle. When livestock is transported in a trailer type vehicle propelled or drawn by a motor truck or tractor, each such trailer shall have the tag or plate attached to the rear of the trailer in a conspicuous place in an upright position, and it shall not be necessary to have a tag attached to the motor truck or tractor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Persons engaged in the business of transporting or hauling livestock in the state shall, upon receiving such livestock for transportation, issue a waybill or bill of lading for all livestock transported or hauled by them, and such waybill or bill of lading shall accompany the shipment of livestock, with a copy thereof being furnished to the person delivering livestock to the hauler. The waybill or bill of lading shall show the place of origin and destination of the shipment, the name of the owner of the livestock, date and time of loading, name of person or company hauling the livestock, and the number of animals and a general description thereof. The waybill or bill of lading shall be signed by the person delivering the livestock to the hauler certifying that the information contained thereon is correct.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 69-333; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 86-70; s. 2, ch. 86-230; s. 40, ch. 91-220.</History></Section>