<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.004" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of Nursing; membership; appointment; terms.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Nursing is created within the department and shall consist of 13 members to be appointed by the Governor and confirmed by the Senate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seven members of the board must be registered nurses who are residents of this state and who have been engaged in the practice of professional nursing for at least 4 years, including at least one advanced registered nurse practitioner, one nurse educator member of an approved program, and one nurse executive. These seven board members should be representative of the diverse areas of practice within the nursing profession. In addition, three members of the board must be licensed practical nurses who are residents of this state and who have been actively engaged in the practice of practical nursing for at least 4 years prior to their appointment. The remaining three members must be residents of the state who have never been licensed as nurses and who are in no way connected with the practice of nursing. No person may be appointed as a lay member who is in any way connected with, or has any financial interest in, any health care facility, agency, or insurer. At least one member of the board must be 60 years of age or older.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As the terms of the members expire, the Governor shall appoint successors for terms of 4 years, and such members shall serve until their successors are appointed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All provisions of chapter 456 relating to activities of the board shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-225; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 4, 17, 18, ch. 86-284; s. 15, ch. 87-172; ss. 12, 58, ch. 91-137; s. 5, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 122, ch. 94-218; s. 3, ch. 96-274; s. 77, ch. 97-264; s. 66, ch. 98-166; s. 123, ch. 2000-160.</History></Section>