<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.016" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Violations and penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each of the following acts constitutes a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practicing advanced or specialized, professional, or practical nursing, as defined in this part, unless holding an active license or certificate to do so.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using or attempting to use a license or certificate which has been suspended or revoked.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly employing unlicensed persons in the practice of nursing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining or attempting to obtain a license or certificate under this part by misleading statements or knowing misrepresentation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each of the following acts constitutes a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Using the name or title “Nurse,” “Registered Nurse,” “Licensed Practical Nurse,” “Clinical Nurse Specialist,” “Certified Registered Nurse Anesthetist,” “Certified Nurse Midwife,” “Advanced Registered Nurse Practitioner,” or any other name or title which implies that a person was licensed or certified as same, unless such person is duly licensed or certified.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Knowingly concealing information relating to violations of this part.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-225; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 13, 17, 18, ch. 86-284; s. 58, ch. 91-137; s. 5, ch. 91-156; s. 90, ch. 91-224; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 183, ch. 99-397; ss. 54, 124, ch. 2000-318; s. 5, ch. 2007-167.</History></Section>