<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.0205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retired volunteer nurse certificate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any retired practical or registered nurse desiring to serve indigent, underserved, or critical need populations in this state may apply to the department for a retired volunteer nurse certificate by providing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A complete application.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Verification that the applicant had been licensed to practice nursing in any jurisdiction in the United States for at least 10 years, had retired or plans to retire, intends to practice nursing only pursuant to the limitations provided by the retired volunteer nurse certificate, and has not committed any act that would constitute a violation under s. 464.018(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that the applicant meets the requirements for licensure under s. 464.008 or s. 464.009.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All related administrative costs shall be borne by the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may deny a retired volunteer nurse certificate to any applicant who has committed, or who is under investigation or prosecution for, any act that would constitute a ground for disciplinary action under s. 464.018.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retired volunteer nurse receiving certification from the board shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work under the direct supervision of the director of a county health department, a physician working under a limited license issued pursuant to s. 458.317 or s. 459.0075, a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459, an advanced registered nurse practitioner certified under s. 464.012, or a registered nurse licensed under s. 464.008 or s. 464.009.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with the minimum standards of practice for nurses and be subject to disciplinary action for violations of s. 464.018, except that the scope of practice for certified volunteers shall be limited to primary and preventive health care, or as further defined by board rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Work only in a setting for which there are provisions for professional liability coverage for acts or omissions of the retired volunteer nurse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide services under the certificate only in settings whose sponsors have been approved by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retired volunteer nurse receiving certification from the board shall not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administer controlled substances.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Supervise other nurses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive monetary compensation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retired volunteer nurse certified under this section may practice only in board-approved settings in public agencies or institutions or in nonprofit agencies or institutions meeting the requirements of s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, which agencies or institutions are located in areas of critical nursing need as determined by the board. Determination of underserved areas shall be made by the board after consultation with the Department of Health, the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Health Care Administration, and the Department of Elderly Affairs; however, such determination shall include, but not be limited to, health manpower shortage areas designated by the United States Department of Health and Human Services. The sponsoring agencies desiring to use certified retired volunteer nurses shall submit to the board verification of their status under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, the sites at which such volunteer nurses would work, the duties and scope of practice intended for such volunteer nurses, and the training or skills validation for such volunteer nurses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The retired volunteer nurse certificate shall be valid for 2 years, and a certificateholder may reapply for a certificate so long as the certificateholder continues to meet the eligibility requirements of this section. Any legislatively mandated continuing education on specific topics must be completed by the certificateholder prior to renewal; otherwise, the provisions of s. 464.013 do not apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 85, ch. 97-264; s. 101, ch. 2001-277.</History></Section>