<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.0115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification of clinical nurse specialists.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nurse seeking certification as a clinical nurse specialist must apply to the department and submit proof that he or she holds a current license to practice professional nursing, a master’s degree in a clinical nursing specialty, and either:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of current certification in a specialty area as a clinical nurse specialist from a nationally recognized certifying body as determined by the board; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that he or she holds a master’s degree in a specialty area for which there is no certification within the clinical nurse specialist role and specialty and proof of having completed 1,000 hours of clinical experience in the clinical specialty for which he or she is academically prepared, with a minimum of 500 hours of clinical practice after graduation. The applicant for certification as a clinical nurse specialist must submit an affidavit to the Board of Nursing affirming the required hours of clinical experience. Falsification of the affidavit constitutes grounds for discipline in accordance with s. 464.018(1)(f).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall certify, and the department shall issue a certificate to, any nurse who fulfills the qualifications of this section. The board shall establish an application fee not to exceed $75 and a biennial renewal fee not to exceed $75.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may adopt rules necessary to administer this section pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2007-167; s. 1, ch. 2008-164.</History></Section>