<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.019" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Approval of nursing education programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM APPLICATIONS.<EmDash />An educational institution that wishes to conduct a program in this state for the prelicensure education of professional or practical nurses must submit to the department a program application and review fee of $1,000 for each prelicensure nursing education program to be offered at the institution’s main campus, branch campus, or other instructional site. Each program application must include the legal name of the educational institution, the legal name of the nursing education program, and, if such program is accredited by an accrediting agency other than an accrediting agency described in s. 464.003(1), the name of the accrediting agency. The application must also document that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a professional nursing education program, the program director and at least 50 percent of the program’s faculty members are registered nurses who have a master’s or higher degree in nursing or a bachelor’s degree in nursing and a master’s or higher degree in a field related to nursing.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a practical nursing education program, the program director and at least 50 percent of the program’s faculty members are registered nurses who have a bachelor’s or higher degree in nursing.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The educational degree requirements of this paragraph may be documented by an official transcript or by a written statement from the educational institution verifying that the institution conferred the degree.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s nursing major curriculum consists of at least:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent clinical training for a practical nursing education program, an associate degree professional nursing education program, or a professional diploma nursing education program.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Forty percent clinical training for a bachelor’s degree professional nursing education program.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 25 percent of the program’s clinical training consists of clinical simulation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program has signed agreements with each agency, facility, and organization included in the curriculum plan as clinical training sites and community-based clinical experience sites.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program has written policies for faculty which include provisions for direct or indirect supervision by program faculty or clinical preceptors for students in clinical training consistent with the following standards:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of program faculty members equals at least one faculty member directly supervising every 12 students unless the written agreement between the program and the agency, facility, or organization providing clinical training sites allows more students, not to exceed 18 students, to be directly supervised by one program faculty member.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a hospital setting, indirect supervision may occur only if there is direct supervision by an assigned clinical preceptor, a supervising program faculty member is available by telephone, and such arrangement is approved by the clinical facility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For community-based clinical experiences that involve student participation in invasive or complex nursing activities, students must be directly supervised by a program faculty member or clinical preceptor and such arrangement must be approved by the community-based clinical facility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For community-based clinical experiences not subject to subparagraph 3., indirect supervision may occur only when a supervising program faculty member is available to the student by telephone.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A program’s policies established under this paragraph must require a clinical preceptor, if supervising students in a professional nursing education program, to be a registered nurse or, if supervising students in a practical nursing education program, to be a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The professional or practical nursing curriculum plan documents clinical experience and theoretical instruction in medical, surgical, obstetric, pediatric, and geriatric nursing. A professional nursing curriculum plan shall also document clinical experience and theoretical instruction in psychiatric nursing. Each curriculum plan must document clinical training experience in appropriate settings that include, but are not limited to, acute care, long-term care, and community settings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The professional or practical nursing education program provides theoretical instruction and clinical application in personal, family, and community health concepts; nutrition; human growth and development throughout the life span; body structure and function; interpersonal relationship skills; mental health concepts; pharmacology and administration of medications; and legal aspects of practice. A professional nursing education program shall also provide theoretical instruction and clinical application in interpersonal relationships and leadership skills; professional role and function; and health teaching and counseling skills.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM APPROVAL.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of a program application and review fee, the department shall examine the application to determine whether it is complete. If a program application is not complete, the department shall notify the educational institution in writing of any errors or omissions within 30 days after the department’s receipt of the application. A program application is deemed complete upon the department’s receipt of:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial application, if the department does not notify the educational institution of any errors or omissions within the 30-day period; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A revised application that corrects each error and omission of which the department notifies the educational institution within the 30-day period.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 90 days after the department’s receipt of a complete program application, the board shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve the application if it documents compliance with paragraphs (1)(a)-(g); or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the educational institution with a notice of intent to deny the application if it does not document compliance with paragraphs (1)(a)-(g). The notice must set forth written reasons for the board’s denial of the application. The board may not deny a program application because of an educational institution’s failure to correct any error or omission of which the department does not notify the institution within the 30-day notice period under paragraph (a). The educational institution may request a hearing on the notice of intent to deny the program application pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A program application is deemed approved if the board does not act within the 90-day review period provided under paragraph (b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the board’s approval of a program application, the program becomes an approved program.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATUS OF CERTAIN PROGRAMS.<EmDash />A professional or practical nursing education program becomes an approved program if, as of June 30, 2009, the program:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has full or provisional approval from the board or, except as provided in paragraph (b), is on probationary status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is on probationary status because the program did not meet the board’s requirement for graduate passage rates. Such program shall remain on probationary status until it achieves a graduate passage rate for calendar year 2009 or 2010 that equals or exceeds the required passage rate for the respective calendar year and must disclose its probationary status in writing to the program’s students and applicants. If the program does not achieve the required passage rate, the board shall terminate the program pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ANNUAL REPORT.<EmDash />By November 1 of each year, each approved program shall submit to the board an annual report comprised of an affidavit certifying continued compliance with paragraphs (1)(a)-(g), a summary description of the program’s compliance with paragraphs (1)(a)-(g), and documentation for the previous academic year that, to the extent applicable, sets forth:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of student applications received, qualified applicants, applicants accepted, accepted applicants who enroll in the program, students enrolled in the program, and program graduates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s retention rates for students tracked from program entry to graduation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s accreditation status, including identification of the accrediting agency if such agency is not an accrediting agency described in s. 464.003(1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INTERNET WEBSITE.<EmDash />By October 1, 2010, the board shall publish the following information on its Internet website:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A list of each accredited program conducted in the state and the program’s graduate passage rates for the most recent 2 calendar years, which the department shall determine through the following sources:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a program’s accreditation status, the specialized accrediting agencies that are nationally recognized by the United States Secretary of Education to accredit nursing education programs.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a program’s graduate passage rates, the contract testing service of the National Council of State Boards of Nursing.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following data for each approved program, which shall include, to the extent applicable:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All documentation provided by the program in its program application if submitted on or after July 1, 2009.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The summary description of the program’s compliance submitted under subsection (4).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s accreditation status, including identification of the accrediting agency if such agency is not an accrediting agency described in s. 464.003(1).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s probationary status.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s graduate passage rates for the most recent 2 calendar years.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each program’s retention rates for students tracked from program entry to graduation.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average passage rates for United States educated first-time test takers on the National Council of State Boards of Nursing Licensing Examination for the most recent 2 calendar years, as calculated by the contract testing service of the National Council of State Boards of Nursing. The average passage rates shall be published separately for each type of comparable degree program listed in sub-subparagraphs (6)(a)1.a.-d.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The information required to be published under this subsection shall be made available in a manner that allows interactive searches and comparisons of individual programs selected by the website user. The board shall update the Internet website at least quarterly with the available information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACCOUNTABILITY.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An approved program must achieve a graduate passage rate that is not lower than 10 percentage points less than the average passage rate for graduates of comparable degree programs who are United States educated first-time test takers on the National Council of State Boards of Nursing Licensing Examination during a calendar year, as calculated by the contract testing service of the National Council of State Boards of Nursing. For purposes of this subparagraph, an approved program is comparable to all degree programs of the same program type from among the following program types:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Professional nursing education programs that terminate in a bachelor’s degree.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Professional nursing education programs that terminate in an associate degree.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Professional nursing education programs that terminate in a diploma.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practical nursing education programs.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with graduate passage rates for calendar year 2010, if an approved program’s graduate passage rates do not equal or exceed the required passage rates for 2 consecutive calendar years, the board shall place the program on probationary status pursuant to chapter 120 and the program director must appear before the board to present a plan for remediation. The program shall remain on probationary status until it achieves a graduate passage rate that equals or exceeds the required passage rate for any 1 calendar year. The board shall deny a program application for a new prelicensure nursing education program submitted by an educational institution if the institution has an existing program that is already on probationary status.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the program’s achievement of a graduate passage rate that equals or exceeds the required passage rate, the board, at its next regularly scheduled meeting following release of the program’s graduate passage rate by the National Council of State Boards of Nursing, shall remove the program’s probationary status. However, if the program, during the 2 calendar years following its placement on probationary status, does not achieve the required passage rate for any 1 calendar year, the board shall terminate the program pursuant to chapter 120.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an approved program fails to submit the annual report required in subsection (4), the board shall notify the program director and president or chief executive officer of the educational institution in writing within 15 days after the due date of the annual report. The program director must appear before the board at the board’s next regularly scheduled meeting to explain the reason for the delay. The board shall terminate the program pursuant to chapter 120 if it does not submit the annual report within 6 months after the due date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An approved program on probationary status shall disclose its probationary status in writing to the program’s students and applicants.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DISCLOSURE OF GRADUATE PASSAGE RATE DATA.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each of an approved program’s or accredited program’s graduates included in the calculation of the program’s graduate passage rate, the department shall disclose to the program director, upon his or her written request, the name, examination date, and determination of whether each graduate passed or failed the National Council for State Boards of Nursing Licensing Examination, to the extent that such information is provided to the department by the contract testing service of the National Council for State Boards of Nursing. The written request must specify the calendar years for which the information is requested.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A program director to whom confidential information exempt from public disclosure pursuant to s. 456.014 is disclosed under this subsection must maintain the confidentiality of the information and is subject to the same penalties provided in s. 456.082 for department employees who unlawfully disclose confidential information.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM CLOSURE.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An educational institution conducting an approved program or accredited program in this state, at least 30 days before voluntarily closing the program, shall notify the board in writing of the institution’s reason for closing the program, the intended closure date, the institution’s plan to provide for or assist in the completion of training by the program’s students, and the arrangements for storage of the program’s permanent records.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An educational institution conducting a nursing education program that is terminated under subsection (6) or closed under subparagraph (10)(b)3.:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May not accept or enroll new students.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must submit to the board within 30 days after the program is terminated or closed a written description of how the institution will assist in the completion of training by the program’s students and the institution’s arrangements for storage of the program’s permanent records.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an educational institution does not comply with paragraph (a) or paragraph (b), the board shall provide a written notice explaining the institution’s noncompliance to the following persons and entities:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The president or chief executive officer of the educational institution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Governors, if the program is conducted by a state university.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The district school board, if the program is conducted by an educational institution operated by a school district.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Commission for Independent Education, if the program is conducted by an educational institution licensed under chapter 1005.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Education, if the program is conducted by an educational institution in the Florida College System or by an educational institution that is not subject to subparagraphs 2.-4.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULEMAKING.<EmDash />The board does not have any rulemaking authority to administer this section, except that the board shall adopt a rule that prescribes the format for submitting program applications under subsection (1) and annual reports under subsection (4). The board may not impose any condition or requirement on an educational institution submitting a program application, an approved program, or an accredited program, except as expressly provided in this section. The board shall repeal all rules, or portions thereof, in existence on July 1, 2009, that are inconsistent with this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">APPLICABILITY TO ACCREDITED PROGRAMS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsections (1)-(4), paragraph (5)(b), and subsection (6) do not apply to an accredited program. An accredited program on probationary status before July 1, 2010, ceases to be subject to the probationary status.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an accredited program ceases to be accredited, the educational institution conducting the program:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 10 business days after the program ceases to be accredited, must provide written notice of the date that the program ceased to be accredited to the board, the program’s students and applicants, and each entity providing clinical training sites or community-based clinical experience sites for the program. The educational institution must continue to provide the written notice to new students, applicants, and entities providing clinical training sites or community-based clinical experience sites for the program until the program becomes an approved program or is closed under subparagraph 3.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after the program ceases to be accredited, must submit an affidavit to the board, signed by the educational institution’s president or chief executive officer, that certifies the institution’s compliance with subparagraph 1. The board shall notify the persons listed in subparagraph (8)(c)1. and the applicable entities listed in subparagraphs (8)(c)2.-5. if an educational institution does not submit the affidavit required by this subparagraph.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May apply to become an approved program under this section. If the educational institution:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after the program ceases to be accredited, submits a program application and review fee to the department under subsection (1) and the affidavit required under subparagraph 2., the program shall be deemed an approved program from the date that the program ceased to be accredited until the date that the board approves or denies the program application. The program application must be denied by the board pursuant to chapter 120 if it does not contain the affidavit. If the board denies the program application under subsection (2) or because the program application does not contain the affidavit, the program shall be closed and the educational institution conducting the program must comply with paragraph (8)(b).</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not apply to become an approved program pursuant to sub-subparagraph a., the program shall be deemed an approved program from the date that the program ceased to be accredited until the 31st day after that date. On the 31st day after the program ceased to be accredited, the program shall be closed and the educational institution conducting the program must comply with paragraph (8)(b).</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IMPLEMENTATION STUDY.<EmDash />The Florida Center for Nursing and the education policy area of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall study the 5-year administration of this section and submit reports to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives by January 30, 2011, and annually thereafter through January 30, 2015. The annual reports shall address the previous academic year; set forth data on the measures specified in paragraphs (a) and (b), as such data becomes available; and include an evaluation of such data for purposes of determining whether this section is increasing the availability of nursing education programs and the production of quality nurses. The department and each approved program or accredited program shall comply with requests for data from the Florida Center for Nursing and the education policy area of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The education policy area of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall evaluate program-specific data for each approved program and accredited program conducted in the state, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of programs and student slots available.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of student applications submitted, the number of qualified applicants, and the number of students accepted.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of program graduates.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program retention rates of students tracked from program entry to graduation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduate passage rates on the National Council of State Boards of Nursing Licensing Examination.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of graduates who become employed as practical or professional nurses in the state.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Center for Nursing shall evaluate the board’s implementation of the:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program application approval process, including, but not limited to, the number of program applications submitted under subsection (1); the number of program applications approved and denied by the board under subsection (2); the number of denials of program applications reviewed under chapter 120; and a description of the outcomes of those reviews.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accountability processes, including, but not limited to, the number of programs on probationary status, the number of approved programs for which the program director is required to appear before the board under subsection (6), the number of approved programs terminated by the board, the number of terminations reviewed under chapter 120, and a description of the outcomes of those reviews.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any state fiscal year in which the Florida Center for Nursing does not receive legislative appropriations, the education policy area of the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability shall perform the duties assigned by this subsection to the Florida Center for Nursing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-225; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 17, 18, ch. 86-284; s. 58, ch. 91-137; s. 5, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 11, ch. 96-274; s. 84, ch. 97-264; s. 126, ch. 2000-318; s. 7, ch. 2002-230; s. 2, ch. 2009-168; s. 5, ch. 2010-37; s. 98, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>