<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0464.012" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certification of advanced registered nurse practitioners; fees.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nurse desiring to be certified as an advanced registered nurse practitioner shall apply to the department and submit proof that he or she holds a current license to practice professional nursing and that he or she meets one or more of the following requirements as determined by the board:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfactory completion of a formal postbasic educational program of at least one academic year, the primary purpose of which is to prepare nurses for advanced or specialized practice.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification by an appropriate specialty board. Such certification shall be required for initial state certification and any recertification as a registered nurse anesthetist or nurse midwife. The board may by rule provide for provisional state certification of graduate nurse anesthetists and nurse midwives for a period of time determined to be appropriate for preparing for and passing the national certification examination.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduation from a program leading to a master’s degree in a nursing clinical specialty area with preparation in specialized practitioner skills. For applicants graduating on or after October 1, 1998, graduation from a master’s degree program shall be required for initial certification as a nurse practitioner under paragraph (4)(c). For applicants graduating on or after October 1, 2001, graduation from a master’s degree program shall be required for initial certification as a registered nurse anesthetist under paragraph (4)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall provide by rule the appropriate requirements for advanced registered nurse practitioners in the categories of certified registered nurse anesthetist, certified nurse midwife, and nurse practitioner.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An advanced registered nurse practitioner shall perform those functions authorized in this section within the framework of an established protocol that is filed with the board upon biennial license renewal and within 30 days after entering into a supervisory relationship with a physician or changes to the protocol. The board shall review the protocol to ensure compliance with applicable regulatory standards for protocols. The board shall refer to the department licensees submitting protocols that are not compliant with the regulatory standards for protocols. A practitioner currently licensed under chapter 458, chapter 459, or chapter 466 shall maintain supervision for directing the specific course of medical treatment. Within the established framework, an advanced registered nurse practitioner may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitor and alter drug therapies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate appropriate therapies for certain conditions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform additional functions as may be determined by rule in accordance with s. 464.003(2).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order diagnostic tests and physical and occupational therapy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the general functions specified in subsection (3), an advanced registered nurse practitioner may perform the following acts within his or her specialty:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certified registered nurse anesthetist may, to the extent authorized by established protocol approved by the medical staff of the facility in which the anesthetic service is performed, perform any or all of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine the health status of the patient as it relates to the risk factors and to the anesthetic management of the patient through the performance of the general functions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on history, physical assessment, and supplemental laboratory results, determine, with the consent of the responsible physician, the appropriate type of anesthesia within the framework of the protocol.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order under the protocol preanesthetic medication.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform under the protocol procedures commonly used to render the patient insensible to pain during the performance of surgical, obstetrical, therapeutic, or diagnostic clinical procedures. These procedures include ordering and administering regional, spinal, and general anesthesia; inhalation agents and techniques; intravenous agents and techniques; and techniques of hypnosis.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order or perform monitoring procedures indicated as pertinent to the anesthetic health care management of the patient.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Support life functions during anesthesia health care, including induction and intubation procedures, the use of appropriate mechanical supportive devices, and the management of fluid, electrolyte, and blood component balances.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize and take appropriate corrective action for abnormal patient responses to anesthesia, adjunctive medication, or other forms of therapy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize and treat a cardiac arrhythmia while the patient is under anesthetic care.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participate in management of the patient while in the postanesthesia recovery area, including ordering the administration of fluids and drugs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place special peripheral and central venous and arterial lines for blood sampling and monitoring as appropriate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The certified nurse midwife may, to the extent authorized by an established protocol which has been approved by the medical staff of the health care facility in which the midwifery services are performed, or approved by the nurse midwife’s physician backup when the delivery is performed in a patient’s home, perform any or all of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform superficial minor surgical procedures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manage the patient during labor and delivery to include amniotomy, episiotomy, and repair.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order, initiate, and perform appropriate anesthetic procedures.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform postpartum examination.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order appropriate medications.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide family-planning services and well-woman care.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manage the medical care of the normal obstetrical patient and the initial care of a newborn patient.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nurse practitioner may perform any or all of the following acts within the framework of established protocol:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manage selected medical problems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Order physical and occupational therapy.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate, monitor, or alter therapies for certain uncomplicated acute illnesses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitor and manage patients with stable chronic diseases.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish behavioral problems and diagnosis and make treatment recommendations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall certify, and the department shall issue a certificate to, any nurse meeting the qualifications in this section. The board shall establish an application fee not to exceed $100 and a biennial renewal fee not to exceed $50. The board is authorized to adopt such other rules as are necessary to implement the provisions of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-225; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 4, ch. 84-268; ss. 8, 17, 18, ch. 86-284; s. 58, ch. 91-137; s. 5, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 7, ch. 96-274; s. 1105, ch. 97-103; s. 80, ch. 97-264; s. 8, ch. 2006-251; s. 3, ch. 2007-167; s. 9, ch. 2010-37.</History>
</Section>