<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.0196" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Center for Nursing; board of directors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Center for Nursing shall be governed by a policy-setting board of directors. The board shall consist of 16 members, with a simple majority of the board being nurses representative of various practice areas. Other members shall include representatives of other health care professions, business and industry, health care providers, and consumers. The members of the board shall be appointed by the Governor as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members recommended by the President of the Senate, at least one of whom shall be a registered nurse recommended by the Florida Organization of Nurse Executives and at least one other representative of the hospital industry recommended by the Florida Hospital Association;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members recommended by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, at least one of whom shall be a registered nurse recommended by the Florida Nurses Association and at least one other representative of the long-term care industry;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members recommended by the Governor, two of whom shall be registered nurses;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One nurse educator recommended by the Board of Governors who is a dean of a College of Nursing at a state university; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three nurse educators recommended by the State Board of Education, one of whom must be a director of a nursing program at a state community college.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial terms of the members shall be as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the members appointed pursuant to paragraph (1)(a), two shall be appointed for terms expiring June 30, 2005, one for a term expiring June 30, 2004, and one for a term expiring June 30, 2003.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the members appointed pursuant to paragraph (1)(b), one shall be appointed for a term expiring June 30, 2005, two for terms expiring June 30, 2004, and one for a term expiring June 20, 2003.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the members appointed pursuant to paragraph (1)(c), one shall be appointed for a term expiring June 30, 2005, one for a term expiring June 30, 2004, and two for terms expiring June 30, 2003.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Of the members appointed pursuant to paragraph (1)(d), the terms of two members recommended by the State Board of Education shall expire June 30, 2005; the term of the member who is a dean of a College of Nursing at a state university shall expire June 30, 2004; and the term of the member who is a director of a state community college nursing program shall expire June 30, 2003.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">After the initial appointments expire, the terms of all the members shall be for 3 years, with no member serving more than two consecutive terms.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall have the following powers and duties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To employ an executive director.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To determine operational policy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To elect a chair and officers, to serve 2-year terms. The chair and officers may not succeed themselves.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To establish committees of the board as needed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To appoint a multidisciplinary advisory council for input and advice on policy matters.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To implement the major functions of the center as established in the goals set out in s. 464.0195.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To seek and accept nonstate funds for sustaining the center and carrying out center policy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the board are entitled to receive per diem and allowances prescribed by law for state boards and commissions.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 98, ch. 2001-277; s. 55, ch. 2007-217.</History></Section>