<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.0195" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Center for Nursing; goals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established the Florida Center for Nursing to address issues of supply and demand for nursing, including issues of recruitment, retention, and utilization of nurse workforce resources. The Legislature finds that the center will repay the state’s investment by providing an ongoing strategy for the allocation of the state’s resources directed towards nursing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The primary goals for the center shall be to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a strategic statewide plan for nursing manpower in this state by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing and maintaining a database on nursing supply and demand in the state, to include current supply and demand, and future projections; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selecting from the plan priorities to be addressed.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Convene various groups representative of nurses, other health care providers, business and industry, consumers, legislators, and educators to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review and comment on data analysis prepared for the center;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend systemic changes, including strategies for implementation of recommended changes; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate and report the results of these efforts to the Legislature and others.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enhance and promote recognition, reward, and renewal activities for nurses in the state by:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting nursing excellence programs such as magnet recognition by the American Nurses Credentialing Center;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proposing and creating additional reward, recognition, and renewal activities for nurses; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting media and positive image-building efforts for nursing.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Nursing shall include on its initial and renewal application forms a question asking each nurse to voluntarily contribute to funding the Florida Center for Nursing in addition to paying the fees imposed at the time of licensure and licensure renewal. Revenues collected from nurses over and above the required fees shall be transferred from the Medical Quality Assurance Trust Fund to the Grants and Donations Trust Fund within the Department of Health and shall be used solely to support and maintain the goals and functions of the center. Before giving a nurse the opportunity to contribute to funding the center at the time of licensure renewal, the Board of Nursing shall provide the nurse with a summary of the center’s work, a link to the center’s Internet website, and the following statement: “The Florida Center for Nursing’s operating revenues are derived in part from your donation. In order for the Florida Center for Nursing to continue its work on behalf of nurses, please donate.”</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 97, ch. 2001-277; s. 1, ch. 2002-229; s. 6, ch. 2004-245; s. 5, ch. 2008-19; s. 1, ch. 2009-145.</History></Section>