<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0464.008" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by examination.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed as a registered nurse or licensed practical nurse shall apply to the department to take the licensure examination. The department shall examine each applicant who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form and remitted a fee set by the board not to exceed $150 and has remitted an examination fee set by the board not to exceed $75 plus the actual per applicant cost to the department for purchase of the examination from the National Council of State Boards of Nursing or a similar national organization.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has provided sufficient information on or after October 1, 1989, which must be submitted by the department for a statewide criminal records correspondence check through the Department of Law Enforcement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is in good mental and physical health, is a recipient of a high school diploma or the equivalent, and has completed the requirements for:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduation from an approved program;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduation from a prelicensure nursing education program that the board determines is equivalent to an approved program;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduation on or after July 1, 2009, from an accredited program; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Graduation before July 1, 2009, from a prelicensure nursing education program whose graduates at that time were eligible for examination.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Courses successfully completed in a professional nursing education program that are at least equivalent to a practical nursing education program may be used to satisfy the education requirements for licensure as a licensed practical nurse.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has the ability to communicate in the English language, which may be determined by an examination given by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant who passes the examination and provides proof of meeting the educational requirements specified in subsection (1) shall, unless denied pursuant to s. 464.018, be entitled to licensure as a registered professional nurse or a licensed practical nurse, whichever is applicable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any applicant who fails the examination three consecutive times, regardless of the jurisdiction in which the examination is taken, shall be required to complete a board-approved remedial course before the applicant will be approved for reexamination. After taking the remedial course, the applicant may be approved to retake the examination up to three additional times before the applicant is required to retake remediation. The applicant shall apply for reexamination within 6 months after completion of remediation. The board shall by rule establish guidelines for remedial courses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 6, ch. 79-225; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 6, 17, 18, ch. 86-284; s. 12, ch. 88-205; s. 10, ch. 88-219; s. 34, ch. 89-162; s. 58, ch. 91-137; s. 5, ch. 91-156; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 94, ch. 92-149; s. 5, ch. 96-274; s. 78, ch. 97-264; s. 116, ch. 99-397; s. 95, ch. 2001-277; s. 3, ch. 2010-37.</History>
</Section>