<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0464.204" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Denial, suspension, or revocation of certification; disciplinary actions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following acts constitute grounds for which the board may impose disciplinary sanctions as specified in subsection (2):</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obtaining or attempting to obtain certification or an exemption, or possessing or attempting to possess certification or a letter of exemption, by bribery, misrepresentation, deceit, or through an error of the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intentionally violating any provision of this chapter, chapter 456, or the rules adopted by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board finds any person guilty of any of the grounds set forth in subsection (1), it may enter an order imposing one or more of the following penalties:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Denial, suspension, or revocation of certification.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine not to exceed $150 for each count or separate offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of probation or restriction of certification, including conditions such as corrective actions as retraining or compliance with an approved treatment program for impaired practitioners.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may, upon the request of a certificateholder, exempt the certificateholder from disqualification of employment in accordance with chapter 435 and issue a letter of exemption. The board must notify an applicant seeking an exemption from disqualification from certification or employment of its decision to approve or deny the request within 30 days after the date the board receives all required documentation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 204, ch. 99-397; s. 165, ch. 2000-160; s. 79, ch. 2000-318.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 468.824.</Text></Note></Section>