<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0348.969" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bonds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds may be issued on behalf of the authority as provided by the State Bond Act. In the alternative, the authority may issue bonds pursuant to the provisions of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds of the authority issued pursuant to the provisions of this subsection, whether on original issuance or on refunding, shall be authorized by one or more resolutions of the members, which resolutions may be adopted at the same meeting at which they are introduced. Bonds of the authority so authorized may be issued in one or more series, may be either term or serial bonds, and shall bear such date or dates, be payable on demand or mature at such time or times (not to exceed 40 years from their respective dates), bear interest, fixed or variable, at such rate or rates not exceeding the maximum lawful interest rate, be in such denominations, be in such form (either coupon or fully registered), carry such registration, replacement, or exchangeability privileges, be payable in such medium of payment and at such place or places, be subject to such terms of redemption, with or without premium, have such rank and be entitled to such priorities on the receipts of the authority as the authority may determine. The bonds shall be executed either by manual or facsimile signature by such officers as the authority shall determine, provided such bonds bear at least one signature which is manually executed thereon for the purpose of authenticating same, which manual signature may be that of an authorized officer of the trustee for such bonds, and the coupons attached to such bonds shall bear the facsimile signature or signatures of such officer or officers as are designated by the authority and shall have the seal of the authority affixed, imprinted, reproduced, or lithographed thereon, all as may be prescribed in such resolution or resolutions. In case any officer whose signature or facsimile signature appears on any bonds or coupons ceases to be such officer before delivery of such bonds or coupons, such signature or facsimile signature shall nevertheless be valid and sufficient for all purposes as fully and to the same extent as if such officer had remained in office until such delivery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such bonds shall be sold at public or private sale at such price or prices as the authority determines to be in its best interest, except that the interest costs to the authority on such bonds may not exceed the maximum lawful interest rate. Pending the preparation of definitive bonds, interim certificates may be issued to the purchaser or purchasers of such bonds and may contain such terms and conditions as the authority may determine.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such resolution or resolutions authorizing any bonds hereunder may contain provisions, and valid and legally binding covenants of the authority, which shall be part of the contract with the holders of such bonds, as to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pledging of all or any part of the authority’s receipts.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The completion, improvement, operation, extension, maintenance, repair, lease or lease-purchase agreement of all or any part of the system and the duties of the authority and others, including the department, with reference thereto.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the purposes to which the proceeds of the bonds, then or thereafter to be issued, or of any advances or grants may be applied.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fixing, charging, establishing, and collecting of tolls, rates, fees, rentals, or other charges for use of the services and facilities of the system or any part thereof.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The setting aside of reserves or sinking funds or repair and replacement funds and the regulation and disposition thereof.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the issuance of additional bonds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and provisions of any lease-purchase agreement, deed of trust, or indenture securing the bonds, or under which the same may be issued.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other provisions, additional covenants, and agreements with the holders of the bonds that the authority may deem desirable and proper, including to enhance the security of such bonds or the marketability thereof and which are customary in accordance with the market requirements of the sale of such bonds.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Board of Administration may, upon request of the authority, act as fiscal agent for the authority in the issuance of any bonds which may be issued pursuant to this subsection or the State Bond Act; and the State Board of Administration may, upon request of the authority, take over the management, control, administration, custody, and payment of any and all debt services or funds or assets now or hereafter available for any bonds issued pursuant to this part. Alternatively, as security for such bonds, the authority may enter into deeds of trust, indentures, or other agreements with a corporate trustee or trustees, which shall act as fiscal agent for the authority and may be any trust company within or without the State of Florida and may, under such instruments, assign and pledge all or any of the revenues. Any such deed of trust, indenture, or other agreement may contain such provisions as are customary in such instruments or as the authority may authorize, including, but without limitation, provisions as to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The completion, improvement, operation, extension, maintenance, repair, and lease of, or lease-purchase agreement relating to, all or any part of the system and the duties of the authority and others, including the department, with reference thereto.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of funds and the safeguarding of funds on hand or on deposit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and remedies of the trustee and the holders of the bonds.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and provisions of the bonds or the resolutions authorizing the issuance of same and terms and conditions for modification or amendments of any of the foregoing and of any covenants of the authority in the proceedings authorizing the issuance of the bonds.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the bonds issued pursuant to this subsection are, and are hereby declared to be, negotiable instruments and shall have all the qualities and incidents of negotiable instruments under the law merchant and the Uniform Commercial Code of this state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-354; s. 138, ch. 92-152.</History></Section>