<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0348.967" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Santa Rosa Bay Bridge Authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is created and established a body politic and corporate, an agency of the state, to be known as the “Santa Rosa Bay Bridge Authority,” hereinafter referred to as the “authority.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of the authority shall consist of seven members. Three members shall be appointed by the Governor and three members shall be appointed by the Board of County Commissioners of Santa Rosa County, none of whom shall be an elected official at the time of his or her appointment. The six members appointed by the Governor and the board of county commissioners shall be permanent residents of Santa Rosa County at all times during their terms of office. The seventh member shall be the district secretary of the Department of Transportation serving in the district that contains Santa Rosa County. The term of each appointed member shall be for 4 years. The district secretary shall serve ex officio. A vacancy occurring during a term shall be filled only for the balance of the unexpired term. Any member of the authority is eligible for reappointment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the effective date of his or her appointment, or as soon as practicable thereafter, each appointed member of the authority shall enter upon his or her duties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the authority, before entering upon his or her official duties, shall take and subscribe to an oath, before some official authorized by law to administer oaths, that he or she will faithfully, honestly, and impartially perform the duties devolving upon him or her in office as a member of the governing body of the authority and that he or she will not neglect any duty imposed upon him or her by this part.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A member of the authority may be removed from office by the Governor for misconduct, malfeasance, misfeasance, or nonfeasance in office.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall elect one of its members as chair of the authority. The authority shall also elect a secretary and a treasurer who may or may not be members of the authority. The chair, secretary, and treasurer shall hold such offices at the will of the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members of the authority constitute a quorum. In all cases, an affirmative vote of at least four members present at a given meeting is necessary for any action taken by the authority. No vacancy in the authority shall impair the right of a quorum of the authority to exercise all of the rights and perform all of the duties of the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority may employ an executive secretary, an executive director, its own counsel and legal staff, technical experts, and such engineers and such employees, permanent or temporary, as it may require; determine the qualifications and fix the compensation of such persons, firms, or corporations; and employ a fiscal agent or agents. The authority may delegate to one or more of its agents or employees such of its powers as it deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this part, subject always to the supervision and control of the authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the authority are entitled to receive from the authority travel and other necessary expenses incurred in connection with the business of the authority, as provided in s. 112.061, but they may draw no salaries or other compensation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-354; s. 10, ch. 88-215; s. 524, ch. 95-148; s. 17, ch. 97-100.</History></Section>