<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0348.765" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">This part complete and additional authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers conferred by this part shall be in addition and supplemental to the existing powers of said board and the department, and this part shall not be construed as repealing any of the provisions, of any other law, general, special or local, but to supersede such other laws in the exercise of the powers provided in this part, and to provide a complete method for the exercise of the powers granted in this part. The extension and improvement of said Orlando-Orange County Expressway System, and the issuance of bonds hereunder to finance all or part of the cost thereof, may be accomplished upon compliance with the provisions of this part without regard to or necessity for compliance with the provisions, limitations, or restrictions contained in any other general, special or local law, including, but not limited to, s. 215.821, and no approval of any bonds issued under this part by the qualified electors or qualified electors who are freeholders in the state or in said County of Orange, or in said City of Orlando, or in any other political subdivision of the state, shall be required for the issuance of such bonds pursuant to this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part shall not be deemed to repeal, rescind, or modify any other law or laws relating to said State Board of Administration, said Department of Transportation, or the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration, but shall be deemed to and shall supersede such other law or laws as are inconsistent with the provisions of this part, including, but not limited to, s. 215.821.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 63-573; ss. 22, 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 291, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 132, ch. 2002-20.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 348.0114.</Text></Note></Section>