<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0348.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bonds of the authority.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds may be issued on behalf of the authority pursuant to the State Bond Act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alternatively, the authority shall have the power and is hereby authorized from time to time to issue bonds in such principal amount as, in the opinion of the authority, shall be necessary to provide sufficient moneys for achieving its corporate purposes, including construction, reconstruction, improvement, extension, repair, maintenance and operation of the expressway system, the cost of acquisition of all real property, interest on bonds during construction and for a reasonable period thereafter, establishment of reserves to secure bonds, and all other expenditures of the authority incident to and necessary or convenient to carry out its corporate purposes and powers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds issued by the authority pursuant to paragraph (1)(a) or paragraph (1)(b) shall be authorized by resolution of the members of the authority and shall bear such date or dates, mature at such time or times, not exceeding 40 years from their respective dates, bear interest at such rate or rates, not exceeding the maximum rate fixed by general law for authorities, be in such denominations, be in such form, either coupon or fully registered, carry such registration, exchangeability and interchangeability privileges, be payable in such medium of payment and at such place or places, be subject to such terms of redemption and be entitled to such priorities of lien on the revenues, other available moneys, and the Hillsborough County gasoline tax funds as such resolution or any resolution subsequent thereto may provide. The bonds shall be executed either by manual or facsimile signature by such officers as the authority shall determine, provided that such bonds shall bear at least one signature which is manually executed thereon. The coupons attached to such bonds shall bear the facsimile signature or signatures of such officer or officers as shall be designated by the authority. Such bonds shall have the seal of the authority affixed, imprinted, reproduced, or lithographed thereon.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (1)(a) or paragraph (1)(b) shall be sold at public sale in the same manner provided in the State Bond Act. However, if the authority determines, by official action at a public meeting, that a negotiated sale of such bonds is in the best interest of the authority, the authority may negotiate the sale of such bonds with the underwriter or underwriters designated by the authority and the Division of Bond Finance within the State Board of Administration with respect to bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (1)(a) or solely by the authority with respect to bonds issued pursuant to paragraph (1)(b). The authority’s determination to negotiate the sale of such bonds may be based, in part, upon the written advice of the authority’s financial adviser. Pending the preparation of definitive bonds, temporary bonds or interim certificates may be issued to the purchaser or purchasers of such bonds and may contain such terms and conditions as the authority may determine.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such resolution or resolutions authorizing any bonds may contain provisions which shall be part of the contract with the holders of such bonds, as to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pledging of all or any part of the revenues, the Hillsborough County gasoline tax funds, or other moneys lawfully available therefor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The construction, reconstruction, improvement, extension, repair, maintenance, operation, lease or lease-purchase of the expressway system, or any part or parts thereof, and the duties and obligations of the authority and others, including the department, with reference thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the purposes to which the proceeds of the bonds, then or thereafter to be issued, or of any loan or grant by any federal agency or the state or any political subdivision thereof may be applied.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fixing, charging, establishing, revising, increasing, reducing and collecting of tolls, rates, fees, rentals, or other charges for use of the services and facilities of the expressway system or any part thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The setting aside of reserves or of sinking funds and the regulation and disposition thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limitations on the issuance of additional bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and provisions of any lease-purchase agreement, deed of trust or indenture securing the bonds, or under which same may be issued.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other or additional matters, of like or different character, which in any way affect the security or protection of the bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority may enter into any deeds of trust, indentures or other agreements with any bank or trust company within or without the state, as security for such bonds, and may, under such agreements, assign and pledge all or any of the revenues and other available moneys, including all or any portion of the Hillsborough County gasoline tax funds, pursuant to the terms of this part. Such deed of trust, indenture or other agreement, may contain such provisions as are customary in such instruments or as the authority may authorize, including, but without limitation, provisions as to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pledging of all or any part of the revenues, the Hillsborough County gasoline tax funds, or other moneys lawfully available therefor.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application of funds and the safeguarding of funds on hand or on deposit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights and remedies of the trustee and the holders of the bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The terms and provisions of the bonds or the resolutions authorizing the issuance of the same.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other or additional matters, of like or different character, which in any way affect the security or protection of the bonds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the bonds issued pursuant to this part are, and are hereby declared to be, negotiable instruments, and shall have all the qualities and incidents of negotiable instruments under the law merchant and the negotiable instruments law of the state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intention hereof that any pledge made by the authority shall be valid and binding from the time when the pledge is made; that the moneys so pledged and thereafter received by the authority shall immediately be subject to the lien of such pledge without any physical delivery thereof or further act, and that the lien of any such pledge shall be valid and binding as against all parties having claims of any kind in tort, contract or otherwise against the authority irrespective of whether such parties have notice thereof. Neither the resolution nor any other instrument by which a pledge is created need be recorded.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the members nor any person executing the bonds shall be liable personally on the bonds or be subject to any personal liability or accountability by reason of the issuance thereof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall have power out of any funds available therefor to purchase bonds, which shall thereupon be canceled, at a price not exceeding, if the bonds are then redeemable, the redemption price then applicable plus accrued interest to the next date of redemption thereof, or if the bonds are not then redeemable, the redemption price applicable on the first date after such purchase upon which the bonds become subject to redemption plus accrued interest to said date.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 63-447; s. 1, ch. 68-120; ss. 23, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-260; s. 30, ch. 2010-225.</History>
</Section>