<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0348.753" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Orlando-Orange County Expressway Authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby created and established a body politic and corporate, an agency of the state, to be known as the Orlando-Orange County Expressway Authority, hereinafter referred to as “authority.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The governing body of the authority shall consist of five members. Three members shall be citizens of Orange County, who shall be appointed by the Governor. The fourth member shall be, ex officio, the chair of the County Commissioners of Orange County, and the fifth member shall be, ex officio, the district secretary of the Department of Transportation serving in the district that contains Orange County. The term of each appointed member shall be for 4 years. Each appointed member shall hold office until his or her successor has been appointed and has qualified. A vacancy occurring during a term shall be filled only for the balance of the unexpired term. Each appointed member of the authority shall be a person of outstanding reputation for integrity, responsibility, and business ability, but no person who is an officer or employee of any city or of Orange County in any other capacity shall be an appointed member of the authority. Any member of the authority shall be eligible for reappointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority shall elect one of its members as chair of the authority. The authority shall also elect a secretary and a treasurer who may or may not be members of the authority. The chair, secretary, and treasurer shall hold such offices at the will of the authority. Three members of the authority shall constitute a quorum, and the vote of three members shall be necessary for any action taken by the authority. No vacancy in the authority shall impair the right of a quorum of the authority to exercise all of the rights and perform all of the duties of the authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the effective date of his or her appointment, or as soon thereafter as practicable, each appointed member of the authority shall enter upon his or her duties.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority may employ an executive secretary, an executive director, its own counsel and legal staff, technical experts, such engineers, and such employees, permanent or temporary, as it may require and may determine the qualifications and fix the compensation of such persons, firms, or corporations and may employ a fiscal agent or agents, provided, however, that the authority shall solicit sealed proposals from at least three persons, firms, or corporations for the performance of any services as fiscal agents. The authority may delegate to one or more of its agents or employees such of its power as it shall deem necessary to carry out the purposes of this part, subject always to the supervision and control of the authority. Members of the authority may be removed from their office by the Governor for misconduct, malfeasance, misfeasance, or nonfeasance in office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the authority shall be entitled to receive from the authority their travel and other necessary expenses incurred in connection with the business of the authority as provided in s. 112.061, but they shall draw no salaries or other compensation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 63-573; s. 9, ch. 88-215; s. 520, ch. 95-148; s. 16, ch. 97-100.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 348.0102.</Text></Note></Section>