<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0348.68" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Consultation with Hillsborough County City-County Planning Commission.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining the route or routes, and the design and type of construction in connection with constructing the expressway system or any extension thereof, consideration shall be given by the authority to the comprehensive plans and the economic needs of the city and county and the usage for which the properties abutting thereon is best suited. In the furtherance of this purpose, the authority shall consult with the Hillsborough County City-County Planning Commission, hereinafter referred to as the commission. The authority may employ a firm of nationally recognized consultants and traffic engineers and the traffic engineers of the Florida Department of Transportation. In conducting their studies and in preparing surveys and estimates in connection with the location of the route or routes and with such construction, the consultants and traffic engineers shall consult with the commission for the purpose of considering any traffic studies, the comprehensive plan and other pertinent information which the commission may have available. After the studies and recommendations of the authority’s traffic engineers, consulting engineers, and other advisers have been made, the authority shall transmit such studies and recommendations to the commission. The commission, within 45 days after receipt thereof, shall transmit to the authority its written recommendations as to the consistency of such proposed route or routes with the adopted comprehensive plan or element or portion thereof. The authority shall thereafter hold a public hearing, on at least 10 days’ notice which shall be published in a newspaper designated by the authority and of general circulation in Hillsborough County, at which all interested persons may be heard with respect to the recommended route or routes or alternate routes of the expressway system. After such public hearing, the authority shall by resolution determine the route or routes of the expressway system or any extension thereof. However, the commission may request additional review of the approved route or routes for the purpose of commenting on continued consistency with the adopted comprehensive plan, element, or portion thereof if:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 5 years of approval of the route or routes, the authority does not reserve or acquire the proposed rights-of-way within the route or routes as provided by s. 337.27; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority reserves or acquires rights-of-way under s. 337.27, but fails to comply with the statutory requirements for land acquisition or design commencement or completion.</Text></Subsection><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If an additional review is requested, the commission shall conduct its review and transmit its recommendations within 45 days.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 63-447; s. 2, ch. 87-218; s. 109, ch. 92-152.</History></Section>