<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0348.9781" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">This part complete and additional authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers conferred by this part shall be in addition and supplemental to the existing respective powers of the authority, the department, and the county, if any, and this part shall not be construed as repealing any of the provisions of any other law, general, special, or local, but shall be deemed to supersede such other law or laws in the exercise of the powers provided in this part insofar as such other law or laws are inconsistent with the provisions of this part and to provide a complete method for the exercise of the powers granted in this part. The construction, reconstruction, improvement, extension, repair, maintenance, and operation of the system, and the issuance of bonds under this part to finance all or part of the cost thereof, may be accomplished upon compliance with the provisions of this part without regard to or necessity for compliance with the provisions, limitations, or restrictions contained in any other general, special, or local law, and neither approval of any bonds issued under this part by the qualified electors or qualified electors who are freeholders in the state or in the county or in any other political subdivision of the state, nor any procedures or proceedings, publications, notices, consents, approvals, orders, acts, or things by the authority or the members thereof, or any other governmental entity, shall be required for the issuance of such bonds, except as may be prescribed in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part shall not be deemed to supersede, repeal, rescind, or modify any other law or laws relating to the State Board of Administration, the Department of Transportation, or the Division of Bond Finance, but shall be deemed to and shall supersede such other law or laws as are inconsistent with the provisions of this part.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 146, ch. 92-152; s. 55, ch. 95-143.</History></Section>