<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0348.0005" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bonds.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds may be issued on behalf of an authority as provided by the State Bond Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authority in any county as defined in s. 125.011(1), may issue bonds pursuant to this part, which do not pledge the full faith and credit of the state in such principal amount as, in the opinion of the authority, is necessary to provide sufficient moneys for achieving its corporate purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bonds of an authority in any county as defined in s. 125.011(1), issued pursuant to the provisions of this part, whether on original issuance or refunding, must be authorized by resolution of the authority, after approval of the issuance of the bonds at a public hearing, and may be either term or serial bonds, shall bear such date or dates, mature at such time or times, bear interest at such rate or rates, be payable semiannually, be in such denominations, be in such form, either coupon or fully registered, shall carry such registration, exchangeability and interchangeability privileges, be payable in such medium of payment and at such place or places, be subject to such terms of redemption and be entitled to such priorities on the revenues, rates, fees, rentals, or other charges or receipts of the authority including any county gasoline tax funds received by an authority pursuant to the terms of any interlocal or lease-purchase agreement between an authority or a county, as such resolution or any resolution subsequent thereto may provide. The bonds must be executed by such officers as the authority determines under the requirements of s. 279.06.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Said bonds shall be sold by the authority at public sale by competitive bid. However, if the authority, after receipt of a written recommendation from a financial adviser, shall determine by official action after public hearing by a two-thirds vote of all voting members of the authority that a negotiated sale of the bonds is in the best interest of the authority, the authority may negotiate for sale of the bonds with the underwriter or underwriters designated by the authority and the county in which the authority exists. The authority shall provide specific findings in a resolution as to the reasons requiring the negotiated sale, which resolution shall incorporate and have attached thereto the written recommendation of the financial adviser required by this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such resolution or resolutions authorizing any bonds hereunder which do not pledge the full faith and credit of the state may contain provisions that are part of the contract with the holders of the bonds, as an authority determines proper. In addition, an authority may enter into trust indentures or other agreements with its fiscal agent, or with any bank or trust company within or without the state, as security for such bonds, and may, under the agreements, assign and pledge the revenues, rates, fees, rentals, tolls, or other charges or receipts of an authority, including any county gasoline tax funds received by an authority.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the bonds issued pursuant to this part are negotiable instruments and have all the qualities and incidents of negotiable instruments under the law merchant and the negotiable instruments law of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this part, in any county as defined in s. 125.011(1), each project, building, or facility which has been or will be financed by the issuance of bonds or other evidence of indebtedness and that does not pledge the full faith and credit of the state under this part and any refinancing thereof is approved for purposes of s. 11(f), Art. VII of the State Constitution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 90-136; s. 57, ch. 94-237; s. 138, ch. 99-13; s. 112, ch. 99-385; s. 57, ch. 2000-152; s. 15, ch. 2011-64.</History>
</Section>