<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0445.028" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transitional benefits and services.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In cooperation with Workforce Florida, Inc., the Department of Children and Family Services shall develop procedures to ensure that families leaving the temporary cash assistance program receive transitional benefits and services that will assist the family in moving toward self-sufficiency. At a minimum, such procedures must include, but are not limited to, the following:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each recipient of cash assistance who is determined ineligible for cash assistance for a reason other than a work activity sanction shall be contacted by the workforce system case manager and provided information about the availability of transitional benefits and services. Such contact shall be attempted prior to closure of the case management file.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each recipient of temporary cash assistance who is determined ineligible for cash assistance due to noncompliance with the work activity requirements shall be contacted and provided information in accordance with s. 414.065(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, in consultation with the board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., shall develop informational material, including posters and brochures, to better inform families about the availability of transitional benefits and services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., in cooperation with the Department of Children and Family Services shall, to the extent permitted by federal law, develop procedures to maximize the utilization of transitional Medicaid by families who leave the temporary cash assistance program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 2000-165.</History></Section>