<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0445.026" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cash assistance severance benefit.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who meets the criteria listed in this section may choose to receive a lump-sum payment in lieu of ongoing cash assistance payments, provided the individual:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is employed and is receiving earnings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received cash assistance for at least 6 consecutive months.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expects to remain employed for at least 6 months.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chooses to receive a one-time, lump-sum payment in lieu of ongoing monthly payments.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provides employment and earnings information to the regional workforce board, so that the regional workforce board can ensure that the family’s eligibility for severance benefits can be evaluated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Signs an agreement not to apply for or accept cash assistance for 6 months after receipt of the one-time payment. In the event of an emergency, such agreement shall provide for an exception to this restriction, provided that the one-time payment shall be deducted from any cash assistance for which the family subsequently is approved. This deduction may be prorated over an 8-month period. The board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., shall adopt criteria defining the conditions under which a family may receive cash assistance due to such emergency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such individual may choose to accept a one-time, lump-sum payment of $1,000 in lieu of receiving ongoing cash assistance. Such payment shall only count toward the time limitation for the month in which the payment is made in lieu of cash assistance. A participant choosing to accept such payment shall be terminated from cash assistance. However, eligibility for Medicaid, food assistance, or child care shall continue, subject to the eligibility requirements of those programs.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 99-241; s. 26, ch. 2000-165; s. 38, ch. 2010-209.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 414.1525.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>