<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0445.022" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Retention Incentive Training Accounts.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To promote job retention and to enable upward job advancement into higher skilled, higher paying employment, the board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., and regional workforce boards may assemble, from postsecondary education institutions, a list of programs and courses for participants who have become employed which promote job retention and advancement.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., may establish Retention Incentive Training Accounts (RITAs). RITAs shall utilize Temporary Assistance to Needy Families (TANF) block grant funds specifically appropriated for this purpose. RITAs must complement the Individual Training Account required by the federal Workforce Investment Act of 1998, Pub. L. No. 105-220.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RITAs may pay for tuition, fees, educational materials, coaching and mentoring, performance incentives, transportation to and from courses, child care costs during education courses, and other such costs as the regional workforce boards determine are necessary to effect successful job retention and advancement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional workforce boards shall retain only those courses that continue to meet their performance standards as established in their local plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional workforce boards shall report annually to the Legislature on the measurable retention and advancement success of each program provider and the effectiveness of RITAs, making recommendations for any needed changes or modifications.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 99-241; s. 22, ch. 2000-165.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 414.223.</Text></Note></Section>