<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0445.021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Relocation assistance program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that the need for public assistance may arise because a family is located in an area with limited employment opportunities, because of geographic isolation, because of formidable transportation barriers, because of isolation from their extended family, or because domestic violence interferes with the ability of a parent to maintain self-sufficiency. Accordingly, there is established a program to assist families in relocating to communities with greater opportunities for self-sufficiency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The relocation assistance program shall involve five steps by the regional workforce board, in cooperation with the Department of Children and Family Services:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination that the family is receiving temporary cash assistance or that all requirements of eligibility for diversion services would likely be met.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination that there is a basis for believing that relocation will contribute to the ability of the applicant to achieve self-sufficiency. For example, the applicant:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is unlikely to achieve economic self-sufficiency at the current community of residence;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has secured a job that provides an increased salary or improved benefits and that requires relocation to another community;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has a family support network that will contribute to job retention in another community;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is determined, pursuant to criteria or procedures established by the board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., to be a victim of domestic violence who would experience reduced probability of further incidents through relocation; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Must relocate in order to receive education or training that is directly related to the applicant’s employment or career advancement.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of a relocation plan that includes such requirements as are necessary to prevent abuse of the benefit and provisions to protect the safety of victims of domestic violence and avoid provisions that place them in anticipated danger. The payment to defray relocation expenses shall be determined based on criteria approved by the board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc. Participants in the relocation program shall be eligible for diversion or transitional benefits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A determination, pursuant to criteria adopted by the board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., that a community receiving a relocated family has the capacity to provide needed services and employment opportunities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitoring the relocation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A family receiving relocation assistance for reasons other than domestic violence must sign an agreement restricting the family from applying for temporary cash assistance for a period of 6 months, unless an emergency is demonstrated to the regional workforce board. If a demonstrated emergency forces the family to reapply for temporary cash assistance within such period, after receiving a relocation assistance payment, repayment must be made on a prorated basis and subtracted from any regular payment of temporary cash assistance for which the applicant may be eligible.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., may establish criteria for developing and implementing relocation plans and for drafting agreements to restrict a family from applying for temporary cash assistance for a specified period after receiving a relocation assistance payment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 98-57; s. 16, ch. 99-241; s. 21, ch. 2000-165.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 414.155.</Text></Note></Section>