<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0445.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Workforce information systems.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., shall implement, subject to legislative appropriation, automated information systems that are necessary for the efficient and effective operation and management of the workforce development system. These information systems shall include, but need not be limited to, the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An integrated management system for the one-stop service delivery system, which includes, at a minimum, common registration and intake, screening for needs and benefits, case planning and tracking, training benefits management, service and training provider management, performance reporting, executive information and reporting, and customer-satisfaction tracking and reporting.</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The system should report current budgeting, expenditure, and performance information for assessing performance related to outcomes, service delivery, and financial administration for workforce programs pursuant to s. 445.004(5) and (9).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information system should include auditable systems and controls to ensure financial integrity and valid and reliable performance information.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The system should support service integration and case management by providing for case tracking for participants in welfare transition programs.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An automated job-matching information system that is accessible to employers, job seekers, and other users via the Internet, and that includes, at a minimum:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Skill match information, including skill gap analysis; resume creation; job order creation; skill tests; job search by area, employer type, and employer name; and training provider linkage;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Job market information based on surveys, including local, state, regional, national, and international occupational and job availability information; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service provider information, including education and training providers, child care facilities and related information, health and social service agencies, and other providers of services that would be useful to job seekers.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In procuring workforce information systems, Workforce Florida, Inc., shall employ competitive processes, including requests for proposals, competitive negotiation, and other competitive processes to ensure that the procurement results in the most cost-effective investment of state funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., may procure independent verification and validation services associated with developing and implementing any workforce information system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., shall coordinate development and implementation of workforce information systems with the executive director of the Agency for Enterprise Information Technology to ensure compatibility with the state’s information system strategy and enterprise architecture.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 2000-165; s. 14, ch. 2008-116.</History></Section>