<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0445.007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Regional workforce boards.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One regional workforce board shall be appointed in each designated service delivery area and shall serve as the local workforce investment board pursuant to Pub. L. No. 105-220. The membership of the board shall be consistent with Pub. L. No. 105-220, Title I, s. 117(b) but may not exceed the minimum membership required in Pub. L. No. 105-220, Title I, s. 117(b)(2)(A) and in this subsection. Upon approval by the Governor, the chief elected official may appoint additional members above the limit set by this subsection. If a public education or training provider is represented on the board, a representative of a private nonprofit provider and a representative of a private for-profit provider must also be appointed to the board. The board shall include one nonvoting representative from a military installation if a military installation is located within the region and the appropriate military command or organization authorizes such representation. It is the intent of the Legislature that membership of a regional workforce board include persons who are current or former recipients of welfare transition assistance as defined in s. 445.002(2) or workforce services as provided in s. 445.009(1) or that such persons be included as ex officio members of the board or of committees organized by the board. The importance of minority and gender representation shall be considered when making appointments to the board. The board, its committees, subcommittees, and subdivisions, and other units of the workforce system, including units that may consist in whole or in part of local governmental units, may use any method of telecommunications to conduct meetings, including establishing a quorum through telecommunications, provided that the public is given proper notice of the telecommunications meeting and reasonable access to observe and, when appropriate, participate. Regional workforce boards are subject to chapters 119 and 286 and s. 24, Art. I of the State Constitution. If the regional workforce board enters into a contract with an organization or individual represented on the board of directors, the contract must be approved by a two-thirds vote of the board, a quorum having been established, and the board member who could benefit financially from the transaction must abstain from voting on the contract. A board member must disclose any such conflict in a manner that is consistent with the procedures outlined in s. 112.3143. Each member of a regional workforce board who is not otherwise required to file a full and public disclosure of financial interests pursuant to s. 8, Art. II of the State Constitution or s. 112.3144 shall file a statement of financial interests pursuant to s. 112.3145. The executive director or designated person responsible for the operational and administrative functions of the regional workforce board who is not otherwise required to file a full and public disclosure of financial interests pursuant to s. 8, Art. II of the State Constitution or s. 112.3144 shall file a statement of financial interests pursuant to s. 112.3145.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regional workforce board shall elect a chair from among the representatives described in Pub. L. No. 105-220, Title I, s. 117(b)(2)(A)(i) to serve for a term of no more than 2 years and shall serve no more than two terms.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Governor may remove a member of the board, the executive director of the board, or the designated person responsible for the operational and administrative functions of the board for cause. As used in this paragraph, the term “cause” includes, but is not limited to, engaging in fraud or other criminal acts, incapacity, unfitness, neglect of duty, official incompetence and irresponsibility, misfeasance, malfeasance, nonfeasance, or lack of performance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Economic Opportunity, under the direction of Workforce Florida, Inc., shall assign staff to meet with each regional workforce board annually to review the board’s performance and to certify that the board is in compliance with applicable state and federal law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the duties and functions specified by Workforce Florida, Inc., and by the interlocal agreement approved by the local county or city governing bodies, the regional workforce board shall have the following responsibilities:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, submit, ratify, or amend the local plan pursuant to Pub. L. No. 105-220, Title I, s. 118, and the provisions of this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conclude agreements necessary to designate the fiscal agent and administrative entity. A public or private entity, including an entity established pursuant to s. 163.01, which makes a majority of the appointments to a regional workforce board may serve as the board’s administrative entity if approved by Workforce Florida, Inc., based upon a showing that a fair and competitive process was used to select the administrative entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complete assurances required for the charter process of Workforce Florida, Inc., and provide ongoing oversight related to administrative costs, duplicated services, career counseling, economic development, equal access, compliance and accountability, and performance outcomes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Oversee the one-stop delivery system in its local area.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., shall implement a training program for the regional workforce boards to familiarize board members with the state’s workforce development goals and strategies.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The regional workforce board shall designate all local service providers and may not transfer this authority to a third party. Consistent with the intent of the Workforce Investment Act, regional workforce boards should provide the greatest possible choice of training providers to those who qualify for training services. A regional workforce board may not restrict the choice of training providers based upon cost, location, or historical training arrangements. However, a board may restrict the amount of training resources available to any one client. Such restrictions may vary based upon the cost of training in the client’s chosen occupational area. The regional workforce board may be designated as a one-stop operator and direct provider of intake, assessment, eligibility determinations, or other direct provider services except training services. Such designation may occur only with the agreement of the chief elected official and the Governor as specified in 29 U.S.C. s. 2832(f)(2). Workforce Florida, Inc., shall establish procedures by which a regional workforce board may request permission to operate under this section and the criteria under which such permission may be granted. The criteria shall include, but need not be limited to, a reduction in the cost of providing the permitted services. Such permission shall be granted for a period not to exceed 3 years for any single request submitted by the regional workforce board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional workforce boards shall adopt a committee structure consistent with applicable federal law and state policies established by Workforce Florida, Inc.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The importance of minority and gender representation shall be considered when appointments are made to any committee established by the regional workforce board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of procurement, regional workforce boards and their administrative entities are not state agencies and are exempt from chapters 120 and 287. The regional workforce boards shall apply the procurement and expenditure procedures required by federal law and policies of the Department of Economic Opportunity and Workforce Florida, Inc., for the expenditure of federal, state, and nonpass-through funds. The making or approval of smaller, multiple payments for a single purchase with the intent to avoid or evade the monetary thresholds and procedures established by federal law and policies of the Department of Economic Opportunity and Workforce Florida, Inc., is grounds for removal for cause. Regional workforce boards, their administrative entities, committees, and subcommittees, and other workforce units may authorize expenditures to award suitable framed certificates, pins, or other tokens of recognition for performance by units of the workforce system. Regional workforce boards; their administrative entities, committees, and subcommittees; and other workforce units may authorize expenditures for promotional items, such as t-shirts, hats, or pens printed with messages promoting Florida’s workforce system to employers, job seekers, and program participants. However, such expenditures are subject to federal regulations applicable to the expenditure of federal funds. All contracts executed by regional workforce boards must include specific performance expectations and deliverables.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State and federal funds provided to the regional workforce boards may not be used directly or indirectly to pay for meals, food, or beverages for board members, staff, or employees of regional workforce boards, Workforce Florida, Inc., or the Department of Economic Opportunity except as expressly authorized by state law. Preapproved, reasonable, and necessary per diem allowances and travel expenses may be reimbursed. Such reimbursement shall be at the standard travel reimbursement rates established in s. 112.061 and shall be in compliance with all applicable federal and state requirements. Workforce Florida, Inc., shall develop a statewide fiscal policy applicable to the state board and all regional workforce boards, to hold both the state and regional boards strictly accountable for adherence to the policy and subject to regular and periodic monitoring by the Department of Economic Opportunity, the administrative entity for Workforce Florida, Inc. Boards are prohibited from expending state or federal funds for entertainment costs and recreational activities for board members and employees as these terms are defined by 2 C.F.R. part 230.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To increase transparency and accountability, a regional workforce board must comply with the requirements of this section before contracting with a member of the board or a relative, as defined in s. 112.3143(1)(b), of a board member or of an employee of the board. Such contracts may not be executed before or without the approval of Workforce Florida, Inc. Such contracts, as well as documentation demonstrating adherence to this section as specified by Workforce Florida, Inc., must be submitted to the Department of Economic Opportunity for review and recommendation according to criteria to be determined by Workforce Florida, Inc. Such a contract must be approved by a two-thirds vote of the board, a quorum having been established; all conflicts of interest must be disclosed before the vote; and any member who may benefit from the contract, or whose relative may benefit from the contract, must abstain from the vote. A contract under $25,000 between a regional workforce board and a member of that board or between a relative, as defined in s. 112.3143(1)(b), of a board member or of an employee of the board is not required to have the prior approval of Workforce Florida, Inc., but must be approved by a two-thirds vote of the board, a quorum having been established, and must be reported to the Department of Economic Opportunity and Workforce Florida, Inc., within 30 days after approval. If a contract cannot be approved by Workforce Florida, Inc., a review of the decision to disapprove the contract may be requested by the regional workforce board or other parties to the disapproved contract.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each regional workforce board shall develop a budget for the purpose of carrying out the duties of the board under this section, subject to the approval of the chief elected official. Each regional workforce board shall submit its annual budget for review to Workforce Florida, Inc., no later than 2 weeks after the chair approves the budget.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., shall evaluate the means to establish a single, statewide workforce-system brand for the state and shall submit its recommendations to the Governor by November 1, 2012.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 96-404; s. 1072, ch. 97-103; s. 54, ch. 99-251; s. 7, ch. 2000-165; s. 3, ch. 2001-160; s. 5, ch. 2001-175; s. 8, ch. 2004-230; s. 5, ch. 2005-255; s. 3, ch. 2006-287; s. 1, ch. 2008-161; s. 49, ch. 2010-153; s. 383, ch. 2011-142; s. 9, ch. 2012-6; s. 2, ch. 2012-29.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 446.602; s. 288.9953.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>