<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0445.0325" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Welfare Transition Trust Fund.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Welfare Transition Trust Fund is created in the State Treasury, to be administered by the Department of Economic Opportunity. Funds shall be credited to the trust fund to be used for the purposes of the welfare transition program set forth in ss. 445.017-445.032.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The intent of the Welfare Transition Trust Fund is to support the welfare transition program, including diversion services, employment and related services, transition services, and support services.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds budgeted for the welfare transition program may be appropriated to the Welfare Transition Trust Fund for implementation of welfare transition services. Additional funds may be placed in the Welfare Transition Trust Fund, including incentive funds earned by the state for purposes of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All funds transferred to and retained in the trust fund shall be invested pursuant to s. 17.61. Any interest accruing to the trust fund shall be for the benefit of the welfare transition program. Notwithstanding s. 216.301 and pursuant to s. 216.351, any undisbursed balance remaining in the trust fund and interest accruing to the trust fund not distributed at the end of the fiscal year shall remain in the trust fund and shall increase the total funds available to implement the welfare transition program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-174; s. 499, ch. 2003-261; s. 2, ch. 2004-212; s. 3, ch. 2004-235; s. 387, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>