<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0445.030" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transitional education and training.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to assist former recipients of temporary cash assistance who are working or actively seeking employment in continuing their training and upgrading their skills, education, or training, support services may be provided for up to 2 years after the family is no longer receiving temporary cash assistance. This section does not constitute an entitlement to transitional education and training. If funds are not sufficient to provide services under this section, the board of directors of Workforce Florida, Inc., may limit or otherwise prioritize transitional education and training.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Education or training resources available in the community at no additional cost shall be used whenever possible.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Regional workforce boards may authorize child care or other support services in addition to services provided in conjunction with employment. For example, a participant who is employed full time may receive child care services related to that employment and may also receive additional child care services in conjunction with training to upgrade the participant’s skills.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transitional education or training must be job-related, but may include training to improve job skills in a participant’s existing area of employment or may include training to prepare a participant for employment in another occupation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A regional workforce board may enter into an agreement with an employer to share the costs relating to upgrading the skills of participants hired by the employer. For example, a regional workforce board may agree to provide support services such as transportation or a wage subsidy in conjunction with training opportunities provided by the employer.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 25, ch. 96-175; s. 19, ch. 97-173; s. 24, ch. 99-241; s. 29, ch. 2000-165; s. 23, ch. 2010-210.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 414.22.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>