<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0445.051" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Individual development accounts.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this act is to provide for the establishment of individual development accounts that can provide families having limited means an opportunity to accumulate assets and to facilitate and mobilize savings; to promote education, homeownership, and microenterprise development; and help to stabilize families and build communities. This section implements the provisions of s. 404(h) of the Social Security Act, as amended, 42 U.S.C. s. 604(h), related to individual development accounts. Nothing in this section is intended to conflict with the provisions of federal law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Individual development account” means an account established exclusively to pay the qualified expenses of an eligible individual or family. The account is funded through periodic contributions by the establishing individual which are matched by or through a qualified entity for a qualified purpose.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified entity” means:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A not-for-profit organization described in s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, and exempt from taxation under s. 501(a) of such code; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state or local government agency acting in cooperation with an organization described in subparagraph 1. For purposes of this section, a regional workforce board is a government agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Financial institution” has the same meaning as in s. 655.005.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Eligible educational institution” means:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An institution described in s. 481(a)(1) or s. 1201(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, 20 U.S.C. s. 1088(a)(1) or s. 1141(a), as such sections are in effect on the date of the enactment of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, Pub. L. No. 104-193.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area vocational education school, as defined in s. 521(4)(C) or (D) of the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act, 20 U.S.C. s. 2471(4), in this state, as such sections are in effect on the date of the enactment of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, Pub. L. No. 104-193.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Postsecondary educational expenses” means:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Tuition and fees required for the enrollment or attendance of a student at an eligible educational institution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees, books, supplies, and equipment required for courses of instruction at an eligible educational institution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified acquisition costs” means the costs of acquiring, constructing, or reconstructing a residence. The term includes any usual or reasonable settlement, financing, or other closing costs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified business” means any business that does not contravene any law or public policy.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified business capitalization expenses” means qualified expenditures for the capitalization of a qualified business pursuant to a qualified plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified expenditures” means expenditures included in a qualified plan, including capital, plant, equipment, working capital, and inventory expenses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified first-time homebuyer” means a taxpayer and, if married, the taxpayer’s spouse, who has no present ownership interest in a principal residence during the 3-year period ending on the date of acquisition of the principal residence.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Date of acquisition” means the date on which a binding contract to acquire, construct, or reconstruct the principal residence is entered into.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified plan” means a business plan or a plan to use a business asset purchased, which:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is approved by a financial institution, a microenterprise development organization, or a nonprofit loan fund having demonstrated fiduciary integrity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Includes a description of services or goods to be sold, a marketing plan, and projected financial statements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">May require the eligible individual to obtain the assistance of an experienced entrepreneurial advisor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualified principal residence” means a principal residence, within the meaning of s. 1034 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, the qualified acquisition costs of which do not exceed 100 percent of the average area purchase price applicable to such residence, determined in accordance with s. 143(e)(2) and (3) of that code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall amend the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families State Plan which was submitted in accordance with s. 402 of the Social Security Act, as amended, 42 U.S.C. s. 602, to provide for the use of funds for individual development accounts in accordance with this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any family subject to time limits and fully complying with work requirements of the temporary cash assistance program, pursuant to ss. 414.045, 414.065, 414.095, 414.105, and 445.024, which enters into an agreement with an approved fiduciary organization is eligible to participate in an individual development account.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contributions to the individual development account by an individual may be derived only from earned income, as defined in s. 911(d)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The individual or family must enter into an individual development account agreement with a certified fiduciary organization as described in subsection (7). This account agreement shall include, but need not be limited to, the matching funds to be contributed to the account, limits on the deposits for which the match will be provided, required documentation necessary for payment of moneys in the account to be made for a qualified purpose, and penalties for withdrawal of funds not used for one or more of the qualified purposes.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligible participants may receive matching funds for contributions to the individual development account, pursuant to the strategic plan for workforce development. When not restricted to the contrary, matching funds may be paid from state and federal funds under the control of the regional workforce board, from local agencies, or from private donations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligible participants may receive bonus payments for program compliance, to the extent provided in the strategic plan for workforce development. Such bonus payments may provide for a matching proportion higher than that of matching funds described in paragraph (d).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual development accounts may be available for any of the following qualified purposes once the family no longer receives cash assistance:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Postsecondary educational expenses paid from an individual development account directly to an eligible educational institution;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Qualified acquisition costs with respect to a qualified principal residence for a qualified first-time homebuyer, if paid from an individual development account directly to the persons to whom the amounts are due; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amounts paid from an individual development account directly to a business capitalization account that is established in a federally insured financial institution and is restricted to use solely for qualified business capitalization.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Workforce Florida, Inc., shall establish procedures for regional workforce boards to include in their annual program and financial plan an application to offer an individual development account program as part of their TANF allocation. These procedures shall include, but need not be limited to, administrative costs permitted for the fiduciary organization and policies relative to identifying the match ratio and limits on the deposits for which the match will be provided in the application process. Workforce Florida, Inc., shall establish policies and procedures that are necessary to ensure that funds held in an individual development account are not withdrawn except for one or more of the qualified purposes described in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fiduciary organizations shall be the regional workforce board or other community-based organizations designated by the regional workforce board to serve as intermediaries between individual account holders and financial institutions holding accounts. Responsibilities of such fiduciary organizations may include marketing participation, soliciting matching contributions, counseling program participants, and conducting verification and compliance activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., shall establish procedures for controlling the withdrawal of funds for uses other than qualified purposes, including specifying conditions under which an account must be closed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fiduciary organization shall establish a grievance committee and a procedure for hearing, reviewing, and responding in writing to any grievance filed by a holder of an individual development account who disputes a decision of the operating organization that funds were withdrawn for uses other than qualified purposes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon an account holder’s death, his or her account may be transferred to the ownership of a contingent beneficiary. An account holder shall name contingent beneficiaries at the time the account is established and may change such beneficiaries at any time.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Financial institutions approved by Workforce Florida, Inc., may establish individual development accounts pursuant to this section. A financial institution shall certify the establishment of the individual development accounts in accordance with the forms, documentation, and requirements prescribed by Workforce Florida, Inc.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 404(h)(4) of the Social Security Act, as amended, 42 U.S.C. s. 604(h)(4), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, other than the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, funds in an individual development account, including interest accruing in such account, shall be disregarded in determining eligibility for any federal or state program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to policy direction by Workforce Florida, Inc., the Department of Economic Opportunity shall adopt such rules as are necessary to implement this act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-96; s. 392, ch. 2011-142; s. 36, ch. 2011-194.</History>
</Section>