<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0445.055" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Employment advocacy and assistance program targeting military spouses and dependents.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that military families are faced with a variety of challenges, including frequent relocations, recurring deployments, lengthy periods of separation, and heightened anxiety and uncertainty during periods of conflict. A military spouse’s ability to gain job skills and maintain a career contributes to the financial well-being of the family, spouse satisfaction with military life, and military retention and readiness. Military spouses are often required to terminate their employment in order to support their spouse’s highly mobile military commitment. The unemployment rate for military spouses is approximately four times the civilian unemployment rate, and military spouse earnings are significantly lower than those of their comparably educated civilian peers. Recognizing the employment challenges faced by military spouses and the importance of military families to our communities and economy, the Legislature declares its intent to establish an employment advocacy and assistance program to serve Florida’s military families.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., shall establish an employment advocacy and assistance program targeting military spouses and dependents. This program shall deliver employment assistance services through military family employment advocates colocated within selected one-stop career centers. Persons eligible for assistance through this program shall include spouses and dependents of active duty military personnel, Florida National Guard members, and military reservists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Military family employment advocates are responsible for providing the following services and activities:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Coordination of employment assistance services through military base family support centers, Florida’s one-stop career centers, and veteran support organizations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Training to one-stop career center managers and staff on the unique employment needs and skills of military family members.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promoting and marketing the benefits of employing military family members to prospective employers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisting employment-seeking military family members through job counseling, job search and placement services, the dissemination of information on educational and training programs, and the availability of support services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other employment assistance services Workforce Florida, Inc., deems necessary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Workforce Florida, Inc., may enter into agreements with public and private entities to provide services authorized under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2004-230.</History></Section>