<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0686.611" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlawful acts and practices.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices in the conduct of the manufacturing, distribution, wholesaling, sale, and advertising of outdoor power equipment are declared to be unlawful.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is deemed a violation of this section for any manufacturer, factory branch, factory representative, distributor, distributor branch, distributor representative, wholesaler, or dealer to engage in any action which is arbitrary, capricious, in bad faith, or unconscionable and which causes damage in terms of law or equity to any of the parties or to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is deemed a violation of this section for a manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor, distributor branch or division, wholesaler, or wholesale branch or division, or officer, agent, or other representative thereof, to coerce, compel, or attempt to coerce or compel any dealer:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To order or accept delivery of any outdoor power equipment or item of such equipment, parts or accessories therefor, or other commodity or commodities which such dealer has not voluntarily ordered.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To order or accept delivery of any outdoor power equipment with special features, accessories, or equipment not included in the base list price of such outdoor power equipment as publicly advertised by the manufacturer of the outdoor power equipment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is deemed a violation of this section for a manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor, distributor branch or division, wholesaler, or wholesale branch or division, or officer, agent, or other representative thereof:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To refuse to deliver to any dealer having a contractual agreement for the retail sale of new outdoor power equipment sold or distributed by such manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor branch or division, or wholesale branch or division, in reasonable quantities and within a reasonable time after receipt of the dealer’s order, any outdoor power equipment or item of such equipment covered by such agreement specifically advertised or represented by such manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor, distributor branch or division, wholesaler, or wholesale branch or division to be available for immediate delivery. However, the failure to deliver any such outdoor power equipment or item of such equipment is not considered a violation of this section if such failure is due to a prudent and reasonable restriction on the extension of credit by the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler to the dealer, an act of God, a work stoppage or delay due to a strike or labor difficulty, a bona fide shortage of materials, a freight embargo, or another cause over which the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler, or any agent thereof, has no control whatsoever.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To coerce, compel, or attempt to coerce or compel any dealer to enter into any agreement, whether written or oral, supplementary to an existing dealer agreement with such manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor, distributor branch or division, wholesaler, or wholesale branch or division, or officer, agent, or other representative thereof; or to do any other act prejudicial to such dealer by threatening to cancel any contractual agreement existing between such manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor, distributor branch or division, wholesaler, or wholesale branch or division and such dealer. However, notice in good faith to any dealer of such dealer’s violation or breach of any terms or provisions of such contractual agreement does not constitute a violation of this section if such notice is in writing and is mailed by registered or certified mail to such dealer at her or his current business address and such notice contains the specific facts as to the dealer’s violation or breach of such contractual agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To terminate or cancel the selling agreement of any dealer without due cause, as defined in subparagraph 2. The nonrenewal of a selling agreement, without due cause, constitutes an unfair termination or cancellation, regardless of the specified time period of such selling agreement. Except when the ground for such termination or cancellation falls within sub-subparagraph 2.c., such manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor, distributor branch or division, wholesaler, or wholesale branch or division, or officer, agent, or other representative thereof, shall notify a dealer in writing of the termination or cancellation of the selling agreement of such dealer at least 90 days before the effective date of the termination or cancellation, stating the specific ground for such termination or cancellation. In no event shall the contractual term of any such selling agreement expire, without the written consent of the dealer involved, prior to the expiration of at least 90 days following such written notice. During the 90-day period, either party may, in appropriate circumstances, petition a court of competent jurisdiction to modify such 90-day stay or to extend it pending a final determination of such proceeding on the merits. The court shall have authority to grant temporary, preliminary, and final injunctive relief.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subparagraph, tests for determining what constitutes due cause for a manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler to terminate, cancel, or refuse to renew a dealer agreement include whether the dealer:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has transferred a majority ownership interest in the dealership without the manufacturer’s, distributor’s, or wholesaler’s consent;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has made a material misrepresentation in applying for or in acting under the agreement;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has filed a voluntary petition in bankruptcy or has had an involuntary petition in bankruptcy filed against the dealer which has not been discharged within 60 days after the filing, is in default under the provisions of a security agreement in effect with the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler, or is in receivership;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has engaged in unfair business or trade practices;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has inadequately represented the manufacturer’s, distributor’s, or wholesaler’s products with respect to sales, service, or warranty work;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has inadequate and insufficient sales and service facilities and personnel;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to comply with an applicable federal, state, or local licensing law;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been convicted of a crime, the effect of which would be detrimental to the manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, or dealership;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to operate in the normal course of business for 10 consecutive business days or has terminated the dealer’s business;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has relocated the dealer’s place of business without the manufacturer’s, distributor’s, or wholesaler’s consent; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has failed to comply with the terms of the agreement.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To resort to or use any false or misleading advertisement in connection with the dealer’s business as such manufacturer, factory branch or division, distributor, distributor branch or division, wholesaler, or wholesale branch or division, or officer, agent, or other representative thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To offer to sell or to sell any new outdoor power equipment or item of such equipment, or parts or accessories therefor, to any other dealer at a lower actual price therefor than the actual price offered to any other dealer for the same model outdoor power equipment identically equipped or to utilize any device, including, but not limited to, sales promotion plans or programs, which results in such lesser actual price or results in a fixed price predetermined solely by the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler. However, the provisions of this paragraph do not apply to sales to a dealer for resale to any unit or agency of the United States Government, the state or any of its political subdivisions, or any municipality located within this state. Further, the provisions of this paragraph do not apply so long as a manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler, or any agent thereof, sells or offers to sell such new outdoor power equipment, parts, or accessories to all dealers of such manufacturer’s, distributor’s, or wholesaler’s dealers at an equal price.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To willfully discriminate, either directly or indirectly, in price, programs, or terms of sale offered to dealers, when the effect of such discrimination may be to substantially lessen competition or to give to one holder of an agreement any economic, business, or competitive advantage not offered to all holders of the same or similar agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prevent or attempt to prevent, by contract or otherwise, any dealer from changing the capital structure of the dealership or the means by or through which the dealer finances the operation of the dealership, provided the dealer at all times meets any reasonable capital standards agreed to between the dealership and the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler and provided such change by the dealer does not result in a change in the executive management of the dealership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To prevent or attempt to prevent, by contract or otherwise, any dealer or any officer, member partner, or stockholder of any dealer from selling or transferring any part of the interest of any of them to any other person or persons or party or parties. However, no dealer, officer, partner, or stockholder has the right to sell, transfer, or assign the agreement or power of management or control thereunder without the written consent of the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler, except that such consent may not be unreasonably withheld.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To obtain money, goods, services, anything of value, or any other benefit from any other person with whom the dealer does business or employs on account of or in relation to the transactions between the dealer, the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler, and such other person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require a dealer to assent to a release, assignment, novation, waiver, or estoppel which would relieve any person from liability imposed by ss. 686.601-686.614.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is deemed a violation of this section for a dealer:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To require a retail purchaser of new outdoor power equipment or item of such equipment, as a condition of sale and delivery of the item or equipment, also to purchase special features, appliances, equipment, parts, or accessories not desired or requested by the purchaser. However, this prohibition does not apply to special features, appliances, equipment, parts, or accessories which are already installed when the outdoor power equipment or item of outdoor power equipment is received by the dealer from the manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler of such equipment or item of such equipment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To represent and sell as new and unused any outdoor power equipment or item of such equipment which has been used and operated for demonstration or other purposes without stating to the purchaser prior to the sale the approximate amount of use the outdoor power equipment or item of such equipment has experienced or undergone.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To resort to or use any false or misleading advertisement in connection with the dealer’s business as such dealer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 97-275; s. 53, ch. 99-7.</History></Section>