<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0686.503" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Contract provisions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a consignee accepts a work of art for the purpose of sale, or exhibition and sale, to the public on a commission, fee, or other basis of compensation, there shall be a written contract or agreement between the consignor and consignee which shall include, but not be limited to, the following provisions:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of the sale of the work of art shall be delivered to the consignor at a schedule agreed upon by the consignor and consignee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The consignee shall be responsible for the stated value of the work of art in the event of the loss of or damage to such work of art while it is in the possession of such consignee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The work of art shall only be sold by the consignee for an amount at least equal to the amount agreed upon by the consignor in writing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The work of art may be used or displayed by the consignee or others only with the prior written consent of the consignor and only if the artist is acknowledged in such use or display.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A work of art delivered to an art dealer by an artist for the purpose of exhibition or sale and the artist’s share of the proceeds of the sale of the work by the dealer, whether to the dealer on his or her own account or to a third person, shall create a priority in favor of the artist over the claims, liens, or security interests of the creditors of the art dealer, notwithstanding any provisions of the Uniform Commercial Code.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 86-118; s. 744, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>