<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0686.417" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Remedies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to temporary, preliminary, or final injunctive relief as provided in s. 686.413(3)(c)1., any person who is aggrieved or injured in his or her business or property by reason of anything forbidden in ss. 686.40-686.418 may bring an action therefor in the appropriate circuit court of this state and shall recover the actual damages sustained and the costs of such action, including a reasonable attorney’s fee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without regard and in addition to any other remedy or relief to which a person is entitled, anyone aggrieved by a violation of ss. 686.40-686.418 may bring an action to obtain a declaratory judgment that an act, action, or practice violates such sections and to enjoin a manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, or dealer who has violated, is violating, or is otherwise likely to violate such sections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When such action is one of common or general interest to many persons or when the parties are numerous and it is impracticable to bring them all before the court, one or more may bring a class action for the benefit of the whole, including an action for injunctive relief.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an action for money damages, if a judge or jury finds that the defendant acted maliciously, the judge or jury may award punitive damages as permitted by state law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Legal Affairs or the state attorney, if a violation of ss. 686.40-686.418 occurs in his or her judicial circuit, may bring an action for injunctive or other appropriate civil relief for any violation of ss. 686.40-686.418.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The remedies provided in this section are in addition to any other remedies provided by law or in equity.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 84-217; s. 742, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>