<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0695.20" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unperformed contracts of record.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever anyone shall have contracted to purchase real estate in the state, prior to January 1, 1930, by written agreement requiring all payments to be made within 10 years from the date of the contract, or has accepted an assignment of such an agreement, and the fact of the existence of such a contract of purchase, or assignment, appears of record from the instrument itself or by reference in some other recorded instrument, and shall not have obtained and placed of record a deed to the property or a decree of a court of competent jurisdiction recognizing her or his rights thereunto, and is not in actual possession of the property covered by the contract or by the assignment, as defined in <Reference Number="1" />s. 95.17, she or he, her or his surviving spouse, heirs, personal representatives, successors, and assigns, shall have no further interest in the property described in the contract, or the assignment, by virtue thereof, and the record of such contract, assignment or other record reference thereto, shall no longer constitute either actual or constructive notice to a purchaser, mortgagee, or other person acquiring an interest in the property, unless within 6 months after this law shall take effect, (approved April 26, 1941) she or he or some one claiming under her or him shall:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place on record a deed or other conveyance of the property from the holder of the record title; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place on record a written instrument executed by the holder of the record title evidencing an extension or modification of the original contract and showing that the original contract remains in force and effect; or</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Institute, or have pending, in a court of competent jurisdiction a suit for the enforcement of her or his rights under such contract.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 20235, 1941; s. 771, ch. 97-102.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transferred to s. 95.16(2) by the reviser incident to compiling the 1974 Supplement to the Florida Statutes 1973.</Text></Note></Section>