<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0695.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Requirements for recording instruments affecting real property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No instrument by which the title to real property or any interest therein is conveyed, assigned, encumbered, or otherwise disposed of shall be recorded by the clerk of the circuit court unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each person who executed such instrument is legibly printed, typewritten, or stamped upon such instrument immediately beneath the signature of such person and the post-office address of each such person is legibly printed, typewritten, or stamped upon such instrument;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and post-office address of the natural person who prepared the instrument or under whose supervision it was prepared are legibly printed, typewritten, or stamped upon such instrument;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of each witness to the instrument is legibly printed, typewritten, or stamped upon such instrument immediately beneath the signature of such witness;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of any notary public or other officer authorized to take acknowledgments or proofs whose signature appears upon the instrument is legibly printed, typewritten, or stamped upon such instrument immediately beneath the signature of such notary public or other officer authorized to take acknowledgment or proofs;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A 3-inch by 3-inch space at the top right-hand corner on the first page and a 1-inch by 3-inch space at the top right-hand corner on each subsequent page are reserved for use by the clerk of the court; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any instrument other than a mortgage conveying or purporting to convey any interest in real property, the name and post-office address of each grantee in such instrument are legibly printed, typewritten, or stamped upon such instrument.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a name or address is printed, typewritten, or stamped on an instrument in a position other than the position required by subsection (1), the clerk of the circuit court may, in her or his discretion, accept the instrument for recordation if she or he determines that the connection between the signature and the name or the name and the address is apparent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An instrument executed before July 1, 1991.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A decree, order, judgment, or writ of any court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An instrument executed, acknowledged, or proved outside of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A will.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plat.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An instrument prepared or executed by any public officer other than a notary public.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of the clerk of the circuit court to comply with this section does not impair the validity of the recordation or of the constructive notice imparted by recordation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-183; ss. 8, 22, ch. 94-348; s. 773, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>