<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0921.187" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disposition and sentencing; alternatives; restitution.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The alternatives provided in this section for the disposition of criminal cases shall be used in a manner that will best serve the needs of society, punish criminal offenders, and provide the opportunity for rehabilitation. If the offender does not receive a state prison sentence, the court may:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose a split sentence whereby the offender is to be placed on probation upon completion of any specified period of such sentence, which period may include a term of years or less.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any other disposition that is authorized by law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place the offender on probation with or without an adjudication of guilt pursuant to s. 948.01.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose a fine and probation pursuant to s. 948.011 when the offense is punishable by both a fine and imprisonment and probation is authorized.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Place the offender into community control requiring intensive supervision and surveillance pursuant to chapter 948.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose, as a condition of probation or community control, a period of treatment which shall be restricted to a county facility, a Department of Corrections probation and restitution center, a probation program drug punishment treatment community, or a community residential or nonresidential facility, excluding a community correctional center as defined in s. 944.026, which is owned and operated by any qualified public or private entity providing such services. Before admission to such a facility, the court shall obtain an individual assessment and recommendations on the appropriate treatment needs, which shall be considered by the court in ordering such placements. Placement in such a facility, except for a county residential probation facility, may not exceed 364 days. Placement in a county residential probation facility may not exceed 3 years. Early termination of placement may be recommended to the court, when appropriate, by the center supervisor, the supervising probation officer, or the probation program manager.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sentence the offender pursuant to s. 922.051 to imprisonment in a county jail when a statute directs imprisonment in a state prison, if the offender’s cumulative sentence, whether from the same circuit or from separate circuits, is not more than 364 days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sentence the offender who is to be punished by imprisonment in a county jail to a jail in another county if there is no jail within the county suitable for such prisoner pursuant to s. 950.01.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the offender to participate in a work-release or educational or technical training program pursuant to s. 951.24 while serving a sentence in a county jail, if such a program is available.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the offender to perform a specified public service pursuant to s. 775.091.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the offender who violates chapter 893 or violates any law while under the influence of a controlled substance or alcohol to participate in a substance abuse program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the offender who violates any criminal provision of chapter 893 to pay an additional assessment in an amount up to the amount of any fine imposed, pursuant to ss. 938.21 and 938.23.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require the offender who violates any provision of s. 893.13 to pay an additional assessment in an amount of $100, pursuant to ss. 938.055 and 943.361.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose a split sentence whereby the offender is to be placed in a county jail or county work camp upon the completion of any specified term of community supervision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose split probation whereby upon satisfactory completion of half the term of probation, the Department of Corrections may place the offender on administrative probation pursuant to s. 948.013 for the remainder of the term of supervision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require residence in a state probation and restitution center or private drug treatment program for offenders on community control or offenders who have violated conditions of probation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose any other sanction which is provided within the community and approved as an intermediate sanction by the county public safety coordinating council as described in s. 951.26.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Impose, as a condition of community control, probation, or probation following incarceration, a requirement that an offender who has not obtained a high school diploma or high school equivalency diploma or who lacks basic or functional literacy skills, upon acceptance by an adult education program, make a good faith effort toward completion of such basic or functional literacy skills or high school equivalency diploma, as defined in s. 1003.435, in accordance with the assessed adult general education needs of the individual offender.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall require an offender to make restitution under s. 775.089 unless the court finds clear and compelling reasons not to order such restitution. If the court does not order restitution, or orders restitution of only a portion of the damages, as provided in s. 775.089, the court shall state the reasons on the record in detail. An order requiring an offender to make restitution to a victim under s. 775.089 does not remove or diminish the requirement that the court order payment to the Crimes Compensation Trust Fund under chapter 960.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 83-131; s. 6, ch. 84-363; s. 6, ch. 88-96; s. 77, ch. 88-122; s. 5, ch. 88-381; s. 44, ch. 89-526; s. 4, ch. 90-111; s. 8, ch. 90-287; s. 8, ch. 91-225; s. 2, ch. 91-280; s. 3, ch. 92-107; ss. 22, 36, ch. 92-310; s. 6, ch. 93-37; s. 2, ch. 93-59; s. 9, ch. 93-227; s. 5, ch. 94-107; s. 22, ch. 94-342; s. 25, ch. 95-184; s. 27, ch. 96-322; s. 58, ch. 96-388; s. 25, ch. 97-194; s. 38, ch. 97-271; s. 4, ch. 2002-81; s. 1041, ch. 2002-387; s. 2, ch. 2003-142; s. 36, ch. 2004-373; s. 20, ch. 2005-128; s. 1, ch. 2008-250; s. 5, ch. 2010-64; s. 7, ch. 2010-113; s. 2, ch. 2012-125.</History>
</Section>