<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0921.0021" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, for any felony offense, except any capital felony, committed on or after October 1, 1998, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Additional offense” means any offense other than the primary offense for which an offender is convicted and which is pending before the court for sentencing at the time of the primary offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Conviction” means a determination of guilt that is the result of a plea or a trial, regardless of whether adjudication is withheld.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Legal status” means an offender’s status if the offender:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Escapes from incarceration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Flees to avoid prosecution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fails to appear for a criminal proceeding;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violates any condition of a supersedeas bond;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is incarcerated;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is under any form of a pretrial intervention or diversion program; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is under any form of court-imposed or postprison release community supervision.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Primary offense” means the offense at conviction pending before the court for sentencing for which the total sentence points recommend a sanction that is as severe as, or more severe than, the sanction recommended for any other offense committed by the offender and pending before the court at sentencing. Only one count of one offense before the court for sentencing shall be classified as the primary offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prior record” means a conviction for a crime committed by the offender, as an adult or a juvenile, prior to the time of the primary offense. Convictions by federal, out-of-state, military, or foreign courts, and convictions for violations of county or municipal ordinances that incorporate by reference a penalty under state law, are included in the offender’s prior record. Convictions for offenses committed by the offender more than 10 years before the primary offense are not included in the offender’s prior record if the offender has not been convicted of any other crime for a period of 10 consecutive years from the most recent date of release from confinement, supervision, or sanction, whichever is later, to the date of the primary offense. Juvenile dispositions of offenses committed by the offender within 5 years before the primary offense are included in the offender’s prior record when the offense would have been a crime had the offender been an adult rather than a juvenile. Juvenile dispositions of sexual offenses committed by the offender which were committed 5 years or more before the primary offense are included in the offender’s prior record if the offender has not maintained a conviction-free record, either as an adult or a juvenile, for a period of 5 consecutive years from the most recent date of release from confinement, supervision, or sanction, whichever is later, to the date of the primary offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community sanction” includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Probation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community control.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pretrial intervention or diversion.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Victim injury” means the physical injury or death suffered by a person as a direct result of the primary offense, or any additional offense, for which an offender is convicted and which is pending before the court for sentencing at the time of the primary offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (c) or paragraph (d),</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the conviction is for an offense involving sexual contact that includes sexual penetration, the sexual penetration must be scored in accordance with the sentence points provided under s. 921.0024 for sexual penetration, regardless of whether there is evidence of any physical injury.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the conviction is for an offense involving sexual contact that does not include sexual penetration, the sexual contact must be scored in accordance with the sentence points provided under s. 921.0024 for sexual contact, regardless of whether there is evidence of any physical injury.</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the victim of an offense involving sexual contact suffers any physical injury as a direct result of the primary offense or any additional offense committed by the offender resulting in conviction, such physical injury must be scored separately and in addition to the points scored for the sexual contact or the sexual penetration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sentence points provided under s. 921.0024 for sexual contact or sexual penetration may not be assessed for a violation of s. 944.35(3)(b)2.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the conviction is for the offense described in s. 872.06, the sentence points provided under s. 921.0024 for sexual contact or sexual penetration may not be assessed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding paragraph (a), if the conviction is for an offense described in s. 316.027 and the court finds that the offender caused victim injury, sentence points for victim injury may be assessed against the offender.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 97-194; s. 3, ch. 98-204; s. 2, ch. 2001-210; s. 4, ch. 2007-211.</History></Section>