<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0921.0026" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mitigating circumstances.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to any felony offense, except any capital felony, committed on or after October 1, 1998.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A downward departure from the lowest permissible sentence, as calculated according to the total sentence points pursuant to s. 921.0024, is prohibited unless there are circumstances or factors that reasonably justify the downward departure. Mitigating factors to be considered include, but are not limited to, those listed in subsection (2). The imposition of a sentence below the lowest permissible sentence is subject to appellate review under chapter 924, but the extent of downward departure is not subject to appellate review.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mitigating circumstances under which a departure from the lowest permissible sentence is reasonably justified include, but are not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The departure results from a legitimate, uncoerced plea bargain.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant was an accomplice to the offense and was a relatively minor participant in the criminal conduct.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The capacity of the defendant to appreciate the criminal nature of the conduct or to conform that conduct to the requirements of law was substantially impaired.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant requires specialized treatment for a mental disorder that is unrelated to substance abuse or addiction or for a physical disability, and the defendant is amenable to treatment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The need for payment of restitution to the victim outweighs the need for a prison sentence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The victim was an initiator, willing participant, aggressor, or provoker of the incident.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant acted under extreme duress or under the domination of another person.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the identity of the defendant was determined, the victim was substantially compensated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant cooperated with the state to resolve the current offense or any other offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offense was committed in an unsophisticated manner and was an isolated incident for which the defendant has shown remorse.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of the offense the defendant was too young to appreciate the consequences of the offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant is to be sentenced as a youthful offender.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant’s offense is a nonviolent felony, the defendant’s Criminal Punishment Code scoresheet total sentence points under s. 921.0024 are 60 points or fewer, and the court determines that the defendant is amenable to the services of a postadjudicatory treatment-based drug court program and is otherwise qualified to participate in the program as part of the sentence. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “nonviolent felony” has the same meaning as provided in s. 948.08(6).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The defendant was making a good faith effort to obtain or provide medical assistance for an individual experiencing a drug-related overdose.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (2)(m), the defendant’s substance abuse or addiction, including intoxication at the time of the offense, is not a mitigating factor under subsection (2) and does not, under any circumstances, justify a downward departure from the permissible sentencing range.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 97-194; s. 8, ch. 98-204; s. 2, ch. 2009-64; s. 2, ch. 2011-33; s. 3, ch. 2012-36.</History>
</Section>