<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.811" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of inspection; copies; inspection reports; plan for correction of deficiencies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authorized officer or employee of the agency may make or cause to be made any inspection or investigation deemed necessary by the agency to determine the state of compliance with this part, authorizing statutes, and applicable rules. The right of inspection extends to any business that the agency has reason to believe is being operated as a provider without a license, but inspection of any business suspected of being operated without the appropriate license may not be made without the permission of the owner or person in charge unless a warrant is first obtained from a circuit court. Any application for a license issued under this part, authorizing statutes, or applicable rules constitutes permission for an appropriate inspection to verify the information submitted on or in connection with the application.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All inspections shall be unannounced, except as specified in s. 408.806.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspections for relicensure shall be conducted biennially unless otherwise specified by authorizing statutes or applicable rules.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inspections conducted in conjunction with certification, comparable licensure requirements, or a recognized or approved accreditation organization may be accepted in lieu of a complete licensure inspection. However, a licensure inspection may also be conducted to review any licensure requirements that are not also requirements for certification.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall have access to and the licensee shall provide, or if requested send, copies of all provider records required during an inspection or other review at no cost to the agency, including records requested during an offsite review.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A deficiency must be corrected within 30 calendar days after the provider is notified of inspection results unless an alternative timeframe is required or approved by the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may require an applicant or licensee to submit a plan of correction for deficiencies. If required, the plan of correction must be filed with the agency within 10 calendar days after notification unless an alternative timeframe is required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee shall maintain as public information, available upon request, records of all inspection reports pertaining to that provider that have been filed by the agency unless those reports are exempt from or contain information that is exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution or is otherwise made confidential by law. Effective October 1, 2006, copies of such reports shall be retained in the records of the provider for at least 3 years following the date the reports are filed and issued, regardless of a change of ownership.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee shall, upon the request of any person who has completed a written application with intent to be admitted by such provider, any person who is a client of such provider, or any relative, spouse, or guardian of any such person, furnish to the requester a copy of the last inspection report pertaining to the licensed provider that was issued by the agency or by an accrediting organization if such report is used in lieu of a licensure inspection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192; s. 51, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>