<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.302" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Interagency agreement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall enter into an interagency agreement with the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, the Department of Health, and the Department of Elderly Affairs to assure coordination and cooperation in serving special needs citizens. The agreement shall include the requirement that the secretaries or directors of the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, the Department of Health, and the Department of Elderly Affairs approve, prior to adoption, any rule developed by the Agency for Health Care Administration where such rule has a direct impact on the mission of the respective state agencies, their programs, or their budgets.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For rules which indirectly impact on the mission of the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, the Department of Health, and the Department of Elderly Affairs, their programs, or their budgets, the concurrence of the respective secretaries or directors on the rule is required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For all other rules developed by the Agency for Health Care Administration, coordination with the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, the Department of Health, and the Department of Elderly Affairs is encouraged.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The interagency agreement shall also include any other provisions necessary to ensure a continued cooperative working relationship between the Agency for Health Care Administration and the Department of Children and Family Services, the Agency for Persons with Disabilities, the Department of Health, and the Department of Elderly Affairs as each strives to meet the needs of the citizens of Florida.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 93-129; s. 180, ch. 99-8; s. 84, ch. 2004-267.</History></Section>