<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.803" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration, which is the licensing agency under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicant” means an individual, corporation, partnership, firm, association, or governmental entity that submits an application for a license to the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Authorizing statute” means the statute authorizing the licensed operation of a provider listed in s. 408.802 and includes chapters 112, 383, 390, 394, 395, 400, 429, 440, 483, and 765.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certification” means certification as a Medicare or Medicaid provider of the services that require licensure, or certification pursuant to the federal Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendment (CLIA).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Change of ownership” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An event in which the licensee sells or otherwise transfers its ownership to a different individual or entity as evidenced by a change in federal employer identification number or taxpayer identification number; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An event in which 51 percent or more of the ownership, shares, membership, or controlling interest of a licensee is in any manner transferred or otherwise assigned. This paragraph does not apply to a licensee that is publicly traded on a recognized stock exchange.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A change solely in the management company or board of directors is not a change of ownership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Client” means any person receiving services from a provider listed in s. 408.802.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Controlling interest” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant or licensee;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or entity that serves as an officer of, is on the board of directors of, or has a 5-percent or greater ownership interest in the applicant or licensee; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or entity that serves as an officer of, is on the board of directors of, or has a 5-percent or greater ownership interest in the management company or other entity, related or unrelated, with which the applicant or licensee contracts to manage the provider.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The term does not include a voluntary board member.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means any permit, registration, certificate, or license issued by the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means an individual, corporation, partnership, firm, association, governmental entity, or other entity that is issued a permit, registration, certificate, or license by the agency. The licensee is legally responsible for all aspects of the provider operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Moratorium” means a prohibition on the acceptance of new clients.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Provider” means any activity, service, agency, or facility regulated by the agency and listed in s. 408.802.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Services that require licensure” means those services, including residential services, that require a valid license before those services may be provided in accordance with authorizing statutes and agency rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Voluntary board member” means a board member or officer of a not-for-profit corporation or organization who serves solely in a voluntary capacity, does not receive any remuneration for his or her services on the board of directors, and has no financial interest in the corporation or organization.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192; s. 90, ch. 2007-5; s. 47, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>