<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.032" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions relating to Health Facility and Services Development Act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 408.031-408.045, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Capital expenditure” means an expenditure, including an expenditure for a construction project undertaken by a health care facility as its own contractor, which, under generally accepted accounting principles, is not properly chargeable as an expense of operation and maintenance, which is made to change the bed capacity of the facility, or substantially change the services or service area of the health care facility, health service provider, or hospice, and which includes the cost of the studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings, specifications, initial financing costs, and other activities essential to acquisition, improvement, expansion, or replacement of the plant and equipment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Certificate of need” means a written statement issued by the agency evidencing community need for a new, converted, expanded, or otherwise significantly modified health care facility, health service, or hospice.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commenced construction” means initiation of and continuous activities beyond site preparation associated with erecting or modifying a health care facility, including procurement of a building permit applying the use of agency-approved construction documents, proof of an executed owner/contractor agreement or an irrevocable or binding forced account, and actual undertaking of foundation forming with steel installation and concrete placing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“District” means a health service planning district composed of the following counties:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 1.—Escambia, Santa Rosa, Okaloosa, and Walton Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 2.—Holmes, Washington, Bay, Jackson, Franklin, Gulf, Gadsden, Liberty, Calhoun, Leon, Wakulla, Jefferson, Madison, and Taylor Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 3.—Hamilton, Suwannee, Lafayette, Dixie, Columbia, Gilchrist, Levy, Union, Bradford, Putnam, Alachua, Marion, Citrus, Hernando, Sumter, and Lake Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 4.—Baker, Nassau, Duval, Clay, St. Johns, Flagler, and Volusia Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 5.—Pasco and Pinellas Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 6.—Hillsborough, Manatee, Polk, Hardee, and Highlands Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 7.—Seminole, Orange, Osceola, and Brevard Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 8.—Sarasota, DeSoto, Charlotte, Lee, Glades, Hendry, and Collier Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 9.—Indian River, Okeechobee, St. Lucie, Martin, and Palm Beach Counties.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 10.—Broward County.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">District 11.—Miami-Dade and Monroe Counties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exemption” means the process by which a proposal that would otherwise require a certificate of need may proceed without a certificate of need.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Expedited review” means the process by which certain types of applications are not subject to the review cycle requirements contained in s. 408.039(1), and the letter of intent requirements contained in s. 408.039(2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care facility” means a hospital, long-term care hospital, skilled nursing facility, hospice, or intermediate care facility for the developmentally disabled. A facility relying solely on spiritual means through prayer for healing is not included as a health care facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health services” means inpatient diagnostic, curative, or comprehensive medical rehabilitative services and includes mental health services. Obstetric services are not health services for purposes of ss. 408.031-408.045.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hospice” or “hospice program” means a hospice as defined in part IV of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hospital” means a health care facility licensed under chapter 395.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Intermediate care facility for the developmentally disabled” means a residential facility licensed under chapter 393 and certified by the Federal Government pursuant to the Social Security Act as a provider of Medicaid services to persons who are mentally retarded or who have a related condition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Long-term care hospital” means a hospital licensed under chapter 395 which meets the requirements of 42 C.F.R. s. 412.23(e) and seeks exclusion from the acute care Medicare prospective payment system for inpatient hospital services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mental health services” means inpatient services provided in a hospital licensed under chapter 395 and listed on the hospital license as psychiatric beds for adults; psychiatric beds for children and adolescents; intensive residential treatment beds for children and adolescents; substance abuse beds for adults; or substance abuse beds for children and adolescents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nursing home geographically underserved area” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county in which there is no existing or approved nursing home;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area with a radius of at least 20 miles in which there is no existing or approved nursing home; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An area with a radius of at least 20 miles in which all existing nursing homes have maintained at least a 95 percent occupancy rate for the most recent 6 months or a 90 percent occupancy rate for the most recent 12 months.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Skilled nursing facility” means an institution, or a distinct part of an institution, which is primarily engaged in providing, to inpatients, skilled nursing care and related services for patients who require medical or nursing care, or rehabilitation services for the rehabilitation of injured, disabled, or sick persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tertiary health service” means a health service which, due to its high level of intensity, complexity, specialized or limited applicability, and cost, should be limited to, and concentrated in, a limited number of hospitals to ensure the quality, availability, and cost-effectiveness of such service. Examples of such service include, but are not limited to, pediatric cardiac catheterization, pediatric open-heart surgery, organ transplantation, neonatal intensive care units, comprehensive rehabilitation, and medical or surgical services which are experimental or developmental in nature to the extent that the provision of such services is not yet contemplated within the commonly accepted course of diagnosis or treatment for the condition addressed by a given service. The agency shall establish by rule a list of all tertiary health services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 87-92; s. 19, ch. 88-294; s. 2, ch. 89-308; s. 7, ch. 89-354; s. 21, ch. 91-158; s. 54, ch. 91-221; s. 1, ch. 91-282; ss. 15, 16, ch. 92-33; s. 10, ch. 92-58; s. 22, ch. 93-214; s. 8, ch. 95-144; s. 28, ch. 95-210; s. 2, ch. 95-394; s. 1, ch. 97-270; s. 3, ch. 2000-256; s. 4, ch. 2000-318; s. 2, ch. 2004-383; s. 74, ch. 2006-197; s. 111, ch. 2008-4.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.702.</Text></Note></Section>