<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.0361" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cardiovascular services and burn unit licensure.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each provider of diagnostic cardiac catheterization services shall comply with rules adopted by the agency that establish licensure standards governing the operation of adult inpatient diagnostic cardiac catheterization programs. The rules shall ensure that such programs:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with the most recent guidelines of the American College of Cardiology and American Heart Association Guidelines for Cardiac Catheterization and Cardiac Catheterization Laboratories.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform only adult inpatient diagnostic cardiac catheterization services and will not provide therapeutic cardiac catheterization or any other cardiology services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain sufficient appropriate equipment and health care personnel to ensure quality and safety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain appropriate times of operation and protocols to ensure availability and appropriate referrals in the event of emergencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate a plan to provide services to Medicaid and charity care patients.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each provider of adult cardiovascular services or operator of a burn unit shall comply with rules adopted by the agency that establish licensure standards that govern the provision of adult cardiovascular services or the operation of a burn unit. Such rules shall consider, at a minimum, staffing, equipment, physical plant, operating protocols, the provision of services to Medicaid and charity care patients, accreditation, licensure period and fees, and enforcement of minimum standards. The certificate-of-need rules for adult cardiovascular services and burn units in effect on June 30, 2004, are authorized pursuant to this subsection and shall remain in effect and shall be enforceable by the agency until the licensure rules are adopted. Existing providers and any provider with a notice of intent to grant a certificate of need or a final order of the agency granting a certificate of need for adult cardiovascular services or burn units shall be considered grandfathered and receive a license for their programs effective on the effective date of this act. The grandfathered licensure shall be for at least 3 years or until July 1, 2008, whichever is longer, but shall be required to meet licensure standards applicable to existing programs for every subsequent licensure period.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In establishing rules for adult cardiovascular services, the agency shall include provisions that allow for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of two hospital program licensure levels: a Level I program authorizing the performance of adult percutaneous cardiac intervention without onsite cardiac surgery and a Level II program authorizing the performance of percutaneous cardiac intervention with onsite cardiac surgery.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a hospital seeking a Level I program, demonstration that, for the most recent 12-month period as reported to the agency, it has provided a minimum of 300 adult inpatient and outpatient diagnostic cardiac catheterizations or, for the most recent 12-month period, has discharged or transferred at least 300 inpatients with the principal diagnosis of ischemic heart disease and that it has a formalized, written transfer agreement with a hospital that has a Level II program, including written transport protocols to ensure safe and efficient transfer of a patient within 60 minutes. However, a hospital located more than 100 road miles from the closest Level II adult cardiovascular services program does not need to meet the 60-minute transfer time protocol if the hospital demonstrates that it has a formalized, written transfer agreement with a hospital that has a Level II program. The agreement must include written transport protocols to ensure the safe and efficient transfer of a patient, taking into consideration the patient’s clinical and physical characteristics, road and weather conditions, and viability of ground and air ambulance service to transfer the patient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a hospital seeking a Level II program, demonstration that, for the most recent 12-month period as reported to the agency, it has performed a minimum of 1,100 adult inpatient and outpatient cardiac catheterizations, of which at least 400 must be therapeutic catheterizations, or, for the most recent 12-month period, has discharged at least 800 patients with the principal diagnosis of ischemic heart disease.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with the most recent guidelines of the American College of Cardiology and American Heart Association guidelines for staffing, physician training and experience, operating procedures, equipment, physical plant, and patient selection criteria to ensure patient quality and safety.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of appropriate hours of operation and protocols to ensure availability and timely referral in the event of emergencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstration of a plan to provide services to Medicaid and charity care patients.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to ensure continuity of available services, the holder of a certificate of need for a newly licensed hospital that meets the requirements of this subsection may apply for and shall be granted Level I program status regardless of whether rules relating to Level I programs have been adopted. To qualify for a Level I program under this subsection, a hospital seeking a Level I program must be a newly licensed hospital established pursuant to a certificate of need in a physical location previously licensed and operated as a hospital, the former hospital must have provided a minimum of 300 adult inpatient and outpatient diagnostic cardiac catheterizations for the most recent 12-month period as reported to the agency, and the newly licensed hospital must have a formalized, written transfer agreement with a hospital that has a Level II program, including written transport protocols to ensure safe and efficient transfer of a patient within 60 minutes. A hospital meeting the requirements of this subsection may apply for certification of Level I program status before taking possession of the physical location of the former hospital, and the effective date of Level I program status shall be concurrent with the effective date of the newly issued hospital license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall establish a technical advisory panel to develop procedures and standards for measuring outcomes of adult cardiovascular services. Members of the panel shall include representatives of the Florida Hospital Association, the Florida Society of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgeons, the Florida Chapter of the American College of Cardiology, and the Florida Chapter of the American Heart Association and others with experience in statistics and outcome measurement. Based on recommendations from the panel, the agency shall develop and adopt rules for the adult cardiovascular services that include at least the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A risk adjustment procedure that accounts for the variations in severity and case mix found in hospitals in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Outcome standards specifying expected levels of performance in Level I and Level II adult cardiovascular services. Such standards may include, but shall not be limited to, in-hospital mortality, infection rates, nonfatal myocardial infarctions, length of stay, postoperative bleeds, and returns to surgery.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specific steps to be taken by the agency and licensed hospitals that do not meet the outcome standards within specified time periods, including time periods for detailed case reviews and development and implementation of corrective action plans.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospitals licensed for Level I or Level II adult cardiovascular services shall participate in clinical outcome reporting systems operated by the American College of Cardiology and the Society for Thoracic Surgeons.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 99-356; s. 48, ch. 2001-62; s. 2, ch. 2004-382; s. 7, ch. 2004-383; s. 1, ch. 2007-214; s. 2, ch. 2007-248; s. 88, ch. 2010-5; s. 21, ch. 2012-160.</History></Section>