<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.40" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public Counsel.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the Public Counsel shall represent the public in any proceeding before the agency or its advisory panels in any administrative hearing conducted pursuant to chapter 120 or before any other state and federal agencies and courts in any issue before the agency, any court, or any agency. With respect to any such proceeding, the Public Counsel is subject to the provisions of and may use the powers granted to him or her by ss. 350.061-350.0614.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Public Counsel shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the agency, by petition, the commencement of any proceeding or action or to appear, in the name of the state or its citizens, in any proceeding or action before the agency and urge therein any position that he or she deems to be in the public interest, whether consistent or inconsistent with positions previously adopted by the agency, and use therein all forms of discovery available to attorneys in civil actions generally, subject to protective orders of the agency, which shall be reviewable by summary procedure in the circuit courts of this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have access to and use of all files, records, and data of the agency available to any other attorney representing parties in a proceeding before the agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any proceeding in which he or she has participated as a party, seek review of any determination, finding, or order of the agency, or of any administrative law judge, or any hearing officer or hearing examiner designated by the agency, in the name of the state or its citizens.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare and issue reports, recommendations, and proposed orders to the agency, the Governor, and the Legislature on any matter or subject within the jurisdiction of the agency, and to make such recommendations as he or she deems appropriate for legislation relative to agency procedures, rules, jurisdiction, personnel, and functions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appear before other state agencies, federal agencies, and state and federal courts in connection with matters under the jurisdiction of the agency, in the name of the state or its citizens.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 80, ch. 92-33; s. 192, ch. 96-410; s. 1017, ch. 97-103; s. 16, ch. 98-89.</History></Section>