<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers of the agency.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the powers granted to the agency elsewhere in this chapter, the agency is authorized to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into contracts and execute all instruments necessary or convenient for carrying out its business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire, own, hold, dispose of, and encumber personal property and to lease real property in exercising its powers and performing its duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements with any federal, state, or municipal agency, or other public institution, or with any private individual, partnership, firm, corporation, association, or other entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish ad hoc advisory committees to expand public participation in agency decisions and draw on the experience of representatives from all areas of health insurance, financing, cost containment, and operations, including, but not limited to, providers, consumers, third-party payors, businesses, and academicians.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish such staff as needed to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Apply for and receive and accept grants, gifts, and other payments, including property and services, from any governmental or other public and private entity or person and make arrangements as to the use of same. Funds obtained under this subsection may be used as matching funds for public or private grants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Seek federal statutory changes and any waivers of federal laws or regulations that will aid in implementing health care reforms. This may include seeking amendments to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Employee Retirement and Income Security Act of 1974 to permit greater state regulation of employer insurance plans.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Medicaid program to permit alternative organizational alignments, elimination of all program eligibility requirements except income, and a moratorium on further federal mandates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Medicare program to seek state administration of benefits, provider payments, or case management of beneficiaries.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal tax laws to permit a 100-percent tax deduction for all private health insurance plans, including those of self-employed persons and unincorporated employers, and reform of the flexible sharing account requirements to maximize pretax health care expenditures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other federal programs to permit full implementation of state health care reforms.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold public hearings, conduct investigations, and subpoena witnesses, papers, records, and documents in connection therewith. The agency may administer oaths or affirmations in any hearing or investigation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exercise all other powers which are reasonably necessary or essential to carry out the expressed intent, objects, and purposes of this chapter, unless specifically prohibited in this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grant extensions of time for compliance with any filing requirement of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish, in coordination with the Department of Health, uniform standards of care to be provided in special needs units or shelters during times of emergency or major disaster.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 77, ch. 92-33; s. 111, ch. 98-200; s. 19, ch. 2000-140; s. 12, ch. 2000-209.</History></Section>