<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.035" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Review criteria.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall determine the reviewability of applications and shall review applications for certificate-of-need determinations for health care facilities and health services in context with the following criteria, except for general hospitals as defined in s. 395.002:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The need for the health care facilities and health services being proposed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The availability, quality of care, accessibility, and extent of utilization of existing health care facilities and health services in the service district of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ability of the applicant to provide quality of care and the applicant’s record of providing quality of care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The availability of resources, including health personnel, management personnel, and funds for capital and operating expenditures, for project accomplishment and operation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the proposed services will enhance access to health care for residents of the service district.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The immediate and long-term financial feasibility of the proposal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which the proposal will foster competition that promotes quality and cost-effectiveness.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The costs and methods of the proposed construction, including the costs and methods of energy provision and the availability of alternative, less costly, or more effective methods of construction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s past and proposed provision of health care services to Medicaid patients and the medically indigent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant’s designation as a Gold Seal Program nursing facility pursuant to s. 400.235, when the applicant is requesting additional nursing home beds at that facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a general hospital, the agency shall consider only the criteria specified in paragraph (1)(a), paragraph (1)(b), except for quality of care in paragraph (1)(b), and paragraphs (1)(e), (g), and (i).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 87-92; s. 20, ch. 88-294; s. 15, ch. 92-33; ss. 37, 50, ch. 93-217; s. 30, ch. 95-210; s. 36, ch. 97-103; s. 39, ch. 97-264; s. 2, ch. 97-270; s. 20, ch. 99-394; s. 6, ch. 2000-256; s. 7, ch. 2000-318; s. 5, ch. 2004-383; s. 1, ch. 2008-29.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.705.</Text></Note></Section>