<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0408.910" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Health Choices Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />The Legislature finds that a significant number of the residents of this state do not have adequate access to affordable, quality health care. The Legislature further finds that increasing access to affordable, quality health care can be best accomplished by establishing a competitive market for purchasing health insurance and health services. It is therefore the intent of the Legislature to create the Florida Health Choices Program to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expand opportunities for Floridians to purchase affordable health insurance and health services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preserve the benefits of employment-sponsored insurance while easing the administrative burden for employers who offer these benefits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enable individual choice in both the manner and amount of health care purchased.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the purchase of individual, portable health care coverage.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disseminate information to consumers on the price and quality of health services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sponsor a competitive market that stimulates product innovation, quality improvement, and efficiency in the production and delivery of health services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporation” means the Florida Health Choices, Inc., established under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporation’s marketplace” means the single, centralized market established by the program that facilitates the purchase of products made available in the marketplace.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health insurance agent” means an agent licensed under part IV of chapter 626.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Insurer” means an entity licensed under chapter 624 which offers an individual health insurance policy or a group health insurance policy, a preferred provider organization as defined in s. 627.6471, an exclusive provider organization as defined in s. 627.6472, or a health maintenance organization licensed under part I of chapter 641, or a prepaid limited health service organization or discount medical plan organization licensed under chapter 636.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Program” means the Florida Health Choices Program established by this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM PURPOSE AND COMPONENTS.<EmDash />The Florida Health Choices Program is created as a single, centralized market for the sale and purchase of various products that enable individuals to pay for health care. These products include, but are not limited to, health insurance plans, health maintenance organization plans, prepaid services, service contracts, and flexible spending accounts. The components of the program include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollment of employers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrative services for participating employers, including:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assistance in seeking federal approval of cafeteria plans.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collection of premiums and other payments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management of individual benefit accounts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribution of premiums to insurers and payments to other eligible vendors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assistance for participants in complying with reporting requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services to individual participants, including:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information about available products and participating vendors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assistance with assessing the benefits and limits of each product, including information necessary to distinguish between policies offering creditable coverage and other products available through the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Account information to assist individual participants with managing available resources.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services that promote healthy behaviors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recruitment of vendors, including insurers, health maintenance organizations, prepaid clinic service providers, provider service networks, and other providers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification of vendors to ensure capability, reliability, and validity of offerings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collection of data, monitoring, assessment, and reporting of vendor performance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information services for individuals and employers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Program evaluation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBILITY AND PARTICIPATION.<EmDash />Participation in the program is voluntary and shall be available to employers, individuals, vendors, and health insurance agents as specified in this subsection.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employers eligible to enroll in the program include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employers that meet criteria established by the corporation and elect to make their employees eligible through the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fiscally constrained counties described in s. 218.67.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Municipalities having populations of fewer than 50,000 residents.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">School districts in fiscally constrained counties.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Statutory rural hospitals.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individuals eligible to participate in the program include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Individual employees of enrolled employers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State employees not eligible for state employee health benefits.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State retirees.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicaid participants who opt out.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employers who choose to participate in the program may enroll by complying with the procedures established by the corporation. The procedures must include, but are not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission of required information.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with federal tax requirements for the establishment of a cafeteria plan, pursuant to s. 125 of the Internal Revenue Code, including designation of the employer’s plan as a premium payment plan, a salary reduction plan that has flexible spending arrangements, or a salary reduction plan that has a premium payment and flexible spending arrangements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determination of the employer’s contribution, if any, per employee, provided that such contribution is equal for each eligible employee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of payroll deduction procedures, subject to the agreement of each individual employee who voluntarily participates in the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designation of the corporation as the third-party administrator for the employer’s health benefit plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Identification of eligible employees.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrangement for periodic payments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employer notification to employees of the intent to transfer from an existing employee health plan to the program at least 90 days before the transition.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All eligible vendors who choose to participate and the products and services that the vendors are permitted to sell are as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurers licensed under chapter 624 may sell health insurance policies, limited benefit policies, other risk-bearing coverage, and other products or services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health maintenance organizations licensed under part I of chapter 641 may sell health maintenance contracts, limited benefit policies, other risk-bearing products, and other products or services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepaid limited health service organizations may sell products and services as authorized under part I of chapter 636, and discount medical plan organizations may sell products and services as authorized under part II of chapter 636.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepaid health clinic service providers licensed under part II of chapter 641 may sell prepaid service contracts and other arrangements for a specified amount and type of health services or treatments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care providers, including hospitals and other licensed health facilities, health care clinics, licensed health professionals, pharmacies, and other licensed health care providers, may sell service contracts and arrangements for a specified amount and type of health services or treatments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provider organizations, including service networks, group practices, professional associations, and other incorporated organizations of providers, may sell service contracts and arrangements for a specified amount and type of health services or treatments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Corporate entities providing specific health services in accordance with applicable state law may sell service contracts and arrangements for a specified amount and type of health services or treatments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A vendor described in subparagraphs 3.-7. may not sell products that provide risk-bearing coverage unless that vendor is authorized under a certificate of authority issued by the Office of Insurance Regulation and is authorized to provide coverage in the relevant geographic area. Otherwise eligible vendors may be excluded from participating in the program for deceptive or predatory practices, financial insolvency, or failure to comply with the terms of the participation agreement or other standards set by the corporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eligible individuals may voluntarily continue participation in the program regardless of subsequent changes in job status or Medicaid eligibility. Individuals who join the program may participate by complying with the procedures established by the corporation. These procedures must include, but are not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission of required information.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorization for payroll deduction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with federal tax requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrangements for payment in the event of job changes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Selection of products and services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vendors who choose to participate in the program may enroll by complying with the procedures established by the corporation. These procedures may include, but are not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submission of required information, including a complete description of the coverage, services, provider network, payment restrictions, and other requirements of each product offered through the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execution of an agreement to comply with requirements established by the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execution of an agreement that prohibits refusal to sell any offered non-risk-bearing product to a participant who elects to buy it.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishment of product prices based on age, gender, and location of the individual participant, which may include medical underwriting.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrangements for receiving payment for enrolled participants.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in ongoing reporting processes established by the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Compliance with grievance procedures established by the corporation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health insurance agents licensed under part IV of chapter 626 are eligible to voluntarily participate as buyers’ representatives. A buyer’s representative acts on behalf of an individual purchasing health insurance and health services through the program by providing information about products and services available through the program and assisting the individual with both the decision and the procedure of selecting specific products. Serving as a buyer’s representative does not constitute a conflict of interest with continuing responsibilities as a health insurance agent if the relationship between each agent and any participating vendor is disclosed before advising an individual participant about the products and services available through the program. In order to participate, a health insurance agent shall comply with the procedures established by the corporation, including:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Completion of training requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execution of a participation agreement specifying the terms and conditions of participation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disclosure of any appointments to solicit insurance or procure applications for vendors participating in the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrangements to receive payment from the corporation for services as a buyer’s representative.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRODUCTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The products that may be made available for purchase through the program include, but are not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health insurance policies.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health maintenance contracts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Limited benefit plans.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepaid clinic services.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service contracts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrangements for purchase of specific amounts and types of health services and treatments.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Flexible spending accounts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health insurance policies, health maintenance contracts, limited benefit plans, prepaid service contracts, and other contracts for services must ensure the availability of covered services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Products may be offered for multiyear periods provided the price of the product is specified for the entire period or for each separately priced segment of the policy or contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall provide a disclosure form for consumers to acknowledge their understanding of the nature of, and any limitations to, the benefits provided by the products and services being purchased by the consumer.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation must determine that making the plan available through the program is in the interest of eligible individuals and eligible employers in the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PRICING.<EmDash />Prices for the products and services sold through the program must be transparent to participants and established by the vendors. The corporation shall annually assess a surcharge for each premium or price set by a participating vendor. The surcharge may not be more than 2.5 percent of the price and shall be used to generate funding for administrative services provided by the corporation and payments to buyers’ representatives.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">THE MARKETPLACE PROCESS.<EmDash />The program shall provide a single, centralized market for purchase of health insurance, health maintenance contracts, and other health products and services. Purchases may be made by participating individuals over the Internet or through the services of a participating health insurance agent. Information about each product and service available through the program shall be made available through printed material and an interactive Internet website. A participant needing personal assistance to select products and services shall be referred to a participating agent in his or her area.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation in the program may begin at any time during a year after the employer completes enrollment and meets the requirements specified by the corporation pursuant to paragraph (4)(c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initial selection of products and services must be made by an individual participant within 60 days after the date the individual’s employer qualified for participation. An individual who fails to enroll in products and services by the end of this period is limited to participation in flexible spending account services until the next annual enrollment period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initial enrollment periods for each product selected by an individual participant must last at least 12 months, unless the individual participant specifically agrees to a different enrollment period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an individual has selected one or more products and enrolled in those products for at least 12 months or any other period specifically agreed to by the individual participant, changes in selected products and services may only be made during the annual enrollment period established by the corporation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The limits established in paragraphs (b)-(d) apply to any risk-bearing product that promises future payment or coverage for a variable amount of benefits or services. The limits do not apply to initiation of flexible spending plans if those plans are not associated with specific high-deductible insurance policies or the use of spending accounts for any products offering individual participants specific amounts and types of health services and treatments at a contracted price.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONSUMER INFORMATION.<EmDash />The corporation shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a secure website to facilitate the purchase of products and services by participating individuals. The website must provide information about each product or service available through the program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform individuals about other public health care programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RISK POOLING.<EmDash />The program may use methods for pooling the risk of individual participants and preventing selection bias. These methods may include, but are not limited to, a postenrollment risk adjustment of the premium payments to the vendors. The corporation may establish a methodology for assessing the risk of enrolled individual participants based on data reported annually by the vendors about their enrollees. Distribution of payments to the vendors may be adjusted based on the assessed relative risk profile of the enrollees in each risk-bearing product for the most recent period for which data is available.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTIONS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Products, other than the products set forth in subparagraphs (4)(d)1.-4., sold as part of the program are not subject to the licensing requirements of the Florida Insurance Code, as defined in s. 624.01 or the mandated offerings or coverages established in part VI of chapter 627 and chapter 641.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may act as an administrator as defined in s. 626.88 but is not required to be certified pursuant to part VII of chapter 626. However, a third party administrator used by the corporation must be certified under part VII of chapter 626.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CORPORATION.<EmDash />There is created the Florida Health Choices, Inc., which shall be registered, incorporated, organized, and operated in compliance with part III of chapter 112 and chapters 119, 286, and 617. The purpose of the corporation is to administer the program created in this section and to conduct such other business as may further the administration of the program.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall be governed by a 15-member board of directors consisting of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three ex officio, nonvoting members to include:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Health Care Administration or a designee with expertise in health care services.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Secretary of Management Services or a designee with expertise in state employee benefits.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioner of the Office of Insurance Regulation or a designee with expertise in insurance regulation.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members appointed by and serving at the pleasure of the Governor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members appointed by and serving at the pleasure of the President of the Senate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Four members appointed by and serving at the pleasure of the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board members may not include insurers, health insurance agents or brokers, health care providers, health maintenance organizations, prepaid service providers, or any other entity, affiliate or subsidiary of eligible vendors.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members shall be appointed for terms of up to 3 years. Any member is eligible for reappointment. A vacancy on the board shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner as the original appointment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall select a chief executive officer for the corporation who shall be responsible for the selection of such other staff as may be authorized by the corporation’s operating budget as adopted by the board.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board members are entitled to receive, from funds of the corporation, reimbursement for per diem and travel expenses as provided by s. 112.061. No other compensation is authorized.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is no liability on the part of, and no cause of action shall arise against, any member of the board or its employees or agents for any action taken by them in the performance of their powers and duties under this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall develop and adopt bylaws and other corporate procedures as necessary for the operation of the corporation and carrying out the purposes of this section. The bylaws shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify procedures for selection of officers and qualifications for reappointment, provided that no board member shall serve more than 9 consecutive years.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require an annual membership meeting that provides an opportunity for input and interaction with individual participants in the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Specify policies and procedures regarding conflicts of interest, including the provisions of part III of chapter 112, which prohibit a member from participating in any decision that would inure to the benefit of the member or the organization that employs the member. The policies and procedures shall also require public disclosure of the interest that prevents the member from participating in a decision on a particular matter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may exercise all powers granted to it under chapter 617 necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including, but not limited to, the power to receive and accept grants, loans, or advances of funds from any public or private agency and to receive and accept from any source contributions of money, property, labor, or any other thing of value to be held, used, and applied for the purposes of this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation may establish technical advisory panels consisting of interested parties, including consumers, health care providers, individuals with expertise in insurance regulation, and insurers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determine eligibility of employers, vendors, individuals, and agents in accordance with subsection (4).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures necessary for the operation of the program, including, but not limited to, procedures for application, enrollment, risk assessment, risk adjustment, plan administration, performance monitoring, and consumer education.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrange for collection of contributions from participating employers and individuals.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arrange for payment of premiums and other appropriate disbursements based on the selections of products and services by the individual participants.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish criteria for disenrollment of participating individuals based on failure to pay the individual’s share of any contribution required to maintain enrollment in selected products.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish criteria for exclusion of vendors pursuant to paragraph (4)(d).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop and implement a plan for promoting public awareness of and participation in the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secure staff and consultant services necessary to the operation of the program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish policies and procedures regarding participation in the program for individuals, vendors, health insurance agents, and employers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the operation of a toll-free hotline to respond to requests for assistance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for initial, open, and special enrollment periods.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluate options for employer participation which may conform with common insurance practices.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REPORT.<EmDash />Beginning in the 2009-2010 fiscal year, submit by February 1 an annual report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives documenting the corporation’s activities in compliance with the duties delineated in this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROGRAM INTEGRITY.<EmDash />To ensure program integrity and to safeguard the financial transactions made under the auspices of the program, the corporation is authorized to establish qualifying criteria and certification procedures for vendors, require performance bonds or other guarantees of ability to complete contractual obligations, monitor the performance of vendors, and enforce the agreements of the program through financial penalty or disqualification from the program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXEMPTION FROM PUBLIC RECORDS REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Definitions.</Font><EmDash />For purposes of this subsection, the term:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Buyer’s representative” means a participating insurance agent as described in paragraph (4)(g).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enrollee” means an employer who is eligible to enroll in the program pursuant to paragraph (4)(a).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Participant” means an individual who is eligible to participate in the program pursuant to paragraph (4)(b).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proprietary confidential business information” means information, regardless of form or characteristics, that is owned or controlled by a vendor requesting confidentiality under this section; that is intended to be and is treated by the vendor as private in that the disclosure of the information would cause harm to the business operations of the vendor; that has not been disclosed unless disclosed pursuant to a statutory provision, an order of a court or administrative body, or a private agreement providing that the information may be released to the public; and that is information concerning:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Business plans.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Internal auditing controls and reports of internal auditors.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reports of external auditors for privately held companies.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Client and customer lists.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Potentially patentable material.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="f">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trade secret as defined in s. 688.002.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vendor” means a participating insurer or other provider of services as described in paragraph (4)(d).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Public record exemptions.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal identifying information of an enrollee or participant who has applied for or participates in the Florida Health Choices Program is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Client and customer lists of a buyer’s representative held by the corporation are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proprietary confidential business information held by the corporation is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Retroactive application.</Font><EmDash />The public record exemptions provided for in paragraph (b) apply to information held by the corporation before, on, or after the effective date of this exemption.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Authorized release.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, information made confidential and exempt pursuant to this subsection shall be disclosed to:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Another governmental entity in the performance of its official duties and responsibilities.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has the written consent of the program applicant.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Kidcare program for the purpose of administering the program authorized in ss. 409.810-409.821.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Paragraph (b) does not prohibit a participant’s legal guardian from obtaining confirmation of coverage, dates of coverage, the name of the participant’s health plan, and the amount of premium being paid.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Penalty.</Font><EmDash />A person who knowingly and willfully violates this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Review and repeal.</Font><EmDash />This subsection is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15, and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2016, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2008-32; s. 4, ch. 2011-195; s. 1, ch. 2011-197.</History>
</Section>