<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.816" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Injunctions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the other powers provided by this part, authorizing statutes, and applicable rules, the agency may institute injunction proceedings in a court of competent jurisdiction to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Restrain or prevent the establishment or operation of a provider that does not have a license or is in violation of any provision of this part, authorizing statutes, or applicable rules. The agency may also institute injunction proceedings in a court of competent jurisdiction when a violation of this part, authorizing statutes, or applicable rules constitutes an emergency affecting the immediate health and safety of a client.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce the provisions of this part, authorizing statutes, or any minimum standard, rule, or order issued or entered into pursuant thereto when the attempt by the agency to correct a violation through administrative sanctions has failed or when the violation materially affects the health, safety, or welfare of clients or involves any operation of an unlicensed provider.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminate the operation of a provider when a violation of any provision of this part, authorizing statutes, or any standard or rule adopted pursuant thereto exists that materially affects the health, safety, or welfare of a client.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Such injunctive relief may be temporary or permanent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If action is necessary to protect clients of providers from immediate, life-threatening situations, the court may allow a temporary injunction without bond upon proper proofs being made. If it appears by competent evidence or a sworn, substantiated affidavit that a temporary injunction should be issued, the court, pending the determination on final hearing, shall enjoin the operation of the provider.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192.</History></Section>