<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.802" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Applicability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this part apply to the provision of services that require licensure as defined in this part and to the following entities licensed, registered, or certified by the agency, as described in chapters 112, 383, 390, 394, 395, 400, 429, 440, 483, and 765:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Laboratories authorized to perform testing under the Drug-Free Workplace Act, as provided under ss. 112.0455 and 440.102.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Birth centers, as provided under chapter 383.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abortion clinics, as provided under chapter 390.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crisis stabilization units, as provided under parts I and IV of chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Short-term residential treatment facilities, as provided under parts I and IV of chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential treatment facilities, as provided under part IV of chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential treatment centers for children and adolescents, as provided under part IV of chapter 394.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospitals, as provided under part I of chapter 395.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ambulatory surgical centers, as provided under part I of chapter 395.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mobile surgical facilities, as provided under part I of chapter 395.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care risk managers, as provided under part I of chapter 395.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nursing homes, as provided under part II of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisted living facilities, as provided under part I of chapter 429.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home health agencies, as provided under part III of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nurse registries, as provided under part III of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Companion services or homemaker services providers, as provided under part III of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult day care centers, as provided under part III of chapter 429.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospices, as provided under part IV of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult family-care homes, as provided under part II of chapter 429.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Homes for special services, as provided under part V of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transitional living facilities, as provided under part V of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribed pediatric extended care centers, as provided under part VI of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home medical equipment providers, as provided under part VII of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intermediate care facilities for persons with developmental disabilities, as provided under part VIII of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care services pools, as provided under part IX of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care clinics, as provided under part X of chapter 400.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical laboratories, as provided under part I of chapter 483.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="28"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Multiphasic health testing centers, as provided under part II of chapter 483.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="29"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organ, tissue, and eye procurement organizations, as provided under part V of chapter 765.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192; s. 89, ch. 2007-5; s. 132, ch. 2007-230; s. 19, ch. 2009-218; s. 23, ch. 2012-160.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 11, ch. 2006-192, provides that “[a]ll provisions that apply to the entities specified in s. 408.802, Florida Statutes, as created by this act, in effect on October 1, 2006, that provide for annual licensure fees are hereby adjusted to provide for biennial licensure fees with a corresponding doubling of the amount.”</Text></Note></Section>