<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0408.820" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as prescribed in authorizing statutes, the following exemptions shall apply to specified requirements of this part:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Laboratories authorized to perform testing under the Drug-Free Workplace Act, as provided under ss. 112.0455 and 440.102, are exempt from s. 408.810(5)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Birth centers, as provided under chapter 383, are exempt from s. 408.810(7)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abortion clinics, as provided under chapter 390, are exempt from s. 408.810(7)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Crisis stabilization units, as provided under parts I and IV of chapter 394, are exempt from s. 408.810(8)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Short-term residential treatment facilities, as provided under parts I and IV of chapter 394, are exempt from s. 408.810(8)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential treatment facilities, as provided under part IV of chapter 394, are exempt from s. 408.810(8)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Residential treatment centers for children and adolescents, as provided under part IV of chapter 394, are exempt from s. 408.810(8)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospitals, as provided under part I of chapter 395, are exempt from s. 408.810(7)-(9).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ambulatory surgical centers, as provided under part I of chapter 395, are exempt from s. 408.810(7)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mobile surgical facilities, as provided under part I of chapter 395, are exempt from s. 408.810(7)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care risk managers, as provided under part I of chapter 395, are exempt from ss. 408.806(7), 408.810(4)-(10), and 408.811.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nursing homes, as provided under part II of chapter 400, are exempt from ss. 408.810(7) and 408.813(2).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisted living facilities, as provided under part I of chapter 429, are exempt from s. 408.810(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home health agencies, as provided under part III of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nurse registries, as provided under part III of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(6) and (10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Companion services or homemaker services providers, as provided under part III of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(6)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult day care centers, as provided under part III of chapter 429, are exempt from s. 408.810(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adult family-care homes, as provided under part II of chapter 429, are exempt from s. 408.810(7)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Homes for special services, as provided under part V of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(7)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transitional living facilities, as provided under part V of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prescribed pediatric extended care centers, as provided under part VI of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home medical equipment providers, as provided under part VII of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intermediate care facilities for persons with developmental disabilities, as provided under part VIII of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(7).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care services pools, as provided under part IX of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(6)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="25">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health care clinics, as provided under part X of chapter 400, are exempt from s. 408.810(6), (7), and (10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="26">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical laboratories, as provided under part I of chapter 483, are exempt from s. 408.810(5)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="27">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Multiphasic health testing centers, as provided under part II of chapter 483, are exempt from s. 408.810(5)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="28">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Organ, tissue, and eye procurement organizations, as provided under part V of chapter 765, are exempt from s. 408.810(5)-(10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192; s. 92, ch. 2007-5; s. 20, ch. 2009-218; s. 53, ch. 2009-223; s. 90, ch. 2010-5.</History>
</Section>