<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.70" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Health care; managed competition; legislative findings and intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that the current health care system in this state does not provide access to affordable health care for all persons in this state. Almost one in five persons is without health insurance. For many, entry into the health care system is through a hospital emergency room rather than a primary care setting. The availability of preventive and primary care and managed, family-based care is limited. Health insurance underwriting practices have led to the avoidance, rather than to the sharing, of insurance risks, limiting access to coverages for small-sized employer groups and high-risk populations. Spiraling premium costs have placed health insurance policies out of the reach of many small-sized and medium-sized businesses and their employees. Lack of outcome and cost information has forced individuals and businesses to make critical health care decisions with little guidance or leverage. Health care resources have not been allocated efficiently, leading to excess and unevenly distributed capacity. These factors have contributed to the high cost of health care. Rural and other medically underserved areas have too few health care resources. Comprehensive, first-dollar coverages have allowed individuals to seek care without regard to cost. Provider competition and liability concerns have led to a medical technology arms race. Rather than competing on the basis of price and patient outcome, health care providers compete for patients on the basis of service, equipping themselves with the latest and best technologies. Managed-care and group-purchasing mechanisms are not widely available to small group purchasers. Health care regulation has placed undue burdens on health care insurers and providers, driving up costs, limiting competition, and preventing market-based solutions to cost and quality problems. Health care costs have been increasing at several times the rate of general inflation, eroding employer profits and investments, increasing government revenue requirements, reducing consumer coverages and purchasing power, and limiting public investments in other vital governmental services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that a structured health care competition model, known as “managed competition,” be implemented throughout the state to improve the efficiency of the health care markets in this state. The managed competition model will promote the pooling of purchaser and consumer buying power; ensure informed cost-conscious consumer choice of managed care plans; reward providers for high-quality, economical care; increase access to care for uninsured persons; and control the rate of inflation in health care costs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 66, ch. 93-129; s. 60, ch. 2000-256; s. 11, ch. 2000-296.</History></Section>