<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.918" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida 211 Network; uniform certification requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature authorizes the planning, development, and, subject to appropriations, the implementation of a statewide Florida 211 Network, which shall serve as the single point of coordination for information and referral for health and human services. The objectives for establishing the Florida 211 Network shall be to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide comprehensive and cost-effective access to health and human services information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improve access to accurate information by simplifying and enhancing state and local health and human services information and referral systems and by fostering collaboration among information and referral systems.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Electronically connect local information and referral systems to each other, to service providers, and to consumers of information and referral services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and promote standards for data collection and for distributing information among state and local organizations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote the use of a common dialing access code and the visibility and public awareness of the availability of information and referral services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a management and administrative structure to support the Florida 211 Network and establish technical assistance, training, and support programs for information and referral-service programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Test methods for integrating information and referral services with local and state health and human services programs and for consolidating and streamlining eligibility and case management processes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide access to standardized, comprehensive data to assist in identifying gaps and needs in health and human services programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a unified systems plan with a developed platform, taxonomy, and standards for data management and access.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to participate in the Florida 211 Network, a 211 provider must be fully accredited by the National Alliance of Information and Referral Services or have received approval to operate, pending accreditation, from its affiliate, the Florida Alliance of Information and Referral Services. If any provider of information and referral services or other entity leases a 211 number from a local exchange company and is not authorized as described in this section, the Public Service Commission shall request that the Federal Communications Commission direct the local exchange company to revoke the use of the 211 number.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Alliance of Information and Referral Services is the 211 collaborative organization for the state which is responsible for studying, designing, implementing, supporting, and coordinating the Florida 211 Network and for receiving federal grants.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2002-223; s. 56, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>