<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.913" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Comprehensive Health and Human Services Eligibility Access System.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall develop a comprehensive, automated system for access to health care services. This system shall, to the greatest extent possible, use the capacity of existing automated systems so as to maximize the benefit of investments already made in information technology and minimize additional costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The benefit eligibility component of the system shall include simplified access through coordination with information and referral telephone systems. This does not preclude use of other methods of application, including mail-in applications, office visits, or online applications via the Internet. The eligibility component of the system shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improved access to eligibility-status information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development and sharing of information with eligible individuals and families regarding choices available to them for using health care services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state agencies providing the medical, clinical, and related health care support services for special populations, including frail elders, adults with disabilities, and children with special needs shall develop systems for these populations which integrate and coordinate care and improved communication. These systems must include development of standard protocols for care planning and assessment, a focus on family involvement, and methods to communicate across systems, including automated methods, in order to improve integration and coordination of services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2002-223.</History></Section>