<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.810" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Minimum licensure requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the licensure requirements specified in this part, authorizing statutes, and applicable rules, each applicant and licensee must comply with the requirements of this section in order to obtain and maintain a license.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for licensure must comply with the background screening requirements of s. 408.809.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for licensure must provide a description and explanation of any exclusions, suspensions, or terminations of the applicant from the Medicare, Medicaid, or federal Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendment (CLIA) programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise specified in this part, authorizing statutes, or applicable rules, any information required to be reported to the agency must be submitted within 21 calendar days after the report period or effective date of the information, whichever is earlier, including, but not limited to, any change of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information contained in the most recent application for licensure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Required insurance or bonds.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a licensee discontinues operation of a provider:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee must inform the agency not less than 30 days prior to the discontinuance of operation and inform clients of such discontinuance as required by authorizing statutes. Immediately upon discontinuance of operation by a provider, the licensee shall surrender the license to the agency and the license shall be canceled.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee shall remain responsible for retaining and appropriately distributing all records within the timeframes prescribed in authorizing statutes and applicable rules. In addition, the licensee or, in the event of death or dissolution of a licensee, the estate or agent of the licensee shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make arrangements to forward records for each client to one of the following, based upon the client’s choice: the client or the client’s legal representative, the client’s attending physician, or the health care provider where the client currently receives services; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cause a notice to be published in the newspaper of greatest general circulation in the county in which the provider was located that advises clients of the discontinuance of the provider operation. The notice must inform clients that they may obtain copies of their records and specify the name, address, and telephone number of the person from whom the copies of records may be obtained. The notice must appear at least once a week for 4 consecutive weeks.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before the first day services are provided to a client, a licensee must inform the client and his or her immediate family or representative, if appropriate, of the right to report:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Complaints. The statewide toll-free telephone number for reporting complaints to the agency must be provided to clients in a manner that is clearly legible and must include the words: “To report a complaint regarding the services you receive, please call toll-free (phone number).”</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abusive, neglectful, or exploitative practices. The statewide toll-free telephone number for the central abuse hotline must be provided to clients in a manner that is clearly legible and must include the words: “To report abuse, neglect, or exploitation, please call toll-free (phone number).”</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicaid fraud. An agency-written description of Medicaid fraud and the statewide toll-free telephone number for the central Medicaid fraud hotline must be provided to clients in a manner that is clearly legible and must include the words: “To report suspected Medicaid fraud, please call toll-free (phone number).”</Text></SubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The agency shall publish a minimum of a 90-day advance notice of a change in the toll-free telephone numbers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each licensee shall establish appropriate policies and procedures for providing such notice to clients.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant must provide the agency with proof of the applicant’s legal right to occupy the property before a license may be issued. Proof may include, but need not be limited to, copies of warranty deeds, lease or rental agreements, contracts for deeds, quitclaim deeds, or other such documentation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If proof of insurance is required by the authorizing statute, that insurance must be in compliance with chapter 624, chapter 626, chapter 627, or chapter 628 and with agency rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application for initial licensure or change of ownership licensure, the applicant shall furnish satisfactory proof of the applicant’s financial ability to operate in accordance with the requirements of this part, authorizing statutes, and applicable rules. The agency shall establish standards for this purpose, including information concerning the applicant’s controlling interests. The agency shall also establish documentation requirements, to be completed by each applicant, that show anticipated provider revenues and expenditures, the basis for financing the anticipated cash-flow requirements of the provider, and an applicant’s access to contingency financing. A current certificate of authority, pursuant to chapter 651, may be provided as proof of financial ability to operate. The agency may require a licensee to provide proof of financial ability to operate at any time if there is evidence of financial instability, including, but not limited to, unpaid expenses necessary for the basic operations of the provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A controlling interest may not withhold from the agency any evidence of financial instability, including, but not limited to, checks returned due to insufficient funds, delinquent accounts, nonpayment of withholding taxes, unpaid utility expenses, nonpayment for essential services, or adverse court action concerning the financial viability of the provider or any other provider licensed under this part that is under the control of the controlling interest. A controlling interest shall notify the agency within 10 days after a court action to initiate bankruptcy, foreclosure, or eviction proceedings concerning the provider in which the controlling interest is a petitioner or defendant. Any person who violates this subsection commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Each day of continuing violation is a separate offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may not issue a license to a health care provider subject to the certificate-of-need provisions in part I of this chapter if the health care provider has not been issued a certificate of need or an exemption. Upon initial licensure of any such provider, the authorization contained in the certificate of need shall be considered fully implemented and merged into the license and shall have no force and effect upon termination of the license for any reason.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192; s. 9, ch. 2009-223; s. 27, ch. 2012-160.</History></Section>