<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0408.808" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">License categories.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STANDARD LICENSE.<EmDash />A standard license may be issued to an applicant at the time of initial licensure, license renewal, or change of ownership. A standard license shall be issued when the applicant is in compliance with all statutory requirements and agency rules. Unless sooner revoked, a standard license expires 2 years after the date of issue.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROVISIONAL LICENSE.<EmDash />An applicant against whom a proceeding denying or revoking a license is pending at the time of license renewal may be issued a provisional license effective until final action not subject to further appeal. A provisional license may also be issued to an applicant applying for a change of ownership. A provisional license must be limited in duration to a specific period of time, up to 12 months, as determined by the agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">INACTIVE LICENSE.<EmDash />An inactive license may be issued to a health care provider subject to the certificate-of-need provisions in part I of this chapter when the provider is currently licensed, does not have a provisional license, and will be temporarily unable to provide services but is reasonably expected to resume services within 12 months. Such designation may be made for a period not to exceed 12 months but may be renewed by the agency for up to 12 additional months upon demonstration by the licensee of the provider’s progress toward reopening. However, if after 20 months in an inactive license status, a statutory rural hospital, as defined in s. 395.602, has demonstrated progress toward reopening, but may not be able to reopen prior to the inactive license expiration date, the inactive designation may be renewed again by the agency for up to 12 additional months. For purposes of such a second renewal, if construction or renovation is required, the licensee must have had plans approved by the agency and construction must have already commenced pursuant to s. 408.032(4); however, if construction or renovation is not required, the licensee must provide proof of having made an enforceable capital expenditure greater than 25 percent of the total costs associated with the hiring of staff and the purchase of equipment and supplies needed to operate the facility upon opening. A request by a licensee for an inactive license or to extend the previously approved inactive period must be submitted to the agency and must include a written justification for the inactive license with the beginning and ending dates of inactivity specified, a plan for the transfer of any clients to other providers, and the appropriate licensure fees. The agency may not accept a request that is submitted after initiating closure, after any suspension of service, or after notifying clients of closure or suspension of service, unless the action is a result of a disaster at the licensed premises. For the purposes of this section, the term “disaster” means a sudden emergency occurrence beyond the control of the licensee, whether natural, technological, or manmade, which renders the provider inoperable at the premises. Upon agency approval, the provider shall notify clients of any necessary discharge or transfer as required by authorizing statutes or applicable rules. The beginning of the inactive license period is the date the provider ceases operations. The end of the inactive license period shall become the license expiration date. All licensure fees must be current, must be paid in full, and may be prorated. Reactivation of an inactive license requires the approval of a renewal application, including payment of licensure fees and agency inspections indicating compliance with all requirements of this part, authorizing statutes, and applicable rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OTHER LICENSES.<EmDash />Other types of license categories may be issued pursuant to authorizing statutes or applicable rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192; s. 2, ch. 2009-45; s. 49, ch. 2009-223; s. 20, ch. 2010-114.</History>
</Section>