<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0408.7056" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Subscriber Assistance Program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Financial Services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Grievance procedure” means an established set of rules that specify a process for appeal of an organizational decision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Health care provider” or “provider” means a state-licensed or state-authorized facility, a facility principally supported by a local government or by funds from a charitable organization that holds a current exemption from federal income tax under s. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, a licensed practitioner, a county health department established under part I of chapter 154, a prescribed pediatric extended care center defined in s. 400.902, a federally supported primary care program such as a migrant health center or a community health center authorized under s. 329 or s. 330 of the United States Public Health Services Act that delivers health care services to individuals, or a community facility that receives funds from the state under the Community Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Services Act and provides mental health services to individuals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Managed care entity” means a health maintenance organization or a prepaid health clinic certified under chapter 641, a prepaid health plan authorized under s. 409.912, or an exclusive provider organization certified under s. 627.6472.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Office” means the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Panel” means a subscriber assistance panel selected as provided in subsection (11).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt and implement a program to provide assistance to subscribers, including those whose grievances are not resolved by the managed care entity to the satisfaction of the subscriber. The program shall consist of one or more panels that meet as often as necessary to timely review, consider, and hear grievances and recommend to the agency or the office any actions that should be taken concerning individual cases heard by the panel. The panel shall hear every grievance filed by subscribers on behalf of subscribers, unless the grievance:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Relates to a managed care entity’s refusal to accept a provider into its network of providers;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is part of an internal grievance in a Medicare managed care entity or a reconsideration appeal through the Medicare appeals process which does not involve a quality of care issue;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is related to a health plan not regulated by the state such as an administrative services organization, third-party administrator, or federal employee health benefit program;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is related to appeals by in-plan suppliers and providers, unless related to quality of care provided by the plan;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is part of a Medicaid fair hearing pursued under 42 C.F.R. ss. 431.220 et seq.;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is the basis for an action pending in state or federal court;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is related to an appeal by nonparticipating providers, unless related to the quality of care provided to a subscriber by the managed care entity and the provider is involved in the care provided to the subscriber;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Was filed before the subscriber completed the entire internal grievance procedure of the managed care entity, the managed care entity has complied with its timeframes for completing the internal grievance procedure, and the circumstances described in subsection (6) do not apply;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been resolved to the satisfaction of the subscriber who filed the grievance, unless the managed care entity’s initial action is egregious or may be indicative of a pattern of inappropriate behavior;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is limited to seeking damages for pain and suffering, lost wages, or other incidental expenses, including accrued interest on unpaid balances, court costs, and transportation costs associated with a grievance procedure;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is limited to issues involving conduct of a health care provider or facility, staff member, or employee of a managed care entity which constitute grounds for disciplinary action by the appropriate professional licensing board and is not indicative of a pattern of inappropriate behavior, and the agency, office, or department has reported these grievances to the appropriate professional licensing board or to the health facility regulation section of the agency for possible investigation; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is withdrawn by the subscriber. Failure of the subscriber to attend the hearing shall be considered a withdrawal of the grievance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall review all grievances within 60 days after receipt and make a determination whether the grievance shall be heard. Once the agency notifies the panel, the subscriber, and the managed care entity that a grievance will be heard by the panel, the panel shall hear the grievance either in the network area or by teleconference no later than 120 days after the date the grievance was filed. The agency shall notify the parties, in writing, by facsimile transmission, or by phone, of the time and place of the hearing. The panel may take testimony under oath, request certified copies of documents, and take similar actions to collect information and documentation that will assist the panel in making findings of fact and a recommendation. The panel shall issue a written recommendation, supported by findings of fact, to the subscriber, to the managed care entity, and to the agency or the office no later than 15 working days after hearing the grievance. If at the hearing the panel requests additional documentation or additional records, the time for issuing a recommendation is tolled until the information or documentation requested has been provided to the panel. The proceedings of the panel are not subject to chapter 120.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, upon receiving a proper patient authorization along with a properly filed grievance, the agency requests records from a health care provider or managed care entity, the health care provider or managed care entity that has custody of the records has 10 days to provide the records to the agency. Records include medical records, communication logs associated with the grievance both to and from the subscriber, and contracts. Failure to provide requested records may result in the imposition of a fine of up to $500. Each day that records are not produced is considered a separate violation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grievances that the agency determines pose an immediate and serious threat to a subscriber’s health must be given priority over other grievances. The panel may meet at the call of the chair to hear the grievances as quickly as possible but no later than 45 days after the date the grievance is filed, unless the panel receives a waiver of the time requirement from the subscriber. The panel shall issue a written recommendation, supported by findings of fact, to the office or the agency within 10 days after hearing the expedited grievance.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the agency determines that the life of a subscriber is in imminent and emergent jeopardy, the chair of the panel may convene an emergency hearing, within 24 hours after notification to the managed care entity and to the subscriber, to hear the grievance. The grievance must be heard notwithstanding that the subscriber has not completed the internal grievance procedure of the managed care entity. The panel shall, upon hearing the grievance, issue a written emergency recommendation, supported by findings of fact, to the managed care entity, to the subscriber, and to the agency or the office for the purpose of deferring the imminent and emergent jeopardy to the subscriber’s life. Within 24 hours after receipt of the panel’s emergency recommendation, the agency or office may issue an emergency order to the managed care entity. An emergency order remains in force until:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grievance has been resolved by the managed care entity;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical intervention is no longer necessary; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The panel has conducted a full hearing under subsection (3) and issued a recommendation to the agency or the office, and the agency or office has issued a final order.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After hearing a grievance, the panel shall make a recommendation to the agency or the office which may include specific actions the managed care entity must take to comply with state laws or rules regulating managed care entities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A managed care entity, subscriber, or provider that is affected by a panel recommendation may within 10 days after receipt of the panel’s recommendation, or 72 hours after receipt of a recommendation in an expedited grievance, furnish to the agency or office written evidence in opposition to the recommendation or findings of fact of the panel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No later than 30 days after the issuance of the panel’s recommendation and, for an expedited grievance, no later than 10 days after the issuance of the panel’s recommendation, the agency or the office may adopt the panel’s recommendation or findings of fact in a proposed order or an emergency order, as provided in chapter 120, which it shall issue to the managed care entity. The agency or office may issue a proposed order or an emergency order, as provided in chapter 120, imposing fines or sanctions, including those contained in ss. 641.25 and 641.52. The agency or the office may reject all or part of the panel’s recommendation. All fines collected under this subsection must be deposited into the Health Care Trust Fund.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In determining any fine or sanction to be imposed, the agency and the office may consider the following factors:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The severity of the noncompliance, including the probability that death or serious harm to the health or safety of the subscriber will result or has resulted, the severity of the actual or potential harm, and the extent to which provisions of chapter 641 were violated.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken by the managed care entity to resolve or remedy any quality-of-care grievance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous incidents of noncompliance by the managed care entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other relevant factors the agency or office considers appropriate in a particular grievance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The panel shall consist of the Insurance Consumer Advocate, or designee thereof, established by s. 627.0613; at least two members employed by the agency and at least two members employed by the department, chosen by their respective agencies; a consumer appointed by the Governor; a physician appointed by the Governor, as a standing member; and, if necessary, physicians who have expertise relevant to the case to be heard, on a rotating basis. The agency may contract with a medical director, a primary care physician, or both, who shall provide additional technical expertise to the panel but shall not be voting members of the panel. The medical director shall be selected from a health maintenance organization with a current certificate of authority to operate in Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A majority of those panel members required under paragraph (a) shall constitute a quorum for any meeting or hearing of the panel. A grievance may not be heard or voted upon at any panel meeting or hearing unless a quorum is present, except that a minority of the panel may adjourn a meeting or hearing until a quorum is present. A panel convened for the purpose of hearing a subscriber’s grievance in accordance with subsections (2) and (3) shall not consist of more than 11 members.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every managed care entity shall submit a quarterly report to the agency, the office, and the department listing the number and the nature of all subscribers’ and providers’ grievances which have not been resolved to the satisfaction of the subscriber or provider after the subscriber or provider follows the entire internal grievance procedure of the managed care entity. The agency shall notify all subscribers and providers included in the quarterly reports of their right to file an unresolved grievance with the panel.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proposed order issued by the agency or office which only requires the managed care entity to take a specific action under subsection (7) is subject to a summary hearing in accordance with s. 120.574, unless all of the parties agree otherwise. If the managed care entity does not prevail at the hearing, the managed care entity must pay reasonable costs and attorney’s fees of the agency or the office incurred in that proceeding.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any information that identifies a subscriber which is held by the panel, agency, or department pursuant to this section is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution. However, at the request of a subscriber or managed care entity involved in a grievance procedure, the panel, agency, or department shall release information identifying the subscriber involved in the grievance procedure to the requesting subscriber or managed care entity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meetings of the panel shall be open to the public unless the provider or subscriber whose grievance will be heard requests a closed meeting or the agency or the department determines that information which discloses the subscriber’s medical treatment or history or information relating to internal risk management programs as defined in s. 641.55(5)(c), (6), and (8) may be revealed at the panel meeting, in which case that portion of the meeting during which a subscriber’s medical treatment or history or internal risk management program information is discussed shall be exempt from the provisions of s. 286.011 and s. 24(b), Art. I of the State Constitution. All closed meetings shall be recorded by a certified court reporter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies only to prepaid health clinics certified under chapter 641, Florida Healthy Kids plans, and health plan health insurance policies or health maintenance contracts that meet the requirements of 45 C.F.R. s. 147.140, but only if the health plan does not elect to have all of its health insurance policies or health maintenance contracts subject to applicable internal grievance and external review processes by an independent review organization. A health plan must notify the agency in writing if it elects to have all of its health insurance policies or health maintenance contracts subject to such external review.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 32, 47, ch. 85-177; s. 15, ch. 88-388; ss. 123, 187, 188, ch. 91-108; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 76, ch. 93-129; s. 23, ch. 95-398; s. 3, ch. 96-199; s. 250, ch. 96-406; s. 24, ch. 96-418; s. 1, ch. 98-10; s. 1, ch. 98-256; s. 2, ch. 99-393; s. 34, ch. 2000-256; s. 1, ch. 2000-296; s. 1, ch. 2003-105; s. 439, ch. 2003-261; s. 13, ch. 2004-297; s. 1, ch. 2012-44.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 641.311; (4) former s. 119.07(3)(s).</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>