<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.8065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional licensure requirements for home health agencies, home medical equipment providers, and health care clinics.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for initial licensure, or initial licensure due to a change of ownership, as a home health agency, home medical equipment provider, or health care clinic shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Demonstrate financial ability to operate, as required under s. 408.810(8) and this section. If the applicant’s assets, credit, and projected revenues meet or exceed projected liabilities and expenses, and the applicant provides independent evidence that the funds necessary for startup costs, working capital, and contingency financing exist and will be available as needed, the applicant has demonstrated the financial ability to operate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit projected financial statements, including a balance sheet, income and expense statement, and a statement of cash flows for the first 2 years of operation which provide evidence that the applicant has sufficient assets, credit, and projected revenues to cover liabilities and expenses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit a statement of the applicant’s estimated startup costs and sources of funds through the break-even point in operations demonstrating that the applicant has the ability to fund all startup costs, working capital <Reference Number="1" />costs, and contingency financing <Reference Number="2" />requirements. The statement must show that the applicant has at a minimum 3 months of average projected expenses to cover startup costs, working capital <Reference Number="1" />costs, and contingency financing <Reference Number="2" />requirements. The minimum amount for contingency funding may not be less than 1 month of average projected expenses.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All documents required under this subsection must be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and may be in a compilation form. The financial statements must be signed by a certified public accountant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For initial, renewal, or change of ownership licenses for a home health agency, a home medical equipment provider, or a health care clinic, applicants and controlling interests who are nonimmigrant aliens, as described in 8 U.S.C. s. 1101, must file a surety bond of at least $500,000, payable to the agency, which guarantees that the home health agency, home medical equipment provider, or health care clinic will act in full conformity with all legal requirements for operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of s. 408.812, any person who offers services that require licensure under part VII or part X of chapter 400, or who offers skilled services that require licensure under part III of chapter 400, without obtaining a valid license; any person who knowingly files a false or misleading license or license renewal application or who submits false or misleading information related to such application, and any person who violates or conspires to violate this section, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2009-193; s. 8, ch. 2009-223; s. 26, ch. 2012-160.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 4, ch. 2009-193. Section 8, ch. 2009-223, also created s. 408.8065, and that version did not include the word “costs.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As created by s. 4, ch. 2009-193. Section 8, ch. 2009-223, also created s. 408.8065, and that version did not include the word “requirements.”</Text></Note></Section>