<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.821" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency management planning; emergency operations; inactive license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensee required by authorizing statutes to have an emergency operations plan must designate a safety liaison to serve as the primary contact for emergency operations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An entity subject to this part may temporarily exceed its licensed capacity to act as a receiving provider in accordance with an approved emergency operations plan for up to 15 days. While in an overcapacity status, each provider must furnish or arrange for appropriate care and services to all clients. In addition, the agency may approve requests for overcapacity in excess of 15 days, which approvals may be based upon satisfactory justification and need as provided by the receiving and sending providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inactive license may be issued to a licensee subject to this section when the provider is located in a geographic area in which a state of emergency was declared by the Governor if the provider:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Suffered damage to its operation during the state of emergency.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is currently licensed.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Does not have a provisional license.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Will be temporarily unable to provide services but is reasonably expected to resume services within 12 months.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inactive license may be issued for a period not to exceed 12 months but may be renewed by the agency for up to 12 additional months upon demonstration to the agency of progress toward reopening. A request by a licensee for an inactive license or to extend the previously approved inactive period must be submitted in writing to the agency, accompanied by written justification for the inactive license, which states the beginning and ending dates of inactivity and includes a plan for the transfer of any clients to other providers and appropriate licensure fees. Upon agency approval, the licensee shall notify clients of any necessary discharge or transfer as required by authorizing statutes or applicable rules. The beginning of the inactive licensure period shall be the date the provider ceases operations. The end of the inactive period shall become the license expiration date, and all licensure fees must be current, must be paid in full, and may be prorated. Reactivation of an inactive license requires the prior approval by the agency of a renewal application, including payment of licensure fees and agency inspections indicating compliance with all requirements of this part and applicable rules and statutes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may adopt rules relating to emergency management planning, communications, and operations. Licensees providing residential or inpatient services must utilize an online database approved by the agency to report information to the agency regarding the provider’s emergency status, planning, or operations.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 54, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>