<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.831" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Denial, suspension, or revocation of a license, registration, certificate, or application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other remedies provided by law, the agency may deny each application or suspend or revoke each license, registration, or certificate of entities regulated or licensed by it:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the applicant, licensee, or a licensee subject to this part which shares a common controlling interest with the applicant has failed to pay all outstanding fines, liens, or overpayments assessed by final order of the agency or final order of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, not subject to further appeal, unless a repayment plan is approved by the agency; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For failure to comply with any repayment plan.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In reviewing any application requesting a change of ownership or change of the licensee, registrant, or certificateholder, the transferor shall, prior to agency approval of the change, repay or make arrangements to repay any amounts owed to the agency. Should the transferor fail to repay or make arrangements to repay the amounts owed to the agency, the issuance of a license, registration, or certificate to the transferee shall be delayed until repayment or until arrangements for repayment are made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section provides standards of enforcement applicable to all entities licensed or regulated by the Agency for Health Care Administration. This section controls over any conflicting provisions of chapters 39, 383, 390, 391, 394, 395, 400, 408, 429, 468, 483, and 765 or rules adopted pursuant to those chapters.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 2002-400; s. 32, ch. 2003-57; s. 28, ch. 2006-71; s. 9, ch. 2006-192; s. 78, ch. 2006-197; s. 55, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>