<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Research, analyses, studies, and reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall conduct research, analyses, and studies relating to health care costs and access to and quality of health care services as access and quality are affected by changes in health care costs. Such research, analyses, and studies shall include, but not be limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial status of any health care facility or facilities subject to the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The impact of uncompensated charity care on health care facilities and health care providers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The state’s role in assisting to fund indigent care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conjunction with the Office of Insurance Regulation, the availability and affordability of health insurance for small businesses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Total health care expenditures in the state according to the sources of payment and the type of expenditure.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The quality of health services, using techniques such as small area analysis, severity adjustments, and risk-adjusted mortality rates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of physician information systems which are capable of providing data for health care consumers taking into account the amount of resources consumed, including such information at licensed facilities as defined in chapter 395, and the outcomes produced in the delivery of care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The collection of a statistically valid sample of data on the retail prices charged by pharmacies for the 100 most frequently prescribed medicines from any pharmacy licensed by this state as a special study authorized by the Legislature to be performed by the agency quarterly. If the drug is available generically, price data shall be reported for the generic drug and price data of a brand-named drug for which the generic drug is the equivalent shall be reported. The agency shall make available on its Internet website for each pharmacy, no later than October 1, 2006, drug prices for a 30-day supply at a standard dose. The data collected shall be reported for each drug by pharmacy and by metropolitan statistical area or region and updated quarterly.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of emergency department services by patient acuity level and the implication of increasing hospital cost by providing nonurgent care in emergency departments. The agency shall submit an annual report based on this monitoring and assessment to the Governor, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, and the substantive legislative committees with the first report due January 1, 2006.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The making available on its Internet website beginning no later than October 1, 2004, and in a hard-copy format upon request, of patient charge, volumes, length of stay, and performance indicators collected from health care facilities pursuant to s. 408.061(1)(a) for specific medical conditions, surgeries, and procedures provided in inpatient and outpatient facilities as determined by the agency. In making the determination of specific medical conditions, surgeries, and procedures to include, the agency shall consider such factors as volume, severity of the illness, urgency of admission, individual and societal costs, and whether the condition is acute or chronic. Performance outcome indicators shall be risk adjusted or severity adjusted, as applicable, using nationally recognized risk adjustment methodologies or software consistent with the standards of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and as selected by the agency. The website shall also provide an interactive search that allows consumers to view and compare the information for specific facilities, a map that allows consumers to select a county or region, definitions of all of the data, descriptions of each procedure, and an explanation about why the data may differ from facility to facility. Such public data shall be updated quarterly. The agency shall submit an annual status report on the collection of data and publication of health care quality measures to the Governor, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, and the substantive legislative committees with the first status report due January 1, 2005.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may assess annually the caesarean section rate in Florida hospitals using the analysis methodology that the agency determines most appropriate. The data from this assessment shall be published periodically on the agency’s Internet website.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may also prepare such summaries and compilations or other supplementary reports based on the information analyzed by the agency under this section, as will advance the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall conduct data-based studies and evaluations and make recommendations to the Legislature and the Governor concerning exemptions, the effectiveness of limitations of referrals, restrictions on investment interests and compensation arrangements, and the effectiveness of public disclosure. Such analysis shall include, but need not be limited to, utilization of services, cost of care, quality of care, and access to care. The agency may require the submission of data necessary to carry out this duty, which may include, but need not be limited to, data concerning ownership, Medicare and Medicaid, charity care, types of services offered to patients, revenues and expenses, patient-encounter data, and other data reasonably necessary to study utilization patterns and the impact of health care provider ownership interests in health-care-related entities on the cost, quality, and accessibility of health care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may collect such data from any health facility or licensed health care provider as a special study.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall develop and implement a strategy for the adoption and use of electronic health records, including the development of an electronic health information network for the sharing of electronic health records among health care facilities, health care providers, and health insurers. The agency may develop rules to facilitate the functionality and protect the confidentiality of electronic health records. The agency shall report to the Governor, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the President of the Senate on legislative recommendations to protect the confidentiality of electronic health records.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 69, ch. 92-33; s. 12, ch. 93-129; s. 12, ch. 98-89; s. 17, ch. 2000-209; s. 31, ch. 2003-57; s. 10, ch. 2004-297; s. 5, ch. 2006-261.</History></Section>