<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.812" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Unlicensed activity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or entity may not offer or advertise services that require licensure as defined by this part, authorizing statutes, or applicable rules to the public without obtaining a valid license from the agency. A licenseholder may not advertise or hold out to the public that he or she holds a license for other than that for which he or she actually holds the license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation or maintenance of an unlicensed provider or the performance of any services that require licensure without proper licensure is a violation of this part and authorizing statutes. Unlicensed activity constitutes harm that materially affects the health, safety, and welfare of clients. The agency or any state attorney may, in addition to other remedies provided in this part, bring an action for an injunction to restrain such violation, or to enjoin the future operation or maintenance of the unlicensed provider or the performance of any services in violation of this part and authorizing statutes, until compliance with this part, authorizing statutes, and agency rules has been demonstrated to the satisfaction of the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person or entity to own, operate, or maintain an unlicensed provider. If after receiving notification from the agency, such person or entity fails to cease operation and apply for a license under this part and authorizing statutes, the person or entity shall be subject to penalties as prescribed by authorizing statutes and applicable rules. Each day of continued operation is a separate offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity that fails to cease operation after agency notification may be fined $1,000 for each day of noncompliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a controlling interest or licensee has an interest in more than one provider and fails to license a provider rendering services that require licensure, the agency may revoke all licenses and impose actions under s. 408.814 and a fine of $1,000 per day, unless otherwise specified by authorizing statutes, against each licensee until such time as the appropriate license is obtained for the unlicensed operation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to granting injunctive relief pursuant to subsection (2), if the agency determines that a person or entity is operating or maintaining a provider without obtaining a license and determines that a condition exists that poses a threat to the health, safety, or welfare of a client of the provider, the person or entity is subject to the same actions and fines imposed against a licensee as specified in this part, authorizing statutes, and agency rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person aware of the operation of an unlicensed provider must report that provider to the agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2006-192.</History></Section>