<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.50" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prospective payment arrangements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospitals as defined in s. 395.002, and health insurers regulated pursuant to parts VI and VII of chapter 627, shall establish prospective payment arrangements that provide hospitals with financial incentives to contain costs. Each hospital shall enter into a rate agreement with each health insurer which represents 10 percent or more of the private-pay patients of the hospital to establish a prospective payment arrangement. Hospitals and health insurers regulated pursuant to this section shall report annually the results of each specific prospective payment arrangement adopted by each hospital and health insurer to the board. The agency shall report a health insurer’s failure to comply to the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission, which shall take into account the failure by the health insurer to comply in conjunction with its approval authority under s. 627.410. The agency shall adopt any rules necessary to carry out its responsibilities required by this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prospective payment system established pursuant to this section shall include, at a minimum, the following elements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A maximum allowable payment amount established for individual hospital products, services, patient diagnoses, patient day, patient admission, or per insured, or any combination thereof, which is preset at the beginning of the budget year of the hospital and fixed for the entirety of that budget year, except when extenuating and unusual circumstances acceptable to the department warrant renegotiation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Timely payment to the hospital by the insurer or the insured, or both, of the maximum allowable payment amount, as so negotiated by the insurer or group of insurers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acceptance by the hospital of the maximum payment amount as payment in full, which shall include any deductible or coinsurance provided for in the insurer’s benefit plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Utilization reviews for appropriateness of treatment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preadmission screening of nonemergency admissions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this section prohibits the inclusion of deductibles, coinsurance, or other cost containment provisions in any health insurance policy.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 81, ch. 92-33; s. 438, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>