<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inspections and audits; violations; penalties; fines; enforcement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may inspect and audit books and records of individual or corporate ownership, including books and records of related organizations with which a health care provider or a health care facility had transactions, for compliance with this chapter. Upon presentation of a written request for inspection to a health care provider or a health care facility by the agency or its staff, the health care provider or the health care facility shall make available to the agency or its staff for inspection, copying, and review all books and records relevant to the determination of whether the health care provider or the health care facility has complied with this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any health care facility that refuses to file a report, fails to timely file a report, files a false report, or files an incomplete report and upon notification fails to timely file a complete report required under s. 408.061; that violates this section, s. 408.061, or s. 408.20, or rule adopted thereunder; or that fails to provide documents or records requested by the agency under this chapter shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $1,000 per day for each day in violation, to be imposed and collected by the agency. Pursuant to rules adopted by the agency, the agency may, upon a showing of good cause, grant a one-time extension of any deadline for a health care facility to timely file a report as required by this section, s. 408.061, or s. 408.20.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any health care provider that refuses to file a report, fails to timely file a report, files a false report, or files an incomplete report and upon notification fails to timely file a complete report required under s. 408.061; that violates this section, s. 408.061, or s. 408.20, or rule adopted thereunder; or that fails to provide documents or records requested by the agency under this chapter shall be referred to the appropriate licensing board which shall take appropriate action against the health care provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a health insurer does not comply with the requirements of s. 408.061, the agency shall report a health insurer’s failure to comply to the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission, which shall take into account the failure by the health insurer to comply in conjunction with its approval authority under s. 627.410. The agency shall adopt any rules necessary to carry out its responsibilities required by this subsection.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to file, failure to timely file, or filing false or incomplete reports or other information required to be filed under the provisions of this chapter, failure to pay or failure to timely pay any assessment authorized to be collected by the agency, or violation of any other provision of this chapter or lawfully entered order of the agency or rule adopted under this chapter, shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $1,000 a day for each day in violation, to be fixed, imposed, and collected by the agency. Each day in violation shall be considered a separate offense.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, when a hospital alleges that a factual determination made by the agency is incorrect, the burden of proof shall be on the hospital to demonstrate that such determination is, in light of the total record, not supported by a preponderance of the evidence. The burden of proof remains with the hospital in all cases involving administrative agency action.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 73, ch. 92-33; s. 77, ch. 92-289; s. 16, ch. 93-129; s. 23, ch. 95-146; s. 15, ch. 98-89; s. 1, ch. 98-120; s. 45, ch. 2000-153; s. 436, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>