<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0408.063" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Dissemination of health care information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, relying on data collected pursuant to this chapter, shall establish a reliable, timely, and consistent information system that distributes information and serves as the basis for the agency’s public education programs. The agency shall seek advice from consumers, health care purchasers, health care providers, health care facilities, health insurers, and local health councils in the development and implementation of its information system. Whenever appropriate, the agency shall use the local health councils for the dissemination of information and education of the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall publish and disseminate information to the public which will enhance informed decisionmaking in the selection of health care providers, facilities, and services. Such publications may identify average charges for specified services, lengths of stay associated with established diagnostic groups, readmission rates, mortality rates, recommended guidelines for selection and use of health care providers, health care facilities, and health care services, and such other information as the agency deems appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall educate consumers and health care purchasers by conducting or sponsoring seminars and other educational programs at locations throughout the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall serve as a clearinghouse for information concerning:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Innovations in the delivery of health care services and the enhancement of competition in the health care market.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Federal and state legislative initiatives affecting the private health care delivery system and governmental health care programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Health promotion, illness prevention, and wellness in the work setting.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall publish annually a comprehensive report of state health expenditures. The report shall identify:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The contribution of health care dollars made by all payors.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The dollars expended by type of health care service in Florida.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The staff of the agency may conduct or sponsor consumer information and education seminars at locations throughout the state and may hold public hearings to solicit consumer concerns or complaints relating to health care costs and make recommendations to the agency for study, action, or investigation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 70, ch. 92-33; s. 13, ch. 98-89.</History></Section>