<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0958.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Judicial disposition of youthful offenders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may sentence as a youthful offender any person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is at least 18 years of age or who has been transferred for prosecution to the criminal division of the circuit court pursuant to chapter 985;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who is found guilty of or who has tendered, and the court has accepted, a plea of nolo contendere or guilty to a crime that is, under the laws of this state, a felony if the offender is younger than 21 years of age at the time sentence is imposed; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has not previously been classified as a youthful offender under the provisions of this act; however, a person who has been found guilty of a capital or life felony may not be sentenced as a youthful offender under this act.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of other criminal penalties authorized by law and notwithstanding any imposition of consecutive sentences, the court shall dispose of the criminal case as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may place a youthful offender under supervision on probation or in a community control program, with or without an adjudication of guilt, under such conditions as the court may lawfully impose for a period of not more than 6 years. Such period of supervision may not exceed the maximum sentence for the offense for which the youthful offender was found guilty.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may impose a period of incarceration as a condition of probation or community control, which period of incarceration shall be served in a county facility, a department probation and restitution center, or a community residential facility that is owned and operated by any public or private entity providing such services. A youthful offender may not be required to serve a period of incarceration in a community correctional center as defined in s. 944.026. Admission to a department facility or center shall be contingent upon the availability of bed space and shall take into account the purpose and function of such facility or center. Placement in such a facility or center may not exceed 364 days.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may impose a split sentence whereby the youthful offender is to be placed on probation or community control upon completion of any specified period of incarceration; however, if the incarceration period is to be served in a department facility other than a probation and restitution center or community residential facility, such period shall be for not less than 1 year or more than 4 years. The period of probation or community control shall commence immediately upon the release of the youthful offender from incarceration. The period of incarceration imposed or served and the period of probation or community control, when added together, may not exceed 6 years.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may commit the youthful offender to the custody of the department for a period of not more than 6 years, provided that any such commitment may not exceed the maximum sentence for the offense for which the youthful offender has been convicted. Successful participation in the youthful offender program by an offender who is sentenced as a youthful offender by the court pursuant to this section, or is classified as such by the department, may result in a recommendation to the court, by the department, for a modification or early termination of probation, community control, or the sentence at any time prior to the scheduled expiration of such term. The department shall adopt rules defining criteria for successful participation in the youthful offender program which shall include program participation, academic and vocational training, and satisfactory adjustment. When a modification of the sentence results in the reduction of a term of incarceration, the court may impose a term of probation or community control which, when added to the term of incarceration, may not exceed the original sentence imposed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section shall not be used to impose a greater sentence than the permissible sentence range as established by the Criminal Punishment Code pursuant to chapter 921 unless reasons are explained in writing by the trial court judge which reasonably justify departure. A sentence imposed outside of the code is subject to appeal pursuant to s. 924.06 or s. 924.07.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Due to severe prison overcrowding, the Legislature declares the construction of a basic training program facility is necessary to aid in alleviating an emergency situation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall provide a special training program for staff selected for the basic training program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 78-84; s. 1, ch. 80-321; s. 20, ch. 85-288; s. 1, ch. 87-58; s. 3, ch. 87-110; s. 7, ch. 90-208; s. 11, ch. 90-211; s. 11, ch. 91-225; s. 8, ch. 93-406; s. 101, ch. 94-209; s. 22, ch. 96-312; s. 31, ch. 97-94; s. 36, ch. 97-194; s. 21, ch. 98-204; s. 61, ch. 98-280; s. 7, ch. 2008-250.</History></Section>