<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0958.09" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Extension of limits of confinement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules permitting the extension of the limits of the place of confinement of a youthful offender when there is reasonable cause to believe that the youthful offender will honor the trust placed in him or her. The department may authorize a youthful offender, under prescribed conditions and following investigation and approval by the department which shall maintain a written record of such action, to leave the place of his or her confinement for a prescribed period of time:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To visit a designated place or places for the purpose of visiting a dying relative, attending the funeral of a relative, or arranging for employment or for a suitable residence for use when released; to otherwise aid in the correction of the youthful offender; or for another compelling reason consistent with the public interest and to return to the same or another institution or facility designated by the department; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To work at paid employment, participate in an educational or a training program, or voluntarily serve a public or nonprofit agency or a public service program in the community; provided, that the youthful offender shall be confined except during the hours of his or her employment, education, training, or service and while traveling thereto and therefrom.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules as to the eligibility of youthful offenders for such extension of confinement, the disbursement of any earnings of youthful offenders, or the entering into of agreements between the department and any municipal, county, or federal agency for the housing of youthful offenders in a local place of confinement. However, no youthful offender convicted of sexual battery pursuant to s. 794.011 is eligible for any extension of the limits of confinement under this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The willful failure of a youthful offender to remain within the extended limits of confinement or to return within the time prescribed to the place of confinement designated by the department is an escape from the custody of the department and a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided by s. 775.082.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may contract with other public and private agencies for the confinement, treatment, counseling, aftercare, or community supervision of youthful offenders when consistent with the youthful offenders’ welfare and the interest of society.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall document and account for all forms for disciplinary reports for inmates placed on extended limits of confinement, which reports shall include, but not be limited to, all violations of rules of conduct, the rule or rules violated, the nature of punishment administered, the authority ordering such punishment, and the duration of time during which the inmate was subjected to confinement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to levy fines only through disciplinary reports and only against inmates placed on extended limits of confinement. Major and minor infractions and their respective punishments for inmates placed on extended limits of confinement shall be defined by the rules of the department, except that any fine shall not exceed $50 for each infraction deemed to be minor and $100 for each infraction deemed to be major. Such fines shall be deposited in the General Revenue Fund, and a receipt shall be given to the inmate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the chief correctional officer determines that a fine would be an appropriate punishment for a violation of the rules of the department, both the determination of guilt and the amount of the fine shall be determined by the disciplinary committee pursuant to the method prescribed in s. 944.28(2)(c).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall develop rules defining the policies and procedures for the administering of such fines.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 78-84; s. 4, ch. 83-274; s. 21, ch. 85-288; s. 24, ch. 93-156; s. 103, ch. 94-209; s. 1705, ch. 97-102; s. 13, ch. 2003-179.</History></Section>