<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0958.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Participation in certain activities required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A youthful offender shall be required to participate in work assignments, and in career, academic, counseling, and other rehabilitative programs in accordance with this section, including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All youthful offenders may be required, as appropriate, to participate in:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reception and orientation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation, needs assessment, and classification.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Educational programs.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Career and job training.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Life and socialization skills training, including anger/aggression control.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prerelease orientation and planning.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appropriate transition services.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements in paragraph (a), the department shall make available:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Religious services and counseling.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Social services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substance abuse treatment and counseling.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Psychological and psychiatric services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Library services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical and dental health care.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Athletic, recreational, and leisure time activities.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Mail and visiting privileges.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Income derived by a youthful offender from participation in such activities may be used, in part, to defray a portion of the costs of his or her incarceration or supervision; to satisfy preexisting obligations; to pay fines, counseling fees, or other costs lawfully imposed; or to pay restitution to the victim of the crime for which the youthful offender has been convicted in an amount determined by the sentencing court. Any such income not used for such reasons or not used as provided in s. 946.513 or s. 958.09 shall be placed in a bank account for use by the youthful offender upon his or her release.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A comprehensive transition and postrelease plan shall be developed for the youthful offender by a team consisting of a transition assistance officer, a classification officer, an educational representative, a health services administrator, a probation and parole officer, and the youthful offender.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community partnerships shall be developed by the department to provide postrelease community resources. The department shall develop partnerships with entities that include, but are not limited to, state agencies, community health agencies, private agencies, and school systems.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If supervision of the youthful offender after release from incarceration is required, this may be accomplished in a residential or nonresidential program or intensive day treatment or through supervision by a correctional probation officer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 78-84; s. 23, ch. 85-288; s. 55, ch. 91-110; s. 105, ch. 94-209; s. 1706, ch. 97-102; s. 326, ch. 99-8; s. 66, ch. 2004-357; s. 9, ch. 2008-250.</History></Section>