<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0704.04" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Judicial remedy and compensation to servient owner.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the owner or owners of such lands across which a statutory way of necessity under s. 704.01(2) is claimed, exclusive of the common-law right, objects or refuses to permit the use of such way under the conditions set forth herein or until she or he receives compensation therefor, either party or the board of county commissioners of such county may file suit in the circuit court of the county wherein the land is located in order to determine if the claim for said easement exists, and the amount of compensation to which said party is entitled for use of such easement. When said easement is awarded to the owner of the dominant tenement, it shall be in compliance with s. 704.01(2) and shall exist so long as such easement is reasonably necessary. The court, in its discretion, shall determine all questions, including the type, duration, extent, and location of the easement, the amount of compensation, and the attorney’s fees and costs to be awarded to either party for unreasonable refusal to comply with the provisions of s. 704.01(2), provided that if either of said parties so requests in her or his original pleadings, the amount of compensation may be determined by a jury trial. The easement shall date from the time the award is paid.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 28070, 1953; s. 2, ch. 91-117; s. 789, ch. 97-102; ss. 3, 4, ch. 2005-214.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 4, ch. 2005-214, reenacted s. 704.04 as it existed prior to amendment by s. 3, ch. 2005-214, “[e]ffective only if a court determines that [s.] 704.04 . . . , as amended by [s. 3, ch. 2005-214], is unconstitutional and such determination is upheld on appeal,” to read:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">704.04 Judicial remedy and compensation to servient owner.</Font>—When the owner or owners of such lands across which a statutory way of necessity under s. 704.01(2) is claimed, exclusive of the common-law right, objects or refuses to permit the use of such way under the conditions set forth herein or until she or he receives compensation therefor, either party or the board of county commissioners of such county may file suit in the circuit court of the county wherein the land is located in order to determine if the claim for said easement exists, and the amount of compensation to which said party is entitled for use of such easement. Where said easement is awarded to the owner of the dominant tenement, it shall be in compliance with s. 704.01(2) and shall exist so long as such easement is reasonably necessary for the purposes stated herein. The court, in its discretion, shall determine all questions, including the type, duration, extent, and location of the easement, the amount of compensation, and the attorney’s fees and costs to be awarded to either party for unreasonable refusal to comply with the provisions of s. 704.01(2) provided that if either of said parties so requests in her or his original pleadings, the amount of compensation may be determined by a jury trial. The easement shall date from the time the award is paid.</Text></Note></Section>