<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0704.01" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Common-law and statutory easements defined and determined.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">IMPLIED GRANT OF WAY OF NECESSITY.<EmDash />The common-law rule of an implied grant of a way of necessity is hereby recognized, specifically adopted, and clarified. Such an implied grant exists where a person has heretofore granted or hereafter grants lands to which there is no accessible right-of-way except over her or his land, or has heretofore retained or hereafter retains land which is inaccessible except over the land which the person conveys. In such instances a right-of-way is presumed to have been granted or reserved. Such an implied grant or easement in lands or estates exists where there is no other reasonable and practicable way of egress, or ingress and same is reasonably necessary for the beneficial use or enjoyment of the part granted or reserved. An implied grant arises only where a unity of title exists from a common source other than the original grant from the state or United States; provided, however, that where there is a common source of title subsequent to the original grant from the state or United States, the right of the dominant tenement shall not be terminated if title of either the dominant or servient tenement has been or should be transferred for nonpayment of taxes either by foreclosure, reversion, or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Reference Number="1" /><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">STATUTORY WAY OF NECESSITY EXCLUSIVE OF COMMON-LAW RIGHT.<EmDash />Based on public policy, convenience, and necessity, a statutory way of necessity exclusive of any common-law right exists when any land, including land formed by accretion, reliction, or other naturally occurring processes, or portion thereof, which is being used or is desired to be used for a dwelling or dwellings or for agricultural or for timber raising or cutting or stockraising purposes is shut off or hemmed in by lands, fencing, or other improvements by other persons so that no practicable route of egress or ingress is available therefrom to the nearest practicable public or private road in which the landlocked owner has vested easement rights. The owner or tenant thereof, or anyone in their behalf, lawfully may use and maintain an easement for persons, vehicles, stock, franchised cable television service, and any utility service, including, but not limited to, water, wastewater, reclaimed water, natural gas, electricity, and telephone service, over, under, through, and upon the lands which lie between the said shut-off or hemmed-in lands and such public or private road by means of the nearest practical route, considering the use to which said lands are being put; and the use thereof, as aforesaid, shall not constitute a trespass; nor shall the party thus using the same be liable in damages for the use thereof, provided that such easement shall be used only in an orderly and proper manner.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 7326, 1917; RGS 4999; CGL 7088; s. 1, ch. 28070, 1953; s. 220, ch. 77-104; s. 1, ch. 91-117; s. 788, ch. 97-102; ss. 1, 2, ch. 2005-214.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 2, ch. 2005-214, reenacted subsection (2) as it existed prior to amendment by s. 1, ch. 2005-214, “[e]ffective only if a court determines that subsection (2) . . . , as amended by [s. 1, ch. 2005-214], is unconstitutional and such determination is upheld on appeal,” to read:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) STATUTORY WAY OF NECESSITY EXCLUSIVE OF COMMON-LAW RIGHT.—Based on public policy, convenience, and necessity, a statutory way of necessity exclusive of any common-law right exists when any land or portion thereof outside any municipality which is being used or desired to be used for a dwelling or dwellings or for agricultural or for timber raising or cutting or stockraising purposes shall be shut off or hemmed in by lands, fencing, or other improvements of other persons so that no practicable route of egress or ingress shall be available therefrom to the nearest practicable public or private road. The owner or tenant thereof, or anyone in their behalf, lawfully may use and maintain an easement for persons, vehicles, stock, franchised cable television service, and any utility service, including, but not limited to, water, wastewater, reclaimed water, natural gas, electricity, and telephone service, over, under, through, and upon the lands which lie between the said shut-off or hemmed-in lands and such public or private road by means of the nearest practical route, considering the use to which said lands are being put; and the use thereof, as aforesaid, shall not constitute a trespass; nor shall the party thus using the same be liable in damages for the use thereof; provided that such easement shall be used only in an orderly and proper manner.</Text></Note></Section>