<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0704.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Solar easements; creation; remedies.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Easements obtained for the purpose of maintaining exposure of a solar energy device shall be created in writing and shall be subject to being recorded and indexed in the same manner as any other instrument affecting the title to real property. Solar easements may be preserved and protected from extinguishment by the filing of a notice in the form and in accordance with the provisions set forth in ss. 712.05 and 712.06.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to fulfilling the requirements of law relating to conveyance of interests in land, the instrument creating the solar easement shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the properties, servient and dominant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vertical and horizontal angles, expressed in degrees, at which the solar easement extends over the real property subject to the solar easement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of where the easement falls across the servient property in relation to existing boundaries and various setbacks established by the local zoning authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The point on the dominant property from where the angles describing the solar easement are to be measured.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terms or conditions under which the solar easement is granted or will terminate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any provisions for compensation of the owner of the property benefiting from the solar easement in the event of interference with the enjoyment of the solar easement or compensation of the owner of the property subject to the solar easement for maintaining the solar easement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No structure under construction on October 1, 1978, shall be subject to any solar easement recorded pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 3, ch. 78-309.</History></Section>