<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0500.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Food deemed misbranded.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A food is deemed to be misbranded:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its labeling is false or misleading in any particular; however, corn meal shall not be considered misbranded because of its being labeled “Water Ground,” where such corn meal so labeled has been ground on rocks having a diameter of not less than 42 inches and which revolve during the grinding of same at a speed not greater than 186 revolutions per minute.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is offered for sale under the name of another food.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is an imitation of another food, unless its label bears, in type of uniform size and prominence, the words “imitation” and, immediately thereafter, the name of the food imitated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its container is so made, formed, or filled as to be misleading.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If in package form, unless it bears a label containing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or numerical count; however, under this subparagraph reasonable variations shall be permitted, and exemptions as to small packages shall be established, by regulations prescribed by the department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any word, statement, or other information required by or under authority of this chapter to appear on the label or labeling is not prominently placed thereon with such conspicuousness, as compared with other words, statements, designs, or devices, in the labeling, and in such terms as to render it likely to be read and understood by the ordinary individual under customary conditions of purchase and use.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it purports to be or is represented as a food for which a definition and standard of identity has been prescribed by statute or by rules as provided by s. 500.09, unless:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It conforms to such definition and standard; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its label bears the name of the food specified in the definition and standard and, insofar as may be required by such rules, the common names of optional ingredients (other than spices, flavoring, and coloring) present in such food.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it purports to be or is represented as:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A food for which a standard of quality has been prescribed by rules as provided by s. 500.09 and its quality falls below such standard unless its label bears, in such manner and form as such rules specify, a statement that it falls below such standard; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A food for which a standard or standards of fill of container have been prescribed by rule as provided by s. 500.09 and it falls below the standard of fill of container applicable thereto, unless its label bears, in such manner and form as such rules specify, a statement that it falls below such standard.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless its label bears:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common or usual name of the food, if any; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is fabricated from two or more ingredients, the common or usual name of each ingredient and, if the food purports to be a beverage containing vegetable or fruit juice, a statement placed with appropriate prominence on the information panel specifying the total percentage of such vegetable or fruit juice contained in the food; except that spices, flavorings, and color additives not required to be certified under 21 U.S.C. s. 379(e), other than those sold as such, may be designated as spices, flavorings, and color additives, without naming each; provided, that, to the extent that compliance with this paragraph is impractical or results in deception or unfair competition, exemptions shall be established by rules adopted by the department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it purports to be or is represented for special dietary uses, unless its label bears such information concerning its vitamin, mineral, and other dietary properties as the department determines to be, and by regulations prescribes as, necessary in order to fully inform purchasers as to its value for such uses.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it bears or contains any artificial flavoring, artificial coloring, or chemical preservative, unless it bears labeling stating that fact; provided that, to the extent that compliance with the requirements of this paragraph is impracticable, exemptions shall be established by regulations promulgated by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a fresh fruit or vegetable or a package of honey or bee pollen not labeled in accordance with the provisions of s. 504.012 or not otherwise labeled in such a manner as to indicate to an ultimate purchaser the country of origin.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is offered for sale and its label or labeling does not comply with the requirements of 21 U.S.C. s. 343(q) pertaining to nutrition information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is offered for sale and its label or labeling does not comply with the requirements of 21 U.S.C. s. 343(r) pertaining to nutritional content claims and health claims.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is bottled water and its label bears a corporate name, brand name, or trademark containing the word “spring,” “springs,” “well,” “artesian well,” “natural,” or any derivative of those words without stating on the label the source of the water in typeface at least equal to the size of the typeface of the corporate name, brand name, or trademark, if the source of the water is different from the source indicated in the corporate name, brand name, or trademark.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is an animal product that fails to have directly thereon or on its container the official inspection legend as required by the United States Department of Agriculture and, unrestricted by any other provision of this section, such other information as the department requires to ensure that it shall not have false or misleading labeling and that the public is informed of the manner of handling required to maintain the product in a wholesome condition.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When soft drinks are offered for sale in sanitary returnable or nonreturnable containers, sealed or securely capped, impervious to contamination by leakage or contact with foreign substances, and when the trade name, net content, and declaration of artificial flavor or color, when used, appear on the principal display panel, which may be the cap, crown, lid, or side of the container of such drinks, and when the manufacturer, at least once every year and oftener when required by the department, files with the department an affidavit stating the trade names of such drinks manufactured by him or her and the territorial limits in the state within which such drinks are offered for sale, the provisions of this chapter requiring additional labeling and branding of such drinks do not apply. However, nothing in this subsection shall in any manner otherwise restrict, modify, or impair the jurisdiction and authority of the department over such drinks as food products and the conditions pertaining to the manufacture of same.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 19656, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(674); s. 1, ch. 26723, 1951; s. 1, ch. 28269, 1953; s. 30, ch. 63-572; s. 1, ch. 69-26; ss. 14, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 80-76; s. 1, ch. 83-14; s. 7, ch. 87-388; s. 6, ch. 92-290; s. 98, ch. 92-291; s. 8, ch. 94-180; s. 603, ch. 97-103; s. 18, ch. 97-220; s. 10, ch. 98-396.</History></Section>