<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0500.459" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Water vending machines.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />It is the intent of the Legislature to protect the public health through licensing and establishing standards for water vending machines to ensure that consumers obtaining water through such means are given appropriate information as to the nature of such water and that such consumers are assured that the water meets acceptable standards for human consumption.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sanitized” means treated in conformity with 21 C.F.R. s. 110.3 (1996).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vended water” means water dispensed by means of a water vending machine.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Water vending machine” means a self-service device that, upon insertion of a coin or token or upon receipt of payment by other means, dispenses a serving of water into a container.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Water vending machine operator” means a person who owns, leases, or manages, or is otherwise responsible for, the operation of a water vending machine.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PERMITTING REQUIREMENTS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person or public body that establishes, maintains, or operates any water vending machine in the state must secure an operating permit from the department each year.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for an operating permit must be made in writing to the department on forms provided by the department and must be accompanied by a fee as provided in subsection (4). The application must state the location of each water vending machine, the source of the water to be vended, the treatment the water will receive prior to being vended, and any other information considered necessary by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FEES.<EmDash />A person seeking an operating permit must pay the department a fee not exceeding $200, which fee shall be set by rule of the department. Such fees shall be deposited in the General Inspection Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OPERATING STANDARDS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A water vending machine operator must obtain a permit prior to operating any water vending machine.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each water vending machine must be located indoors or otherwise protected against tampering and vandalism and must be located in an area that can be maintained in a clean condition and in a manner that avoids insect and rodent harborage. The floor upon which the water vending machine is located should be smooth and of cleanable construction.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The source of water supply must be an approved public water system.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each water vending machine must have a backflow prevention device that conforms with the applicable provision of the Florida Building Code and an adequate system for collecting and handling dripping, spillage, and overflow of water.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All parts and surfaces of a water vending machine with which water comes into contact must be made of nontoxic, corrosion-resistant, nonabsorbent material capable of withstanding repeated cleaning and sanitizing treatments.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each water vending machine must be maintained in a clean and sanitary condition, free from rust, dirt, and vermin.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vended water must receive treatment and postdisinfection according to approved methods established by rule of the department. Activated carbon, if used, must comply with specifications for granular activated carbon used in water treatment applications as established by rule of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vended water may not be described as “purified water” unless the water conforms to the definition of that term. Further, a water vending machine operator must not claim that the vended water has medicinal or health-giving properties and must not describe any vended water as “spring water.”</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operator shall place on each water vending machine, in a position clearly visible to customers, the following information: the name and address of the operator; the operating permit number; the fact that the water is obtained from a public water supply; the method of treatment used; the method of postdisinfection used; and a local or toll-free telephone number that may be called for obtaining further information, reporting problems, or making complaints.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DUTIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement the provisions of this section conferring duties upon it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, considering the source of water and the treatment process provided by the water vending machine, the department finds that the vended water will not meet the primary and secondary drinking water quality standards as provided for in department rules, the permit shall be denied. Specific technical reasons for the denial shall be given by the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The water from each water vending machine shall be sampled and tested for compliance with the water quality standards established by rule of the department at regular intervals established by rule of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The vended water from each water vending machine using silver-impregnated carbon filters in the treatment process shall be sampled for silver at regular intervals established by rule of the department.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall order a water vending machine operator to discontinue the operation of any water vending machine the condition of which represents a threat to the life or health of any person, or when the vended water does not meet the standards provided in this section. Such water vending machine must not be returned to use or be used until the department determines that the condition that caused the discontinuance of operation no longer exists.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PENALTIES.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke a permit if it finds that there has been a substantial failure to comply with this section or rules adopted under this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who operates a water vending machine without first obtaining an operating permit as required by subsection (3), who operates a water vending machine in violation of an order to discontinue operation, or who maintains or operates a water vending machine after revocation of the operating permit is guilty of a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 84-118; s. 1, ch. 85-65; s. 40, ch. 85-81; s. 61, ch. 91-224; s. 30, ch. 91-297; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 36, ch. 92-78; s. 3, ch. 92-180; s. 31, ch. 94-180; s. 24, ch. 97-220; s. 170, ch. 98-200; s. 32, ch. 98-287; s. 128, ch. 2000-141; s. 16, ch. 2000-308; s. 35, ch. 2001-186; s. 4, ch. 2001-372.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 381.295; s. 381.0071.</Text></Note></Section>