<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0500.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Standards of enrichment for grain products; definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 500.301-500.306, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enrichment” means the replacement of those essential nutrients removed in the processing and refining of grain products. The nutrients specified in state bread and cereal enrichment laws and stipulated in federal standards of identity are iron, thiamine, riboflavin, and niacin.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Federal standard of enrichment” means the definition and standard of identity for a food established pursuant to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and acts amendatory thereof.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State standard” means the rules adopted by this state and now in effect under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and Fair Packaging and Labeling Act as amended in 21 U.S.C. ss. 301 et seq.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Wheat flour” includes, and is limited to, the following foods made from wheat, as defined in federal standards: flour (white flour, wheat flour, plain flour); enriched flour; bromated flour; enriched bromated flour; durum flour; self-rising flour (self-rising white flour, self-rising wheat flour); enriched self-rising flour; phosphated flour (phosphated white flour, phosphated wheat flour); instantized flours (instant blending flours, quick mixing flours); whole wheat flour (graham flour, entire wheat flour); bromated whole wheat flour; whole durum wheat flour; crushed wheat (coarse ground wheat); cracked wheat; farina; enriched farina; and semolina.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Enriched flour” includes, and is limited to, the following kinds of wheat flour, as defined in federal standards for enrichment: enriched flour; enriched bromated flour; enriched self-rising flour (including instantized, instant blending, and quick-mixing forms of each of the foregoing); enriched farina; and any other enriched wheat flour for which a federal standard for enrichment is established after January 1, 1975.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corn flour and related products” includes, but is not limited to, foods made from corn meeting the standards for white cornmeal, yellow cornmeal, bolted white cornmeal, bolted yellow cornmeal, degerminated white cornmeal, degermed white cornmeal, degerminated yellow cornmeal, degermed yellow cornmeal, self-rising white cornmeal, self-rising yellow cornmeal, white corn flour, yellow corn flour, grits, corn grits, hominy grits, yellow grits, yellow corn grits, yellow hominy grits, quick grits, quick-cooking grits, and instant grits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rice” includes the following kinds of products defined in the federal standards: all forms of milled rice, except rice coated with talc and glucose and known as coated rice, to which nutrients may be added.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“White bread” includes, and is limited to, any bread made with wheat flour, whether baked in a pan or on a hearth or screen, which is commonly known or usually represented as white bread.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rolls” includes, but is not limited to, rolls and buns of the semibread type, such as soft rolls, hamburger rolls, hot dog rolls, Parker House rolls, and hard rolls.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Macaroni products” means, and is limited to, foods that are prepared by drying formed units of dough made from semolina, durum flour, or farina, or any combination of two or more of these, and water and with or without one or more of the ingredients as identified by the federal Food and Drug Administration. These products include macaroni, spaghetti, and vermicelli.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Noodle products” includes, and is limited to, foods that are prepared by drying formed units of dough made from semolina, durum flour, or farina, or any combination of two or more of these, with liquid eggs, frozen eggs, dried eggs, egg yolks, frozen yolks, or dried yolks, or any combination of two or more of these, with or without water and with or without one or more of the optional ingredients identified by the federal Food and Drug Administration. These products include noodles, egg noodles, egg macaroni, egg spaghetti, and egg vermicelli.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sell at retail,” if used with reference to a food intended for human consumption, means sale of the food to a purchaser for her or his personal, family, or household consumption, and not for resale.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-41; s. 27, ch. 82-225; s. 43, ch. 83-216; s. 23, ch. 87-388; s. 21, ch. 94-180; s. 608, ch. 97-103.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 500.500.</Text></Note></Section>