<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0500.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Food deemed adulterated.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A food is deemed to be adulterated:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it bears or contains any poisonous or deleterious substance which may render it injurious to health; but in case the substance is not an added substance such food shall not be considered adulterated under this clause if the quantity of such substance in such food does not ordinarily render it injurious to health;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it bears or contains any added poisonous or added deleterious substance, other than one which is a pesticide chemical in or on a raw agricultural commodity; a food additive; or a color additive, which is unsafe within the meaning of s. 500.13(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a raw agricultural commodity and it bears or contains a pesticide chemical which is unsafe within the meaning of 21 U.S.C. s. 346(a) or s. 500.13(1);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is or it bears or contains, any food additive which is unsafe within the meaning of 21 U.S.C. s. 348 or s. 500.13(1); provided that where a pesticide chemical has been used in or on a raw agricultural commodity in conformity with an exemption granted or tolerance prescribed under 21 U.S.C. s. 346 or s. 500.13(1), and such raw agricultural commodity has been subjected to processing such as canning, cooking, freezing, dehydrating, or milling, the residue of such pesticide chemical remaining in or on such processed food shall, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 500.13, and this paragraph, not be deemed unsafe if such residue in or on the raw agricultural commodity has been removed to the extent possible in good manufacturing practice, and the concentration of such residue in the processed food when ready to eat, is not greater than the tolerance prescribed for the raw agricultural commodity;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it consists in whole or in part of a diseased, contaminated, filthy, putrid, or decomposed substance, or if it is otherwise unfit for food;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it has been produced, prepared, packed, or held under insanitary conditions whereby it may become contaminated with filth, or whereby it may have been rendered diseased, unwholesome, or injurious to health;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is the product of a diseased animal or an animal which has died otherwise than by slaughter, or that has been fed upon the uncooked offal from a slaughterhouse; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its container is composed, in whole or in part, of any poisonous or deleterious substance which may render the contents injurious to health.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any valuable constituent has been in whole or in part omitted or abstracted therefrom;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any substance has been substituted wholly or in part therefor;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If damage or inferiority has been concealed in any manner; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any substance has been added thereto or mixed or packed therewith so as to increase its bulk or weight, or reduce its quality or strength or make it appear better or of greater value than it is.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is confectionery and it bears or contains any alcohol or nonnutritive article or substance except harmless coloring, harmless flavoring, harmless resinous glaze not in excess of 0.4 percent, harmless natural gum, and pectin; however, this subsection shall not apply to any chewing gum by reason of its containing harmless nonnutritive masticatory substances; to any confectionery by reason of its containing less than 0.5 percent by volume of alcohol derived solely from the use of flavoring extracts; or to any candy by reason of its containing more than 0.5 percent but less than 5 percent by volume of alcohol derived from any source, if such candy:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not sold to persons under 21 years of age;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is labeled with the following statement written in conspicuous print on the principal display panel of the package, or if sold in individual units, in a conspicuous manner adjacent to the product: “This product may not be sold to anyone under 21 years of age”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not sold in a form containing liquid alcohol so that it constitutes an alcoholic beverage under the Beverage Law; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is distributed directly to Florida consumers only from permanent facilities owned or controlled by the product’s manufacturer, or from a vendor licensed pursuant to chapter 565, or from a vendor approved by the Department of Business and Professional Regulation consistent with rules adopted by such department establishing standards for such vendors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is or bears or contains any color additive which is unsafe within the meaning of the federal act or s. 500.13.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 19656, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(678); s. 2, ch. 63-259; s. 1, ch. 87-269; s. 7, ch. 94-180; s. 200, ch. 94-218.</History></Section>