<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0500.148" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Reports and dissemination of information; confidentiality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information that is deemed confidential under 21 C.F.R. part 20.61, part 20.62, or part 20.88, or 5 U.S.C. s. 552(b), and that is provided to the department during a joint investigation concerning food safety or food-borne illness, as a requirement for conducting a federal-state contract or partnership activity, or for regulatory review, is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such confidential and exempt information may not be disclosed except under a final determination by the appropriate federal agency that the information is no longer entitled to protection or pursuant to an order of the court.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit the department from collecting, reporting, or illustrating the results of these investigations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publish reports summarizing all judgments and court orders that have been rendered under this chapter, including the nature of the charges and the disposition thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Disseminate any information regarding food which it considers necessary in the interest of public health and the protection of the consumer against fraud.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request of a food establishment, the department may issue a report certifying that the requesting food establishment currently complies with the sanitation and permitting requirements of this chapter and the rules adopted thereunder. Such certification may be requested for the purpose of exporting food to a foreign country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may recover the cost associated with carrying out the provisions of this subsection, the amount of which shall be set by rule.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 19656, 1939; CGL 1940 Supp. 4151(685); ss. 14, 19, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 3, 5, ch. 76-47; s. 427, ch. 77-147; s. 16, ch. 82-225; s. 12, ch. 87-388; s. 13, ch. 94-180; s. 27, ch. 2002-295; s. 1, ch. 2003-172; s. 137, ch. 2008-4; s. 1, ch. 2008-218.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 500.22.</Text></Note></Section>