<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0500.80" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Cottage food operations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cottage food operation must comply with the applicable requirements of this chapter but is exempt from the permitting requirements of s. 500.12 if the cottage food operation complies with this section and has annual gross sales of cottage food products that do not exceed $15,000.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this subsection, a cottage food operation’s annual gross sales include all sales of cottage food products at any location, regardless of the types of products sold or the number of persons involved in the operation. A cottage food operation must provide the department, upon request, with written documentation to verify the operation’s annual gross sales.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cottage food operation may not sell or offer for sale cottage food products over the Internet, by mail order, or at wholesale.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cottage food operation may only sell cottage food products which are prepackaged with a label affixed that contains the following information:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the cottage food operation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the cottage food product.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ingredients of the cottage food product, in descending order of predominance by weight.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The net weight or net volume of the cottage food product.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allergen information as specified by federal labeling requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any nutritional claim is made, appropriate nutritional information as specified by federal labeling requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement printed in at least 10-point type in a color that provides a clear contrast to the background of the label: “Made in a cottage food operation that is not subject to Florida’s food safety regulations.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cottage food operation may only sell cottage food products that it stores on the premises of the cottage food operation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not exempt a cottage food operation from any state or federal tax law, rule, regulation, or certificate that applies to all cottage food operations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cottage food operation must comply with all applicable county and municipal laws and ordinances regulating the preparation, processing, storage, and sale of cottage food products by a cottage food operation or from a person’s residence.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may investigate any complaint which alleges that a cottage food operation has violated an applicable provision of this chapter or rule adopted under this chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Only upon receipt of a complaint, the department’s authorized officer or employee may enter and inspect the premises of a cottage food operation to determine compliance with this chapter and department rules, as applicable. A cottage food operation’s refusal to permit the department’s authorized officer or employee entry to the premises or to conduct the inspection is grounds for disciplinary action pursuant to s. 500.121.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to a person operating under a food permit issued pursuant to s. 500.12.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 2011-205.</History>
</Section>