<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0721.02" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purposes.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes of this chapter are to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Give statutory recognition to real property timeshare plans and personal property timeshare plans in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish procedures for the creation, sale, exchange, promotion, and operation of timeshare plans.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide full and fair disclosure to the purchasers and prospective purchasers of timeshare plans.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require every timeshare plan offered for sale or created and existing in this state to be subjected to the provisions of this chapter.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require full and fair disclosure of terms, conditions, and services by resale service providers acting on behalf of consumer timeshare resellers or on behalf of prospective consumer resale purchasers, regardless of the business model employed by the resale service provider.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that the tourism industry in this state is a vital part of the state’s economy; that the sale, promotion, and use of timeshare plans is an emerging, dynamic segment of the tourism industry; that this segment of the tourism industry continues to grow, both in volume of sales and in complexity and variety of product structure; and that a uniform and consistent method of regulation is necessary in order to safeguard Florida’s tourism industry and the state’s economic well-being. In order to protect the quality of Florida timeshare plans and the consumers who purchase them, it is the intent of the Legislature that this chapter be interpreted broadly in order to encompass all forms of timeshare plans with a duration of at least 3 years that are created with respect to accommodations and facilities that are located in the state or that are offered for sale in the state as provided herein, including, but not limited to, condominiums, cooperatives, undivided interest campgrounds, cruise ships, vessels, houseboats, and recreational vehicles and other motor vehicles, and including vacation clubs, multisite vacation plans, and multiyear vacation and lodging certificates.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 1, ch. 83-264; s. 47, ch. 85-62; s. 3, ch. 91-236; s. 1, ch. 2004-279; s. 1, ch. 2012-76.</History>
</Section>