<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.55" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Multisite timeshare plan public offering statement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each filed public offering statement for a multisite timeshare plan shall contain the information required by this section and shall comply with the provisions of s. 721.07, except as otherwise provided therein. The division is authorized to provide by rule the method by which a developer must provide such information to the division. Each multisite timeshare plan filed public offering statement shall contain the following information and disclosures:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cover page containing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the multisite timeshare plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement in conspicuous type:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This public offering statement contains important matters to be considered in acquiring an interest in a multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club). The statements contained herein are only summary in nature. A prospective purchaser should refer to all references, accompanying exhibits, contract documents, and sales materials. The prospective purchaser should not rely upon oral representations as being correct and should refer to this document and accompanying exhibits for correct representations.</Font></Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary containing all statements required to be in conspicuous type in the public offering statement and in all exhibits thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate index for the contents and exhibits of the public offering statement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A text, which shall include, where applicable, the information and disclosures set forth in paragraphs (a)-(l).</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the multisite timeshare plan, including its term, legal structure, and form of ownership. For multisite timeshare plans in which the purchaser will receive a timeshare estate pursuant to s. 721.57 and for specific multisite timeshare plans, the description must also include the term of each component site within the multisite timeshare plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the structure and ownership of the reservation system together with a disclosure of the entity responsible for the operation of the reservation system. The description shall include the financial terms of any lease of the reservation system, if applicable. The developer shall not be required to disclose the financial terms of any such lease if such lease is prepaid in full for the term of the multisite timeshare plan or to any extent that neither purchasers nor the managing entity will be required to make payments for the continued use of the system following default by the developer or termination of the managing entity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the manner in which the reservation system operates. The description shall include a disclosure in compliance with the demand balancing standard set forth in s. 721.56(6) and shall describe the developer’s efforts to comply with same in creating the reservation system. The description shall also include a summary of the rules and regulations governing access to and use of the reservation system.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of describing the rules and regulations of the reservation system in the public offering statement text, the developer may attach the rules and regulations as a separate public offering statement exhibit, together with a cross-reference in the public offering statement text to such exhibit.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existence of and an explanation regarding any priority reservation features that affect a purchaser’s ability to make reservations for the use of a given accommodation or facility on a first come, first served basis, including, if applicable, the following statement in conspicuous type:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Component sites contained in the multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club) are subject to priority reservation features which may affect your ability to obtain a reservation.</Font></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary of the material rules and regulations, if any, other than the reservation system rules and regulations, affecting the purchaser’s use of each accommodation and facility at each component site.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the provisions of s. 721.552 and the timeshare instrument permit additions, substitutions, or deletions of accommodations or facilities, the public offering statement must include substantially the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Additions.<EmDash /></Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the basis upon which new accommodations and facilities may be added to the multisite timeshare plan; by whom additions may be made; and the anticipated effect of the addition of new accommodations and facilities upon the reservation system, its priorities, its rules and regulations, and the availability of existing accommodations and facilities.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer must disclose the existence of any cap on annual increases in common expenses of the multisite timeshare plan that would apply in the event that additional accommodations and facilities are made a part of the plan.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall also disclose any extent to which the purchasers of the multisite timeshare plan will have the right to consent to any proposed additions; if the purchasers do not have the right to consent, the developer must include the following disclosure in conspicuous type:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Accommodations and facilities may be added to this multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club) without the consent of the purchasers. The addition of accommodations and facilities to the plan may result in the addition of new purchasers who will compete with existing purchasers in making reservations for the use of available accommodations and facilities within the plan, and may also result in an increase in the annual assessment against purchasers for common expenses.</Font></Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Substitutions.<EmDash /></Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the basis upon which new accommodations and facilities may be substituted for existing accommodations and facilities of the multisite timeshare plan; by whom substitutions may be made; the basis upon which the determination may be made to cause such substitutions to occur; and any limitations upon the ability to cause substitutions to occur.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall also disclose any extent to which purchasers will have the right to consent to any proposed substitutions; if the purchasers do not have the right to consent, the developer must include the following disclosure in conspicuous type:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">New accommodations and facilities may be substituted for existing accommodations and facilities of this multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club) without the consent of the purchasers. The replacement accommodations and facilities may be located at a different place or may be of a different type or quality than the replaced accommodations and facilities. The substitution of accommodations and facilities may also result in an increase in the annual assessment against purchasers for common expenses.</Font></Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deletions.<EmDash />A description of any provision of the timeshare instrument governing deletion of accommodations or facilities from the multisite timeshare plan. If the timeshare instrument does not provide for business interruption insurance in the event of a casualty, or if it is unavailable, or if the instrument permits the developer, the managing entity, or the purchasers to elect not to reconstruct after casualty under certain circumstances or to secure replacement accommodations or facilities in lieu of reconstruction, the public offering statement must contain a disclosure that during the reconstruction, replacement, or acquisition period, or as a result of a decision not to reconstruct, purchasers of the plan may temporarily compete for available accommodations on a greater than one-to-one use right to use night requirement ratio.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the developer and the managing entity of the multisite timeshare plan, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of the developer; the developer’s business address; the number of years of experience the developer has in the timeshare, hotel, motel, travel, resort, or leisure industries; and a description of any pending lawsuit or judgment against the developer which is material to the plan. If there are no such pending lawsuits or judgments, there shall be a statement to that effect.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of the managing entity of the multisite timeshare plan; the managing entity’s business address; the number of years of experience the managing entity has in the timeshare, hotel, motel, travel, resort, or leisure industries; and a description of any lawsuit or judgment against the managing entity which is material to the plan. If there are no pending lawsuits or judgments, there shall be a statement to that effect. The description of the managing entity shall also include a description of the relationship among the managing entity of the multisite timeshare plan and the various component site managing entities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the purchaser’s liability for common expenses of the multisite timeshare plan, including the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the common expenses of the plan, including the method of allocation and assessment of such common expenses, whether component site common expenses and real estate taxes are included within the total common expense assessment of the multisite timeshare plan, and, if not, the manner in which timely payment of component site common expenses and real estate taxes shall be accomplished.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any cap imposed upon the level of common expenses payable by the purchaser. In no event shall the total common expense assessment for the multisite timeshare plan in a given calendar year exceed 125 percent of the total common expense assessment for the plan in the previous calendar year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the entity responsible for the determination of the common expenses of the multisite timeshare plan, as well as any entity which may increase the level of common expenses assessed against the purchaser at the multisite timeshare plan level.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the method used to collect common expenses, including the entity responsible for such collections, and the lien rights of any entity for nonpayment of common expenses. If the common expenses of any component site are collected by the managing entity of the multisite timeshare plan, a statement to that effect together with the identity and address of the escrow agent required by s. 721.56(3).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the purchaser will receive an interest in a nonspecific multisite timeshare plan, a statement that a multisite timeshare plan budget is attached to the public offering statement as an exhibit pursuant to paragraph (7)(c). The multisite timeshare plan budget shall comply with the provisions of s. 721.07(5)(t).</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the developer intends to guarantee the level of assessments for the multisite timeshare plan, such guarantee must be based upon a good faith estimate of the revenues and expenses of the multisite timeshare plan. The guarantee must include a description of the following:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific time period, measured in one or more calendar or fiscal years, during which the guarantee will be in effect.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the developer will pay all common expenses incurred in excess of the total revenues of the multisite timeshare plan, if the developer is to be excused from the payment of assessments during the guarantee period.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The level, expressed in total dollars, at which the developer guarantees the assessments. If the developer has reserved the right to extend or increase the guarantee level, a disclosure must be included to that effect.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If required under applicable law, the developer shall also disclose the following matters for each component site:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any limitation upon annual increases in common expenses;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existence of any bad debt or working capital reserve; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existence of any replacement or deferred maintenance reserve.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there are any restrictions upon the sale, transfer, conveyance, or leasing of an interest in a multisite timeshare plan, a description of the restrictions together with a statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The sale, lease, or transfer of interests in this multisite timeshare plan is restricted or controlled.</Font></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The purchase of an interest in a multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club) should be based upon its value as a vacation experience or for spending leisure time, and not considered for purposes of acquiring an appreciating investment or with an expectation that the interest may be resold.</Font></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the multisite timeshare plan provides purchasers with the opportunity to participate in an exchange program, a description of the name and address of the exchange company and the method by which a purchaser accesses the exchange program. In lieu of this requirement, the public offering statement text may contain a cross-reference to other provisions in the public offering statement or in an exhibit containing this information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of each component site, which description may be disclosed in a written, graphic, tabular, or other form approved by the division. The description of each component site shall include the following information:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of each component site.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of accommodations, timeshare interests, and timeshare periods, expressed in periods of 7-day use availability, committed to the multisite timeshare plan and available for use by purchasers.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each type of accommodation in terms of the number of bedrooms, bathrooms, sleeping capacity, and whether or not the accommodation contains a full kitchen. For purposes of this description, a full kitchen shall mean a kitchen having a minimum of a dishwasher, range, sink, oven, and refrigerator.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of facilities available for use by the purchaser at each component site, including the following:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The intended use of the facility, if not apparent from the description.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any user fees associated with a purchaser’s use of the facility.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cross-reference to the location in the public offering statement of the description of any priority reservation features which may affect a purchaser’s ability to obtain a reservation in the component site.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other information as the division determines is necessary to fairly, meaningfully, and effectively disclose all aspects of the multisite timeshare plan, including, but not limited to, any disclosures made necessary by the operation of s. 721.03(8). However, if a developer has, in good faith, attempted to comply with the requirements of this section, and if, in fact, the developer has substantially complied with the disclosure requirements of this chapter, nonmaterial errors or omissions shall not be actionable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information that the developer, with the approval of the division, desires to include in the public offering statement text.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following documents shall be included as exhibits to the filed public offering statement, if applicable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The timeshare instrument.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The reservation system rules and regulations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The multisite timeshare plan budget pursuant to subparagraph (4)(h)5.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any document containing the material rules and regulations described in paragraph (4)(e).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contract, agreement, or other document through which component sites are affiliated with the multisite timeshare plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any escrow agreement required pursuant to s. 721.08 or s. 721.56(3).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The form agreement for sale or lease of an interest in the multisite timeshare plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The form receipt for multisite timeshare plan documents required to be given to the purchaser pursuant to s. 721.551(2)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The description of documents list required to be given to the purchaser by s. 721.551(2)(b).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The component site managing entity affidavit or statement required by s. 721.56(1).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any subordination instrument required by s. 721.53.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the multisite timeshare plan contains any component sites located in this state, the information required by s. 721.07(5) pertaining to each such component site unless exempt pursuant to s. 721.03.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the purchaser will receive a timeshare estate pursuant to s. 721.57, or an interest in a specific multisite timeshare plan, in a component site located outside of this state but which is offered in this state, the information required by s. 721.07(5) pertaining to that component site, provided, however, that the provisions of s. 721.07(5)(t) shall only require disclosure of information related to the estimated budget for the timeshare plan and purchaser’s expenses as required by the jurisdiction in which the component site is located.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A timeshare plan containing only one component site must be filed with the division as a multisite timeshare plan if the timeshare instrument reserves the right for the developer to add future component sites. However, if the developer fails to add at least one additional component site to a timeshare plan described in this paragraph within 3 years after the date the plan is initially filed with the division, the multisite filing for such plan shall thereupon terminate, and the developer may not thereafter offer any further interests in such plan unless and until he or she refiles such plan with the division pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The public offering statement for any timeshare plan described in paragraph (a) must include the following disclosure in conspicuous type:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This timeshare plan has been filed as a multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club); however, this plan currently contains only one component site. The developer is not required to add any additional component sites to the plan. Do not purchase an interest in this plan in reliance upon the addition of any other component sites.</Font></Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 93-58; s. 22, ch. 95-274; s. 14, ch. 97-93; s. 908, ch. 97-102; s. 37, ch. 2000-302; s. 25, ch. 2004-279; s. 11, ch. 2007-75.</History></Section>