<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.551" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Delivery of multisite timeshare plan purchaser public offering statement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to prescribe by rule the form of the approved multisite timeshare plan public offering statement that must be furnished by a seller to each purchaser pursuant to this section. The form of the public offering statement that is furnished to purchasers must provide fair, meaningful, and effective disclosure of all aspects of the multisite timeshare plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall furnish each purchaser with the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the approved multisite timeshare plan public offering statement text containing the information required by s. 721.55(1)-(6).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A receipt for multisite timeshare plan documents and a list describing any exhibit to the filed public offering statement which is not delivered to the purchaser. The division is authorized to prescribe by rule the form of the receipt for multisite timeshare plan documents and the description of exhibits list that must be furnished to the purchaser pursuant to this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the purchaser will receive a timeshare estate pursuant to s. 721.57, or an interest in a specific multisite timeshare plan, in a component site located in this state, the developer shall also furnish the purchaser with the information required to be delivered pursuant to s. 721.07(6)(a) and (b) for the component site in which the purchaser will receive an estate or interest in a specific multisite timeshare plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other exhibit that the developer elects to include as part of the purchaser public offering statement, provided that the developer first files the exhibit with the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An executed copy of any document which the purchaser signs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall be required to provide the managing entity of the multisite timeshare plan with a copy of the approved filed public offering statement and any approved amendments thereto to be maintained by the managing entity as part of the books and records of the timeshare plan pursuant to s. 721.13(3)(d).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 95-274; s. 38, ch. 2000-302; s. 26, ch. 2004-279.</History></Section>