<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.065" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Resale purchase agreements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owner who acquires a timeshare interest for her or his own use and occupancy and later offers it for resale, or any agent of such person, must utilize a resale purchase agreement which complies with the provisions of subsection (2) to effectuate any resale of the timeshare interest. A managing entity, not otherwise a developer, that sells, or engages a third party to sell on its behalf, 50 or fewer timeshare interests in the timeshare plan which it manages in a given calendar year to persons who are not existing purchasers of that timeshare plan may also use a resale purchase agreement which complies with subsection (2) in lieu of complying with the provisions of ss. 721.06-721.12 and 721.20. A managing entity, not otherwise a developer, that sells, or engages a third party to sell on its behalf, timeshare interests in the timeshare plan which it manages to persons who are existing purchasers of that timeshare plan may also use a resale purchase agreement in compliance with subsection (2) in lieu of complying with the provisions of ss. 721.06-721.12 and 721.20. For purposes of this subsection, a rebuttable presumption shall exist that an owner who has acquired more than seven timeshare interests did not acquire them for her or his own use and occupancy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resale purchase agreement utilized by a person described in subsection (1) must contain all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the timeshare plan and of the managing entity of the timeshare plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One of the following statements in conspicuous type located immediately prior to the disclosure required by paragraph (c):</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the resale purchase agreement pertains to a real property timeshare plan:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The current year’s assessment for common expenses allocable to the timeshare interest you are purchasing is $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />. This assessment, which may be increased from time to time by the managing entity of the timeshare plan, is payable in full each year on or before <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />. This assessment (includes/does not include) yearly ad valorem real estate taxes, which (are/are not) billed and collected separately. (If ad valorem real property taxes are not included in the current year’s assessment for common expenses, the following statement must be included: The most recent annual assessment for ad valorem real estate taxes for the timeshare interest you are purchasing is $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />.) (If there are any delinquent assessments for common expenses or ad valorem taxes outstanding with respect to the timeshare interest in question, the following statement must be included: A delinquency in the amount of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> for unpaid common expenses or ad valorem taxes currently exists with respect to the timeshare interest you are purchasing, together with a per diem charge of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> for interest and late charges.) For the purpose of ad valorem assessment, taxation, and special assessments, the managing entity will be considered the taxpayer as your agent pursuant to section 192.037, Florida Statutes. Each owner is personally liable for the payment of her or his assessments for common expenses, and failure to timely pay these assessments may result in restriction or loss of your use and/or ownership rights.</Font></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">There are many important documents relating to the timeshare plan which you should review prior to purchasing a timeshare interest, including the declaration of condominium or covenants and restrictions; the owners’ association articles and bylaws; the current year’s operating and reserve budgets; and any rules and regulations affecting the use of timeshare plan accommodations and facilities.</Font></Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the resale purchase agreement pertains to a personal property timeshare plan:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The current year’s assessment for any common expenses, use charges, fees, or taxes allocable to the timeshare interest you are purchasing is $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />. This assessment, which may be increased from time to time by the managing entity of the timeshare plan, is payable in full each year on or before <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" />. (If there are any delinquent assessments for common expenses, use charges, fees, or taxes outstanding with respect to the timeshare interest in question, the following statement must be included: A delinquency in the amount of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> for unpaid common expenses, use charges, fees, or taxes currently exists with respect to the timeshare interest you are purchasing, together with a per diem charge of $<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> for interest and late charges.) Each owner is personally liable for the payment of her or his assessments for common expenses, and failure to timely pay these assessments may result in restriction or loss of your use and/or ownership rights.</Font></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">There are many important documents relating to the timeshare plan which you should review prior to purchasing a timeshare interest, including any owners’ association articles and bylaws; the current year’s operating and reserve budgets; and any rules and regulations affecting the use of timeshare plan accommodations and facilities.</Font></Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement in conspicuous type located immediately prior to the space in the contract reserved for the signature of the purchaser:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">You may cancel this contract without any penalty or obligation within 10 days after the date you sign this contract. If you decide to cancel this contract, you must notify the seller in writing of your intent to cancel. Your notice of cancellation shall be effective upon the date sent and shall be sent to the seller at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(address)</Directions>. Any attempt to obtain a waiver of your cancellation right is void and of no effect. While you may execute all closing documents in advance, the closing, as evidenced by delivery of the deed or other document, before expiration of your 10-day cancellation period, is prohibited.</Font></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The year in which the purchaser will first be entitled to occupancy of a timeshare period associated with the timeshare interest that is the subject of the resale purchase agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a resale purchase agreement utilized by a person described in subsection (1) does not comply with the provisions of subsection (2), the contract shall be voidable at the option of the purchaser for a period of 1 year after the date of closing.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 95-274; s. 892, ch. 97-102; s. 11, ch. 2000-302; s. 5, ch. 2004-279.</History></Section>