<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0721.82" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Amounts secured by the lien” means all amounts secured by an assessment lien or mortgage lien, including, but not limited to, all past due amounts, accrued interest, late fees, taxes, advances for the payment of taxes, insurance and maintenance of the timeshare interest, and any fees or costs incurred by the lienholder or trustee, including any reasonable attorney’s fees, trustee’s fees, and costs incurred in connection with the default.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assessment lien” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lien for delinquent assessments as provided in ss. 718.116, 719.108, and 721.16; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A lien for unpaid ad valorem assessments, tax assessments, and special assessments as provided in s. 192.037(8).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Junior interestholder” means any person who has a lien or interest of record against a timeshare interest in the county or counties in which the timeshare interest is located, which is inferior to the mortgage lien or assessment lien being foreclosed under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Lienholder” means a holder of an assessment lien or a holder of a mortgage lien, as applicable. A receiver appointed under s. 721.26 is a lienholder for purposes of foreclosure of assessment liens under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgage” has the same meaning set forth in s. 697.01.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgage lien” means a security interest in a timeshare interest created by a mortgage encumbering the timeshare interest.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgagee” means a person holding a mortgage lien.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mortgagor” means a person granting a mortgage lien or a person who has assumed the obligation secured by a mortgage lien.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Notice address” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to an assessment lien, the address of the owner of a timeshare interest as reflected by the books and records of the timeshare plan under ss. 721.13(4) and 721.15(7).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to a mortgage lien:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The address of the mortgagor as set forth in the mortgage, the promissory note or a separate document executed by the mortgagor at the time the mortgage lien was created, or the most current address of the mortgagor according to the records of the mortgagee; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the owner of the timeshare interest is different from the mortgagor, the address of the owner of the timeshare interest as reflected by the books and records of the mortgagee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As to a junior interestholder, the address as set forth in the recorded instrument creating the junior lien or interest, or in any recorded amendment thereto changing the address, or in any written notification by the junior interestholder to the foreclosing lienholder changing the address.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Obligor” means the mortgagor, the person subject to an assessment lien, or the record owner of the timeshare interest.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permitted delivery service” means any nationally recognized common carrier delivery service or international airmail service that allows for return receipt service.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registered agent” means an agent duly appointed by the obligor under s. 721.84 for the purpose of accepting all notices and service of process under this part. A registered agent may be an individual resident in this state whose business office qualifies as a registered office, or a domestic or foreign corporation or a not-for-profit corporation as defined in chapter 617 authorized to transact business or to conduct its affairs in this state, whose business office qualifies as a registered office. A registered agent for any obligor may not be the lienholder or the attorney for the lienholder.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registered office” means the street address of the business office of the registered agent appointed under s. 721.84, located in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trustee” means an attorney who is a member in good standing of The Florida Bar and who has been practicing law for at least 5 years or that attorney’s law firm, or a title insurer authorized to transact business in this state under s. 624.401 and who has been authorized to transact business for at least 5 years, appointed as trustee or as substitute trustee in accordance with s. 721.855 or s. 721.856. A receiver appointed under s. 721.26 may act as a trustee under s. 721.855. A trustee must be independent as defined in s. 721.05(20).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 98-36; s. 43, ch. 2000-302; s. 6, ch. 2010-134.</History>
</Section>