<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0721.83" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Consolidation of judicial foreclosure actions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A complaint in a foreclosure proceeding involving timeshare interests may join in the same action multiple defendant obligors and junior interestholders of separate timeshare interests, provided:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreclosure proceeding involves a single timeshare property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The foreclosure proceeding is filed by a single plaintiff.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The default and remedy provisions in the written instruments on which the foreclosure proceeding is based are substantially the same for each defendant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of the defaults alleged is the same for each defendant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 15 timeshare interests, without regard to the number of defendants, are joined within the same consolidated foreclosure action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any foreclosure proceeding involving multiple defendants filed under subsection (1), the court shall sever for separate trial any count of the complaint in which a defense or counterclaim is timely raised by a defendant.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A consolidated timeshare foreclosure action shall be considered a single action, suit, or proceeding for the payment of filing fees and service charges pursuant to general law. In addition to the payment of such filing fees and service charges, an additional filing fee of up to $10 for each timeshare interest joined in that action shall be paid to the clerk of court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 98-36; s. 112, ch. 2003-402; s. 74, ch. 2004-265; s. 39, ch. 2008-111; s. 7, ch. 2010-134.</History>
</Section>