<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0721.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public offering statement.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to offering any timeshare plan, the developer must submit a filed public offering statement to the division for approval as prescribed by s. 721.03, s. 721.55, or this section. Until the division approves such filing, any contract regarding the sale of that timeshare plan is subject to cancellation by the purchaser pursuant to s. 721.10.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall, upon receiving a filed public offering statement from a developer, mail to the developer an acknowledgment of receipt. The failure of the division to send such acknowledgment will not, however, relieve the developer from the duty of complying with this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 45 days after receipt of a filed public offering statement which is subject only to this part and is submitted in proper form as prescribed by rule, or within 120 days after receipt of a filed public offering statement which is subject to part II and is submitted in proper form as prescribed by rule, the division shall determine whether the proposed filed public offering statement is adequate to meet the requirements of this section and shall notify the developer by mail that the division has either approved the statement or found specified deficiencies in the statement. If the division fails to approve the statement or specify deficiencies in the statement within the period specified in this paragraph, the filing will be deemed approved.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the developer fails to respond to any cited deficiencies within 20 days after receipt of the division’s deficiency notice, the division may reject the filing. Subsequent to such rejection, a new filing fee pursuant to subsection (4) and a new division initial review period pursuant to paragraph (a) shall apply to any refiling or further review of the rejected filing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 20 days after receipt of the developer’s timely and complete response to any deficiency notice, the division shall notify the developer by mail that the division has either approved the filing, found additional specified deficiencies in it, or determined that any previously specified deficiency has not been corrected. If the division fails to approve or specify additional deficiencies within 20 days after receipt of the developer’s timely and complete response, the filing will be deemed approved.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer shall have the authority to deliver to purchasers any purchaser public offering statement that is not yet approved by the division, provided that the following shall apply:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the developer delivers an unapproved purchaser public offering statement to a purchaser pursuant to this paragraph, the developer shall deliver a fully completed and executed copy of the purchase contract required by s. 721.06 that contains the following statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form which shall replace the statements required by s. 721.06(1)(g):</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The developer is delivering to you a public offering statement that has been filed with but not yet approved by the Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes. Any revisions to the unapproved public offering statement you have received must be delivered to you, but only if the revisions materially alter or modify the offering in a manner adverse to you. After the division approves the public offering statement, you will receive notice of the approval from the developer and the required revisions, if any.</Font></Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Your statutory right to cancel this transaction without any penalty or obligation expires 10 calendar days after the date you signed your purchase contract or the date on which you receive the last of all documents required to be given to you pursuant to section 721.07(6), Florida Statutes, or 10 calendar days after you receive revisions required to be delivered to you, if any, whichever is later. If you decide to cancel this contract, you must notify the seller in writing of your intent to cancel. Your notice of cancellation shall be effective upon the date sent and shall be sent to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of Seller)</Directions> at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Address of Seller)</Directions>. Any attempt to obtain a waiver of your cancellation right is void and of no effect. While you may execute all closing documents in advance, the closing, as evidenced by delivery of the deed or other document, before expiration of your 10-day cancellation period, is prohibited.</Font></Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After receipt of approval from the division and prior to closing, if any revisions made to the documents contained in the purchaser public offering statement materially alter or modify the offering in a manner adverse to a purchaser, the developer shall send the purchaser such revisions, together with a notice containing a statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The unapproved public offering statement previously delivered to you, together with the enclosed revisions, has been approved by the Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes. Accordingly, your cancellation right expires 10 calendar days after you sign your purchase contract or 10 calendar days after you receive these revisions, whichever is later. If you have any questions regarding your cancellation rights, you may contact the division at [insert division’s current address].</Font></Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After receipt of approval from the division and prior to closing, if no revisions have been made to the documents contained in the unapproved purchaser public offering statement, or if such revisions do not materially alter or modify the offering in a manner adverse to a purchaser, the developer shall send the purchaser a notice containing a statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The unapproved public offering statement previously delivered to you has been approved by the Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes. Revisions made to the unapproved public offering statement, if any, are not required to be delivered to you or are not deemed by the developer, in its opinion, to materially alter or modify the offering in a manner that is adverse to you. Accordingly, your cancellation right expired 10 days after you signed your purchase contract. A complete copy of the approved public offering statement is available through the managing entity for inspection as part of the books and records of the plan. If you have any questions regarding your cancellation rights, you may contact the division at [insert division’s current address].</Font></Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change to an approved public offering statement filing shall be filed with the division for approval as an amendment prior to becoming effective. The division shall have 20 days after receipt of a proposed amendment to approve or cite deficiencies in the proposed amendment. If the division fails to act within 20 days, the amendment will be deemed approved. If the proposed amendment adds a new component site to an approved multisite timeshare plan, the division’s initial period in which to approve or cite deficiencies is 45 days. If the developer fails to adequately respond to any deficiency notice within 30 days, the division may reject the amendment. Subsequent to such rejection, a new filing fee pursuant to subsection (4) and a new division initial review period pursuant to this paragraph shall apply to any refiling or further review of the rejected amendment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For filings only subject to this part, each approved amendment to the approved purchaser public offering statement, other than an amendment made only for the purpose of the addition of a phase or phases to the timeshare plan in the manner described in the timeshare instrument or any amendment that does not materially alter or modify the offering in a manner that is adverse to a purchaser, shall be delivered to a purchaser no later than 10 days prior to closing. For filings made under part II, each approved amendment to the multisite timeshare plan purchaser public offering statement, other than an amendment made only for the purpose of the addition, substitution, or deletion of a component site pursuant to part II or the addition of a phase or phases to a component site of a multisite timeshare plan in the manner described in the timeshare instrument or any amendment that does not materially alter or modify the offering in a manner that is adverse to a purchaser, shall be delivered to a purchaser no later than 10 days prior to closing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amendments made to a timeshare instrument for a component site located in this state are not required to be delivered to purchasers who do not receive a timeshare estate or an interest in a specific multisite timeshare plan in that component site. Amendments made to a timeshare instrument for a component site not located in this state are not required to be delivered to purchasers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time that any amendments required to be delivered to purchasers, as provided in paragraph (a), are delivered to purchasers, the developer shall provide to those purchasers who have not closed a written statement that the purchaser or lessee will have a 10-day voidability period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of a filed public offering statement, the developer shall pay a filing fee of $2 for each 7 days of annual use availability in each timeshare unit that may be offered as a part of the proposed timeshare plan pursuant to the filing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the filing of an amendment to an approved filed public offering statement, the developer shall pay a filing fee of $100.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every filed public offering statement for a timeshare plan which is not a multisite timeshare plan shall contain the information required by this subsection. The division is authorized to provide by rule the method by which a developer must provide such information to the division.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cover page stating only:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the timeshare plan; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement, in conspicuous type: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This public offering statement contains important matters to be considered in acquiring a timeshare interest. The statements contained in this public offering statement are only summary in nature. A prospective purchaser should refer to all references, accompanying exhibits, contract documents, and sales materials. You should not rely upon oral representations as being correct. Refer to this document and accompanying exhibits for correct representations. The seller is prohibited from making any representations other than those contained in the contract and this public offering statement.</Font></Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A listing of all statements required to be in conspicuous type in the public offering statement and in all exhibits thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate index of the contents and exhibits of the public offering statement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A text which shall include, where applicable, the disclosures set forth in paragraphs (e)-(hh).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the timeshare plan, including, but not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Its name and location.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An explanation of the form of timeshare ownership that is being offered, including a statement as to whether any interest in the underlying real property will be conveyed to the purchaser. If the plan is being created or being sold on a leasehold, a description of the material terms of the lease shall be included. If the plan is a plan in which timeshare estates or personal property timeshare interests are sold as interests in a trust pursuant to the requirements of this chapter, a full and accurate description of the trust arrangement and the trustee’s duties shall be included. If the plan is a personal property timeshare plan, a description of the material terms of the arrangement for the ownership or use of the personal property shall be included.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An explanation of the manner in which the apportionment of common expenses and ownership of the common elements has been determined.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If ownership or use of the timeshare plan is based on a point system, a statement indicating the circumstances by which the point values may change, the extent of such changes, and the person or entity responsible for the changes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the accommodations or facilities are part of a personal property timeshare plan in which the accommodations or facilities are located on or in a documented vessel or foreign vessel as provided in s. 721.08(2)(c)3.e., the disclosure required by s. 721.08(2)(c)3.e.(IV).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the accommodations, including, but not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of timeshare units in each building, the total number of timeshare periods declared as part of the timeshare plan and filed with the division, and the number of bathrooms and bedrooms in each type of timeshare unit.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The latest date estimated for completion of constructing, finishing, and equipping the timeshare units declared as part of the timeshare plan and filed with the division.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated maximum number of units and timeshare periods that will use the accommodations and facilities. If the maximum number of timeshare units or timeshare periods will vary, a description of the basis for variation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duration, in years, of the timeshare plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the accommodations are part of a personal property timeshare plan, the name, vehicle registration number, title certificate number, or any other identifying registration number assigned to the accommodation of a personal property timeshare plan by a state, federal, or international governmental agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any of the accommodations are part of a personal property timeshare plan, the fire detection system and firesafety equipment and description of method of compliance with any applicable firesafety or fire detection regulations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any facilities that will be used by purchasers of the plan, including, but not limited to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The intended purpose, if not apparent from the description.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated date when each facility will be available for use by the purchaser.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to whether the facilities will be used exclusively by purchasers of the timeshare plan, and, if not, a statement as to whether the purchasers of the timeshare plan are required to pay any portion of the maintenance and expenses of such facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any facilities offered by the developer for use by purchasers are to be leased or have club memberships associated with them, other than participation in a vacation club, one of the following statements in conspicuous type: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">There is a lease associated with one or more facilities of the timeshare plan;</Font> or, <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">There is a club membership associated with one or more facilities of the timeshare plan.</Font></Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is mandatory that purchasers pay fees, rent, dues, or other charges under a facilities lease or club membership for the use of the facilities, other than participation in a vacation club, the applicable statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Membership in a facilities club is mandatory for purchasers;</Font></Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Purchasers or the owners’ association(s) are required, as a condition of ownership, to be lessees under the facilities lease;</Font></Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Purchasers or the owners’ association(s) are required to pay their share of the rent or costs and expenses of maintenance, management, upkeep, and replacement under the facilities lease (or the other instruments providing the facilities);</Font> or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A similar statement of the nature of the organization or the manner in which the use rights are created, and that purchasers are required to pay.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Immediately following the applicable statement, a description of the lease or other instrument shall be stated, including a description of terms of the payment of rent or costs and expenses of maintenance, management, upkeep, and replacement of the facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the purchasers are required to pay a use fee, or other payment for the use of the facilities, not including the rent or maintenance, management, upkeep, or replacement costs and expenses, the following statement in conspicuous type: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The purchasers or the owners’ association(s) must pay use fees for one or more facilities.</Font> Immediately following this statement, a description of the use fees shall be included.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person other than the owners’ association has the right to a lien on the timeshare interests to secure the payment of assessments, rent, or other exactions, a statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">There is a lien or lien right against each timeshare interest to secure the payment of rent and other exactions under the facilities lease. A purchaser’s failure to make these payments may result in foreclosure of the lien;</Font> or</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">There is a lien or lien right against each timeshare interest to secure the payment of assessments or other exactions coming due for the use, maintenance, upkeep, or repair of one or more facilities. A purchaser’s failure to make these payments may result in foreclosure of the lien.</Font></Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Immediately following the applicable statement, a description of the lien right shall be included.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the developer or any other person has the right to increase or add to the facilities at any time after the establishment of the timeshare plan, without the consent of the purchasers or owners’ association being required, a statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Facilities may be expanded or added without consent of the purchasers or the owners’ association(s).</Font> Immediately following this statement, a description of such reserved rights shall be included.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a real property timeshare plan, an explanation of the status of the title to the real property underlying the timeshare plan, including a statement of the existence of any lien, defect, judgment, mortgage, or other encumbrance affecting the title to the property, and how such lien, defect, judgment, mortgage, or other encumbrance will be removed or satisfied prior to closing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a personal property timeshare plan, an explanation of the status of title to the personal property underlying the timeshare plan, including a statement of the existence of any lien, defect, judgment, or other encumbrance affecting the title to the personal property, and how such lien, defect, judgment, or other encumbrance will be removed or satisfied prior to closing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any judgment against the developer, the managing entity, the owner of the underlying fee, or the owner of the underlying personal property, which judgment is material to the timeshare plan; the status of any pending suit to which the developer, the managing entity, the owner of the underlying fee, or the owner of the underlying personal property is a party, which suit is material to the timeshare plan; and any other suit which is material to the timeshare plan of which the developer, managing entity, the owner of the underlying fee, or the owner of the underlying personal property has actual knowledge. If no judgments or pending suits exist, there shall be a statement of such fact.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of all unusual and material circumstances, features, and characteristics of the real property or personal property underlying or comprising the timeshare plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A detailed explanation of any financial arrangements which have been provided for completion of all promised improvements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the managing entity; a statement whether the seller may change the managing entity or its control and, if so, the manner by which the seller may change the managing entity; a statement of the arrangements for management, maintenance, and operation of the accommodations and facilities and of other property that will serve the purchasers; and a description of the management arrangement and any contracts for these purposes having a term in excess of 1 year, including the names of the contracting parties, the term of the contract, the nature of the services included, and the compensation, stated for a month and for a year, and provisions for increases in the compensation. In the case of a personal property timeshare plan in which the accommodations or facilities are located on or in a documented vessel or foreign vessel as provided in s. 721.08(2)(c)3.e., a statement shall be included that describes the trustee’s or owners’ association’s access to the certificates of classification and that the certificate of classification will be made available to purchasers on request.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person other than the purchasers has the right to retain control of the board of administration of the owners’ association, if any, for a period of time which may exceed 1 year after the closing of the sale of a majority of the timeshare interests in that timeshare plan to persons other than successors or concurrent developers and the plan is one in which all purchasers automatically become members of the owners’ association, a statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The developer (or other person) has the right to retain control of the owners’ association after a majority of the timeshare interests have been sold.</Font> Immediately following this statement, a description of the applicable transfer of control provisions of the timeshare plan shall be included.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there are any restrictions upon the sale, transfer, conveyance, or leasing of a timeshare interest, a statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The sale, lease, or transfer of timeshare interests is restricted or controlled.</Font> Immediately following this statement, a description of the nature of the restriction, limitation, or control on the sale, lease, or transfer of timeshare interests shall be included.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement in conspicuous type in substantially the following form: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The purchase of a timeshare interest should be based upon its value as a vacation experience or for spending leisure time, and not considered for purposes of acquiring an appreciating investment or with an expectation that the timeshare interest may be resold.</Font></Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the timeshare plan is part of a phase project, a statement to that effect and a complete description of the phasing. Notwithstanding any provisions of s. 718.110 or s. 719.1055, a developer may develop a timeshare condominium or a timeshare cooperative in phases if the original declaration of condominium or cooperative documents submitting the initial phase to condominium ownership or cooperative ownership or an amendment to the declaration of condominium or cooperative documents which has been approved by all of the unit owners and unit mortgagees provides for phasing. Notwithstanding any provisions of s. 718.403 or s. 719.403 to the contrary, the original declaration of condominium or cooperative documents, or an amendment to the declaration of condominium or cooperative documents adopted pursuant to this subsection, need only generally describe the developer’s phasing plan and the land which may become part of the condominium or cooperative, and, in conjunction therewith, the developer may also reserve all rights to vary his or her phasing plan as to phase boundaries, plot plans and floor plans, timeshare unit types, timeshare unit sizes and timeshare unit type mixes, numbers of timeshare units, and facilities with respect to each subsequent phase. There shall be no time limit during which a developer of a timeshare condominium or timeshare cooperative must complete his or her phasing plan, and the developer shall not be required to notify owners of existing timeshare estates of his or her decision not to add one or more proposed phases.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the material restrictions, if any, to be imposed on timeshare interests concerning the use of any of the accommodations or facilities, including statements as to whether there are restrictions upon children and pets or a reference to a copy of the documents containing the restrictions which shall be attached as an exhibit. If there are no restrictions, there shall be a statement of such fact.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If there is any land or personal property that is offered by the developer for use by the purchasers and which is neither owned by them nor leased to them, the owners’ association, or any entity controlled by the purchasers, a statement describing the land or personal property, how it will serve the timeshare plan, and the nature and term of service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An estimated operating budget for the timeshare plan and a schedule of the purchaser’s expenses shall be attached as an exhibit and shall contain the following information:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated annual expenses of the timeshare plan collectible from purchasers by assessments. The estimated payments by the purchaser for assessments shall also be stated in the estimated amounts for the times when they will be due. Expenses shall also be shown for the shortest timeshare period offered for sale by the developer. If the timeshare plan provides for the offer and sale of units to be used on a nontimeshare basis, the estimated monthly and annual expenses of such units shall be set forth in a separate schedule.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated weekly, monthly, and annual expenses of the purchaser of each timeshare interest, other than assessments payable to the managing entity. Expenses which are personal to purchasers that are not uniformly incurred by all purchasers or that are not provided for or contemplated by the timeshare plan documents may be excluded from this estimate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated items of expenses of the timeshare plan and the managing entity, except as excluded under subparagraph 2., including, but not limited to, if applicable, the following items, which shall be stated either as management expenses collectible by assessments or as expenses of the purchaser payable to persons other than the managing entity:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses for the managing entity:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administration of the managing entity.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management fees.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="III">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IV">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rent for facilities.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="V">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taxes upon timeshare property.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VI">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Taxes upon leased areas.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insurance.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="VIII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Security provisions.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="IX">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other expenses.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="X">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Operating capital.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="XI">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves for deferred maintenance and reserves for capital expenditures, including:</Text>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="A">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves for deferred maintenance or capital expenditures of accommodations and facilities of a real property timeshare plan, if any. All reserves for any accommodations and facilities of real property timeshare plans located in this state shall be calculated by a formula which is based upon estimated life and replacement cost of each reserve item. Reserves for deferred maintenance for such accommodations and facilities shall include accounts for roof replacement, building painting, pavement resurfacing, replacement of timeshare unit furnishings and equipment, and any other component, the useful life of which is less than the useful life of the overall structure. For any accommodations and facilities of real property timeshare plans located outside of this state, the developer shall disclose the amount of reserves for deferred maintenance or capital expenditures required by the law of the situs state, if applicable, and maintained for such accommodations and facilities.</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<SubSubSubSubParagraph Id="B">
								<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves for deferred maintenance or capital expenditures of accommodations and facilities of a personal property timeshare plan, if any. If such reserves are maintained, the estimated operating budget shall disclose the methodology of how the reserves are calculated. If a personal property timeshare plan does not require reserves, the following statement, in conspicuous type, shall appear in both the budget and the public offering statement:</Text>
							</SubSubSubSubParagraph>
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The estimated operating budget for this personal property timeshare plan does not include reserves for deferred maintenance or capital expenditures; each timeshare interest may be subject to substantial special assessments from time to time because no such reserves exist.</Font></Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="XII">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees payable to the division.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses for a purchaser:</Text>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="I">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rent for the timeshare unit, if subject to a lease.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
						<SubSubSubParagraph Id="II">
							<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rent payable by the purchaser directly to the lessor or agent under any lease for the use of facilities, which use and payment is a mandatory condition of ownership and is not included in the common expenses or assessments for common maintenance paid by the purchasers to the managing entity.</Text>
						</SubSubSubParagraph>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated amounts shall be stated for a period of at least 12 months and may distinguish between the period prior to the time that purchasers elect a majority of the board of administration and the period after that date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the developer intends to guarantee the level of assessments, such guarantee must be based upon a good faith estimate of the revenues and expenses of the timeshare plan. The guarantee must include a description of the following:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific time period measured in one or more calendar or fiscal years during which the guarantee will be in effect.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the developer will pay all common expenses incurred in excess of the total revenues of the timeshare plan pursuant to s. 721.15(2) if the developer has excused himself or herself from the payment of assessments during the guarantee period.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The level, expressed in total dollars, at which the developer guarantees the budget. If the developer has reserved the right to extend or increase the guarantee level pursuant to s. 721.15(2), a disclosure must be included to that effect.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the developer intends to provide a trust fund to defer or reduce the payment of annual assessments, a copy of the trust instrument shall be attached as an exhibit and shall include a description of such arrangement, including, but not limited to:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The specific amount of such trust funds and the source of the funds.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the trustee.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The investment methods permitted by the trust agreement.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement in conspicuous type that the funds from the trust account may not cover all assessments and that there is no guarantee that purchasers will not have to pay assessments in the future.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The budget of a phase timeshare plan may contain a note identifying the number of timeshare interests covered by the budget, indicating the number of timeshare interests, if any, estimated to be declared as part of the timeshare plan during that calendar year, and projecting the common expenses for the timeshare plan based upon the number of timeshare interests estimated to be declared as part of the timeshare plan during that calendar year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any timeshare plan for which the purchase or closing of timeshare interests is not subject to the requirements of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act, 12 U.S.C. ss. 2601 et seq., a schedule of estimated closing expenses to be paid by a purchaser or lessee of a timeshare interest.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="v">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to whether a title opinion or title insurance policy is available to the purchaser and, if so, at whose expense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="w">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The identity of the developer and the chief operating officer or principal directing the creation and sale of the timeshare plan and a statement of the experience of each in this field or, if no experience, a statement of that fact.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="x">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the total financial obligation of the purchaser, including the purchase price and any additional charges to which the purchaser may be subject.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="y">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of any person who will or may have the right to alter, amend, or add to the charges to which the purchaser may be subject and the terms and conditions under which such alterations, amendments, or additions may be imposed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="z">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of the purchaser’s right of cancellation of the purchase contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="aa">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the insurance coverage provided for the timeshare plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="bb">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement as to whether the timeshare plan is participating in an exchange program and, if so, the name and address of the exchange company offering the exchange program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="cc">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The existence of rules and regulations regarding any reservation features governing a purchaser’s ability to make reservations for a timeshare period, including, if applicable, a conspicuous type disclaimer in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The right to reserve a timeshare period is subject to rules and regulations of the timeshare plan reservation system.</Font></Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="dd">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a developer is filing a timeshare plan that includes a timeshare instrument or component site document that was in conformance with the laws and rules in existence at the time the timeshare plan was created but does not conform to existing laws and rules that govern the timeshare plan and the developer does not have the authority or power to amend or change the timeshare instrument or component site document to conform to such existing laws or rules as directed by the division, a brief explanation of current law and the conflict with the timeshare instrument or component site document, preceded by disclaimer in conspicuous type in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Florida law has been amended and certain provisions in [insert appropriate reference to timeshare instrument or component site document] that were in conformance with Florida law as it existed at the time the timeshare plan was created are not in conformance with current Florida law. These documents may only be amended by [insert appropriate reference to person or entity that has the right to amend or change the timeshare instrument or component site document]. The developer does not warrant that such documents are in technical compliance with all applicable Florida laws and regulations. All questions regarding amendment of these documents should be directed to [insert appropriate reference to person or entity that has the right to amend or change the timeshare instrument or component site document].</Font></Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ee">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other information that a seller, with the approval of the division, desires to include in the public offering statement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ff">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of the following documents and plans, to the extent they are applicable, shall be included as exhibits to the filed public offering statement provided, if the timeshare plan has not been declared or created at the time of the filing, the developer shall provide proposed documents:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The declaration of condominium.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cooperative documents.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The declaration of covenants and restrictions.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The articles of incorporation creating the owners’ association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bylaws of the owners’ association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any ground lease or other underlying lease of the real property associated with the timeshare plan. In the case of a personal property timeshare plan, any lease of the personal property associated with the personal property timeshare plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The management agreement and all maintenance and other contracts regarding the management and operation of the timeshare property which have terms in excess of 1 year.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The estimated operating budget for the timeshare plan and the required schedule of purchasers’ expenses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The floor plan of each type of accommodation and the plot plan showing the location of all accommodations and facilities declared as part of the timeshare plan and filed with the division.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The lease for any facilities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A declaration of servitude of properties serving the accommodations and facilities, but not owned by purchasers or leased to them or the owners’ association.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any documents required by s. 721.03(3)(e) as the result of the inclusion of a timeshare plan in the conversion of the building to condominium or cooperative ownership.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The form of agreement for sale or lease of timeshare interests.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executed agreement for escrow of payments made to the developer prior to closing and the form of any agreement for escrow of ad valorem tax escrow payments, if any, to be made into an ad valorem tax escrow account pursuant to s. 192.037(6).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The documents containing any restrictions on use of the property required by paragraph (r).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="16">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A letter from the escrow agent or filing attorney confirming that the escrow agent and its officers, directors, or other partners are independent pursuant to the requirements of this chapter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="17">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nondisturbance and notice to creditors instrument required by s. 721.08.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="18">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of any personal property timeshare plan in which the accommodations and facilities are located on or in a documented vessel or foreign vessel as provided in s. 721.08(2)(c)3.e., a copy of the certificate of ownership of such vessel and either a copy of the certificate of documentation or certificate of registry of such vessel.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="19">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An executed affidavit given under oath by an attorney licensed to practice law in any jurisdiction in the United States stating that the attorney has researched the applicable laws of the jurisdiction in which governing law has been established and the laws of the jurisdiction in which the vessel is registered, and has found that the timeshare instrument complies with the provisions of s. 721.08(2)(c)3.e.(II)(C) and (III).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="20">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other documents or instruments creating the timeshare plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="gg">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such other information as is necessary to fairly, meaningfully, and effectively disclose all aspects of the timeshare plan, including, but not limited to, any disclosures made necessary by the operation of s. 721.03(8). However, if a developer has, in good faith, attempted to comply with the requirements of this section, and if, in fact, he or she has substantially complied with the disclosure requirements of this chapter, nonmaterial errors or omissions shall not be actionable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="hh">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, the filed public offering statement for a component site of a multisite timeshare plan filed pursuant to this subsection may contain cross-references to information contained in the related multisite timeshare plan filed public offering statement filed pursuant to s. 721.55 in lieu of repeating such information.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="ii">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the owner’s obligation to pay assessments continues for as long as he or she owns the timeshare interest and that when a person inherits a timeshare interest, that person is responsible for paying those assessments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="jj">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following statement in conspicuous type:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The managing entity has a lien against each timeshare interest to secure the payment of assessments, ad valorem assessments, tax assessments, and special assessments. Your failure to make any required payments may result in the judicial or trustee foreclosure of an assessment lien and the loss of your timeshare interest. If the managing entity initiates a trustee foreclosure procedure, you shall have the option to object to the use of the trustee foreclosure procedure and the managing entity may only proceed by filing a judicial foreclosure action.</Font></Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to prescribe by rule the form of the approved purchaser public offering statement that must be furnished by the developer to each purchaser. The form of the purchaser public offering statement must provide fair, meaningful, and effective disclosure of all aspects of the timeshare plan. For timeshare plans filed pursuant to this part, the developer shall furnish each purchaser with the following:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the purchaser public offering statement text in the form approved by the division for delivery to purchasers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copies of the exhibits required to be filed with the division pursuant to subparagraphs (5)(ff)1., 2., 4., 5., 8., and 20.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A receipt for timeshare plan documents and a list describing any exhibit to the filed public offering statement filed with the division which is not delivered to the purchaser. The division is authorized to prescribe by rule the form of the receipt for timeshare plan documents and the description of exhibits list that must be furnished to the purchaser. The description of documents list utilized by a developer shall be filed with the division for review as part of the filed public offering statement pursuant to this section. The developer shall be required to provide the managing entity with a copy of the approved filed public offering statement and any approved amendments thereto to be maintained by the managing entity as part of the books and records of the timeshare plan pursuant to s. 721.13(3)(d).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other exhibit which the developer includes as part of the purchaser public offering statement, provided that the developer first files the exhibit with the division.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An executed copy of any document which the purchaser signs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each purchaser shall receive a fully executed paper copy of the purchase contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may accept an alternate form of timeshare disclosure statement under an agreement with another state. At a minimum, the alternate form of timeshare disclosure statement must have provisions substantially similar to this section. The division may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 156, ch. 83-216; s. 6, ch. 83-264; s. 3, ch. 84-256; s. 48, ch. 85-62; s. 53, ch. 90-339; s. 6, ch. 91-236; s. 4, ch. 93-58; s. 5, ch. 95-274; s. 893, ch. 97-102; s. 4, ch. 98-36; s. 12, ch. 2000-302; s. 6, ch. 2004-279; s. 3, ch. 2007-75; s. 66, ch. 2008-240; s. 8, ch. 2009-133; s. 1, ch. 2010-134.</History>
</Section>