<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Recordkeeping by resale service providers and lead dealers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resale service providers and lead dealers shall maintain the following records for a period of 5 years from the date each piece of personal contact information is obtained:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, home address, work address, home telephone number, work telephone number, and cellular telephone number of the lead dealer from which the personal contact information was obtained.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of a current government-issued photographic identification for the lead dealer from which the personal contact information was obtained, such as a driver’s license, passport, or military identification card.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date, time, and place of the transaction at which the personal contact information was obtained, along with the amount of consideration paid and a signed receipt from the lead dealer or copy of a canceled check.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of all pieces of personal contact information obtained in the exact form and media in which they were received.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If personal contact information was directly researched and assembled by the resale service provider or lead dealer and not obtained from another lead dealer, a complete written description of the sources from which personal contact information was obtained, the methodologies used for researching and assembling it, the items set forth in paragraphs (a) and (b) for the individuals who performed the work, and the date such work was done.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any civil or criminal action relating to the wrongful possession or wrongful use of personal contact information by a resale service provider or lead dealer, any failure by a resale service provider or lead dealer to produce the records required by subsection (1) shall lead to a presumption that the personal contact information was wrongfully obtained.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any use by a resale service provider or lead dealer of personal contact information that is wrongfully obtained pursuant to this section shall be considered wrongful use of such personal contact information by the resale service provider or lead dealer, as applicable. Any party who establishes that a resale service provider or lead dealer wrongfully obtained or wrongfully used personal contact information with respect to owners of a timeshare plan or members of an exchange program shall, in addition to any other remedies that may be available in law or equity, be entitled to recover from such resale service provider or lead dealer an amount equal to $1,000 for each owner about whom personal contact information was wrongfully obtained or used. Upon prevailing, the plaintiff in any such action shall also be entitled to recover reasonable attorney’s fees and costs.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 2007-75.</History></Section>