<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0721.205" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Resale service providers; disclosure obligations.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before engaging in resale advertising services, a resale service provider must provide to the consumer timeshare reseller:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any fees or costs related to such services that the consumer timeshare reseller, or any other person, is required pay to the resale service provider or to any third party.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of when such fees or costs are due.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resale service provider may not engage in those activities described in s. 475.01(1)(a) without being the holder of a valid and current active license in accordance with chapter 475.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the course of offering resale advertising services, a resale advertiser may not:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State or imply that the resale advertiser will provide or assist in providing any type of direct sales or resale brokerage services other than the advertising of the consumer resale timeshare interest for sale or rent by the consumer timeshare reseller.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State or imply to a consumer timeshare reseller, directly or indirectly, that the resale advertiser has identified a person interested in buying or renting the timeshare resale interest without providing the name, address, and telephone number of such represented interested resale purchaser.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State or imply to a consumer timeshare reseller, directly or indirectly, that sales or rentals have been achieved or generated as a result of its advertising services unless the resale advertiser, at the time of making such representation, possesses and is able to provide documentation to substantiate the statement or implication made to the consumer timeshare reseller. In addition, to the extent that a resale advertiser states or implies to a consumer timeshare reseller that the resale advertiser has sold or rented any specific number of timeshare interests, the resale advertiser must also provide the consumer timeshare reseller the ratio or percentage of all the timeshare interests that have resulted in a sale versus the number of timeshare interests advertised for sale by the resale advertiser for each of the previous 2 calendar years if the statement or implication is about a sale or sales, or the ratio or percentage of all the timeshare interests that have actually resulted in a rental versus the number of timeshare interests advertised for rental by the resale advertiser for each of the previous 2 calendar years if the statement or implication is about a rental or rentals.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">State or imply to a consumer timeshare reseller that the timeshare interest has a specific resale value.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make or submit any charge to a consumer timeshare reseller’s credit card account; make or cause to be made any electronic transfer of consumer timeshare reseller funds; or collect any payment from a consumer timeshare reseller that exceeds an aggregate total amount of $75 or more in any 12-month period until after the resale advertiser has received a written contract complying in all respects with paragraph (f) that has been signed by the consumer timeshare reseller.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engage in any resale advertising services for compensation or valuable consideration without first obtaining a written contract to provide such services signed by the consumer timeshare reseller. Notwithstanding any other law, the contract must be printed in at least 12-point type and must contain the following information:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, telephone number, and web address, if any, of the resale advertiser and a mailing address and e-mail address to which a contract cancellation notice may be delivered at the consumer timeshare reseller’s election.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A complete description of all resale advertising services to be provided, including, but not limited to, details regarding the publications, Internet sites, and other media in or on which the consumer resale timeshare interest will be advertised; the dates or time intervals for such advertising or the minimum number of times such advertising will be run in each specific medium; the itemized cost to the consumer timeshare reseller of each resale advertising service to be provided; and a statement of the total cost to the consumer timeshare reseller of all resale advertising services to be provided.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement printed in at least 12-point boldfaced type immediately preceding the space in the contract provided for the consumer timeshare reseller’s signature in substantially the following form:</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">TIMESHARE OWNER’S RIGHT OF CANCELLATION</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of resale advertiser)</Directions> will provide resale advertising services pursuant to this contract. If <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of resale advertiser)</Directions> represents that <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of resale advertiser)</Directions> has identified a person who is interested in purchasing or renting your timeshare interest, then <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of resale advertiser)</Directions> must provide you with the name, address, and telephone number of such represented interested resale purchaser.</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">You have an unwaivable right to cancel this contract for any reason within 10 days after the date you sign this contract. If you decide to cancel this contract, you must notify <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of resale advertiser)</Directions> in writing of your intent to cancel. Your notice of cancellation shall be effective upon the date sent and shall be sent to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(resale advertiser’s physical address)</Directions> or to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(resale advertiser’s e-mail address)</Directions>. Your refund will be made within 20 days after receipt of notice of cancellation or within 5 days after receipt of funds from your cleared check, whichever is later.</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">You are not obligated to pay <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of resale advertiser)</Directions> any money unless you sign this contract and return it to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(name of resale advertiser)</Directions>.</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true">IMPORTANT: Before signing this contract, you should carefully review your original timeshare purchase contract and other project documents to determine whether the developer has reserved a right of first refusal or other option to purchase your timeshare interest or to determine whether there are any restrictions or special conditions applicable to the resale or rental of your timeshare interest.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro" SpaceAbove="true">A statement that any resale contract entered into by or on behalf of the consumer timeshare reseller must comply in all respects with s. 721.065, including the provision of a 10-day cancellation period for the prospective consumer resale purchaser.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make or submit any charge to a consumer timeshare reseller’s credit card account; make or cause to be made any electronic transfer of consumer timeshare reseller funds; or collect any payment from a consumer timeshare reseller in an aggregate amount totaling less than $75 in any 12-month period unless the consumer timeshare reseller has been provided a copy of the terms and conditions of the contract provided for in paragraph (f) and the consumer timeshare reseller has agreed to such terms and conditions by mail or electronic transmission.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to honor any cancellation notice sent by the consumer timeshare reseller within 10 days after the date the consumer timeshare reseller signs the contract for resale advertising services in compliance with subparagraph (f)3.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fail to provide a full refund of all money paid by a consumer timeshare reseller within 20 days after receipt of notice of cancellation or within 5 days after receipt of funds from a cleared check, whichever is later.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a resale service provider uses a contract for resale advertising services that fails to comply with subsection (2), such contract shall be voidable at the option of the consumer timeshare reseller for a period of 1 year after the date it is executed by the consumer timeshare reseller.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding obligations placed upon any other persons by this section, it is the duty of a resale service provider to supervise, manage, and control all aspects of the offering of resale advertising services by any agent or employee of the resale service provider. Any violation of this section that occurs during such offering shall be deemed a violation by the resale service provider as well as by the person actually committing the violation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing resale advertising services with respect to a consumer resale timeshare interest in a timeshare property located or offered within this state, or in a multisite timeshare plan registered or required to be registered to be offered in this state, including acting as an agent or third-party service provider for a resale service provider, constitutes operating, conducting, engaging in, or carrying on a business or business venture in this state for the purposes of s. 48.193(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of any unfair or deceptive act or practice by any person in connection with resale advertising services is a violation of this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other penalties provided for in this section, any violation of this section is subject to a civil penalty of not more than $15,000 per violation. In addition, a person who violates any provision of this section commits an unfair and deceptive trade practice as prohibited by s. 501.204 and is subject to the penalties and remedies provided in part II of chapter 501.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2012-76.</History>
</Section>