<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discharge of managing entity.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If timeshare estates are being sold to purchasers of a timeshare plan, any contract between the owners’ association and a manager or management firm shall be automatically renewable every 3 years, beginning with the third year after the owners’ association is first created, unless the purchasers vote to discharge the manager or management firm. Such a vote shall be conducted by the board of administration of the owners’ association. The manager or management firm shall be deemed discharged if at least 66 percent of the purchasers voting, which shall be at least 50 percent of all votes allocated to purchasers, vote to discharge.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event the manager or management firm is discharged, the board of administration of the owners’ association shall remain responsible for operating and maintaining the timeshare plan pursuant to the timeshare instrument and s. 721.13(1). If the board of administration fails to do so, any timeshare owner may apply to the circuit court within the jurisdiction of which the accommodations and facilities lie for the appointment of a receiver to manage the affairs of the owners’ association and the timeshare plan. At least 30 days before applying to the circuit court, the timeshare owner shall mail to the owners’ association and post in a conspicuous place on the timeshare property a notice describing the intended action. If a receiver is appointed, the owners’ association shall be responsible as a common expense of the timeshare plan, for payment of the salary and expenses of the receiver, relating to the discharge of her or his duties and obligations as receiver, together with the receiver’s court costs, and reasonable attorney’s fees. The receiver shall have all powers and duties of a duly constituted board of administration and shall serve until discharged by the circuit court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing entity of a timeshare plan subject to the provisions of chapter 718 or chapter 719 may be discharged pursuant to chapter 718 or chapter 719, respectively, or its successor or pursuant to this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section shall not apply to personal property timeshare plans.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 14, ch. 83-264; s. 9, ch. 85-63; s. 12, ch. 95-274; s. 899, ch. 97-102; s. 21, ch. 2000-302; s. 13, ch. 2004-279.</History></Section>