<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Regulation by division.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division has the power to enforce and ensure compliance with this chapter, except for parts III and IV, using the powers provided in this chapter, as well as the powers prescribed in chapters 718 and 719. In performing its duties, the division shall have the following powers and duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To aid in the enforcement of this chapter, or any division rule adopted or order issued pursuant to this chapter, the division may make necessary public or private investigations within or outside this state to determine whether any person has violated or is about to violate this chapter, or any division rule adopted or order issued pursuant to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may require or permit any person to file a written statement under oath or otherwise, as the division determines, as to the facts and circumstances concerning a matter under investigation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of any investigation under this chapter, the director of the division or any officer or employee designated by the director may administer oaths or affirmations, subpoena witnesses and compel their attendance, take evidence, and require the production of any matter which is relevant to the investigation, including the identity, existence, description, nature, custody, condition, and location of any books, documents, or other tangible things and the identity and location of persons having knowledge of relevant facts or any other matter reasonably calculated to lead to the discovery of material evidence. Failure to obey a subpoena or to answer questions propounded by the investigating officer and upon reasonable notice to all persons affected thereby shall be a violation of this chapter. In addition to the other enforcement powers authorized in this subsection, the division may apply to the circuit court for an order compelling compliance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may prepare and disseminate a prospectus and other information to assist prospective purchasers, sellers, and managing entities of timeshare plans in assessing the rights, privileges, and duties pertaining thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any remedies available to purchasers, if the division has reasonable cause to believe that a violation of this chapter, or of any division rule adopted or order issued pursuant to this chapter, has occurred, the division may institute enforcement proceedings in its own name against any regulated party, as such term is defined in this subsection:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Regulated party,” for purposes of this section, means any developer, exchange company, seller, managing entity, owners’ association, owners’ association director, owners’ association officer, manager, management firm, escrow agent, trustee, any respective assignees or agents, or any other person having duties or obligations pursuant to this chapter.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who materially participates in any offer or disposition of any interest in, or the management or operation of, a timeshare plan in violation of this chapter or relevant rules involving fraud, deception, false pretenses, misrepresentation, or false advertising or the disbursement, concealment, or diversion of any funds or assets, which conduct adversely affects the interests of a purchaser, and which person directly or indirectly controls a regulated party or is a general partner, officer, director, agent, or employee of such regulated party, shall be jointly and severally liable under this subsection with such regulated party, unless such person did not know, and in the exercise of reasonable care could not have known, of the existence of the facts giving rise to the violation of this chapter. A right of contribution shall exist among jointly and severally liable persons pursuant to this paragraph.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may permit any person whose conduct or actions may be under investigation to waive formal proceedings and enter into a consent proceeding whereby an order, rule, or letter of censure or warning, whether formal or informal, may be entered against that person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may issue an order requiring a regulated party to cease and desist from an unlawful practice under this chapter and take such affirmative action as in the judgment of the division will carry out the purposes of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may bring an action in circuit court for declaratory or injunctive relief or for other appropriate relief, including restitution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall have broad authority and discretion to petition the circuit court to appoint a receiver with respect to any managing entity which fails to perform its duties and obligations under this chapter with respect to the operation of a timeshare plan. The circumstances giving rise to an appropriate petition for receivership under this subparagraph include, but are not limited to:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Damage to or destruction of any of the accommodations or facilities of a timeshare plan, where the managing entity has failed to repair or reconstruct same.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A breach of fiduciary duty by the managing entity, including, but not limited to, undisclosed self-dealing or failure to timely assess, collect, or disburse the common expenses of the timeshare plan.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the managing entity to operate the timeshare plan in accordance with the timeshare instrument and this chapter.</Text></SubSubParagraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If, under the circumstances, it appears that the events giving rise to the petition for receivership cannot be reasonably and timely corrected in a cost-effective manner consistent with the timeshare instrument, the receiver may petition the circuit court to implement such amendments or revisions to the timeshare instrument as may be necessary to enable the managing entity to resume effective operation of the timeshare plan, or to enter an order terminating the timeshare plan, or to enter such further orders regarding the disposition of the timeshare property as the court deems appropriate, including the disposition and sale of the timeshare property held by the owners’ association or the purchasers. In the event of a receiver’s sale, all rights, title, and interest held by the owners’ association or any purchaser shall be extinguished and title shall vest in the buyer. This provision applies to timeshare estates, personal property timeshare interests, and timeshare licenses. All reasonable costs and fees of the receiver relating to the receivership shall become common expenses of the timeshare plan upon order of the court.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may revoke its approval of any filing for any timeshare plan for which a petition for receivership has been filed pursuant to this paragraph.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may impose a penalty against any regulated party for a violation of this chapter or any rule adopted thereunder. A penalty may be imposed on the basis of each day of continuing violation, but in no event may the penalty for any offense exceed $10,000. All accounts collected shall be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer to the credit of the Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes Trust Fund.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a regulated party fails to pay a penalty, the division shall thereupon issue an order directing that such regulated party cease and desist from further operation until such time as the penalty is paid; or the division may pursue enforcement of the penalty in a court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an owners’ association or managing entity fails to pay a civil penalty, the division may pursue enforcement in a court of competent jurisdiction.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to permit the regulated party an opportunity to appeal such decision administratively or to seek relief in a court of competent jurisdiction, the order imposing the penalty or the cease and desist order shall not become effective until 20 days after the date of such order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action commenced by the division shall be brought in the county in which the division has its executive offices or in the county where the violation occurred.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notice to any regulated party shall be complete when delivered by United States mail, return receipt requested, to the party’s address currently on file with the division or to such other address at which the division is able to locate the party. Every regulated party has an affirmative duty to notify the division of any change of address at least 5 business days prior to such change.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division has authority to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement and enforce the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of any unfair or deceptive act or practice by any person in connection with the sales or other operations of an exchange program or timeshare plan is a violation of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of the Florida Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act, ss. 501.201 et seq., relating to the creation, promotion, sale, operation, or management of any timeshare plan shall also be a violation of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may institute proceedings against any such person and take any appropriate action authorized in this section in connection therewith, notwithstanding any remedies available to purchasers.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The failure of any person to comply with any order of the division is a violation of this chapter.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 22, ch. 83-264; s. 23, ch. 87-102; s. 15, ch. 95-274; s. 11, ch. 98-36; s. 223, ch. 98-200; s. 31, ch. 2000-302; s. 1894, ch. 2003-261; s. 21, ch. 2004-279; s. 68, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>