<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Insurance.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision contained in the timeshare instrument or in this chapter, chapter 718, or chapter 719 to the contrary, the managing entity shall use due diligence to obtain adequate casualty insurance as a common expense of the timeshare plan to protect the timeshare property against all reasonably foreseeable perils, in such covered amounts and subject to such reasonable exclusions and reasonable deductibles as are consistent with the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In making the determination as to whether the insurance obtained pursuant to subsection (1) is adequate, the managing entity shall take into account the following factors, among others as may be applicable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Available insurance coverages and related premiums in the marketplace.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amounts of any related deductibles, types of exclusions, and coverage limitations; provided that, for purposes of this paragraph, a deductible of 5 percent or less shall be deemed to be reasonable per se.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The probable maximum loss relating to the insured timeshare property during the policy term.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The extent to which a given peril is insurable under commercially reasonable terms.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Amounts of any deferred maintenance or replacement reserves on hand.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Geography and any special risks associated with the location of the timeshare property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The age and type of construction of the timeshare property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision contained in this section or in the timeshare instrument to the contrary, insurance shall be procured and maintained by the managing entity for the timeshare property as a common expense of the timeshare plan against such perils, in such coverages, and subject to such reasonable deductions or reasonable exclusions as may be required by:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An institutional lender to a developer, for so long as such lender holds a mortgage encumbering any interest in or lien against a portion of the timeshare property; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any holder or pledgee of, or any institutional lender having a security interest in, a pool of promissory notes secured by mortgages or other security interests relating to the timeshare plan, executed by purchasers in connection with such purchasers’ acquisition of timeshare interests in such timeshare property, or any agent, underwriter, placement agent, trustee, servicer, custodian, or other portfolio manager acting on behalf of such holder, pledgee, or institutional lender, for so long as any such notes and mortgages or other security interests remain outstanding.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision contained in the timeshare instrument or in this chapter, chapter 718, or chapter 719 to the contrary, the managing entity is authorized to apply any existing reserves for deferred maintenance and capital expenditures toward payment of insurance deductibles or the repair or replacement of the timeshare property after a casualty without regard to the purposes for which such reserves were originally established.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of each policy of insurance in effect shall be made available for reasonable inspection by purchasers and their authorized agents.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 54, ch. 85-62; s. 24, ch. 2000-302; s. 9, ch. 2007-75.</History></Section>