<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.301" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Timesharing, Vacation Club, and Hospitality Program.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is established the Florida Timesharing, Vacation Club, and Hospitality Program. The primary purpose of this program is to provide the opportunity for a public-private partnership between the state and the timeshare, vacation club, hospitality, and tourism industries affecting this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conducting the program, the director, or the director’s designee, shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicit research and educational projects and proposals from the timeshare, vacation club, hospitality, and tourism industries;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consult with the Florida chapter of the American Resort Development Association (ARDA-Florida), the Chancellor of the State University System, or the chancellor’s designee; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist in the preparation of appropriate reports produced by the program partnership.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director may designate funds from the Division of Florida Condominiums, Timeshares, and Mobile Homes Trust Fund, not to exceed $50,000 annually, to support the projects and proposals undertaken pursuant to paragraph (b). All state trust funds to be expended pursuant to this section must be matched equally with private moneys and shall comprise no more than half of the total moneys expended annually.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to adopt, amend, and repeal rules prescribing criteria for processing and approval of project applications.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 95-274; s. 13, ch. 97-93; s. 905, ch. 97-102; s. 72, ch. 99-5; s. 70, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>