<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Scope of chapter.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter applies to all timeshare plans consisting of more than seven timeshare periods over a period of at least 3 years in which the accommodations and facilities, if any, are located within this state or offered within this state; provided that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a timeshare plan containing accommodations or facilities located in this state which has previously been filed with and approved by the division and which is offered for sale in other jurisdictions within the jurisdictional limits of the United States, the offering or sale of the timeshare plan in such jurisdictions shall not be subject to the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a timeshare plan containing accommodations or facilities located in this state which is offered for sale outside the jurisdictional limits of the United States, such offer or sale shall be exempt from the requirements of this chapter, provided that the developer shall either file the timeshare plan with the division for approval pursuant to this chapter, or pay an exemption registration fee of $100 and file the following minimum information pertaining to the timeshare plan with the division for approval:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the timeshare plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the developer and seller, if any.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location and a brief description of the accommodations and facilities, if any, that are located in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of timeshare interests and timeshare periods to be offered.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term of the timeshare plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the timeshare instrument relating to the management and operation of accommodations and facilities, if any, that are located in this state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the budget required by s. 721.07(5)(t) or s. 721.55(4)(h)5., as applicable.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the management agreement and any other contracts regarding management or operation of the accommodations and facilities, if any, that are located in this state, and which have terms in excess of 1 year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the provision of the purchase contract to be utilized in offering the timeshare plan containing the following disclosure in conspicuous type immediately above the space provided for the purchaser’s signature:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The offering of this timeshare plan outside the jurisdictional limits of the United States of America is exempt from regulation under Florida law, and any such purchase is not protected by the State of Florida. However, the management and operation of any accommodations or facilities located in Florida is subject to Florida law and may give rise to enforcement action regardless of the location of any offer.</Font></Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All timeshare accommodations or facilities which are located outside the state but offered for sale in this state shall be governed by the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The offering for sale in this state of timeshare accommodations and facilities located outside the state is subject only to the provisions of ss. 721.01-721.12, 721.18, 721.20, 721.21, 721.26, 721.28, and part II.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall not require a developer of timeshare accommodations or facilities located outside of this state to make changes in any timeshare instrument to conform to the provisions of s. 721.07 or s. 721.55. The division shall have the power to require disclosure of those provisions of the timeshare instrument that do not conform to s. 721.07 or s. 721.55 as the director determines is necessary to fairly, meaningfully, and effectively disclose all aspects of the timeshare plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this subparagraph, the division shall have no authority to determine whether any person has complied with another state’s laws or to disapprove any filing out-of-state, timeshare instrument, or component site document, based solely upon the lack or degree of timeshare regulation in another state. The division may require a developer to obtain and provide to the division existing documentation relating to an out-of-state filing, timeshare instrument, or component site document and prove compliance of same with the laws of that state. In this regard, the division may accept any evidence of the approval or acceptance of any out-of-state filing, timeshare instrument, or component site document by another state in lieu of requiring a developer to file the out-of-state filing, timeshare instrument, or component site document with the division pursuant to this section, or the division may accept an opinion letter from an attorney or law firm opining as to the compliance of such out-of-state filing, timeshare instrument, or component site document with the laws of another state. The division may refuse to approve the inclusion of any out-of-state filing, timeshare instrument, or component site document as part of a public offering statement based upon the inability of the developer to establish the compliance of same with the laws of another state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to enter into an agreement with another state for the purpose of facilitating the processing of out-of-state timeshare instruments or other component site documents pursuant to this chapter and for the purpose of facilitating the referral of consumer complaints to the appropriate state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, the offer, in this state, of an additional interest to existing purchasers in the same timeshare plan, the same nonspecific multisite timeshare plan, or the same component site of a multisite timeshare plan with accommodations and facilities located outside of this state shall not be subject to the provisions of this chapter if the offer complies with the provisions of s. 721.11(4).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a timeshare plan is subject to both the provisions of this chapter and the provisions of chapter 718 or chapter 719, the plan shall meet the requirements of both chapters unless exempted as provided in this section. The division shall have the authority to adopt rules differentiating between timeshare condominiums and nontimeshare condominiums, and between timeshare cooperatives and nontimeshare cooperatives, in the interpretation and implementation of chapters 718 and 719, respectively. In the event of a conflict between the provisions of this chapter and the provisions of chapter 718 or chapter 719, the provisions of this chapter shall prevail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A timeshare plan which is subject to the provisions of chapter 718 or chapter 719, if fully in compliance with the provisions of this chapter, is exempt from the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 718.202 and 719.202, relating to sales or reservation deposits prior to closing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 718.502 and 719.502, relating to filing prior to sale or lease.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 718.503 and 719.503, relating to disclosure prior to sale.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sections 718.504 and 719.504, relating to prospectus or offering circular.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Part VI of chapter 718 and part VI of chapter 719, relating to conversion of existing improvements to the condominium or cooperative form of ownership, respectively, provided that a developer converting existing improvements to a timeshare condominium or timeshare cooperative must comply with ss. 718.606, 718.608, 718.61, and 718.62, or ss. 719.606, 719.608, 719.61, and 719.62, if applicable, and, if the existing improvements received a certificate of occupancy more than 18 months before such conversion, one of the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The accommodations and facilities shall be renovated and improved to a condition such that the remaining useful life in years of the roof, plumbing, air-conditioning, and any component of the structure which has a useful life less than the useful life of the overall structure is equal to the useful life of accommodations or facilities that would exist if such accommodations and facilities were newly constructed and not previously occupied.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall fund reserve accounts for capital expenditures and deferred maintenance for the roof, plumbing, air-conditioning, and any component of the structure the useful life of which is less than the useful life of the overall structure. The reserve accounts shall be funded for each component in an amount equal to the product of the estimated current replacement cost of such component as of the date of such conversion (as disclosed and substantiated by a certificate under the seal of an architect or engineer authorized to practice in this state) multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be the age of the component in years (as disclosed and substantiated by a certificate under the seal of an architect or engineer authorized to practice in this state) and the denominator of which shall be the total useful life of the component in years (as disclosed and substantiated by a certificate under the seal of an architect or engineer authorized to practice in this state). Alternatively, the reserve accounts may be funded for each component in an amount equal to the amount that, except for the application of this subsection, would be required to be maintained pursuant to s. 718.618(1) or s. 719.618(1). The developer shall fund the reserve accounts contemplated in this subparagraph out of the proceeds of each sale of a timeshare interest, on a pro rata basis, in an amount not less than a percentage of the total amount to be deposited in the reserve account equal to the percentage of ownership allocable to the timeshare interest sold. When an owners’ association makes an expenditure of reserve account funds before the developer has initially sold all timeshare interests, the developer shall make a deposit in the reserve account if the reserve account is insufficient to pay the expenditure. Such deposit shall be at least equal to that portion of the expenditure which would be charged against the reserve account deposit that would have been made for any such timeshare interest had the timeshare interest been initially sold. When a developer deposits amounts in excess of the minimum reserve account funding, later deposits may be reduced to the extent of the excess funding.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer shall provide each purchaser with a warranty of fitness and merchantability pursuant to s. 718.618(6) or s. 719.618(6).</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The treatment of timeshare estates for ad valorem tax purposes and special assessments shall be as prescribed in chapters 192-200.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Membership camping plans shall be subject to the provisions of ss. 509.501-509.512 and not to the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise provided herein, this chapter shall not apply to the offering of any timeshare plan under which the prospective purchaser’s total financial obligation will be $3,000 or less during the entire term of the plan.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every escrow agent or trustee required under this chapter, or under chapter 192 as it relates to timeshare plans, must be independent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any personal property timeshare plan:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter applies only to personal property timeshare plans that are offered in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division shall have the authority to adopt rules interpreting and implementing the provisions of this chapter as they apply to any personal property timeshare plan or any accommodation or facility that is part of a personal property timeshare plan offered in this state, or as the provisions of this chapter apply to any other laws of this state, of the several states, of the United States, or of any other jurisdiction, with respect to any personal property timeshare plan or any accommodation or facility that is part of a personal property timeshare plan offered in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any developer and any managing entity of a personal property timeshare plan must submit to personal jurisdiction in this state in a form satisfactory to the division at the time of filing a public offering statement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, s. 687.03 shall govern with respect to the rate of interest permitted for any loan, advance of money, line of credit, forbearance to enforce the collection of any sum of money, or other obligation in connection with a timeshare license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer or seller may not offer any number of timeshare interests that would cause the total number of timeshare interests offered to exceed a one-to-one use right to use night requirement ratio.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A seller may offer timeshare interests in a real property timeshare plan located outside of this state without filing a public offering statement for such out-of-state real property timeshare plan pursuant to s. 721.07 or s. 721.55, provided all of the following criteria have been satisfied:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The seller shall provide a disclosure statement to each prospective purchaser of such out-of-state timeshare plan. The disclosure statement for a single-site timeshare plan shall contain information otherwise required under s. 721.07(5)(e)-(cc) and the exhibits required by s. 721.07(5)(ff)1., 2., 3., 4., 5., 7., 8., and 20. The disclosure statement for a multisite timeshare plan shall contain information otherwise required under s. 721.55(4) and (5) and the exhibits required under s. 721.55(7). If a developer has, in good faith, attempted to comply with the requirements of this subsection and if the developer has substantially complied with the disclosure requirements of this subsection, nonmaterial errors or omissions shall not be actionable. With respect to any offer for an out-of-state timeshare plan made pursuant to this subsection, the delivery by the seller to a prospective purchaser of the disclosure statement required by this subparagraph shall be deemed to satisfy any requirement of this chapter regarding a public offering statement.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The seller shall utilize and furnish to each purchaser of an out-of-state timeshare plan offered under this subsection a fully completed and executed copy of a purchase contract that contains the statement set forth in s. 721.065(2)(c) in conspicuous type located immediately prior to the space in the contract reserved for the purchaser’s signature. The purchase contract shall also contain the initial purchase price and any additional charges to which the purchaser may be subject in connection with the purchase of the timeshare plan, such as financing, or that will be collected from the purchaser on or before closing, such as the current year’s annual assessment for common expenses.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All purchase contracts for out-of-state timeshare plans offered under this subsection must also contain the following statements in conspicuous type:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This timeshare plan has not been reviewed or approved by the State of Florida.</Font></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The timeshare interest you are purchasing requires certain procedures to be followed in order for you to use your interest. These procedures may be different from those followed in other timeshare plans. You should read and understand these procedures prior to purchasing.</Font></Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An out-of-state timeshare plan may only be offered pursuant to this subsection by the seller on behalf of:</Text><SubSubSubParagraph Id="I"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The developer of a timeshare plan that has been approved by the division within the preceding 7 years pursuant to s. 721.07 or s. 721.55, or concerning which an amendment by the developer has been approved by the division within the preceding 7 years, which timeshare plan has been neither terminated nor withdrawn; or</Text></SubSubSubParagraph><SubSubSubParagraph Id="II"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer under common ownership or control with a developer described in sub-sub-subparagraph (I), provided that any common ownership shall constitute at least a 50-percent ownership interest.</Text></SubSubSubParagraph></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An out-of-state timeshare plan may only be offered pursuant to this subsection to a person who already owns a timeshare interest in a timeshare plan filed by a developer described in sub-subparagraph a.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any seller of an out-of-state timeshare plan offered pursuant to this subsection shall be required to provide notice of such plan to the division on a form prescribed by the division, along with payment of a one-time fee not to exceed $1,000 per filing.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Timeshare plans offered pursuant to this subsection shall be exempt from the requirements of ss. 721.06, 721.065, 721.07, 721.27, 721.55, and 721.58 in addition to the exemptions otherwise applicable to accommodations and facilities located outside of the state pursuant to subparagraph (1)(c)1.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any escrow account required to be established by s. 721.08 for any out-of-state timeshare plan offered under this subsection may be maintained in the situs jurisdiction provided the escrow agent submits to personal jurisdiction in this state in a form satisfactory to the division.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 60, ch. 82-226; s. 2, ch. 83-264; s. 4, ch. 91-236; s. 1, ch. 93-58; s. 1, ch. 95-274; s. 1, ch. 98-36; s. 8, ch. 2000-302; s. 2, ch. 2004-279; s. 1, ch. 2007-75; s. 64, ch. 2008-240.</History></Section>