<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0721.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Management.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For each timeshare plan, the developer shall provide for a managing entity, which shall be either the developer, a separate manager or management firm, or an owners’ association. Any owners’ association shall be created prior to the first closing of the sale of a timeshare interest.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to a timeshare plan which is also regulated under chapter 718 or chapter 719, or which contains a mandatory owners’ association, the board of administration of the owners’ association shall be considered the managing entity of the timeshare plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During any period of time in which such owners’ association has entered into a contract with a manager or management firm to provide some or all of the management services to the timeshare plan, both the board of administration and the manager or management firm shall be considered the managing entity of the timeshare plan and shall be jointly and severally responsible for the faithful discharge of the duties of the managing entity.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An owners’ association which is the managing entity of a timeshare plan that includes condominium units or cooperative units shall not be considered a condominium association pursuant to the provisions of chapter 718 or a cooperative association pursuant to the provisions of chapter 719, unless such owners’ association also operates the entire condominium pursuant to s. 718.111 or the entire cooperative pursuant to s. 719.104.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any timeshare plan other than one described in paragraph (b), any developer shall be considered the managing entity of the timeshare plan unless and until such developer clearly provides in the timeshare instrument that a different party will serve as managing entity, which party has acknowledged in writing that it has accepted the duties and obligations of serving as managing entity. In the event such other party subsequently resigns or otherwise ceases to perform its duties as managing entity, any developer shall again be considered the managing entity until the developer arranges for a new managing entity pursuant to this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event no one described in paragraph (b) or paragraph (c) is operating and maintaining the timeshare plan, anyone who operates or maintains the timeshare plan shall be considered the managing entity of the timeshare plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any managing entity performing community association management must comply with part VIII of chapter 468.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing entity shall act in the capacity of a fiduciary to the purchasers of the timeshare plan. No penalty imposed by the division pursuant to s. 721.26 against any managing entity for breach of fiduciary duty shall be assessed as a common expense of any timeshare plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing entity shall invest the operating and reserve funds of the timeshare plan in accordance with s. 518.11(1); however, the managing entity shall give safety of capital greater weight than production of income. In no event shall the managing entity invest timeshare plan funds with a developer or with any entity that is not independent of any developer or any managing entity within the meaning of s. 721.05(22), and in no event shall the managing entity invest timeshare plan funds in notes and mortgages related in any way to the timeshare plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure by a managing entity to obtain and maintain insurance coverage as required under s. 721.165 during any period of developer control of the managing entity shall constitute a breach of the managing entity’s fiduciary duty.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The duties of the managing entity include, but are not limited to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management and maintenance of all accommodations and facilities constituting the timeshare plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Collection of all assessments for common expenses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing each year to all purchasers an itemized annual budget which shall include all estimated revenues and expenses. The budget shall be in the form required by s. 721.07(5)(t). The budget shall be the final budget adopted by the managing entity for the current fiscal year. The final adopted budget is not required to be delivered if the managing entity has previously delivered a proposed annual budget for the current fiscal year to purchasers in accordance with chapter 718 or chapter 719 and the managing entity includes a description of any changes in the adopted budget with the assessment notice and a disclosure regarding the purchasers’ right to receive a copy of the adopted budget, if desired. The budget shall contain, as a footnote or otherwise, any related party transaction disclosures or notes which appear in the audited financial statements of the managing entity for the previous budget year as required by paragraph (e). A copy of the final budget shall be filed with the division for review within 30 days after the beginning of each fiscal year, together with a statement of the number of periods of 7-day annual use availability that exist within the timeshare plan, including those periods filed for sale by the developer but not yet committed to the timeshare plan, for which annual fees are required to be paid to the division under s. 721.27.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding anything contained in chapter 718 or chapter 719 to the contrary, the board of administration of an owners’ association which serves as the managing entity may from time to time reallocate reserves for deferred maintenance and capital expenditures required by s. 721.07(5)(t)3.a.(XI) from any deferred maintenance or capital expenditure reserve account to any other deferred maintenance or capital expenditure reserve account or accounts in its discretion without the consent of purchasers of the timeshare plan. Funds in any deferred maintenance or capital expenditure reserve account may not be transferred to any operating account without the consent of a majority of the purchasers of the timeshare plan. The managing entity may from time to time transfer excess funds in any operating account to any deferred maintenance or capital expenditure reserve account without the vote or approval of purchasers of the timeshare plan. In the event any amount of reserves for accommodations and facilities of a timeshare plan containing timeshare licenses or personal property timeshare interests exists at the end of the term of the timeshare plan, such reserves shall be refunded to purchasers on a pro rata basis.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With respect to any timeshare plan that has a managing entity that is an owners’ association, reserves may be waived or reduced by a majority vote of those voting interests that are present, in person or by proxy, at a duly called meeting of the owners’ association. If a meeting of the purchasers has been called to determine whether to waive or reduce the funding of reserves and no such result is achieved or a quorum is not attained, the reserves as included in the budget shall go into effect.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintenance of all books and records concerning the timeshare plan so that all such books and records are reasonably available for inspection by any purchaser or the authorized agent of such purchaser. For purposes of this subparagraph, the books and records of the timeshare plan shall be considered “reasonably available” if copies of the requested portions are delivered to the purchaser or the purchaser’s agent within 7 days after the date the managing entity receives a written request for the records signed by the purchaser. The managing entity may charge the purchaser a reasonable fee for copying the requested information not to exceed 25 cents per page. However, any purchaser or agent of such purchaser shall be permitted to personally inspect and examine the books and records wherever located at any reasonable time, under reasonable conditions, and under the supervision of the custodian of those records. The custodian shall supply copies of the records where requested and upon payment of the copying fee. No fees other than those set forth in this section may be charged for the providing of, inspection, or examination of books and records. All books and financial records of the timeshare plan must be maintained in accordance with generally accepted accounting practices.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the books and records of the timeshare plan are not maintained on the premises of the accommodations and facilities of the timeshare plan, the managing entity shall inform the division in writing of the location of the books and records and the name and address of the person who acts as custodian of the books and records at that location. In the event that the location of the books and records changes, the managing entity shall notify the division of the change in location and the name and address of the new custodian within 30 days after the date the books and records are moved. The purchasers shall be notified of the location of the books and records and the name and address of the custodian in the copy of the annual budget provided to them pursuant to paragraph (c).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division is authorized to adopt rules which specify those items and matters that shall be included in the books and records of the timeshare plan and which specify procedures to be followed in requesting and delivering copies of the books and records.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of chapter 718 or chapter 719 to the contrary, the managing entity may not furnish the name, address, or electronic mail address of any purchaser to any other purchaser or authorized agent thereof unless the purchaser whose name, address, or electronic mail address is requested first approves the disclosure in writing.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Arranging for an annual audit of the financial statements of the timeshare plan by a certified public accountant licensed by the Board of Accountancy of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation, in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards as defined by the rules of the Board of Accountancy of the Department of Business and Professional Regulation. The financial statements required by this section must be prepared on an accrual basis using fund accounting, and must be presented in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles. A copy of the audited financial statements must be filed with the division for review and forwarded to the board of directors and officers of the owners’ association, if one exists, no later than 5 calendar months after the end of the timeshare plan’s fiscal year. If no owners’ association exists, each purchaser must be notified, no later than 5 months after the end of the timeshare plan’s fiscal year, that a copy of the audited financial statements is available upon request to the managing entity. Notwithstanding any requirement of s. 718.111(13) or s. 719.104(4), the audited financial statements required by this section are the only annual financial reporting requirements for timeshare condominiums or timeshare cooperatives.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making available for inspection by the division any books and records of the timeshare plan upon the request of the division. The division may enforce this paragraph by making direct application to the circuit court.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Scheduling occupancy of the timeshare units, when purchasers are not entitled to use specific timeshare periods, so that all purchasers will be provided the use and possession of the accommodations and facilities of the timeshare plan which they have purchased.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performing any other functions and duties which are necessary and proper to maintain the accommodations or facilities, as provided in the contract and as advertised.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entering into an ad valorem tax escrow agreement prior to the receipt of any ad valorem tax escrow payments into the ad valorem tax escrow account, as long as an independent escrow agent is required by s. 192.037.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submitting to the division the statement of receipts and disbursements regarding the ad valorem tax escrow account as required by s. 192.037(6)(e). The statement of receipts and disbursements must also include a statement disclosing that all ad valorem taxes have been paid in full to the tax collector through the current assessment year, or, if all such ad valorem taxes have not been paid in full to the tax collector, a statement disclosing those assessment years for which there are outstanding ad valorem taxes due and the total amount of all delinquent taxes, interest, and penalties for each such assessment year as of the date of the statement of receipts and disbursements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding anything contained in chapter 718 or chapter 719 to the contrary, purchasers shall not have the power to cancel contracts entered into by the managing entity relating to a master or community antenna television system, a franchised cable television service, or any similar paid television programming service or bulk rate services agreement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing entity shall maintain among its records and provide to the division upon request a complete list of the names and addresses of all purchasers and owners of timeshare units in the timeshare plan. The managing entity shall update this list no less frequently than quarterly. Pursuant to paragraph (3)(d), the managing entity may not publish this owner’s list or provide a copy of it to any purchaser or to any third party other than the division. However, the managing entity <Reference Number="1" />shall to those persons listed on the owner’s list materials provided by any purchaser, upon the written request of that purchaser, if the purpose of the mailing is to advance legitimate owners’ association business, such as a proxy solicitation for any purpose, including the recall of one or more board members elected by the owners or the discharge of the manager or management firm. The use of any proxies solicited in this manner must comply with the provisions of the timeshare instrument and this chapter. A mailing requested for the purpose of advancing legitimate owners’ association business shall occur within 30 days after receipt of a request from a purchaser. The board of administration of the owners’ association shall be responsible for determining the appropriateness of any mailing requested pursuant to this subsection. The purchaser who requests the mailing must reimburse the owners’ association in advance for the owners’ association’s actual costs in performing the mailing. It shall be a violation of this chapter and, if applicable, of part VIII of chapter 468, for the board of administration or the manager or management firm to refuse to mail any material requested by the purchaser to be mailed, provided the sole purpose of the materials is to advance legitimate owners’ association business. If the purpose of the mailing is a proxy solicitation to recall one or more board members elected by the owners or to discharge the manager or management firm and the managing entity does not mail the materials within 30 days after receipt of a request from a purchaser, the circuit court in the county where the timeshare plan is located may, upon application from the requesting purchaser, summarily order the mailing of the materials solely related to the recall of one or more board members elected by the owners or the discharge of the manager or management firm. The court shall dispose of an application on an expedited basis. In the event of such an order, the court may order the managing entity to pay the purchaser’s costs, including attorney’s fees reasonably incurred to enforce the purchaser’s rights, unless the managing entity can prove it refused the mailing in good faith because of a reasonable basis for doubt about the legitimacy of the mailing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any managing entity, or individual officer, director, employee, or agent thereof, who willfully misappropriates the property or funds of a timeshare plan commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, or the successor thereof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing entity of any timeshare plan located in this state, including, but not limited to, those plans created with respect to a condominium pursuant to chapter 718 or a cooperative pursuant to chapter 719, may deny the use of the accommodations and facilities of the timeshare plan, including the denial of the right to make a reservation or the cancellation of a confirmed reservation for timeshare periods in a floating reservation timeshare plan, to any purchaser who is delinquent in the payment of any assessments made by the managing entity against such purchaser for common expenses or for ad valorem real estate taxes pursuant to this chapter or pursuant to s. 192.037. Such denial of use shall also extend to those parties claiming under the delinquent purchaser described in paragraphs (b) and (c). For purposes of this subsection, a purchaser shall be considered delinquent in the payment of a given assessment only upon the expiration of 60 days after the date the assessment is billed to the purchaser or upon the expiration of 60 days after the date the assessment is due, whichever is later. For purposes of this subsection, an affiliated exchange program shall be any exchange program which has a contractual relationship with the creating developer or the managing entity of the timeshare plan, or any exchange program that notifies the managing entity in writing that it has members that are purchasers of the timeshare plan, and the exchange companies operating such affiliated exchange programs shall be affiliated exchange companies. Any denial of use for failure to pay assessments shall be implemented only pursuant to this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A managing entity desiring to deny the use of the accommodations and facilities of the timeshare plan to a delinquent purchaser and to those claiming under the purchaser, including his or her guests, lessees, and third parties receiving use rights in the timeshare period in question through a nonaffiliated exchange program, shall, no less than 30 days after the date the assessment is due in accordance with the timeshare instrument, notify the purchaser in writing of the total amount of any delinquency which then exists, including any accrued interest and late charges permitted to be imposed under the terms of the timeshare plan or by law and including a per diem amount, if any, to account for further accrual of interest and late charges between the stated effective date of the notice and the first date of use. The notice shall also clearly state that the purchaser will not be permitted to use his or her timeshare period, that the purchaser will not be permitted to make a reservation in the timeshare plan’s reservation system, or that any confirmed reservation may be canceled, as applicable, until the total amount of such delinquency is satisfied in full or until the purchaser produces satisfactory evidence that the delinquency does not exist. The notice shall be mailed to the purchaser at his or her last known address as recorded in the books and records of the timeshare plan, and the notice shall be effective to bar the use of the purchaser and those claiming use rights under the purchaser, including his or her guests, lessees, and third parties receiving use rights in the timeshare period in question through a nonaffiliated exchange program, until such time as the purchaser is no longer delinquent. The notice shall not be effective to bar the use of third parties receiving use rights in the timeshare period in question through an affiliated exchange program without the additional notice to the affiliated exchange program required by paragraph (c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to giving notice to the delinquent purchaser as required by paragraph (b), a managing entity desiring to deny the use of the accommodations and facilities of the timeshare plan to third parties receiving use rights in the delinquent purchaser’s timeshare period through any affiliated exchange program shall notify the affiliated exchange company in writing of the denial of use. The receipt of such written notice by the affiliated exchange company shall be effective to bar the use of all third parties claiming through the affiliated exchange program, and such notice shall be binding upon the affiliated exchange company and all third parties claiming through the affiliated exchange program until such time as the affiliated exchange company receives notice from the managing entity that the purchaser is no longer delinquent. However, any third party claiming through the affiliated exchange program who has received a confirmed assignment of the delinquent purchaser’s use rights from the affiliated exchange company prior to the expiration of 48 hours after the receipt by the affiliated exchange company of such written notice from the managing entity shall be permitted by the managing entity to use the accommodations and facilities of the timeshare plan to the same extent that he or she would be allowed to use such accommodations and facilities if the delinquent purchaser were not delinquent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any costs reasonably incurred by the managing entity in connection with its compliance with the requirements of paragraphs (b) and (c), together with any costs reasonably incurred by an affiliated exchange company in connection with its compliance with the requirements of paragraph (c), may be assessed by the managing entity against the delinquent purchaser and collected in the same manner as if such costs were common expenses of the timeshare plan allocable solely to the delinquent purchaser. The costs incurred by the affiliated exchange company shall be collected by the managing entity as the agent for the affiliated exchange company. In no event shall the total costs to be assessed against the delinquent purchaser pursuant to this paragraph at any one time exceed 5 percent of the total amount of delinquency contained in the notice given to the delinquent purchaser pursuant to paragraph (b) per timeshare period or $15 per timeshare period, whichever is less.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An exchange company may elect to deny exchange privileges to any member whose use of the accommodations and facilities of the member’s timeshare plan is denied pursuant to paragraph (b), and no exchange program or exchange company shall be liable to any of its members or third parties on account of any such denial of exchange privileges.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provided that the managing entity has properly and timely given notice to a delinquent purchaser pursuant to paragraph (b) and to any affiliated exchange program pursuant to paragraph (c), the managing entity may give further notice to the delinquent purchaser that it may rent the delinquent purchaser’s timeshare period, or any use rights appurtenant thereto, and will apply the proceeds of such rental, net of any rental commissions, cleaning charges, travel agent commissions, or any other commercially reasonable charges reasonably and usually incurred by the managing entity in securing rentals, to the delinquent purchaser’s account. Such further notice of intent to rent must be given at least 30 days prior to the first day of the purchaser’s use period, and must be delivered to the purchaser in the manner required for notices under paragraph (b). A managing entity may make a reasonable determination regarding the priority of rentals of timeshare periods to be rented pursuant to this paragraph and, in the event that the delinquent purchaser of a timeshare period rented pursuant to this paragraph cannot be specifically determined due to the structure of the timeshare plan, may allocate such net rental proceeds by the managing entity in any reasonable manner.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice of intent to rent, which may be included in the notice required by paragraph (b), must state in conspicuous type that:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing entity’s efforts to secure a rental will not commence on a date earlier than 10 days after the date of the notice of intent to rent.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the purchaser satisfies the delinquency in full, or unless the purchaser produces satisfactory evidence that the delinquency does not exist pursuant to paragraph (b), the purchaser will be bound by the terms of any rental contract entered into by the managing entity with respect to the purchaser’s timeshare period or appurtenant use rights.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchaser will remain liable for any difference between the amount of the delinquency and the net amount produced by the rental contract and applied against the delinquency pursuant to this paragraph, and the managing entity shall not be required to provide any further notice to the purchaser regarding any residual delinquency pursuant to this paragraph.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In securing a rental pursuant to this paragraph, the managing entity shall not be required to obtain the highest nightly rental rate available, nor any particular rental rate, and the managing entity shall not be required to rent the entire timeshare period; however, the managing entity must use reasonable efforts to secure a rental that is commensurate with other rentals of similar timeshare periods or use rights generally secured at that time. Alternatively, the managing entity may rent such units at a bulk rate that is below the rate described above but not less than $200 per week, which amount may be prorated for daily rentals.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A managing entity shall have breached its fiduciary duty described in subsection (2) in the event it enforces the denial of use pursuant to paragraph (b) against any one purchaser or group of purchasers without similarly enforcing it against all purchasers, including all developers and owners of the underlying fee or underlying personal property; however, a managing entity shall not be required to solicit rentals pursuant to paragraph (f) for every delinquent purchaser. A managing entity shall also have breached its fiduciary duty in the event an error in the books and records of the timeshare plan results in a denial of use pursuant to this subsection of any purchaser who is not, in fact, delinquent. In addition to any remedies otherwise available to purchasers of the timeshare plan arising from such breaches of fiduciary duty, such breach shall also constitute a violation of this chapter. In addition, any purchaser receiving a notice of delinquency pursuant to paragraph (b), or any third party claiming under such purchaser pursuant to paragraph (b), may immediately bring an action for injunctive or declaratory relief against the managing entity seeking to have the notice invalidated on the grounds that the purchaser is not, in fact, delinquent, that the managing entity failed to follow the procedures prescribed by this section, or on any other available grounds. The prevailing party in any such action shall be entitled to recover his or her reasonable attorney’s fees from the losing party.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the articles of incorporation, the bylaws, or the provisions of this chapter provide for a higher quorum requirement, the percentage of voting interests required to make decisions and to constitute a quorum at a meeting of the members of a timeshare condominium or owners’ association shall be 15 percent of the voting interests. If a quorum is not present at any meeting of the owners’ association at which members of the board of administration are to be elected, the meeting may be adjourned and reconvened within 90 days for the sole purpose of electing members of the board of administration, and the quorum for such adjourned meeting shall be 15 percent of the voting interests. This provision shall apply notwithstanding any provision of chapter 718 or chapter 719 to the contrary.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in s. 718.110, s. 718.113, s. 718.114, or s. 719.1055, the board of administration of any owners’ association that operates a timeshare condominium pursuant to s. 718.111, or a timeshare cooperative pursuant to s. 719.104, shall have the power to make material alterations or substantial additions to the accommodations or facilities of such timeshare condominium or timeshare cooperative without the approval of the owners’ association. However, if the timeshare condominium or timeshare cooperative contains any residential units that are not subject to the timeshare plan, such action by the board of administration must be approved by a majority of the owners of such residential units. Unless otherwise provided in the timeshare instrument as originally recorded, no such amendment may change the configuration or size of any accommodation in any material fashion, or change the proportion or percentage by which a member of the owners’ association shares the common expenses, unless the record owners of the affected units or timeshare interests and all record owners of liens on the affected units or timeshare interests join in the execution of the amendment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All notices or other information sent by a board of administration of an owners’ association may be delivered to a purchaser by electronic mail, provided that the purchaser first consents electronically to the use of electronic mail for notice purposes in a manner that reasonably demonstrates that the purchaser has the ability to access the notice by electronic mail. The consent to receive notice by electronic mail is effective until revoked by the purchaser. Proxies or written consents on votes of any owners’ association may be received by electronic mail, shall have legal effect, and may be utilized for votes of an owners’ association, provided that the electronic signature is authenticated through use of a password, cryptography software, or other reasonable means and that proof of such authentication is made available to the board of directors.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any failure of the managing entity to faithfully discharge the fiduciary duty to purchasers imposed by this section or to otherwise comply with the provisions of this section shall be a violation of this chapter and of part VIII of chapter 468.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, personal property timeshare plans are only subject to the provisions of paragraphs (1)(a)-(d), (2)(a), (3)(a)-(h) and subsections (5), (6), (9), and (10).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other rights granted by the rules and regulations of the timeshare plan, the managing entity of a timeshare plan is authorized to manage the reservation and use of accommodations using those processes, analyses, procedures, and methods that are in the best interests of the owners as a whole to efficiently manage the timeshare plan and encourage the maximum use and enjoyment of the accommodations and other benefits made available through the timeshare plan. The managing entity shall have the right to forecast anticipated reservation and use of the accommodations, including the right to take into account current and previous reservation and use of the accommodations, information about events that are scheduled to occur, seasonal use patterns, and other pertinent factors that affect the reservation or use of the accommodations. In furtherance of the provisions of this subsection, the managing entity is authorized to reserve accommodations, in the best interests of the owners as a whole, for the purposes of depositing such reserved use with an affiliated exchange program or renting such reserved accommodations in order to facilitate the use or future use of the accommodations or other benefits made available through the timeshare plan.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement in conspicuous type, in substantially the following form, shall appear in the public offering statement as provided in s. 721.07:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">The managing entity shall have the right to forecast anticipated reservation and use of the accommodations of the timeshare plan and is authorized to reasonably reserve, deposit, or rent the accommodations for the purpose of facilitating the use or future use of the accommodations or other benefits made available through the timeshare plan.</Font></Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The managing entity shall maintain copies of all records, data, and information supporting the processes, analyses, procedures, and methods utilized by the managing entity in its determination to reserve accommodations of the timeshare plan pursuant to this subsection for a period of 5 years from the date of such determination. In the event of an investigation by the division for failure of a managing entity to comply with this subsection, the managing entity shall make all such records, data, and information available to the division for inspection, provided that if the managing entity complies with the provisions of s. 721.071, any such records, data, and information provided to the division shall constitute a trade secret pursuant to that section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provisions of chapter 607, chapter 617, or chapter 718, an officer, director, or agent of an owners’ association shall discharge his or her duties in good faith, with the care an ordinarily prudent person in a like position would exercise under similar circumstances, and in a manner he or she reasonably believes to be in the interests of the owners’ association. An officer, director, or agent of an owners’ association shall be exempt from liability for monetary damages in the same manner as provided in s. 617.0834 unless such officer, director, or agent breached or failed to perform his or her duties and the breach of, or failure to perform, his or her duties constitutes a violation of criminal law as provided in s. 617.0834; constitutes a transaction from which the officer or director derived an improper personal benefit, either directly or indirectly; or constitutes recklessness or an act or omission that was in bad faith, with malicious purpose, or in a manner exhibiting wanton and willful disregard of human rights, safety, or property.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 13, ch. 83-264; s. 5, ch. 84-256; s. 52, ch. 85-62; s. 4, ch. 87-343; s. 2, ch. 88-403; s. 24, ch. 91-103; s. 9, ch. 91-236; s. 5, ch. 91-426; s. 8, ch. 93-58; s. 241, ch. 94-218; s. 11, ch. 95-274; s. 898, ch. 97-102; s. 8, ch. 98-36; s. 20, ch. 2000-302; s. 2, ch. 2002-87; s. 12, ch. 2004-279; s. 101, ch. 2006-1; s. 7, ch. 2007-75; s. 2, ch. 2010-134.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 20, ch. 2000-302. Committee Substitute for Committee Substitute for House Bill 593 became ch. 2000-302; an earlier version of that legislation added the word “mail,” without coding, after the word “shall,” but this change was not carried forward to the version of the legislation that became ch. 2000-302.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>