<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0721.81" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative purpose.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purposes of this part are to:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that timeshare interests are used for vacation experience rather than for homestead or investment purposes and that there are numerous timeshare interests in this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that the economic health and efficient operation of the vacation ownership industry are in part dependent upon the availability of an efficient and economical process for all timeshare interest foreclosures.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize the need to assist both owners’ associations and mortgagees by simplifying and expediting the process for the judicial and trustee foreclosure of assessment liens and mortgage liens against timeshare interests.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Improve judicial economy and reduce court congestion and the cost to taxpayers by establishing streamlined procedures for the judicial and trustee foreclosure of assessment liens and mortgage liens against timeshare interests.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that nearly all timeshare interest foreclosures are uncontested.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Protect the ability of consumers who own timeshare interests located in this state to choose a judicial proceeding for the foreclosure of an assessment lien or a mortgage lien against their timeshare interest.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recognize that the use of the trustee foreclosure procedure established under ss. 721.855 and 721.856 shall have the same force and effect as the use of the judicial foreclosure procedure against a timeshare interest with respect to the provisions of this chapter or any other applicable law. However, obligors shall not be subject to a deficiency judgment even if the proceeds from the sale of the timeshare interest are insufficient to offset the amounts secured by the lien.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 98-36; s. 42, ch. 2000-302; s. 5, ch. 2010-134.</History>
</Section>