<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prize and gift promotional offers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used herein, the term “prize and gift promotional offer” means any advertising material wherein a prospective purchaser may receive goods or services other than the timeshare plan itself, either free or at a discount, including, but not limited to, the use of any prize, gift, award, premium, or lodging or vacation certificate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A game promotion, such as a contest of chance, gift enterprise, or sweepstakes, in which the elements of chance and prize are present may not be used in connection with the offering or sale of timeshare interests, except for drawings, as that term is defined in s. 849.0935(1)(a), in which no more than 26 prizes are promoted and in which all promoted prizes are actually awarded. All such drawings must meet all requirements of this chapter and of ss. 849.092 and 849.094(1), (2), and (7).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any prize, gift, or other item offered pursuant to a prize and gift promotional offer must be delivered to the prospective purchaser on the day she or he appears to claim it, whether or not she or he purchases a timeshare interest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate filing for each prize and gift promotional offer to be used in the sale of timeshare interests shall be made with the division pursuant to s. 721.11(1). The developer shall pay a $100 filing fee for each prize and gift promotional offer. One item of each prize or gift, except cash, must be made available for inspection by the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each filing of a prize and gift promotional offer with the division shall include, when applicable:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of all advertising material to be used in connection with the prize and gift promotional offer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number (including area code) of the supplier or manufacturer from whom each type or variety of prize, gift, or other item is obtained.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer’s model number or other description of such item.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The information on which the developer relies in determining the verifiable retail value, if the value is in excess of $50.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number (including area code) of the promotional entity responsible for overseeing and operating the prize and gift promotional offer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the registered agent in this state of the promotional entity for service of process purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Full disclosure of all pertinent information concerning the use of lodging or vacation certificates, including the terms and conditions of the campaign and the fact and extent of participation in such campaign by the developer. The developer shall provide to the division, upon the request of the division, an affidavit, certification, or other reasonable evidence that the obligation incurred by a seller or the seller’s agent in a lodging certificate program can be met.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All advertising material to be distributed in connection with a prize and gift promotional offer shall contain, in addition to the information required pursuant to the provisions of s. 721.11, the following disclosures:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of the prize, gift, or other item that the prospective purchaser will actually receive, including, if the price is in excess of $50, the manufacturer’s suggested retail price or, if none is available, the verifiable retail value. If the value is $50 or less, the description shall contain a statement of such.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All rules, terms, requirements, and preconditions which must be fulfilled or met before a prospective purchaser may claim any prize, gift, or other item involved in the prize and gift promotional plan, including whether the prospective purchaser is required to attend a sales presentation in order to receive the prize, gift, or other item.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The date upon which the offer expires.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the number of prizes, gifts, or other items to be awarded is limited, a statement of the number of items that will be awarded.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The method by which prizes, gifts, or other items are to be awarded.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All prizes, gifts, or other items represented by the developer to be awarded in connection with any prize and gift promotional offer shall be awarded by the date referenced in the advertising material used in connection with such offer.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-264; s. 3, ch. 87-343; s. 8, ch. 91-236; s. 897, ch. 97-102; s. 18, ch. 2000-302; s. 1, ch. 2002-87.</History></Section>