<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0721.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Advertising materials; oral statements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer may file advertising material with the division for review. The division shall review any advertising material filed for review by the developer and notify the developer of any deficiencies within 10 days after the filing. If the developer corrects the deficiencies or if there are no deficiencies, the division shall notify the developer of its approval of the advertising materials. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained in this subsection, so long as the developer uses advertising materials approved by the division, following the developer’s request for a review, the developer shall not be liable for any violation of this section or s. 721.111 with respect to such advertising materials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All advertising materials must be substantially in compliance with this chapter and in full compliance with the mandatory provisions of this chapter. In the event that any such material is not in substantial compliance with this chapter, the division may file administrative charges and an injunction against the developer and exact such penalties or remedies as provided in s. 721.26, or may require the developer to correct any deficiency in the materials by notifying the developer of the deficiency. If the developer fails to correct the deficiency after such notification, the division may file administrative charges against the developer and exact such penalties or remedies as provided in s. 721.26.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “advertising material” includes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any promotional brochure, pamphlet, advertisement, or other material to be disseminated to the public in connection with the sale of a timeshare plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any radio or television advertisement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any lodging or vacation certificate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any standard oral sales presentation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any billboard or other sign posted on or off the premises, except that such billboard or sign shall not be required to contain the disclosure set forth in paragraph (5)(a) or paragraph (5)(b), unless it relates to a prize and gift promotional offer. For purposes of this section, a “sign” shall mean advertising which is affixed to real or personal property and which is not disseminated by other than visual means to prospective purchasers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any photograph, drawing, or artist’s representation of accommodations or facilities of a timeshare plan which exists or which will or may exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any paid publication relating to a timeshare plan which exists or which will or may exist.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other promotional device used, or statement related to a timeshare plan, including any prize and gift promotional offer as described in s. 721.111.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “advertising material” does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any stockholder communication such as an annual report or interim financial report, proxy material, registration statement, securities prospectus, registration, property report, or other material required to be delivered to a prospective purchaser by an agency of any other state or the Federal Government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any communication addressed to and relating to the account of any person who has previously executed a contract for the sale and purchase of a timeshare interest in the timeshare plan to which the communication relates, except when directed to the sale of timeshare interests in a different timeshare plan or in a different component site of a multisite timeshare plan subject to part II.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any audio, written, or visual publication or material relating to an exchange company or exchange program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any audio, written, or visual publication or material relating to the promotion of the availability of any accommodations or facilities, or both, for transient rental, including any arrangement governed by part XI of chapter 559, so long as a mandatory tour of a timeshare plan or attendance at a mandatory sales presentation is not a term or condition of the availability of such accommodations or facilities, or both, and so long as the failure of any transient renter to take a tour of a timeshare plan or attend a sales presentation does not result in the transient renter receiving less than what was promised to the transient renter in such materials.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any oral or written statement disseminated by a developer to broadcast or print media, other than paid advertising or promotional material, regarding plans for the acquisition or development of timeshare property, including possible accommodations or facilities of a timeshare plan pursuant to subsection (7) or subsection (8), or possible component sites of a multisite timeshare plan pursuant to subsection (9). However, any rebroadcast or any other dissemination of such oral statements to a prospective purchaser by a seller in any manner, or any distribution of copies of newspaper or magazine articles, press releases, or any other dissemination of such written statements to a prospective purchaser by a seller in any manner, shall constitute advertising material.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any promotional materials relating to a timeshare plan that are not directed specifically at residents of this state, regardless of whether such materials relate to accommodations or facilities located in this state, provided that such materials do not contain any statements that would be in violation of subsection (4). For purposes of this paragraph, a rebuttable presumption shall exist that promotional materials are not directed specifically at residents of this state if the materials include a disclaimer in substantially the following form:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This offer is not directed to residents in any state [or the offer is void in any states] in which a registration of the timeshare plan is required but in which registration requirements have not yet been met.</Font></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any materials delivered to a purchaser after the purchase contract is executed that are not delivered for the purpose of soliciting the sale of a timeshare interest in a different timeshare plan or a different component site in a multisite timeshare plan subject to part II, provided that such materials do not contain any statements that would be in violation of subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any materials exclusively shown, displayed, or presented in a sales center or during a sales presentation provided that such materials do not contain any statements that would be in violation of subsection (4) and that any description of any facility that is not required to be built or that has not been completed shall be conspicuously labeled as “NEED NOT BE BUILT,” “PROPOSED,” or “UNDER CONSTRUCTION.” If the facility is labeled “NEED NOT BE BUILT” or “PROPOSED,” the seller may indicate the estimated date that such facility will be made part of the timeshare plan. If the facility is labeled “UNDER CONSTRUCTION,” the estimated date of completion must be included.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No advertising or oral statement made by any seller or resale service provider shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent a fact or create a false or misleading impression regarding the timeshare plan or promotion thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make a prediction of specific or immediate increases in the price or value of timeshare interests.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain a statement concerning future price increases by a seller which are nonspecific or not bona fide.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain any asterisk or other reference symbol as a means of contradicting or substantially changing any previously made statement or as a means of obscuring a material fact.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe any facility that is not required to be built or that is uncompleted unless the improvement is conspicuously labeled as “NEED NOT BE BUILT,” “PROPOSED,” or “UNDER CONSTRUCTION.” If the facility is labeled “NEED NOT BE BUILT” or “PROPOSED,” the seller may indicate the estimated date that such facility will be made part of the timeshare plan. If the facility is labeled “UNDER CONSTRUCTION,” the estimated date of completion must be included.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the size, nature, extent, qualities, or characteristics of the offered accommodations or facilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the amount or period of time during which the accommodations or facilities will be available to any purchaser.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the nature or extent of any incidental benefit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make any misleading or deceptive representation with respect to the contents of the public offering statement and the contract or the rights, privileges, benefits, or obligations of the purchaser under the contract or this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the conditions under which a purchaser may exchange the right to use accommodations or facilities in one location for the right to use accommodations or facilities in another location.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the availability of a resale or rental program or resale or rental opportunity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contain an offer or inducement to purchase which purports to be limited as to quantity or restricted as to time unless the numerical quantity or time limit applicable to the offer or inducement is clearly stated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imply that a facility is available for the exclusive use of purchasers if the facility will actually be shared by others or by the general public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purport to have resulted from a referral unless the name of the person making the referral can be produced upon demand of the division.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the source of the advertising or statement by leading a prospective purchaser to believe that the advertising material is mailed by a governmental or official agency, credit bureau, bank, or attorney, if that is not the case.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="p"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent the value of any prize, gift, or other item to be awarded in connection with any prize and gift promotional offer, as described in s. 721.111, or any incidental benefit.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="q"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Misrepresent or falsely imply that the resale service provider is affiliated with, or obtained personal contact information from, a developer, managing entity, or exchange company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No written advertising material, including any lodging certificate, gift award, premium, discount, or display booth, may be utilized without each prospective purchaser being provided a disclosure in conspicuous type in substantially the following form: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This advertising material is being used for the purpose of soliciting sales of timeshare interests;</Font> or <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This advertising material is being used for the purpose of soliciting sales of a vacation (or vacation membership or vacation ownership) plan.</Font> The division shall have the discretion to approve the use of an alternate disclosure. The conspicuous disclosure required in this subsection shall only be required to be given to each prospective purchaser on one piece of advertising for each advertising promotion or marketing campaign, provided that if the promotion or campaign contains terms and conditions, the conspicuous disclosure required in this subsection shall be included on any piece containing such terms and conditions. The conspicuous disclosure required in this subsection shall be provided before the purchaser is required to take any affirmative action pursuant to the promotion. If the advertising material containing the conspicuous disclosure is a display booth, the disclosure required by this subsection must be conspicuously displayed on or within the display booth.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection does not apply to any advertising material which involves a project or development which includes sales of real estate or other commodities or services in addition to timeshare interests, including, but not limited to, lot sales, condominium or home sales, or the rental of resort accommodations. However, if the sale of timeshare interests, as compared with such other sales or rentals, is the primary purpose of the advertising material, a disclosure shall be made in conspicuous type that: <Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">This advertising material is being used for the purpose of soliciting the sale of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Disclosure shall include timeshare interests and may include other types of sales)</Directions>.</Font> Factors which the division may consider in determining whether the primary purpose of the advertising material is the sale of timeshare interests include:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The retail value of the timeshare interests compared to the retail value of the other real estate, commodities, or services being offered in the advertising material.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of space devoted to the timeshare portion of the project in the advertising material compared to the amount of space devoted to other portions of the project, including, but not limited to, printed material, photographs, or drawings.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to provide cancellation rights or disclosures as required by this subsection in connection with the sale of a regulated short-term product constitutes misrepresentation in accordance with paragraph (4)(a). Any agreement relating to the sale of a regulated short-term product must be regulated as advertising material and is subject to the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A standard form of any agreement relating to the sale of a regulated short-term product may be filed 10 days prior to use with the division as advertising material under this section. Each seller shall furnish each purchaser of a regulated short-term product with a fully completed and executed copy of the agreement at the time of execution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A purchaser of a regulated short-term product has the right to cancel the agreement until midnight of the 10th calendar day following the execution date of the agreement. The right of cancellation may not be waived by the prospective purchaser or by any other person on behalf of the prospective purchaser. Notice of cancellation must be given in the same manner prescribed for giving notice of cancellation under s. 721.10(2). If the prospective purchaser gives a valid notice of cancellation or is otherwise entitled to cancel the sale, the funds or other property received from or on behalf of the prospective purchaser, or the proceeds thereof, must be returned to the prospective purchaser. Such refund must be made in the same manner prescribed for refunds under s. 721.10.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agreement for purchase of a regulated short-term product must contain substantially the following statements, given at the time the agreement is made:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that if the purchaser of a regulated short-term product cancels the agreement during the 10-day cancellation period, the seller will refund to the prospective purchaser the total amount of all payments made by the prospective purchaser under the agreement, reduced by the proportion of any benefits the prospective purchaser has actually received under the agreement prior to the effective date of the cancellation; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement that the specific value for each benefit received by the prospective purchaser under the agreement will be as agreed to between the prospective purchaser and the seller.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An agreement for purchase of a regulated short-term product must contain substantially the following statements in conspicuous type immediately above the space reserved in the agreement for the signature of the prospective purchaser:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">You may cancel this agreement without any penalty or obligation within 10 calendar days [or specify a longer time period represented to the purchaser] after the date you sign this agreement. If you decide to cancel this agreement, you must notify the seller in writing of your intent to cancel. Your notice of cancellation is effective upon the date sent and must be sent to <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Name of Seller)</Directions> at <Directions xml:space="preserve">(Address of Seller)</Directions>. Any attempt to obtain a waiver of your cancellation right is unlawful.</Font></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">If you execute a purchase contract for a timeshare interest, section 721.08, Florida Statutes (escrow accounts), will apply to any funds or other property received from you or on your behalf. Section 721.10, Florida Statutes (cancellation), will apply to the purchase and you will not be entitled to a cancellation refund of the short-term product [or specify an alternate refund policy under these circumstances].</Font></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the seller provides the purchaser with the right to cancel the purchase of a regulated short-term product at any time up to 7 days prior to the purchaser’s reserved use of the accommodations, but in no event less than 10 days, and if the seller refunds the total amount of all payments made by the purchaser reduced by the proportion of any benefits the purchaser has actually received prior to the effective date of the cancellation, the specific value of which has been agreed to between the purchaser and the seller, the short-term product offer shall be exempt from the requirements of paragraphs (b), (c), and (d). An agreement relating to the sale of the regulated short-term product made pursuant to this paragraph must contain a statement setting forth the cancellation and refund rights of the prospective purchaser in a manner that is consistent with this section and s. 721.10, including a description of the length of the cancellation right, a statement that the purchaser’s intent to cancel must be in writing and sent to the seller at a specified address, a statement that the notice of cancellation is effective upon the date sent, and a statement that any attempt to waive the cancellation right is unlawful. The right of cancellation provided to the purchaser pursuant to this paragraph may not be waived by the prospective purchaser or by any other person on behalf of the prospective purchaser. Notice of cancellation must be given in the same manner prescribed for giving notice of cancellation pursuant to s. 721.10(2). If the prospective purchaser gives a valid notice of cancellation, or is otherwise entitled to cancel the sale, the funds or other property received from or on behalf of the prospective purchaser, or the proceeds thereof, shall be returned to the prospective purchaser. Such refund shall be made in the manner prescribed for refunds under s. 721.10.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 721.05(7)(b), a seller may portray possible accommodations or facilities to prospective purchasers in advertising material, or a purchaser public offering statement, without such accommodations or facilities being available for use by purchasers so long as the advertising material or purchaser public offering statement complies with the provisions of subsection (4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 721.05(7)(b), a developer may portray possible accommodations or facilities to prospective purchasers by disseminating oral or written statements regarding same to broadcast or print media with no obligation on the developer’s part to actually construct such accommodations or facilities or to file such accommodations or facilities with the division, but only so long as such oral or written statements are not considered advertising material pursuant to paragraph (3)(e).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 721.05(7)(b), a seller of a multisite timeshare plan may portray a possible component site to prospective purchasers with no accommodations or facilities located at such component site being available for use by purchasers so long as the seller satisfies the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A developer of a multisite timeshare plan may disseminate oral or written statements to broadcast or print media describing a possible component site with no obligation on the developer’s part to actually add such component site to the multisite timeshare plan or to amend the developer’s filing with the division, but only so long as such oral or written statements are not considered advertising material pursuant to paragraph (3)(e).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A seller may make representations to purchasers in advertising material or in a purchaser public offering statement regarding the possible accommodations and facilities of a possible component site without such accommodations or facilities being available for use by purchasers so long as the advertising material or purchaser public offering statement complies with the provisions of subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event a seller makes any of the representations permitted by paragraph (b), the purchase agreement must contain the following conspicuous disclosure unless and until such time as the developer has committed itself in the timeshare instrument to adding the possible component site to the multisite timeshare plan, at which time the seller may portray the component site pursuant to the timeshare instrument without restriction:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">[Description of possible component site] is only a possible component site which may never be added to the multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club). Do not purchase an interest in the multisite timeshare plan (or multisite vacation ownership plan or multisite vacation plan or vacation club) in reliance upon the addition of this component site.</Font></Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding anything contained in this chapter to the contrary, a developer or managing entity may communicate with existing purchasers regarding possible component sites without restriction, so long as all oral and written statements made to existing purchasers pursuant to this subsection comply with the provisions of subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any violation of this subsection by a developer, seller, or managing entity shall constitute a violation of this chapter. Any violation of this subsection with respect to a purchaser whose purchase has not yet closed shall be deemed to provide that purchaser with a new 10-day voidability period.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 81-172; s. 157, ch. 83-216; s. 10, ch. 83-264; s. 2, ch. 87-343; s. 54, ch. 90-339; s. 64, ch. 91-110; s. 7, ch. 91-236; s. 7, ch. 93-58; s. 10, ch. 95-274; s. 7, ch. 98-36; s. 17, ch. 2000-302; s. 10, ch. 2004-279; s. 5, ch. 2007-75.</History></Section>