<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0049.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice of action, publication, proof.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All notices of action, except those referred to in paragraphs (b) and (c), shall be published once during each week for 4 consecutive weeks (four publications being sufficient) in some newspaper published in the county where the court is located. The newspaper shall meet such requirements as are prescribed by law for such purpose.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In proceedings described in s. 49.011(4), (10), and (11), the clerk of the court shall post notices of action in the manner prescribed by s. 49.11 when such notices are required of persons authorized to proceed as indigent under s. 57.081.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notices of action in foreclosure proceedings as defined in s. 702.09 shall be published once during each week for 2 consecutive weeks (two publications being sufficient) in some newspaper published in the county where the court is located. The newspaper shall meet such requirements as are prescribed by law for such purpose.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of publication shall be made by affidavit of the owner, publisher, proprietor, editor, business manager, foreman or other officer or employee of the newspaper having knowledge of such publication. The affidavit shall set forth or have attached a copy of the notice, shall set forth the dates of each publication and otherwise comply with the requirements of law.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 20452, 1941; s. 5, ch. 28301, 1953; s. 2, ch. 29737, 1955; s. 5, ch. 67-254; s. 2, ch. 74-152; s. 1, ch. 75-205; s. 8, ch. 93-250; s. 67, ch. 2003-402.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 48.10.</Text></Note></Section>