<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0049.061" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sworn statement, parties doing business under a corporate name as defendants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sworn statement of the plaintiff, his or her agent or attorney, for service of process by publication against parties who have or may have done business under a corporate name, shall show:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name under which said parties have operated or done business; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That, after diligent search and inquiry, the affiant has been unable to ascertain whether or not the organization operating under said name was a corporation, either domestic or foreign; and</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names, and places of residence if known, of all persons known to have been interested in such organization, and whether or not other or unknown persons may have been interested in such organization; or that, after diligent search and inquiry, all persons interested in such organization are unknown to the affiant, and, unless all such persons are unknown to the affiant,</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the known persons interested in such organization, either:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Are absent from this state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cannot be found within this state; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conceal themselves so that process cannot be personally served upon them; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That their whereabouts are unknown to the affiant.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 20452, 1941; s. 5, ch. 67-254; s. 289, ch. 95-147.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 48.06.</Text></Note></Section>