<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0049.011" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Service of process by publication; cases in which allowed.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Service of process by publication may be made in any court on any party identified in s. 49.021 in any action or proceeding:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To enforce any legal or equitable lien or claim to any title or interest in real or personal property within the jurisdiction of the court or any fund held or debt owing by any party on whom process can be served within this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To quiet title or remove any encumbrance, lien, or cloud on the title to any real or personal property within the jurisdiction of the court or any fund held or debt owing by any party on whom process can be served within this state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To partition real or personal property within the jurisdiction of the court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For dissolution or annulment of marriage.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the construction of any will, deed, contract, or other written instrument and for a judicial declaration or enforcement of any legal or equitable right, title, claim, lien, or interest thereunder.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To reestablish a lost instrument or record which has or should have its situs within the jurisdiction of the court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In which a writ of replevin, garnishment, or attachment has been issued and executed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In which any other writ or process has been issued and executed which places any property, fund, or debt in the custody of a court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To revive a judgment by motion or scire facias.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For adoption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In which personal service of process or notice is not required by the statutes or constitution of this state or by the Constitution of the United States.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In probate or guardianship proceedings in which personal service of process or notice is not required by the statutes or constitution of this state or by the Constitution of the United States.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For termination of parental rights pursuant to part VIII of chapter 39 or chapter 63.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For temporary custody of a minor child, under chapter 751.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To determine paternity, but only as to the legal father in a paternity action in which another man is alleged to be the biological father, in which case it is necessary to serve process on the legal father in order to establish paternity with regard to the alleged biological father.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 20452, 1941; s. 5, ch. 67-254; s. 15, ch. 71-355; s. 1, ch. 73-5; s. 1, ch. 73-300; s. 13, ch. 84-311; s. 7, ch. 93-104; s. 45, ch. 94-164; s. 14, ch. 98-280; s. 20, ch. 99-2; s. 1, ch. 2007-85; s. 2, ch. 2008-151; s. 8, ch. 2010-30; s. 44, ch. 2011-213.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 48.01.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>