<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0049.071" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Sworn statement, unknown parties as defendants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If relief is demanded against unknown parties, the sworn statement for service of process by publication against them shall show:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That affiant believes that there are persons who are or may be interested in the subject matter of the action or proceedings whose names, after diligent search and inquiry, are unknown to the affiant; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether said unknown parties claim as heirs, devisees, grantees, assignees, lienors, creditors, trustees, or other claimants:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By, through, under or against a known person who is dead or not known to be dead or alive; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By, through, under or against some corporation, domestic or foreign, that has been dissolved or which is not known to be existing or dissolved; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By, through, under or against some organization which operated or did business under a name indicating a corporation; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Otherwise as the case may be.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any case alleged against a named defendant, natural or corporate, who is stated, either in the pleadings or in the sworn statement, to be either dead or dissolved, or not known to be dead or alive, or dissolved or existing, any judgment, decree or order rendered against such defendant shall be as good, valid and effectual as if it had not been so stated.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 20452, 1941; s. 5, ch. 67-254.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 48.07.</Text></Note></Section>