<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.625" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petition for support, or support and education, of ward’s dependents; payments of apportioned benefits prohibit contempt action against veteran.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is dependent on a ward for support may petition a court of competent jurisdiction for an order directing the guardian of the ward’s estate to contribute from the estate of the ward to the support, or support and education, of the dependent person, when the estate of the ward is derived in whole or in part from payments of compensation, adjusted compensation, pension, insurance, or other benefits made directly to the guardian of the ward by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs. A notice of the application for support, or support and education, shall be given by the applicant to the office of the United States Department of Veterans Affairs having jurisdiction over the area in which the court is located at least 15 days before the hearing on the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The grant or denial of an order for support, or support and education, does not preclude a further petition for an increase, decrease, modification, or termination of the allowance for such support, or support and education, by either the petitioner or the guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order for the support, or support and education, of the petitioner is valid for any payment made pursuant to the order, but no valid payment can be made after the termination of the guardianship. The receipt of the petitioner shall be a sufficient release of the guardian for payments made pursuant to the order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a claim for apportionment of benefits filed with the United States Department of Veterans Affairs on behalf of a dependent or dependents of a disabled veteran is approved by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, subsequent payments of such apportioned benefits by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs prohibit an action for contempt from being instituted against the veteran.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 84-62; s. 47, ch. 93-268.</History></Section>