<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.107" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Court monitors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may, upon inquiry from any interested person or upon its own motion in any proceeding over which it has jurisdiction, appoint a monitor. The court shall not appoint as a monitor a family member or any person with a personal interest in the proceedings. The order of appointment shall be served upon the guardian, the ward, and such other persons as the court may determine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The monitor may investigate, seek information, examine documents, or interview the ward and shall report to the court his or her findings. The report shall be verified and shall be served on the guardian, the ward, and such other persons as the court may determine.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it appears from the monitor’s report that further action by the court to protect the interests of the ward is necessary, the court shall, after a hearing with notice, enter any order necessary to protect the ward or the ward’s estate, including amending the plan, requiring an accounting, ordering production of assets, freezing assets, suspending a guardian, or initiating proceedings to remove a guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless otherwise prohibited by law, a monitor may be allowed a reasonable fee as determined by the court and paid from the property of the ward. No full-time state, county, or municipal employee or officer shall be paid a fee for such investigation and report. If the court finds the motion for court monitor to have been filed in bad faith, the costs of the proceeding, including attorney’s fees, may be assessed against the movant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 18, 26, ch. 75-222; s. 10, ch. 89-96; s. 4, ch. 90-271; s. 1068, ch. 97-102; s. 2, ch. 2006-77.</History></Section>