<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.365" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Verified inventory.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FILING.<EmDash />A guardian of the property shall file a verified inventory of the ward’s property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CONTENTS.<EmDash />The verified inventory must include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All property of the ward, real and personal, that has come into the guardian’s possession or knowledge, including a statement of all encumbrances, liens, and other secured claims on any item, any claims against the property, any cause of action accruing to the ward, and any trusts of which the ward is a beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The location of the real and personal property in sufficient detail so that it may be clearly identified or located.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of all sources of income, including, without limitation, social security benefits and pensions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CASH ASSETS.<EmDash />Along with the verified inventory, the guardian must file a copy of the most current statement of all of the ward’s cash assets from all institutions where the cash is on deposit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SAFE-DEPOSIT BOX.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial opening of any safe-deposit box of the ward must be conducted in the presence of an employee of the institution where the box is located. The inventory of the contents of the box also must be conducted in the presence of the employee, who must verify the contents of the box by signing a copy of the inventory. This safe-deposit box inventory shall be filed with the court within 10 days after the box is opened.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guardian shall provide the ward with a copy of each signed safe-deposit box inventory unless the ward is a minor or has been adjudicated totally incapacitated or unless the order appointing the guardian states otherwise.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing may be removed from the ward’s safe-deposit box without specific court approval.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDS RETENTION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The guardian shall maintain substantiating papers and records sufficient to demonstrate the accuracy of the initial inventory for a period of 3 years after her or his discharge. The substantiating papers need not be filed with the court but must be made available for inspection and review at such time and place and before such persons as the court may order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of the substantiating papers, the guardian must identify by name, address, and occupation, the witness or witnesses, if any, who were present during the initial inventory of the ward’s personal property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">AUDIT FEE.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where the value of the ward’s property exceeds $25,000, a guardian shall pay from the ward’s property to the clerk of the circuit court a fee of up to $85, upon the filing of the verified inventory, for the auditing of the inventory. Upon petition by the guardian, the court may waive the auditing fee upon a showing of insufficient funds in the ward’s estate. Any guardian unable to pay the auditing fee may petition the court for waiver of the fee. The court may waive the fee after it has reviewed the documentation filed by the guardian in support of the waiver.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An audit fee may not be charged to any ward whose property has a value of less than $25,000.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 49, ch. 89-96; s. 32, ch. 90-271; s. 1087, ch. 97-102; s. 115, ch. 2003-402; s. 77, ch. 2004-265; s. 14, ch. 2006-178; s. 40, ch. 2008-111.</History></Section>