<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.446" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conflicts of interest; prohibited activities; court approval; breach of fiduciary duty.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is essential to the proper conduct and management of a guardianship that the guardian be independent and impartial. The fiduciary relationship which exists between the guardian and the ward may not be used for the private gain of the guardian other than the remuneration for fees and expenses provided by law. The guardian may not incur any obligation on behalf of the guardianship which conflicts with the proper discharge of the guardian’s duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless prior approval is obtained by court order, or unless such relationship existed prior to appointment of the guardian and is disclosed to the court in the petition for appointment of guardian, a guardian may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have any interest, financial or otherwise, direct or indirect, in any business transaction or activity with the guardianship;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire an ownership, possessory, security, or other pecuniary interest adverse to the ward;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be designated as a beneficiary on any life insurance policy, pension, or benefit plan of the ward unless such designation was validly made by the ward prior to adjudication of incapacity of the ward; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Directly or indirectly purchase, rent, lease, or sell any property or services from or to any business entity of which the guardian or the guardian’s spouse or any of the guardian’s lineal descendants, or collateral kindred, is an officer, partner, director, shareholder, or proprietor, or has any financial interest.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any activity prohibited by this section is voidable during the term of the guardianship or by the personal representative of the ward’s estate, and the guardian is subject to removal and to imposition of personal liability through a proceeding for surcharge, in addition to any other remedies otherwise available.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event of a breach by the guardian of the guardian’s fiduciary duty, the court shall take those necessary actions to protect the ward and the ward’s assets.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 75, ch. 89-96; s. 54, ch. 90-271; s. 1102, ch. 97-102; s. 6, ch. 2002-195.</History></Section>