<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.306" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Foreign guardians.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the residence of a ward of a foreign guardian is moved to this state, the guardian shall, within 60 days after such change of residence, file the authenticated order of her or his appointment with the clerk of the court in the county where the ward resides. Such order shall be recognized and given full faith and credit in the courts of this state. The guardian and the ward are subject to this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guardian appointed in any state, territory, or country may maintain or defend any action in this state as a representative of her or his ward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Debtors who have received no written demand for payment from a guardian appointed in this state within 60 days after the appointment of a guardian, curator, conservator, or committee in any state, territory, or country other than this state, and whose property in this state is subject to a mortgage or other lien securing the debt held by the foreign guardian, curator, conservator, or committee, may pay the debt to the foreign guardian, curator, conservator, or committee after the expiration of 60 days from the date of her or his appointment. A satisfaction of the mortgage or lien, executed after the 60 days have expired by the foreign guardian, curator, conservator, or committee, with an authenticated copy of the letters or other evidence of authority of the foreign guardian, curator, conservator, or committee attached, may be recorded in the public records of this state and shall constitute an effective discharge of the mortgage or lien, irrespective of whether the debtor had received written demand before paying the debt.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All persons indebted to a ward, or having possession of personal property belonging to a ward, who have received no written demand for payment of the indebtedness or the delivery of the property from a guardian appointed in this state are authorized to pay the indebtedness or to deliver the personal property to the foreign guardian, curator, conservator, or committee after the expiration of the 60 days from the date of her or his appointment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 7, ch. 75-222; s. 23, ch. 89-96; s. 1072, ch. 97-102.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 744.15.</Text></Note></Section>