<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.3145" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Guardian education requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each ward is entitled to a guardian competent to perform the duties of a guardian necessary to protect the interests of the ward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person appointed by the court to be a guardian, other than a parent who is the guardian of the property of a minor child, must receive a minimum of 8 hours of instruction and training which covers:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The legal duties and responsibilities of the guardian;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rights of the ward;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The availability of local resources to aid the ward; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preparation of habilitation plans and annual guardianship reports, including financial accounting for the ward’s property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person appointed by the court to be the guardian of the property of his or her minor child must receive a minimum of 4 hours of instruction and training that covers:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The legal duties and responsibilities of the guardian of the property;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preparation of the initial inventory and annual guardianship accountings for the ward’s property; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use of guardianship assets.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person appointed by the court to be a guardian must complete the required number of hours of instruction and education within 4 months after his or her appointment as guardian. The instruction and education must be completed through a course approved by the chief judge of the circuit court and taught by a court-approved organization. Court-approved organizations may include, but are not limited to, community or junior colleges, guardianship organizations, and the local bar association or The Florida Bar.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses incurred by the guardian to satisfy the education requirement may be paid from the ward’s estate, unless the court directs that such expenses be paid by the guardian individually.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may, in its discretion, waive some or all of the requirements of this section or impose additional requirements. The court shall make its decision on a case-by-case basis and, in making its decision, shall consider the experience and education of the guardian, the duties assigned to the guardian, and the needs of the ward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section do not apply to professional guardians.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 31, ch. 89-96; s. 17, ch. 90-271; s. 1077, ch. 97-102; s. 3, ch. 97-161; s. 11, ch. 2003-57; s. 9, ch. 2006-178.</History></Section>