<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.712" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Joining Forces for Public Guardianship grant program; purpose.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Joining Forces for Public Guardianship matching grant program shall be established and administered by the Statewide Public Guardianship Office within the Department of Elderly Affairs. The purpose of the program is to provide startup funding to encourage communities to develop and administer locally funded and supported public guardianship programs to address the needs of indigent and incapacitated residents.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Statewide Public Guardianship Office may distribute the grant funds as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As initial startup funding to encourage counties that have no office of public guardian to establish an office, or as initial startup funding to open an additional office of public guardian within a county whose public guardianship needs require more than one office of public guardian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As support funding to operational offices of public guardian that demonstrate a necessity for funds to meet the public guardianship needs of a particular geographic area in the state which the office serves.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assist counties that have an operating public guardianship program but that propose to expand the geographic area or population of persons they serve, or to develop and administer innovative programs to increase access to public guardianship in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding this subsection, the executive director of the office may award emergency grants if he or she determines that the award is in the best interests of public guardianship in this state. Before making an emergency grant, the executive director must obtain the written approval of the Secretary of Elderly Affairs. Subsections (2), (3), and (4) do not apply to the distribution of emergency grant funds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more grants may be awarded within a county. However, a county may not receive an award that equals, or multiple awards that cumulatively equal, more than 20 percent of the total amount of grant funds appropriated during any fiscal year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an applicant is eligible and meets the requirements to receive grant funds more than once, the Statewide Public Guardianship Office shall award funds to prior awardees in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the second year that grant funds are awarded, the cumulative sum of the award provided to one or more applicants within the same county may not exceed 75 percent of the total amount of grant funds awarded within that county in year one.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the third year that grant funds are awarded, the cumulative sum of the award provided to one or more applicants within the same county may not exceed 60 percent of the total amount of grant funds awarded within that county in year one.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the fourth year that grant funds are awarded, the cumulative sum of the award provided to one or more applicants within the same county may not exceed 45 percent of the total amount of grant funds awarded within that county in year one.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the fifth year that grant funds are awarded, the cumulative sum of the award provided to one or more applicants within the same county may not exceed 30 percent of the total amount of grant funds awarded within that county in year one.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the sixth year that grant funds are awarded, the cumulative sum of the award provided to one or more applicants within the same county may not exceed 15 percent of the total amount of grant funds awarded within that county in year one.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The Statewide Public Guardianship Office may not award grant funds to any applicant within a county that has received grant funds for more than 6 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Grant funds shall be used only to provide direct services to indigent wards, except that up to 10 percent of the grant funds may be retained by the awardee for administrative expenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Implementation of the program is subject to a specific appropriation by the Legislature in the General Appropriations Act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2004-260.</History></Section>