<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Guardian’s and attorney’s fees and expenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guardian, or an attorney who has rendered services to the ward or to the guardian on the ward’s behalf, is entitled to a reasonable fee for services rendered and reimbursement for costs incurred on behalf of the ward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When fees for a guardian or an attorney are submitted to the court for determination, the court shall consider the following criteria:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time and labor required;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The novelty and difficulty of the questions involved and the skill required to perform the services properly;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The likelihood that the acceptance of the particular employment will preclude other employment of the person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fee customarily charged in the locality for similar services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and value of the incapacitated person’s property, the amount of income earned by the estate, and the responsibilities and potential liabilities assumed by the person;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The results obtained;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The time limits imposed by the circumstances;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and length of the relationship with the incapacitated person; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The experience, reputation, diligence, and ability of the person performing the service.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In awarding fees to attorney guardians, the court must clearly distinguish between fees and expenses for legal services and fees and expenses for guardian services and must have determined that no conflict of interest exists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fees for legal services may include customary and reasonable charges for work performed by legal assistants employed by and working under the direction of the attorney.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All petitions for guardian’s and attorney’s fees and expenses must be accompanied by an itemized description of the services performed for the fees and expenses sought to be recovered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for fees or expenses may not be approved without prior notice to the guardian and to the ward, unless the ward is a minor or is totally incapacitated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for fees shall include the period covered and the total amount of all prior fees paid or costs awarded to the petitioner in the guardianship proceeding currently before the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When court proceedings are instituted to review or determine a guardian’s or an attorney’s fees under subsection (2), such proceedings are part of the guardianship administration process and the costs, including fees for the guardian’s attorney, shall be determined by the court and paid from the assets of the guardianship estate unless the court finds the requested compensation under subsection (2) to be substantially unreasonable.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 18, 26, ch. 75-222; s. 11, ch. 89-96; s. 5, ch. 90-271; s. 2, ch. 96-354; s. 7, ch. 2003-57.</History></Section>