<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.3215" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rights of persons determined incapacitated.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who has been determined to be incapacitated retains the right:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have an annual review of the guardianship report and plan.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have continuing review of the need for restriction of his or her rights.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be restored to capacity at the earliest possible time.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be treated humanely, with dignity and respect, and to be protected against abuse, neglect, and exploitation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have a qualified guardian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To remain as independent as possible, including having his or her preference as to place and standard of living honored, either as he or she expressed or demonstrated his or her preference prior to the determination of his or her incapacity or as he or she currently expresses his or her preference, insofar as such request is reasonable.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be properly educated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive prudent financial management for his or her property and to be informed how his or her property is being managed, if he or she has lost the right to manage property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive services and rehabilitation necessary to maximize the quality of life.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be free from discrimination because of his or her incapacity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have access to the courts.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To counsel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To receive visitors and communicate with others.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To notice of all proceedings related to determination of capacity and guardianship, unless the court finds the incapacitated person lacks the ability to comprehend the notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="o"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To privacy.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rights that may be removed from a person by an order determining incapacity but not delegated to a guardian include the right:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To marry. If the right to enter into a contract has been removed, the right to marry is subject to court approval.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To vote.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To personally apply for government benefits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To have a driver’s license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To travel.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To seek or retain employment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rights that may be removed from a person by an order determining incapacity and which may be delegated to the guardian include the right:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To contract.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To sue and defend lawsuits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To apply for government benefits.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To manage property or to make any gift or disposition of property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To determine his or her residence.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To consent to medical and mental health treatment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make decisions about his or her social environment or other social aspects of his or her life.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without first obtaining specific authority from the court, as described in s. 744.3725, a guardian may not:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commit the ward to a facility, institution, or licensed service provider without formal placement proceeding, pursuant to chapter 393, chapter 394, or chapter 397.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent on behalf of the ward to the performance on the ward of any experimental biomedical or behavioral procedure or to the participation by the ward in any biomedical or behavioral experiment. The court may permit such performance or participation only if:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is of direct benefit to, and is intended to preserve the life of or prevent serious impairment to the mental or physical health of the ward; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is intended to assist the ward to develop or regain his or her abilities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Initiate a petition for dissolution of marriage for the ward.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent on behalf of the ward to termination of the ward’s parental rights.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consent on behalf of the ward to the performance of a sterilization or abortion procedure on the ward.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 89-96; s. 19, ch. 90-271; s. 36, ch. 93-39; s. 13, ch. 94-183; s. 44, ch. 96-169; s. 6, ch. 96-354; s. 1782, ch. 97-102; s. 10, ch. 2006-178.</History></Section>