<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.3675" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Annual guardianship plan.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each guardian of the person must file with the court an annual guardianship plan which updates information about the condition of the ward. The annual plan must specify the current needs of the ward and how those needs are proposed to be met in the coming year.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each plan for an adult ward must, if applicable, include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning the residence of the ward, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ward’s address at the time of filing the plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of each place where the ward was maintained during the preceding year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The length of stay of the ward at each place.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of whether the current residential setting is best suited for the current needs of the ward.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Plans for ensuring during the coming year that the ward is in the best residential setting to meet his or her needs.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning the medical and mental health conditions and treatment and rehabilitation needs of the ward, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resume of any professional medical treatment given to the ward during the preceding year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The report of a physician who examined the ward no more than 90 days before the beginning of the applicable reporting period. The report must contain an evaluation of the ward’s condition and a statement of the current level of capacity of the ward.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan for providing medical, mental health, and rehabilitative services in the coming year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning the social condition of the ward, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The social and personal services currently used by the ward.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The social skills of the ward, including a statement of how well the ward communicates and maintains interpersonal relationships.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The social needs of the ward.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each plan filed by the legal guardian of a minor must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning the residence of the minor, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The minor’s address at the time of filing the plan.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of each place the minor lived during the preceding year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning the medical and mental health conditions and treatment and rehabilitation needs of the minor, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A resume of any professional medical treatment given to the minor during the preceding year.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A report from the physician who examined the minor no more than 180 days before the beginning of the applicable reporting period that contains an evaluation of the minor’s physical and mental conditions.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan for providing medical services in the coming year.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information concerning the education of the minor, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary of the school progress report.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The social development of the minor, including a statement of how well the minor communicates and maintains interpersonal relationships.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The social needs of the minor.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each plan for an adult ward must address the issue of restoration of rights to the ward and include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A summary of activities during the preceding year that were designed to enhance the capacity of the ward.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of whether the ward can have any rights restored.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A statement of whether restoration of any rights will be sought.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court, in its discretion, may require reexamination of the ward by a physician at any time.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 51, ch. 89-96; s. 34, ch. 90-271; s. 11, ch. 96-354; s. 1786, ch. 97-102; s. 4, ch. 97-161; s. 16, ch. 2006-178.</History></Section>