<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.312" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Considerations in appointment of guardian.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of subsection (4), the court may appoint any person who is fit and proper and qualified to act as guardian, whether related to the ward or not.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall give preference to the appointment of a person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is related by blood or marriage to the ward;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has educational, professional, or business experience relevant to the nature of the services sought to be provided;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has the capacity to manage the financial resources involved; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has the ability to meet the requirements of the law and the unique needs of the individual case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court shall also:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider the wishes expressed by an incapacitated person as to who shall be appointed guardian;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider the preference of a minor who is age 14 or over as to who should be appointed guardian;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consider any person designated as guardian in any will in which the ward is a beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person designated is qualified to serve pursuant to s. 744.309, the court shall appoint any standby guardian or preneed guardian, unless the court determines that appointing such person is contrary to the best interests of the ward.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 12, ch. 75-222; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 5, ch. 79-221; s. 27, ch. 89-96; s. 15, ch. 90-271.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 744.35.</Text></Note></Section>