<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.341" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Voluntary guardianship.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without adjudication of incapacity, the court shall appoint a guardian of the property of a resident or nonresident person who, though mentally competent, is incapable of the care, custody, and management of his or her estate by reason of age or physical infirmity and who has voluntarily petitioned for the appointment. The petition shall be accompanied by a certificate of a licensed physician specifying that he or she has examined the petitioner and that the petitioner is competent to understand the nature of the guardianship and his or her delegation of authority. Notice of hearing on any petition for appointment and for authority to act shall be given to the petitioner and to any person to whom the petitioner requests that notice be given. Such request may be made in the petition for appointment of guardian or in a subsequent written request for notice signed by the petitioner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If requested in the petition for appointment of a guardian brought under this section, the court may direct the guardian to take possession of less than all of the ward’s property and of the rents, income, issues, and profits from it. In such case, the court shall specify in its order the property to be included in the guardianship estate, and the duties and responsibilities of the guardian appointed under this section will extend only to such property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the voluntary guardianship is limited pursuant to subsection (2), any guardian appointed under this section has the same duties and responsibilities as are provided by law for plenary guardians of the property, generally.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guardian must include in the annual report filed with the court a certificate from a licensed physician who examined the ward not more than 90 days before the annual report is filed with the court. The certificate must certify that the ward is competent to understand the nature of the guardianship and of the ward’s authority to delegate powers to the voluntary guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A voluntary guardianship may be terminated by the ward by filing a notice with the court that the voluntary guardianship is terminated. A copy of the notice must be served on all interested persons.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 26, ch. 75-222; s. 9, ch. 79-221; s. 4, ch. 84-31; s. 38, ch. 89-96; s. 23, ch. 90-271; s. 1080, ch. 97-102; s. 12, ch. 2006-178.</History></Section>