<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.1083" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Professional guardian registration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A professional guardian must register with the Statewide Public Guardianship Office established in part IX of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annual registration shall be made on forms furnished by the Statewide Public Guardianship Office and accompanied by the applicable registration fee as determined by rule. The fee may not exceed $100.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registration must include the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient information to identify the professional guardian, as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the professional guardian is a natural person, the name, address, date of birth, and employer identification or social security number of the person.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the professional guardian is a partnership or association, the name, address, and employer identification number of the entity.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Documentation that the bonding and educational requirements of s. 744.1085 have been met.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sufficient information to distinguish a guardian providing guardianship services as a public guardian, individually, through partnership, corporation, or any other business organization.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to registering a professional guardian, the Statewide Public Guardianship Office must receive and review copies of the credit and criminal investigations conducted under s. 744.3135. The credit and criminal investigations must have been completed within the previous 2 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the office may deny registration to a professional guardian if the executive director determines that the guardian’s proposed registration, including the guardian’s credit or criminal investigations, indicates that registering the professional guardian would violate any provision of this chapter. If a guardian who is currently registered with the office violates a provision of this chapter, the executive director of the office may suspend or revoke the guardian’s registration. If the executive director denies registration to a professional guardian or suspends or revokes a professional guardian’s registration, the Statewide Public Guardianship Office must send written notification of the denial, suspension, or revocation to the chief judge of each judicial circuit in which the guardian was serving on the day of the office’s decision to deny, suspend, or revoke the registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs may adopt rules necessary to administer this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trust company, a state banking corporation or state savings association authorized and qualified to exercise fiduciary powers in this state, or a national banking association or federal savings and loan association authorized and qualified to exercise fiduciary powers in this state, may, but is not required to, register as a professional guardian under this section. If a trust company, state banking corporation, state savings association, national banking association, or federal savings and loan association described in this subsection elects to register as a professional guardian under this subsection, the requirements of subsections (3) and (4) do not apply and the registration must include only the name, address, and employer identification number of the registrant, the name and address of its registered agent, if any, and the documentation described in paragraph (3)(b).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs may contract with the Florida Guardianship Foundation or other not-for-profit entity to register professional guardians.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or its contractor shall ensure that the clerks of the court and the chief judge of each judicial circuit receive information about each registered professional guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state college or university or an independent college or university that is located and chartered in Florida, that is accredited by the Commission on Colleges of the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools or the Accrediting Council for Independent Colleges and Schools, and that confers degrees as defined in s. 1005.02(7) may, but is not required to, register as a professional guardian under this section. If a state college or university or independent college or university elects to register as a professional guardian under this subsection, the requirements of subsections (3) and (4) do not apply and the registration must include only the name, address, and employer identification number of the registrant.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 2002-195; s. 8, ch. 2003-57; s. 10, ch. 2004-260; s. 2, ch. 2006-178; s. 2, ch. 2009-175.</History></Section>