<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Attorney for the alleged incapacitated person” means an attorney who represents the alleged incapacitated person. The attorney shall represent the expressed wishes of the alleged incapacitated person to the extent it is consistent with the rules regulating The Florida Bar.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Audit” means a systematic review of financial and all other documents to ensure compliance with s. 744.368, rules of court, and local procedures using generally accepted accounting principles.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Clerk” means the clerk or deputy clerk of the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Corporate guardian” means a corporation authorized to exercise fiduciary or guardianship powers in this state and includes a nonprofit corporate guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court” means the circuit court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court monitor” means a person appointed by the court under s. 744.107 to provide the court with information concerning a ward.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Estate” means the property of a ward subject to administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Foreign guardian” means a guardian appointed in another state or country.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Guardian” means a person who has been appointed by the court to act on behalf of a ward’s person or property, or both.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Limited guardian” means a guardian who has been appointed by the court to exercise the legal rights and powers specifically designated by court order entered after the court has found that the ward lacks the capacity to do some, but not all, of the tasks necessary to care for his or her person or property, or after the person has voluntarily petitioned for appointment of a limited guardian.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Plenary guardian” means a person who has been appointed by the court to exercise all delegable legal rights and powers of the ward after the court has found that the ward lacks the capacity to perform all of the tasks necessary to care for his or her person or property.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Guardian ad litem” means a person who is appointed by the court having jurisdiction of the guardianship or a court in which a particular legal matter is pending to represent a ward in that proceeding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Guardian advocate” means a person appointed by a written order of the court to represent a person with developmental disabilities under s. 393.12. As used in this chapter, the term does not apply to a guardian advocate appointed for a person determined incompetent to consent to treatment under s. 394.4598.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Incapacitated person” means a person who has been judicially determined to lack the capacity to manage at least some of the property or to meet at least some of the essential health and safety requirements of the person.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To “manage property” means to take those actions necessary to obtain, administer, and dispose of real and personal property, intangible property, business property, benefits, and income.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To “meet essential requirements for health or safety” means to take those actions necessary to provide the health care, food, shelter, clothing, personal hygiene, or other care without which serious and imminent physical injury or illness is more likely than not to occur.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Minor” means a person under 18 years of age whose disabilities have not been removed by marriage or otherwise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Next of kin” means those persons who would be heirs at law of the ward or alleged incapacitated person if the person were deceased and includes the lineal descendants of the ward or alleged incapacitated person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Nonprofit corporate guardian” means a nonprofit corporation organized for religious or charitable purposes and existing under the laws of this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preneed guardian” means a person named in a written declaration to serve as guardian in the event of the incapacity of the declarant as provided in s. 744.3045.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Professional guardian” means any guardian who has at any time rendered services to three or more wards as their guardian. A person serving as a guardian for two or more relatives as defined in s. 744.309(2) is not considered a professional guardian. A public guardian shall be considered a professional guardian for purposes of regulation, education, and registration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property” means both real and personal property or any interest in it and anything that may be the subject of ownership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Standby guardian” means a person empowered to assume the duties of guardianship upon the death or adjudication of incapacity of the last surviving natural or appointed guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Surrogate guardian” means a guardian designated according to s. 744.442.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Totally incapacitated” means incapable of exercising any of the rights enumerated in s. 744.3215(2) and (3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ward” means a person for whom a guardian has been appointed.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 2, ch. 75-222; s. 231, ch. 77-104; s. 1, ch. 79-221; s. 3, ch. 80-171; s. 4, ch. 89-96; s. 2, ch. 90-271; s. 1, ch. 96-354; s. 1780, ch. 97-102; s. 6, ch. 2003-57; s. 9, ch. 2004-260; s. 1, ch. 2006-178.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 744.03.</Text></Note></Section>