<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.3031" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency temporary guardianship.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court, prior to appointment of a guardian but after a petition for determination of incapacity has been filed pursuant to this chapter, may appoint an emergency temporary guardian for the person or property, or both, of an alleged incapacitated person. The court must specifically find that there appears to be imminent danger that the physical or mental health or safety of the person will be seriously impaired or that the person’s property is in danger of being wasted, misappropriated, or lost unless immediate action is taken. The subject of the proceeding or any adult interested in the welfare of that person may apply to the court in which the proceeding is pending for the emergency appointment of a temporary guardian. The powers and duties of the emergency temporary guardian must be specifically enumerated by court order. The court shall appoint counsel to represent the alleged incapacitated person during any such summary proceedings, and such appointed counsel may request that the proceeding be recorded and transcribed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may appoint an emergency temporary guardian on its own motion if no petition for appointment of guardian has been filed at the time of entry of an order determining incapacity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority of an emergency temporary guardian expires 90 days after the date of appointment or when a guardian is appointed, whichever occurs first. The authority of the emergency temporary guardian may be extended for an additional 90 days upon a showing that the emergency conditions still exist.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may issue an injunction, restraining order, or other appropriate writ to protect the physical or mental health or safety of the person who is the ward of the emergency temporary guardianship.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The emergency temporary guardian shall take an oath to faithfully perform the duties of a guardian before letters of emergency temporary guardianship are issued.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before exercising authority as guardian, the emergency temporary guardian of the property may be required to file a bond in accordance with s. 744.351.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An emergency temporary guardian’s authority and responsibility begins upon issuance of letters of emergency temporary guardianship in accordance with s. 744.345.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An emergency temporary guardian shall file a final report no later than 30 days after the expiration of the emergency temporary guardianship.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an emergency temporary guardian is a guardian for the property, the final report must consist of a verified inventory of the property, as provided in s. 744.365, as of the date the letters of emergency temporary guardianship were issued, a final accounting that gives a full and correct account of the receipts and disbursements of all the property of the ward over which the guardian had control, and a statement of the property of the ward on hand at the end of the emergency temporary guardianship. If the emergency temporary guardian becomes the successor guardian of the property, the final report must satisfy the requirements of the initial guardianship report for the guardian of the property as provided in s. 744.362.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the emergency temporary guardian is a guardian of the person, the final report must summarize the activities of the temporary guardian with regard to residential placement, medical condition, mental health and rehabilitative services, and the social condition of the ward to the extent of the authority granted to the temporary guardian in the letters of guardianship. If the emergency temporary guardian becomes the successor guardian of the person, the report must satisfy the requirements of the initial report for a guardian of the person as stated in s. 744.362.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copy of the final report of the emergency temporary guardianship shall be served on the successor guardian and the ward.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 89-96; s. 10, ch. 90-271; s. 1070, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 2006-178.</History></Section>