<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.344" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Order of appointment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may hear testimony on the question of who is entitled to preference in the appointment of a guardian. Any interested person may intervene in the proceedings. The order appointing a guardian must state the nature of the guardianship as either plenary or limited. If limited, the order must state that the guardian may exercise only those delegable rights which have been removed from the incapacitated person and specifically delegated to the guardian. The order shall state the specific powers and duties of the guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The order appointing a guardian must be consistent with the incapacitated person’s welfare and safety, must be the least restrictive appropriate alternative, and must reserve to the incapacitated person the right to make decisions in all matters commensurate with the person’s ability to do so.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a petition for appointment of guardian has been filed, an order appointing a guardian must be issued contemporaneously with the order adjudicating the person incapacitated. The order must specify the amount of the bond to be given by the guardian and must state specifically whether the guardian must place all, or part, of the property of the ward in a restricted account in a financial institution designated pursuant to s. 69.031.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a petition for the appointment of a guardian has not been filed at the time of the hearing on the petition to determine capacity, the court may appoint an emergency temporary guardian in the manner and for the purposes specified in s. 744.3031.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plenary guardian shall exercise all delegable rights and powers of the incapacitated person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person for whom a limited guardian has been appointed retains all legal rights except those which have been specifically granted to the guardian in the court’s written order.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; ss. 12, 26, ch. 75-222; s. 39, ch. 89-96; s. 24, ch. 90-271; s. 1081, ch. 97-102.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 744.34.</Text></Note></Section>