<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.613" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appointment of guardian for ward authorized.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever, pursuant to any law of the United States or regulation of the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, the secretary requires, prior to the payment of benefits, that a guardian be appointed for a ward, the appointment may be made in the manner hereinafter provided.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a petition is filed for the appointment of a guardian of a minor ward, a certificate of the secretary or the secretary’s authorized representative setting forth the age of such minor, as shown by the records of the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, and a statement that the appointment of a guardian is a condition precedent to the payment of any moneys due to the minor by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs are prima facie evidence of the necessity for such appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a petition is filed for the appointment of a guardian of a mentally incompetent ward, a certificate of the secretary or the secretary’s authorized representative, setting forth the fact that the person has been found incompetent and has been rated incompetent by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, on examination in accordance with the laws and regulations governing the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, and that the appointment of a guardian is a condition precedent to the payment of any moneys due to such person by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, is prima facie evidence of the necessity for such appointment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 5, 6, ch. 14579, 1929; CGL 1936 Supp. 2146(3), (6), (7); s. 1, ch. 73-304; s. 5, ch. 84-62; s. 42, ch. 93-268; s. 1116, ch. 97-102.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of former ss. 293.03, 293.06, 293.07.</Text></Note></Section>