<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.3045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Preneed guardian.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A competent adult may name a preneed guardian by making a written declaration that names such guardian to serve in the event of the declarant’s incapacity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The written declaration must reasonably identify the declarant and preneed guardian and be signed by the declarant in the presence of at least two attesting witnesses present at the same time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The declarant may file the declaration with the clerk of the court. When a petition for incapacity is filed, the clerk shall produce the declaration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Production of the declaration in a proceeding for incapacity shall constitute a rebuttable presumption that the preneed guardian is entitled to serve as guardian. The court shall not be bound to appoint the preneed guardian if the preneed guardian is found to be unqualified to serve as guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The preneed guardian shall assume the duties of guardian immediately upon an adjudication of incapacity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the preneed guardian refuses to serve, a written declaration appointing an alternate preneed guardian constitutes a rebuttable presumption that such preneed guardian is entitled to serve as guardian. The court is not bound to appoint the alternate preneed guardian if the alternate preneed guardian is found to be unqualified to serve as guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 20 days after assumption of duties as guardian, a preneed guardian shall petition for confirmation of appointment. If the court finds the preneed guardian to be qualified to serve as guardian pursuant to ss. 744.309 and 744.312, appointment of the guardian must be confirmed. Each guardian so confirmed shall file an oath in accordance with s. 744.347 and shall file a bond, if required. Letters of guardianship must then be issued in the manner provided in s. 744.345.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 21, ch. 89-96; s. 12, ch. 90-271.</History></Section>