<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0744.616" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Petition for appointment of guardian.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for the appointment of a guardian may be filed in any court of competent jurisdiction by, or on behalf of, any person who under existing law is entitled to priority of appointment. If no person is so entitled, or if the person so entitled neglects or refuses to file such a petition within 30 days after the mailing of notice by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs to the last known address of such person, indicating the necessity for filing the petition, a petition for such appointment may be filed in any court of competent jurisdiction by, or on behalf of, any responsible person residing in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The petition for appointment shall set forth:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, age, and place of residence of the ward;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names and places of residence of the nearest relative, if known;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The fact that the ward is entitled to receive moneys payable by or through the United States Department of Veterans Affairs;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of moneys then due and the amount of probable future payments;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and address of the person or institution, if any, having actual custody of the ward; and</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, age, relationship, if any, occupation, and address of the proposed guardian.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a mentally incompetent ward, the petition shall show that the ward has been found incompetent and has been rated incompetent on examination by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, in accordance with the laws and regulations governing the United States Department of Veterans Affairs.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 14579, 1929; CGL 1936 Supp. 2146(5); s. 1, ch. 73-304; s. 6, ch. 84-62; s. 43, ch. 93-268.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 293.05.</Text></Note></Section>