<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.9905" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicant” means an individual owner, corporation, partnership, firm, business, association, or other entity that owns or controls, directly or indirectly, 5 percent or more of an interest in the clinic and that applies for a clinic license.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Chief financial officer” means an individual who has at least a minimum of a bachelor’s degree from an accredited university in accounting or finance, or a related field, and who is the person responsible for the preparation of a clinic’s billing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Clinic” means an entity where health care services are provided to individuals and which tenders charges for reimbursement for such services, including a mobile clinic and a portable equipment provider. As used in this part, the term does not include and the licensure requirements of this part do not apply to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities licensed or registered by the state under chapter 395; entities licensed or registered by the state and providing only health care services within the scope of services authorized under their respective licenses under ss. 383.30-383.335, chapter 390, chapter 394, chapter 397, this chapter except part X, chapter 429, chapter 463, chapter 465, chapter 466, chapter 478, part I of chapter 483, chapter 484, or chapter 651; end-stage renal disease providers authorized under 42 C.F.R. part 405, subpart U; providers certified under 42 C.F.R. part 485, subpart B or subpart H; or any entity that provides neonatal or pediatric hospital-based health care services or other health care services by licensed practitioners solely within a hospital licensed under chapter 395.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities that own, directly or indirectly, entities licensed or registered by the state pursuant to chapter 395; entities that own, directly or indirectly, entities licensed or registered by the state and providing only health care services within the scope of services authorized pursuant to their respective licenses under ss. 383.30-383.335, chapter 390, chapter 394, chapter 397, this chapter except part X, chapter 429, chapter 463, chapter 465, chapter 466, chapter 478, part I of chapter 483, chapter 484, <Reference Number="1"/>or chapter 651; end-stage renal disease providers authorized under 42 C.F.R. part 405, subpart U; providers certified under 42 C.F.R. part 485, subpart B or subpart H; or any entity that provides neonatal or pediatric hospital-based health care services by licensed practitioners solely within a hospital licensed under chapter 395.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, by an entity licensed or registered by the state pursuant to chapter 395; entities that are owned, directly or indirectly, by an entity licensed or registered by the state and providing only health care services within the scope of services authorized pursuant to their respective licenses under ss. 383.30-383.335, chapter 390, chapter 394, chapter 397, this chapter except part X, chapter 429, chapter 463, chapter 465, chapter 466, chapter 478, part I of chapter 483, chapter 484, or chapter 651; end-stage renal disease providers authorized under 42 C.F.R. part 405, subpart U; providers certified under 42 C.F.R. part 485, subpart B or subpart H; or any entity that provides neonatal or pediatric hospital-based health care services by licensed practitioners solely within a hospital under chapter 395.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities that are under common ownership, directly or indirectly, with an entity licensed or registered by the state pursuant to chapter 395; entities that are under common ownership, directly or indirectly, with an entity licensed or registered by the state and providing only health care services within the scope of services authorized pursuant to their respective licenses under ss. 383.30-383.335, chapter 390, chapter 394, chapter 397, this chapter except part X, chapter 429, chapter 463, chapter 465, chapter 466, chapter 478, part I of chapter 483, chapter 484, or chapter 651; end-stage renal disease providers authorized under 42 C.F.R. part 405, subpart U; providers certified under 42 C.F.R. part 485, subpart B or subpart H; or any entity that provides neonatal or pediatric hospital-based health care services by licensed practitioners solely within a hospital licensed under chapter 395.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An entity that is exempt from federal taxation under 26 U.S.C. s. 501(c)(3) or (4), an employee stock ownership plan under 26 U.S.C. s. 409 that has a board of trustees at least two-thirds of which are Florida-licensed health care practitioners and provides only physical therapy services under physician orders, any community college or university clinic, and any entity owned or operated by the federal or state government, including agencies, subdivisions, or municipalities thereof.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sole proprietorship, group practice, partnership, or corporation that provides health care services by physicians covered by s. 627.419, that is directly supervised by one or more of such physicians, and that is wholly owned by one or more of those physicians or by a physician and the spouse, parent, child, or sibling of that physician.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sole proprietorship, group practice, partnership, or corporation that provides health care services by licensed health care practitioners under chapter 457, chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, chapter 461, chapter 462, chapter 463, chapter 466, chapter 467, chapter 480, chapter 484, chapter 486, chapter 490, chapter 491, or part I, part III, part X, part XIII, or part XIV of chapter 468, or s. 464.012, and that is wholly owned by one or more licensed health care practitioners, or the licensed health care practitioners set forth in this paragraph and the spouse, parent, child, or sibling of a licensed health care practitioner if one of the owners who is a licensed health care practitioner is supervising the business activities and is legally responsible for the entity’s compliance with all federal and state laws. However, a health care practitioner may not supervise services beyond the scope of the practitioner’s license, except that, for the purposes of this part, a clinic owned by a licensee in s. 456.053(3)(b) which provides only services authorized pursuant to s. 456.053(3)(b) may be supervised by a licensee specified in s. 456.053(3)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical facilities affiliated with an accredited medical school at which training is provided for medical students, residents, or fellows.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities that provide only oncology or radiation therapy services by physicians licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 or entities that provide oncology or radiation therapy services by physicians licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 which are owned by a corporation whose shares are publicly traded on a recognized stock exchange.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Clinical facilities affiliated with a college of chiropractic accredited by the Council on Chiropractic Education at which training is provided for chiropractic students.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities that provide licensed practitioners to staff emergency departments or to deliver anesthesia services in facilities licensed under chapter 395 and that derive at least 90 percent of their gross annual revenues from the provision of such services. Entities claiming an exemption from licensure under this paragraph must provide documentation demonstrating compliance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Orthotic or prosthetic clinical facilities that are a publicly traded corporation or that are wholly owned, directly or indirectly, by a publicly traded corporation. As used in this paragraph, a publicly traded corporation is a corporation that issues securities traded on an exchange registered with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission as a national securities exchange.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities that are owned by a corporation that has $250 million or more in total annual sales of health care services provided by licensed health care practitioners where one or more of the owners is a health care practitioner who is licensed in this state and who is responsible for supervising the business activities of the entity and is legally responsible for the entity’s compliance with state law for purposes of this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Entities that employ 50 or more licensed health care practitioners licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 where the billing for medical services is under a single tax identification number. The application for exemption under this subsection shall contain information that includes: the name, residence, and business address and phone number of the entity that owns the practice; a complete list of the names and contact information of all the officers and directors of the corporation; the name, residence address, business address, and medical license number of each licensed Florida health care practitioner employed by the entity; the corporate tax identification number of the entity seeking an exemption; a listing of health care services to be provided by the entity at the health care clinics owned or operated by the entity and a certified statement prepared by an independent certified public accountant which states that the entity and the health care clinics owned or operated by the entity have not received payment for health care services under personal injury protection insurance coverage for the preceding year. If the agency determines that an entity which is exempt under this subsection has received payments for medical services under personal injury protection insurance coverage, the agency may deny or revoke the exemption from licensure under this subsection.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Notwithstanding this subsection, an entity shall be deemed a clinic and must be licensed under this part in order to receive reimbursement under the Florida Motor Vehicle No-Fault Law, ss. 627.730-627.7405, unless exempted under s. 627.736(5)(h).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical director” means a physician who is employed or under contract with a clinic and who maintains a full and unencumbered physician license in accordance with chapter 458, chapter 459, chapter 460, or chapter 461. However, if the clinic does not provide services pursuant to the respective physician practices acts listed in this subsection, it may appoint a Florida-licensed health care practitioner who does not provide services pursuant to the respective physician practices acts listed in this subsection to serve as a clinic director who is responsible for the clinic’s activities. A health care practitioner may not serve as the clinic director if the services provided at the clinic are beyond the scope of that practitioner’s license, except that a licensee specified in s. 456.053(3)(b) who provides only services authorized pursuant to s. 456.053(3)(b) may serve as clinic director of an entity providing services as specified in s. 456.053(3)(b).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mobile clinic” means a movable or detached self-contained health care unit within or from which direct health care services are provided to individuals and which otherwise meets the definition of a clinic in subsection (4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Portable equipment provider” means an entity that contracts with or employs persons to provide portable equipment to multiple locations performing treatment or diagnostic testing of individuals, that bills third-party payors for those services, and that otherwise meets the definition of a clinic in subsection (4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2003-411; s. 14, ch. 2004-298; ss. 26, 33, ch. 2004-350; s. 1, ch. 2005-262; s. 7, ch. 2006-192; s. 71, ch. 2006-197; s. 122, ch. 2007-230; s. 38, ch. 2012-160; s. 2, ch. 2012-197.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The word “or” was inserted by the editors.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>