<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.995" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Agency administrative penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of part II of chapter 408, the agency may deny the application for a license renewal, revoke and suspend the license, and impose administrative fines of up to $5,000 per violation for violations of the requirements of this part or rules of the agency. In determining if a penalty is to be imposed and in fixing the amount of the fine, the agency shall consider the following factors:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The gravity of the violation, including the probability that death or serious physical or emotional harm to a patient will result or has resulted, the severity of the action or potential harm, and the extent to which the provisions of the applicable laws or rules were violated.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Actions taken by the owner, medical director, or clinic director to correct violations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous violations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The financial benefit to the clinic of committing or continuing the violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each day of continuing violation after the date fixed for termination of the violation, as ordered by the agency, constitutes an additional, separate, and distinct violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action taken to correct a violation shall be documented in writing by the owner, medical director, or clinic director of the clinic and verified through followup visits by agency personnel. The agency may impose a fine and, in the case of an owner-operated clinic, revoke or deny a clinic’s license when a clinic medical director or clinic director knowingly misrepresents actions taken to correct a violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensed clinic whose owner, medical director, or clinic director concurrently operates an unlicensed clinic shall be subject to an administrative fine of $5,000 per day.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any clinic whose owner fails to apply for a change-of-ownership license and operates the clinic under the new ownership is subject to a fine of $5,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">During an inspection, the agency shall make a reasonable attempt to discuss each violation with the owner, medical director, or clinic director of the clinic, prior to written notification.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2003-411; s. 18, ch. 2004-298; s. 30, ch. 2004-350; s. 131, ch. 2007-230; s. 104, ch. 2008-4; s. 46, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>