<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.93" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure required; exemptions; unlawful acts; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity that holds itself out to the public as providing home medical equipment and services or accepts physician orders for home medical equipment and services is subject to licensure under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity that holds itself out to the public as providing home medical equipment that typically requires home medical services is subject to licensure under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this part and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the agency pursuant to this part. A license issued by the agency is required in order to provide home medical equipment and services in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A separate license is required of all home medical equipment providers operating on separate premises, even if the providers are operated under the same management.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from home medical equipment provider licensure, unless they have a separate company, corporation, or division that is in the business of providing home medical equipment and services for sale or rent to consumers at their regular or temporary place of residence pursuant to the provisions of this part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providers operated by the Department of Health or Federal Government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nursing homes licensed under part II.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisted living facilities licensed under chapter 429, when serving their residents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home health agencies licensed under part III.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospices licensed under part IV.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Intermediate care facilities, homes for special services, and transitional living facilities licensed under part V.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hospitals and ambulatory surgical centers licensed under chapter 395.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufacturers and wholesale distributors when not selling directly to consumers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensed health care practitioners who utilize home medical equipment in the course of their practice, but do not sell or rent home medical equipment to their patients.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pharmacies licensed under chapter 465.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of s. 408.812 is a deceptive and unfair trade practice and constitutes a violation of the Florida Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates s. 408.812 commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. A person who commits a second or subsequent violation commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Each day of continuing violation constitutes a separate offense.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-189; s. 2, ch. 2001-214; s. 68, ch. 2006-197; s. 107, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>