<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.147" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Internal risk management and quality assurance program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every facility shall, as part of its administrative functions, establish an internal risk management and quality assurance program, the purpose of which is to assess resident care practices; review facility quality indicators, facility incident reports, deficiencies cited by the agency, and resident grievances; and develop plans of action to correct and respond quickly to identified quality deficiencies. The program must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A designated person to serve as risk manager, who is responsible for implementation and oversight of the facility’s risk management and quality assurance program as required by this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A risk management and quality assurance committee consisting of the facility risk manager, the administrator, the director of nursing, the medical director, and at least three other members of the facility staff. The risk management and quality assurance committee shall meet at least monthly.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Policies and procedures to implement the internal risk management and quality assurance program, which must include the investigation and analysis of the frequency and causes of general categories and specific types of adverse incidents to residents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development and implementation of an incident reporting system based upon the affirmative duty of all health care providers and all agents and employees of the licensed health care facility to report adverse incidents to the risk manager, or to his or her designee, within 3 business days after their occurrence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The development of appropriate measures to minimize the risk of adverse incidents to residents, including, but not limited to, education and training in risk management and risk prevention for all nonphysician personnel, as follows:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such education and training of all nonphysician personnel must be part of their initial orientation; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 1 hour of such education and training must be provided annually for all nonphysician personnel of the licensed facility working in clinical areas and providing resident care.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The analysis of resident grievances that relate to resident care and the quality of clinical services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The internal risk management and quality assurance program is the responsibility of the facility administrator.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the programs mandated by this section, other innovative approaches intended to reduce the frequency and severity of adverse incidents to residents and violations of residents’ rights shall be encouraged and their implementation and operation facilitated.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each internal risk management and quality assurance program shall include the use of incident reports to be filed with the risk manager and the facility administrator. The risk manager shall have free access to all resident records of the licensed facility. The incident reports are part of the workpapers of the attorney defending the licensed facility in litigation relating to the licensed facility and are subject to discovery, but are not admissible as evidence in court. A person filing an incident report is not subject to civil suit by virtue of such incident report. As a part of each internal risk management and quality assurance program, the incident reports shall be used to develop categories of incidents which identify problem areas. Once identified, procedures shall be adjusted to correct the problem areas.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of reporting to the agency under this section, the term “adverse incident” means:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An event over which facility personnel could exercise control and which is associated in whole or in part with the facility’s intervention, rather than the condition for which such intervention occurred, and which results in one of the following:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Death;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Brain or spinal damage;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Permanent disfigurement;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fracture or dislocation of bones or joints;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A limitation of neurological, physical, or sensory function;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any condition that required medical attention to which the resident has not given his or her informed consent, including failure to honor advanced directives;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any condition that required the transfer of the resident, within or outside the facility, to a unit providing a more acute level of care due to the adverse incident, rather than the resident’s condition prior to the adverse incident; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An event that is reported to law enforcement or its personnel for investigation; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resident elopement, if the elopement places the resident at risk of harm or injury.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The internal risk manager of each licensed facility shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Investigate every allegation of sexual misconduct which is made against a member of the facility’s personnel who has direct patient contact when the allegation is that the sexual misconduct occurred at the facility or at the grounds of the facility;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Report every allegation of sexual misconduct to the administrator of the licensed facility; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the resident representative or guardian of the victim that an allegation of sexual misconduct has been made and that an investigation is being conducted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nursing home facility shall initiate an investigation within 1 business day after the risk manager or his or her designee has received a report pursuant to paragraph (1)(d). The facility must complete the investigation and submit a report to the agency within 15 calendar days after the adverse incident occurred. The agency shall develop a form for the report which must include the name of the risk manager, information regarding the identity of the affected resident, the type of adverse incident, the initiation of an investigation by the facility, and whether the events causing or resulting in the adverse incident represent a potential risk to any other resident. The report is confidential as provided by law and is not discoverable or admissible in any civil or administrative action, except in disciplinary proceedings by the agency or the appropriate regulatory board. The agency may investigate, as it deems appropriate, any such incident and prescribe measures that must or may be taken in response to the incident. The agency shall review each report and determine whether it potentially involved conduct by the health care professional who is subject to disciplinary action, in which case the provisions of s. 456.073 shall apply.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abuse, neglect, or exploitation must be reported to the agency as required by 42 C.F.R. s. 483.13(c) and to the department as required by chapters 39 and 415.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall review, as part of its licensure inspection process, the internal risk management and quality assurance program at each facility regulated by this section to determine whether the program meets standards established in statutory laws and rules, is being conducted in a manner designed to reduce adverse incidents, and is appropriately reporting incidents as required by this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is no monetary liability on the part of, and a cause of action for damages may not arise against, any risk manager for the implementation and oversight of the internal risk management and quality assurance program in a facility licensed under this part as required by this section, or for any act or proceeding undertaken or performed within the scope of the functions of such internal risk management and quality assurance program if the risk manager acts without intentional fraud.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the agency, through its receipt of the adverse incident reports prescribed in subsection (7), or through any investigation, has a reasonable belief that conduct by a staff member or employee of a facility is grounds for disciplinary action by the appropriate regulatory board, the agency shall report this fact to the regulatory board.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may adopt rules to administer this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information gathered by a credentialing organization under a quality assurance program is not discoverable from the credentialing organization. This subsection does not limit discovery of, access to, or use of facility records, including those records from which the credentialing organization gathered its information.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 24, ch. 2001-45; s. 8, ch. 2002-400; s. 40, ch. 2009-223; s. 8, ch. 2012-160.</History>
</Section>