<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.925" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Accrediting organizations” means the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations or other national accreditation agencies whose standards for accreditation are comparable to those required by this part for licensure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Consumer” or “patient” means any person who uses home medical equipment in his or her place of residence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General manager” means the individual who has the general administrative charge of the premises of a licensed home medical equipment provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home medical equipment” includes any product as defined by the Federal Drug Administration’s Drugs, Devices and Cosmetics Act, any products reimbursed under the Medicare Part B Durable Medical Equipment benefits, or any products reimbursed under the Florida Medicaid durable medical equipment program. Home medical equipment includes oxygen and related respiratory equipment; manual, motorized, or customized wheelchairs and related seating and positioning, but does not include prosthetics or orthotics or any splints, braces, or aids custom fabricated by a licensed health care practitioner; motorized scooters; personal transfer systems; and specialty beds, for use by a person with a medical need.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home medical equipment provider” means any person or entity that sells or rents or offers to sell or rent to or for a consumer:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any home medical equipment and services; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home medical equipment that requires any home medical equipment services.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home medical equipment provider personnel” means persons who are employed by or under contract with a home medical equipment provider.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home medical equipment services” means equipment management and consumer instruction, including selection, delivery, setup, and maintenance of equipment, and other related services for the use of home medical equipment in the consumer’s regular or temporary place of residence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Life-supporting or life-sustaining equipment” means a device that is essential to, or that yields information that is essential to, the restoration or continuation of a bodily function important to the continuation of human life. Life-supporting or life-sustaining equipment includes apnea monitors, enteral feeding pumps, infusion pumps, portable home dialysis equipment, and ventilator equipment and supplies for all related equipment, including oxygen equipment and related respiratory equipment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Moratorium” means a mandated temporary cessation or suspension of the sale, rental, or offering of equipment after the imposition of the moratorium, in accordance with part II of chapter 408. Services related to equipment sold or rented prior to the moratorium must be continued without interruption, unless determined otherwise by the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Premises” means those buildings and equipment which are located at the address of the licensed home medical equipment provider for the provision of home medical equipment services, which are in such reasonable proximity as to appear to the public to be a single provider location, and which comply with zoning ordinances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residence” means the consumer’s home or place of residence, which may include nursing homes, assisted living facilities, transitional living facilities, adult family-care homes, or other congregate residential facilities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-189; s. 1, ch. 2001-214; s. 11, ch. 2002-400; s. 25, ch. 2006-71; s. 106, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>