<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.119" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Confidentiality of records and meetings of risk management and quality assurance committees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Incident reports filed with the risk manager and administrator of a long-term care facility licensed under this part or part I of chapter 429, notifications of the occurrence of an adverse incident, and adverse incident reports from the facility are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The meetings of an internal risk management and quality assurance committee of a long-term care facility licensed under this part or part I of chapter 429 are exempt from s. 286.011 and s. 24(b), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records of those meetings are confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Agency for Health Care Administration has a reasonable belief that conduct by a staff member or employee of a facility is criminal activity or grounds for disciplinary action by a regulatory board, the agency may disclose records made confidential and exempt pursuant to this section to the appropriate law enforcement agency or regulatory board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records disclosed to a law enforcement agency remain confidential and exempt until criminal charges are filed.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records made confidential and exempt under this section and that are obtained by a regulatory board are not available to the public as part of the record of investigation and prosecution in a disciplinary proceeding made available to the public by the agency or the appropriate regulatory board. However, the agency or the appropriate regulatory board shall make available, upon request by a health care professional against whom probable cause has been found, any such records that form the basis of the determination of probable cause.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-44; s. 59, ch. 2002-1; s. 1, ch. 2006-110; s. 25, ch. 2006-197.</History></Section>