<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Denial, suspension, revocation of license; administrative fines; procedure; order to increase staffing.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may deny an application, revoke or suspend a license, and impose an administrative fine, not to exceed $500 per violation per day for the violation of any provision of this part, part II of chapter 408, or applicable rules, against any applicant or licensee for the following violations by the applicant, licensee, or other controlling interest:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of any provision of this part, part II of chapter 408, or applicable rules; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An adverse action by a regulatory agency against any other licensed facility that has a common controlling interest with the licensee or applicant against whom the action under this section is being brought. If the adverse action involves solely the management company, the applicant or licensee shall be given 30 days to remedy before final action is taken. If the adverse action is based solely upon actions by a controlling interest, the applicant or licensee may present factors in mitigation of any proposed penalty based upon a showing that such penalty is inappropriate under the circumstances.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All hearings shall be held within the county in which the licensee or applicant operates or applies for a license to operate a facility as defined herein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 400.23(8), a $500 fine shall be imposed for each violation. Each day a violation of this part or part II of chapter 408 occurs constitutes a separate violation and is subject to a separate fine, but in no event may any fine aggregate more than $5,000. A fine may be levied pursuant to this section in lieu of and notwithstanding the provisions of s. 400.23. Fines paid shall be deposited in the Health Care Trust Fund and expended as provided in s. 400.063.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall revoke or deny a nursing home license if the licensee or controlling interest operates a facility in this state that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has had two moratoria issued pursuant to this part or part II of chapter 408 which are imposed by final order for substandard quality of care, as defined by 42 C.F.R. part 483, within any 30-month period;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is conditionally licensed for 180 or more continuous days;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is cited for two class I deficiencies arising from unrelated circumstances during the same survey or investigation; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is cited for two class I deficiencies arising from separate surveys or investigations within a 30-month period.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The licensee may present factors in mitigation of revocation, and the agency may make a determination not to revoke a license based upon a showing that revocation is inappropriate under the circumstances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the agency has placed a moratorium pursuant to this part or part II of chapter 408 on any facility two times within a 7-year period, the agency may suspend the nursing home license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An action taken by the agency to deny, suspend, or revoke a facility’s license under this part or part II of chapter 408 shall be heard by the Division of Administrative Hearings of the Department of Management Services within 60 days after the assignment of an administrative law judge, unless the time limitation is waived by both parties. The administrative law judge must render a decision within 30 days after receipt of a proposed recommended order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency is authorized to require a facility to increase staffing beyond the minimum required by law, if the agency has taken administrative action against the facility for care-related deficiencies directly attributable to insufficient staff. Under such circumstances, the facility may request an expedited interim rate increase. The agency shall process the request within 10 days after receipt of all required documentation from the facility. A facility that fails to maintain the required increased staffing is subject to a fine of $500 per day for each day the staffing is below the level required by the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, agency action in an administrative proceeding under this section may be overcome by the licensee upon a showing by a preponderance of the evidence to the contrary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other sanction imposed under this part or part II of chapter 408, in any final order that imposes sanctions, the agency may assess costs related to the investigation and prosecution of the case. Payment of agency costs shall be deposited into the Health Care Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 69-309; s. 1, ch. 69-267; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 9, ch. 70-361; s. 1, ch. 70-439; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 239, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 19, ch. 78-95; ss. 6, 9, ch. 79-268; ss. 7, 18, ch. 80-186; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 15, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 30, ch. 93-177; ss. 14, 49, ch. 93-217; s. 36, ch. 96-169; s. 1, ch. 98-248; s. 11, ch. 99-394; s. 20, ch. 2001-45; s. 65, ch. 2007-230; s. 13, ch. 2008-9.</History></Section>