<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.232" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Review and approval of plans; fees and costs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The design, construction, erection, alteration, modification, repair, and demolition of all public and private health care facilities are governed by the Florida Building Code and the Florida Fire Prevention Code under ss. 553.73 and 633.022. In addition to the requirements of ss. 553.79 and 553.80, the agency shall review the facility plans and survey the construction of facilities licensed under this chapter.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall approve or disapprove the plans and specifications within 60 days after receipt of the final plans and specifications. The agency may be granted one 15-day extension for the review period, if the director of the agency so approves. If the agency fails to act within the specified time, it shall be deemed to have approved the plans and specifications. When the agency disapproves plans and specifications, it shall set forth in writing the reasons for disapproval. Conferences and consultations may be provided as necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency is authorized to charge an initial fee of $2,000 for review of plans and construction on all projects, no part of which is refundable. The agency may also collect a fee, not to exceed 1 percent of the estimated construction cost or the actual cost of review, whichever is less, for the portion of the review which encompasses initial review through the initial revised construction document review. The agency is further authorized to collect its actual costs on all subsequent portions of the review and construction inspections. Initial fee payment shall accompany the initial submission of plans and specifications. Any subsequent payment that is due is payable upon receipt of the invoice from the agency. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law to the contrary, all money received by the agency pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be deemed to be trust funds, to be held and applied solely for the operations required under this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 22, ch. 69-309; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 19, ch. 70-361; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 7, ch. 76-201; s. 2, ch. 77-188; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 8, 9, ch. 79-268; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 30, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 1, ch. 90-125; ss. 9, 77, ch. 91-282; s. 30, ch. 93-177; ss. 29, 49, ch. 93-217; s. 17, ch. 99-394; s. 30, ch. 2000-141; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.23(11), (12).</Text></Note></Section>