<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.484" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of inspection; deficiencies; fines.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of s. 408.811, the agency may make such inspections and investigations as are necessary in order to determine the state of compliance with this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall impose fines for various classes of deficiencies in accordance with the following schedule:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A class I deficiency is any act, omission, or practice that results in a patient’s death, disablement, or permanent injury, or places a patient at imminent risk of death, disablement, or permanent injury. Upon finding a class I deficiency, the agency shall impose an administrative fine in the amount of $15,000 for each occurrence and each day that the deficiency exists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A class II deficiency is any act, omission, or practice that has a direct adverse effect on the health, safety, or security of a patient. Upon finding a class II deficiency, the agency shall impose an administrative fine in the amount of $5,000 for each occurrence and each day that the deficiency exists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A class III deficiency is any act, omission, or practice that has an indirect, adverse effect on the health, safety, or security of a patient. Upon finding an uncorrected or repeated class III deficiency, the agency shall impose an administrative fine not to exceed $1,000 for each occurrence and each day that the uncorrected or repeated deficiency exists.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A class IV deficiency is any act, omission, or practice related to required reports, forms, or documents which does not have the potential of negatively affecting patients. These violations are of a type that the agency determines do not threaten the health, safety, or security of patients. Upon finding an uncorrected or repeated class IV deficiency, the agency shall impose an administrative fine not to exceed $500 for each occurrence and each day that the uncorrected or repeated deficiency exists.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalties imposed pursuant to this section or part, the agency may assess costs related to an investigation that results in a successful prosecution, excluding costs associated with an attorney’s time.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 45, ch. 75-233; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 79, 83, ch. 83-181; ss. 8, 23, ch. 93-214; s. 5, ch. 99-332; s. 158, ch. 2000-318; s. 77, ch. 2007-230; s. 6, ch. 2008-246.</History></Section>