<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.142" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Emergency medication kits; orders not to resuscitate.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other provisions of this chapter or of chapter 465, chapter 499, or chapter 893 to the contrary notwithstanding, each nursing home operating pursuant to a license issued by the agency may maintain an emergency medication kit for the purpose of storing medicinal drugs to be administered under emergency conditions to residents residing in such facility.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt such rules as it may deem appropriate to the effective implementation of this act, including, but not limited to, rules which:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Define the term “emergency medication kit.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Describe the medicinal drugs eligible to be placed in emergency medication kits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish requirements for the storing of medicinal drugs in emergency medication kits and the maintenance of records with respect thereto.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish requirements for the administration of medicinal drugs to residents under emergency conditions from emergency medication kits.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facility staff may withhold or withdraw cardiopulmonary resuscitation if presented with an order not to resuscitate executed pursuant to s. 401.45. Facility staff and facilities are not subject to criminal prosecution or civil liability, or considered to have engaged in negligent or unprofessional conduct, for withholding or withdrawing cardiopulmonary resuscitation pursuant to such order. The absence of an order not to resuscitate executed pursuant to s. 401.45 does not preclude a physician from withholding or withdrawing cardiopulmonary resuscitation as otherwise permitted by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 40, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 30, ch. 93-177; ss. 32, 49, ch. 93-217; s. 3, ch. 99-331; s. 2, ch. 2000-295; s. 7, ch. 2012-160.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.3221.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>