<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.0073" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">State and local ombudsman council investigations.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A local council shall investigate, within a reasonable time after a complaint is made, any complaint of a resident, a representative of a resident, or any other credible source based on an action or omission by an administrator, an employee, or a representative of a long-term care facility which might be:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contrary to law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unreasonable, unfair, oppressive, or unnecessarily discriminatory, even though in accordance with law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on a mistake of fact;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Based on improper or irrelevant grounds;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unaccompanied by an adequate statement of reasons;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Performed in an inefficient manner; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Otherwise adversely affecting the health, safety, welfare, or rights of a resident.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In an investigation, both the state and local councils have the authority to hold public hearings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsequent to an appeal from a local council, the state council may investigate any complaint received by the local council involving a long-term care facility or a resident.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the ombudsman or any state or local council member is not allowed to enter a long-term care facility, the administrator of the facility shall be considered to have interfered with a representative of the office, the state council, or the local council in the performance of official duties as described in s. 400.0083(1) and to have committed a violation of this part. The ombudsman shall report a facility’s refusal to allow entry to the agency, and the agency shall record the report and take it into consideration when determining actions allowable under s. 400.102, s. 400.121, s. 429.14, s. 429.19, s. 429.69, or s. 429.71.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 29, ch. 75-233; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 10, ch. 77-401; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 8, 12, ch. 80-198; ss. 4, 6, ch. 81-184; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 4, ch. 82-46; ss. 16, 19, ch. 82-148; ss. 37, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; ss. 7, 29, 30, ch. 93-177; s. 49, ch. 93-217; s. 761, ch. 95-148; s. 127, ch. 2000-349; s. 47, ch. 2000-367; s. 1, ch. 2001-45; s. 10, ch. 2006-121; s. 22, ch. 2006-197; s. 76, ch. 2007-5; s. 53, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.314.</Text></Note></Section>