<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.497" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Rules establishing minimum standards.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt, publish, and enforce rules to implement part II of chapter 408 and this part, including, as applicable, ss. 400.506 and 400.509, which must provide reasonable and fair minimum standards relating to:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home health aide competency test and home health aide training. The agency shall create the home health aide competency test and establish the curriculum and instructor qualifications for home health aide training. Licensed home health agencies may provide this training and shall furnish documentation of such training to other licensed home health agencies upon request. Successful passage of the competency test by home health aides may be substituted for the training required under this section and any rule adopted pursuant thereto.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shared staffing. The agency shall allow shared staffing if the home health agency is part of a retirement community that provides multiple levels of care, is located on one campus, is licensed under this chapter or chapter 429, and otherwise meets the requirements of law and rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The criteria for the frequency of onsite licensure surveys.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure application and renewal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Oversight by the director of nursing. The agency shall develop rules related to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Standards that address oversight responsibilities by the director of nursing of skilled nursing and personal care services provided by the home health agency’s staff;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requirements for a director of nursing to provide to the agency, upon request, a certified daily report of the home health services provided by a specified direct employee or contracted staff member on behalf of the home health agency. The agency may request a certified daily report only for a period not to exceed 2 years prior to the date of the request; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A quality assurance program for home health services provided by the home health agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conditions for using a recent unannounced licensure inspection for the inspection required in s. 408.806 related to a licensure application associated with a change in ownership of a licensed home health agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements for onsite and electronic accessibility of supervisory personnel of home health agencies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Information to be included in patients’ records.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Geographic service areas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Preparation of a comprehensive emergency management plan pursuant to s. 400.492.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall adopt rules establishing minimum criteria for the plan and plan updates, with the concurrence of the Department of Health and in consultation with the Division of Emergency Management.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rules must address the requirements in s. 400.492. In addition, the rules shall provide for the maintenance of patient-specific medication lists that can accompany patients who are transported from their homes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The plan is subject to review and approval by the county health department. During its review, the county health department shall contact state and local health and medical stakeholders when necessary. The county health department shall complete its review to ensure that the plan is in accordance with the criteria in the Agency for Health Care Administration rules within 90 days after receipt of the plan and shall approve the plan or advise the home health agency of necessary revisions. If the home health agency fails to submit a plan or fails to submit the requested information or revisions to the county health department within 30 days after written notification from the county health department, the county health department shall notify the Agency for Health Care Administration. The agency shall notify the home health agency that its failure constitutes a deficiency, subject to a fine of $5,000 per occurrence. If the plan is not submitted, information is not provided, or revisions are not made as requested, the agency may impose the fine.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any home health agency that operates in more than one county, the Department of Health shall review the plan, after consulting with state and local health and medical stakeholders when necessary. The department shall complete its review within 90 days after receipt of the plan and shall approve the plan or advise the home health agency of necessary revisions. The department shall make every effort to avoid imposing differing requirements on a home health agency that operates in more than one county as a result of differing or conflicting comprehensive plan requirements of the counties in which the home health agency operates.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements in this subsection do not apply to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that is certified under chapter 651 and has a licensed home health agency used exclusively by residents of the facility; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A retirement community that consists of residential units for independent living and either a licensed nursing home or an assisted living facility, and has a licensed home health agency used exclusively by the residents of the retirement community, provided the comprehensive emergency management plan for the facility or retirement community provides for continuous care of all residents with special needs during an emergency.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 49, ch. 75-233; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 6, ch. 88-219; s. 4, ch. 89-354; s. 6, ch. 90-319; s. 38, ch. 90-347; s. 26, ch. 91-57; s. 31, ch. 91-263; ss. 12, 23, ch. 93-214; s. 786, ch. 95-148; s. 9, ch. 99-332; s. 13, ch. 2000-140; s. 160, ch. 2000-318; s. 22, ch. 2006-71; s. 62, ch. 2006-197; s. 79, ch. 2007-230; s. 8, ch. 2008-246; s. 276, ch. 2011-142.</History></Section>