<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.0712" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for inactive license.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As specified in this section, the agency may issue an inactive license to a nursing home facility for all or a portion of its beds. Any request by a licensee that a nursing home or portion of a nursing home become inactive must be submitted to the agency in the approved format. The facility may not initiate any suspension of services, notify residents, or initiate inactivity before receiving approval from the agency; and a licensee that violates this provision may not be issued an inactive license.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may issue an inactive license to a nursing home that chooses to use an unoccupied contiguous portion of the facility for an alternative use to meet the needs of elderly persons through the use of less restrictive, less institutional services.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An inactive license issued under this subsection may be granted for a period not to exceed the current licensure expiration date but may be renewed by the agency at the time of licensure renewal.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request to extend the inactive license must be submitted to the agency in the approved format and approved by the agency in writing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nursing homes that receive an inactive license to provide alternative services shall not receive preference for participation in the Assisted Living for the Elderly Medicaid waiver.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 necessary to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2004-298; s. 61, ch. 2007-230; s. 102, ch. 2008-4; s. 37, ch. 2009-223.</History></Section>