<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.805" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transitional living facilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transitional living facility” means a site where specialized health care services are provided, including, but not limited to, rehabilitative services, community reentry training, aids for independent living, and counseling to spinal-cord-injured persons and head-injured persons. This term does not include a hospital licensed under chapter 395 or any federally operated hospital or facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this section and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the agency pursuant to this section. A license issued by the agency is required for the operation of a transitional living facility in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with this section, an applicant or a licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. The fee shall consist of a $4,000 license fee and a $78.50 per bed fee per biennium.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may not issue a license to an applicant until the agency receives notice from the department as provided in paragraph (3)(b).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall require level 2 background screening for personnel as required in s. 408.809(1)(e) pursuant to chapter 435 and s. 408.809.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall adopt rules in consultation with the department governing the physical plant of transitional living facilities and the fiscal management of transitional living facilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules in consultation with the agency governing the services provided to clients of transitional living facilities. The department shall enforce all requirements for providing services to the facility’s clients. The department must notify the agency when it determines that an applicant for licensure meets the service requirements adopted by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency and the department shall enforce requirements under this section and part II of chapter 408, as such requirements relate to them respectively, and their respective adopted rules.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 408.811, any designated officer or employee of the agency, of the state, or of the local fire marshal may enter unannounced upon and into the premises of any facility licensed under this section in order to determine the state of compliance with this section, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with part II of chapter 408, a violation of any provision of this section, part II of chapter 408, or applicable rules is punishable by payment of an administrative or a civil penalty fine not to exceed $5,000.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unlicensed activity pursuant to s. 408.812 is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Each day of a continuing violation is a separate offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may adopt rules to administer the requirements of part II of chapter 408.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 93-217; s. 1, ch. 98-12; ss. 60, 71, ch. 98-171; s. 16, ch. 99-240; s. 22, ch. 2000-153; s. 86, ch. 2000-349; s. 25, ch. 2001-53; s. 2, ch. 2001-67; s. 148, ch. 2001-277; s. 52, ch. 2004-267; s. 91, ch. 2007-230; s. 11, ch. 2010-114.</History>
</Section>