<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.1183" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Resident grievance procedures.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every nursing home must have a grievance procedure available to its residents and their families. The grievance procedure must include:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An explanation of how to pursue redress of a grievance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The names, job titles, and telephone numbers of the employees responsible for implementing the facility’s grievance procedure. The list must include the address and the toll-free telephone numbers of the ombudsman and the agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A simple description of the process through which a resident may, at any time, contact the toll-free telephone hotline of the ombudsman or the agency to report the unresolved grievance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A procedure for providing assistance to residents who cannot prepare a written grievance without help.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each nursing home facility shall maintain records of all grievances and a report, subject to agency inspection, of the total number of grievances handled, a categorization of the cases underlying the grievances, and the final disposition of the grievances.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each facility must respond to the grievance within a reasonable time after its submission.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may investigate any grievance at any time.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 19, ch. 2001-45; s. 64, ch. 2007-230; s. 5, ch. 2012-160.</History>
</Section>