<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.801" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Homes for special services.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the “Agency for Health Care Administration.”</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Home for special services” means a site licensed by the agency prior to January 1, 2006, where specialized health care services are provided, including personal and custodial care, but not continuous nursing services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this section and part II of chapter 408 and entities licensed by or applying for licensure from the agency pursuant to this section. A license issued by the agency is required in order to operate a home for special services in this state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall require level 2 background screening for personnel as required in s. 408.809(1)(e) pursuant to chapter 435 and s. 408.809.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. The amount of the fee shall be established by rule and may not be more than $2,000 per biennium.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may adopt rules for implementing and enforcing this section and part II of chapter 408.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of part II of chapter 408, a violation of any provision of this section, part II of chapter 408, or applicable rules is punishable by payment of an administrative fine not to exceed $5,000.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of s. 408.812 or rules adopted under that section is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Each day of continuing violation is a separate offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 35, ch. 93-217; ss. 59, 71, ch. 98-171; s. 85, ch. 2000-349; s. 25, ch. 2001-53; s. 2, ch. 2001-67; s. 148, ch. 2001-277; s. 51, ch. 2004-267; s. 6, ch. 2006-192; s. 90, ch. 2007-230; s. 10, ch. 2010-114.</History>
</Section>