<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.17" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Bribes, kickbacks, certain solicitations prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bribe” means any consideration corruptly given, received, promised, solicited, or offered to any individual with intent or purpose to influence the performance of any act or omission.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Kickback” means that part of the payment for items or services which is returned to the payor by the provider of such items or services with the intent or purpose to induce the payor to purchase the items or services from the provider.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever furnishes items or services directly or indirectly to a nursing home resident and solicits, offers, or receives any:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Kickback or bribe in connection with the furnishing of such items or services or the making or receipt of such payment; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Return of part of an amount given in payment for referring any such individual to another person for the furnishing of such items or services;</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or by fine not exceeding $5,000, or both.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall, in connection with the solicitation of contributions to nursing homes, willfully misrepresent or mislead anyone, by any manner, means, practice, or device whatsoever, to believe that the receipts of such solicitation will be used for charitable purposes, if such is not the fact.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Solicitation of contributions of any kind in a threatening, coercive, or unduly forceful manner by or on behalf of a nursing home by any agent, employee, owner, or representative of a nursing home shall be grounds for denial, suspension, or revocation of the license for any nursing home on behalf of which such contributions were solicited.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The admission, maintenance, or treatment of a nursing home resident whose care is supported in whole or in part by state funds may not be made conditional upon the receipt of any manner of contribution or donation from any person. However, this may not be construed to prohibit the offer or receipt of contributions or donations to a nursing home which are not related to the care of a specific resident. Contributions solicited or received in violation of this subsection shall be grounds for denial, suspension, or revocation of a license for any nursing home on behalf of which such contributions were solicited.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 69-309; s. 16, ch. 70-361; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 3, ch. 76-201; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 22, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 30, ch. 93-177; s. 49, ch. 93-217.</History></Section>