<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.0091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Training.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ombudsman shall ensure that appropriate training is provided to all employees of the office and to the members of the state and local councils.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state and local council members and employees of the office shall be given a minimum of 20 hours of training upon employment with the office or approval as a state or local council member and 10 hours of continuing education annually thereafter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ombudsman shall approve the curriculum for the initial and continuing education training, which must, at a minimum, address:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resident confidentiality.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Guardianships and powers of attorney.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medication administration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Care and medication of residents with dementia and Alzheimer’s disease.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Accounting for residents’ funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Discharge rights and responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Cultural sensitivity.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other topic recommended by the secretary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No employee, officer, or representative of the office or of the state or local councils, other than the ombudsman, may hold himself or herself out as a representative of the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program or conduct any authorized program duty described in this part unless the person has received the training required by this section and has been certified by the ombudsman as qualified to carry out ombudsman activities on behalf of the office or the state or local councils.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 30, ch. 93-177; s. 135, ch. 2000-349; s. 55, ch. 2000-367; s. 32, ch. 2001-62; s. 27, ch. 2002-223; s. 20, ch. 2006-121.</History></Section>