<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.464" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Home health agencies to be licensed; expiration of license; exemptions; unlawful acts; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this part and part II of chapter 408 and entities licensed or registered by or applying for such licensure or registration from the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to this part. A license issued by the agency is required in order to operate a home health agency in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the licensed home health agency operates related offices, each related office outside the county where the main office is located must be separately licensed. The counties where the related offices are operating must be specified on the license in the main office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A home infusion therapy provider must be licensed as a home health agency or nurse registry.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An organization that offers or advertises to the public any service for which licensure or registration is required under this part must include in the advertisement the license number or registration number issued to the organization by the agency. The agency shall assess a fine of not less than $100 to any licensee or registrant who fails to include the license or registration number when submitting the advertisement for publication, broadcast, or printing. The fine for a second or subsequent offense is $500. The holder of a license issued under this part may not advertise or indicate to the public that it holds a home health agency or nurse registry license other than the one it has been issued.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation or maintenance of an unlicensed home health agency or the performance of any home health services in violation of this part is declared a nuisance, inimical to the public health, welfare, and safety. The agency or any state attorney may, in addition to other remedies provided in this part, bring an action for an injunction to restrain such violation, or to enjoin the future operation or maintenance of the home health agency or the provision of home health services in violation of this part, until compliance with this part or the rules adopted under this part has been demonstrated to the satisfaction of the agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates paragraph (a) is subject to an injunctive proceeding under s. 408.816. A violation of paragraph (a) or s. 408.812 is a deceptive and unfair trade practice and constitutes a violation of the Florida Deceptive and Unfair Trade Practices Act under part II of chapter 501.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who violates the provisions of paragraph (a) commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Any person who commits a second or subsequent violation commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Each day of continuing violation constitutes a separate offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who owns, operates, or maintains an unlicensed home health agency and who, within 10 working days after receiving notification from the agency, fails to cease operation and apply for a license under this part commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083. Each day of continued operation is a separate offense.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any home health agency that fails to cease operation after agency notification may be fined $500 for each day of noncompliance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following are exempt from the licensure requirements of this part:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A home health agency operated by the Federal Government.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home health services provided by a state agency, either directly or through a contractor with:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health, a community health center, or a rural health network that furnishes home visits for the purpose of providing environmental assessments, case management, health education, personal care services, family planning, or followup treatment, or for the purpose of monitoring and tracking disease.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services provided to persons with developmental disabilities, as defined in s. 393.063.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Companion and sitter organizations that were registered under s. 400.509(1) on January 1, 1999, and were authorized to provide personal services under a developmental services provider certificate on January 1, 1999, may continue to provide such services to past, present, and future clients of the organization who need such services, notwithstanding the provisions of this act.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health care professional, whether or not incorporated, who is licensed under chapter 457; chapter 458; chapter 459; part I of chapter 464; chapter 467; part I, part III, part V, or part X of chapter 468; chapter 480; chapter 486; chapter 490; or chapter 491; and who is acting alone within the scope of his or her professional license to provide care to patients in their homes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A home health aide or certified nursing assistant who is acting in his or her individual capacity, within the definitions and standards of his or her occupation, and who provides hands-on care to patients in their homes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual who acts alone, in his or her individual capacity, and who is not employed by or affiliated with a licensed home health agency or registered with a licensed nurse registry. This exemption does not entitle an individual to perform home health services without the required professional license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery of instructional services in home dialysis and home dialysis supplies and equipment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery of nursing home services for which the nursing home is licensed under part II of this chapter, to serve its residents in its facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery of assisted living facility services for which the assisted living facility is licensed under part I of chapter 429, to serve its residents in its facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery of hospice services for which the hospice is licensed under part IV of this chapter, to serve hospice patients admitted to its service.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hospital that provides services for which it is licensed under chapter 395.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery of community residential services for which the community residential home is licensed under chapter 419, to serve the residents in its facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A not-for-profit, community-based agency that provides early intervention services to infants and toddlers.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certified rehabilitation agencies and comprehensive outpatient rehabilitation facilities that are certified under Title 18 of the Social Security Act.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The delivery of adult family-care home services for which the adult family-care home is licensed under part II of chapter 429, to serve the residents in its facility.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 39, ch. 75-233; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 29, ch. 91-263; ss. 3, 23, ch. 93-214; s. 782, ch. 95-148; ss. 41, 129, ch. 95-418; s. 100, ch. 97-101; s. 2, ch. 99-332; s. 18, ch. 2000-153; s. 59, ch. 2000-256; ss. 17, 103, ch. 2000-318; s. 5, ch. 2000-338; s. 37, ch. 2001-62; s. 92, ch. 2004-267; s. 3, ch. 2005-243; s. 61, ch. 2006-197; s. 70, ch. 2006-227; s. 74, ch. 2007-230; s. 2, ch. 2008-246.</History></Section>