<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.962" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License required; license application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this part and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the Agency for Health Care Administration pursuant to this part. A license issued by the agency is required in order to operate an intermediate care facility for the developmentally disabled in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Separate licenses are required for facilities maintained on separate premises even if operated under the same management. However, a separate license is not required for separate buildings on the same grounds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 408.805, an applicant or licensee shall pay a fee for each license application submitted under this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules. The amount of the fee shall be $234 per bed unless modified by rule. The application must indicate the location of the facility for which a license is sought and that such location conforms to the local zoning ordinances.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must demonstrate that sufficient numbers of staff, qualified by training or experience, will be employed to properly care for the type and number of residents who will reside in the facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant must agree to provide or arrange for active treatment services by an interdisciplinary team to maximize individual independence or prevent regression or loss of functional status. Standards for active treatment shall be adopted by the Agency for Health Care Administration by rule pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54. Active treatment services shall be provided in accordance with the individual support plan and shall be reimbursed as part of the per diem rate as paid under the Medicaid program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 99-144; s. 92, ch. 2000-349; s. 8, ch. 2000-350; s. 59, ch. 2001-45; s. 421, ch. 2003-261; s. 55, ch. 2004-267; s. 69, ch. 2006-197; s. 43, ch. 2006-227; s. 115, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>