<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration and management of nursing home facilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every licensed facility shall comply with all applicable standards and rules of the agency and shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be under the administrative direction and charge of a licensed administrator.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Appoint a medical director licensed pursuant to chapter 458 or chapter 459. The agency may establish by rule more specific criteria for the appointment of a medical director.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have available the regular, consultative, and emergency services of physicians licensed by the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for resident use of a community pharmacy as specified in s. 400.022(1)(q). Any other law to the contrary notwithstanding, a registered pharmacist licensed in Florida, that is under contract with a facility licensed under this chapter or chapter 429, shall repackage a nursing facility resident’s bulk prescription medication which has been packaged by another pharmacist licensed in any state in the United States into a unit dose system compatible with the system used by the nursing facility, if the pharmacist is requested to offer such service. In order to be eligible for the repackaging, a resident or the resident’s spouse must receive prescription medication benefits provided through a former employer as part of his or her retirement benefits, a qualified pension plan as specified in s. 4972 of the Internal Revenue Code, a federal retirement program as specified under 5 C.F.R. s. 831, or a long-term care policy as defined in s. 627.9404(1). A pharmacist who correctly repackages and relabels the medication and the nursing facility which correctly administers such repackaged medication under this paragraph may not be held liable in any civil or administrative action arising from the repackaging. In order to be eligible for the repackaging, a nursing facility resident for whom the medication is to be repackaged shall sign an informed consent form provided by the facility which includes an explanation of the repackaging process and which notifies the resident of the immunities from liability provided in this paragraph. A pharmacist who repackages and relabels prescription medications, as authorized under this paragraph, may charge a reasonable fee for costs resulting from the implementation of this provision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for the access of the facility residents to dental and other health-related services, recreational services, rehabilitative services, and social work services appropriate to their needs and conditions and not directly furnished by the licensee. When a geriatric outpatient nurse clinic is conducted in accordance with rules adopted by the agency, outpatients attending such clinic shall not be counted as part of the general resident population of the nursing home facility, nor shall the nursing staff of the geriatric outpatient clinic be counted as part of the nursing staff of the facility, until the outpatient clinic load exceeds 15 a day.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be allowed and encouraged by the agency to provide other needed services under certain conditions. If the facility has a standard licensure status, it may provide services, including, but not limited to, respite, therapeutic spa, and adult day services to nonresidents of the facility. A facility is not subject to any additional licensure requirements for providing these services. Respite care may be offered to persons in need of short-term or temporary nursing home services. Respite care must be provided in accordance with this part. Providers of adult day services must comply with the requirements of s. 429.905(2). The agency shall allow for shared programming and staff in a facility which meets minimum standards and offers services pursuant to this paragraph, but, if the facility is cited for deficiencies in patient care, may require additional staff and programs appropriate to the needs of service recipients. A person who receives respite care may not be counted as a resident of the facility for purposes of the facility’s licensed capacity unless that person receives 24-hour respite care. A person receiving either respite care for 24 hours or longer or adult day services must be included when calculating minimum staffing for the facility. Any costs and revenues generated by a nursing home facility from nonresidential programs or services shall be excluded from the calculations of Medicaid per diems for nursing home institutional care reimbursement.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the facility has a standard license, exceeds the minimum required hours of licensed nursing and certified nursing assistant direct care per resident per day, and is part of a continuing care facility licensed under chapter 651 or a retirement community that offers other services pursuant to part III of this chapter or part I or part III of chapter 429 on a single campus, be allowed to share programming and staff. At the time of inspection, a continuing care facility or retirement community that uses this option must demonstrate through staffing records that minimum staffing requirements for the facility were met. Licensed nurses and certified nursing assistants who work in the facility may be used to provide services elsewhere on campus if the facility exceeds the minimum number of direct care hours required per resident per day and the total number of residents receiving direct care services from a licensed nurse or a certified nursing assistant does not cause the facility to violate the staffing ratios required under s. 400.23(3)(a). Compliance with the minimum staffing ratios must be based on the total number of residents receiving direct care services, regardless of where they reside on campus. If the facility receives a conditional license, it may not share staff until the conditional license status ends. This paragraph does not restrict the agency’s authority under federal or state law to require additional staff if a facility is cited for deficiencies in care which are caused by an insufficient number of certified nursing assistants or licensed nurses. The agency may adopt rules for the documentation necessary to determine compliance with this provision.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain the facility premises and equipment and conduct its operations in a safe and sanitary manner.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the licensee furnishes food service, provide a wholesome and nourishing diet sufficient to meet generally accepted standards of proper nutrition for its residents and provide such therapeutic diets as may be prescribed by attending physicians. In making rules to implement this paragraph, the agency shall be guided by standards recommended by nationally recognized professional groups and associations with knowledge of dietetics.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Keep full records of resident admissions and discharges; medical and general health status, including medical records, personal and social history, and identity and address of next of kin or other persons who may have responsibility for the affairs of the resident; and individual resident care plans, including, but not limited to, prescribed services, service frequency and duration, and service goals. The records must be open to agency inspection. The licensee shall maintain clinical records on each resident in accordance with accepted professional standards and practices, which must be complete, accurately documented, readily accessible, and systematically organized.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Keep such fiscal records of its operations and conditions as may be necessary to provide information pursuant to this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Furnish copies of personnel records for employees affiliated with such facility, to any other facility licensed by this state requesting this information pursuant to this part. Such information contained in the records may include, but is not limited to, disciplinary matters and any reason for termination. Any facility releasing such records pursuant to this part shall be considered to be acting in good faith and may not be held liable for information contained in such records, absent a showing that the facility maliciously falsified such records.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publicly display a poster provided by the agency containing the names, addresses, and telephone numbers for the state’s abuse hotline, the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman, the Agency for Health Care Administration consumer hotline, the Advocacy Center for Persons with Disabilities, the Florida Statewide Advocacy Council, and the Medicaid Fraud Control Unit, with a clear description of the assistance to be expected from each.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="n">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Comply with state minimum-staffing requirements:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that has failed to comply with state minimum-staffing requirements for 2 consecutive days is prohibited from accepting new admissions until the facility has achieved the minimum-staffing requirements for 6 consecutive days. For the purposes of this subparagraph, any person who was a resident of the facility and was absent from the facility for the purpose of receiving medical care at a separate location or was on a leave of absence is not considered a new admission. Failure by the facility to impose such an admissions moratorium is subject to a $1,000 fine.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that does not have a conditional license may be cited for failure to comply with the standards in s. 400.23(3)(a)1.b. and c. only if it has failed to meet those standards on 2 consecutive days or if it has failed to meet at least 97 percent of those standards on any one day.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A facility that has a conditional license must be in compliance with the standards in s. 400.23(3)(a) at all times.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="o">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify a licensed physician when a resident exhibits signs of dementia or cognitive impairment or has a change of condition in order to rule out the presence of an underlying physiological condition that may be contributing to such dementia or impairment. The notification must occur within 30 days after the acknowledgment of such signs by facility staff. If an underlying condition is determined to exist, the facility shall, with the appropriate health care provider, arrange for the necessary care and services to treat the condition.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="p">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the facility implements a dining and hospitality attendant program, ensure that the program is developed and implemented under the supervision of the facility director of nursing. A licensed nurse, licensed speech or occupational therapist, or a registered dietitian must conduct training of dining and hospitality attendants. A person employed by a facility as a dining and hospitality attendant must perform tasks under the direct supervision of a licensed nurse.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="q">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain general and professional liability insurance coverage that is in force at all times. In lieu of such coverage, a state-designated teaching nursing home and its affiliated assisted living facilities created under s. 430.80 may demonstrate proof of financial responsibility as provided in s. 430.80(3)(g).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="r">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Maintain in the medical record for each resident a daily chart of certified nursing assistant services provided to the resident. The certified nursing assistant who is caring for the resident must complete this record by the end of his or her shift. This record must indicate assistance with activities of daily living, assistance with eating, and assistance with drinking, and must record each offering of nutrition and hydration for those residents whose plan of care or assessment indicates a risk for malnutrition or dehydration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="s">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before November 30 of each year, subject to the availability of an adequate supply of the necessary vaccine, provide for immunizations against influenza viruses to all its consenting residents in accordance with the recommendations of the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, subject to exemptions for medical contraindications and religious or personal beliefs. Subject to these exemptions, any consenting person who becomes a resident of the facility after November 30 but before March 31 of the following year must be immunized within 5 working days after becoming a resident. Immunization shall not be provided to any resident who provides documentation that he or she has been immunized as required by this paragraph. This paragraph does not prohibit a resident from receiving the immunization from his or her personal physician if he or she so chooses. A resident who chooses to receive the immunization from his or her personal physician shall provide proof of immunization to the facility. The agency may adopt and enforce any rules necessary to comply with or implement this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="t">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assess all residents for eligibility for pneumococcal polysaccharide vaccination (PPV) and vaccinate residents when indicated within 60 days after the effective date of this act in accordance with the recommendations of the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, subject to exemptions for medical contraindications and religious or personal beliefs. Residents admitted after the effective date of this act shall be assessed within 5 working days of admission and, when indicated, vaccinated within 60 days in accordance with the recommendations of the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, subject to exemptions for medical contraindications and religious or personal beliefs. Immunization shall not be provided to any resident who provides documentation that he or she has been immunized as required by this paragraph. This paragraph does not prohibit a resident from receiving the immunization from his or her personal physician if he or she so chooses. A resident who chooses to receive the immunization from his or her personal physician shall provide proof of immunization to the facility. The agency may adopt and enforce any rules necessary to comply with or implement this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="u">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Annually encourage and promote to its employees the benefits associated with immunizations against influenza viruses in accordance with the recommendations of the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. The agency may adopt and enforce any rules necessary to comply with or implement this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Facilities that have been awarded a Gold Seal under the program established in s. 400.235 may develop a plan to provide certified nursing assistant training as prescribed by federal regulations and state rules and may apply to the agency for approval of their program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 69-309; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 12, ch. 70-361; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 241, ch. 77-147; s. 3, ch. 77-401; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 9, 18, ch. 80-186; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 18, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 30, ch. 93-177; ss. 17, 49, ch. 93-217; s. 21, ch. 95-418; s. 12, ch. 99-394; s. 18, ch. 2000-263; s. 4, ch. 2000-350; s. 1, ch. 2001-42; ss. 22, 57, ch. 2001-45; s. 35, ch. 2001-62; s. 144, ch. 2001-277; s. 60, ch. 2002-1; s. 29, ch. 2002-223; s. 6, ch. 2002-400; s. 23, ch. 2003-57; s. 2, ch. 2003-120; s. 1, ch. 2005-136; s. 2, ch. 2006-28; s. 26, ch. 2006-197; s. 67, ch. 2007-230; s. 39, ch. 2009-223; s. 82, ch. 2010-5; s. 1, ch. 2010-156; s. 2, ch. 2010-197; s. 6, ch. 2012-160.</History>
</Section>