<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.902" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prescribed pediatric extended care center,” hereinafter referred to as a “PPEC center,” means any building or buildings, or other place, whether operated for profit or not, which undertakes through its ownership or management to provide basic nonresidential services to three or more medically dependent or technologically dependent children who are not related to the owner or operator by blood, marriage, or adoption and who require such services. Infants and children considered for admission to a PPEC center must have complex medical conditions that require continual care. Prerequisites for admission are a prescription from the child’s attending physician and consent of a parent or guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Basic services” includes, but is not limited to, development, implementation, and monitoring of a comprehensive protocol of care, developed in conjunction with the parent or guardian, which specifies the medical, nursing, psychosocial, and developmental therapies required by the medically dependent or technologically dependent child served as well as the caregiver training needs of the child’s legal guardian.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner or operator” means a licensee.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medical records” means medical records maintained in accordance with accepted professional standards and practices as specified in the rules implementing this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medically dependent or technologically dependent child” means a child who because of a medical condition requires continuous therapeutic interventions or skilled nursing supervision which must be prescribed by a licensed physician and administered by, or under the direct supervision of, a licensed registered nurse.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Supportive services or contracted services” include, but are not limited to, speech therapy, occupational therapy, physical therapy, social work, developmental, child life, and psychological services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 17, ch. 87-290; ss. 1, 14, ch. 93-66; s. 19, ch. 98-288; s. 92, ch. 2007-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 391.202.</Text></Note></Section>