<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Closing of nursing facility.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of part II of chapter 408, the licensee also shall inform each resident or the next of kin, legal representative, or agency acting on behalf of the resident of the fact, and the proposed time, of discontinuance of operation and give at least 90 days’ notice so that suitable arrangements may be made for the transfer and care of the resident. In the event any resident has no such person to represent him or her, the licensee shall be responsible for securing a suitable transfer of the resident before the discontinuance of operation. The agency shall be responsible for arranging for the transfer of those residents requiring transfer who are receiving assistance under the Medicaid program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A representative of the agency shall be placed in a facility 30 days before the voluntary discontinuance of operation, or immediately upon the determination by the agency that the licensee is discontinuing operation or that existing conditions or practices represent an immediate danger to the health, safety, or security of the residents in the facility, to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitor the transfer of residents to other facilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the rights of residents are protected.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Observe the operation of the facility.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assist the management of the facility by advising the management on compliance with state and federal laws and rules.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend further action by the agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall discontinue the monitoring of a facility pursuant to subsection (2) when:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All residents in the facility have been relocated; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency determines that the conditions which gave rise to the placement of a representative of the agency in the facility no longer exist and the agency is reasonably assured that those conditions will not recur.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 17, ch. 69-309; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 15, ch. 70-361; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 4, ch. 76-201; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 11, 18, ch. 80-186; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 5, 22, ch. 82-182; ss. 25, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 58, ch. 91-282; s. 30, ch. 93-177; ss. 24, 49, ch. 93-217; s. 770, ch. 95-148; s. 69, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>