<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.9935" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Clinic responsibilities.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each clinic shall appoint a medical director or clinic director who shall agree in writing to accept legal responsibility for the following activities on behalf of the clinic. The medical director or the clinic director shall:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have signs identifying the medical director or clinic director posted in a conspicuous location within the clinic readily visible to all patients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that all practitioners providing health care services or supplies to patients maintain a current active and unencumbered Florida license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Review any patient referral contracts or agreements executed by the clinic.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that all health care practitioners at the clinic have active appropriate certification or licensure for the level of care being provided.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Serve as the clinic records owner as defined in s. 456.057.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure compliance with the recordkeeping, office surgery, and adverse incident reporting requirements of chapter 456, the respective practice acts, and rules adopted under this part and part II of chapter 408.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conduct systematic reviews of clinic billings to ensure that the billings are not fraudulent or unlawful. Upon discovery of an unlawful charge, the medical director or clinic director shall take immediate corrective action. If the clinic performs only the technical component of magnetic resonance imaging, static radiographs, computed tomography, or positron emission tomography, and provides the professional interpretation of such services, in a fixed facility that is accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations or the Accreditation Association for Ambulatory Health Care, and the American College of Radiology; and if, in the preceding quarter, the percentage of scans performed by that clinic which was billed to all personal injury protection insurance carriers was less than 15 percent, the chief financial officer of the clinic may, in a written acknowledgment provided to the agency, assume the responsibility for the conduct of the systematic reviews of clinic billings to ensure that the billings are not fraudulent or unlawful.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not refer a patient to the clinic if the clinic performs magnetic resonance imaging, static radiographs, computed tomography, or positron emission tomography. The term “refer a patient” means the referral of one or more patients of the medical or clinical director or a member of the medical or clinical director’s group practice to the clinic for magnetic resonance imaging, static radiographs, computed tomography, or positron emission tomography. A medical director who is found to violate this paragraph commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Ensure that the clinic publishes a schedule of charges for the medical services offered to patients. The schedule must include the prices charged to an uninsured person paying for such services by cash, check, credit card, or debit card. The schedule must be posted in a conspicuous place in the reception area of the urgent care center and must include, but is not limited to, the 50 services most frequently provided by the clinic. The schedule may group services by three price levels, listing services in each price level. The posting may be a sign that must be at least 15 square feet in size or through an electronic messaging board that is at least 3 square feet in size. The failure of a clinic to publish and post a schedule of charges as required by this section shall result in a fine of not more than $1,000, per day, until the schedule is published and posted.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any contract to serve as a medical director or a clinic director entered into or renewed by a physician or a licensed health care practitioner in violation of this part is void as contrary to public policy. This subsection shall apply to contracts entered into or renewed on or after March 1, 2004.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All charges or reimbursement claims made by or on behalf of a clinic that is required to be licensed under this part, but that is not so licensed, or that is otherwise operating in violation of this part, are unlawful charges, and therefore are noncompensable and unenforceable.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of s. 408.812, any person establishing, operating, or managing an unlicensed clinic otherwise required to be licensed under this part or part II of chapter 408, or any person who knowingly files a false or misleading license application or license renewal application, or false or misleading information related to such application or department rule, commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any licensed health care provider who violates this part is subject to discipline in accordance with this chapter and his or her respective practice act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity providing health care services which is not a clinic, as defined under s. 400.9905, may voluntarily apply for a certificate of exemption from licensure under its exempt status with the agency on a form that sets forth its name or names and addresses, a statement of the reasons why it cannot be defined as a clinic, and other information deemed necessary by the agency. An exemption is not transferable. The agency may charge an applicant for a certificate of exemption in an amount equal to $100 or the actual cost of processing the certificate, whichever is less. An entity seeking a certificate of exemption must publish and maintain a schedule of charges for the medical services offered to patients. The schedule must include the prices charged to an uninsured person paying for such services by cash, check, credit card, or debit card. The schedule must be posted in a conspicuous place in the reception area of the entity and must include, but is not limited to, the 50 services most frequently provided by the entity. The schedule may group services by three price levels, listing services in each price level. The posting must be at least 15 square feet in size. As a condition precedent to receiving a certificate of exemption, an applicant must provide to the agency documentation of compliance with these requirements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each clinic engaged in magnetic resonance imaging services must be accredited by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations, the American College of Radiology, or the Accreditation Association for Ambulatory Health Care, within 1 year after licensure. A clinic that is accredited by the American College of Radiology or is within the original 1-year period after licensure and replaces its core magnetic resonance imaging equipment shall be given 1 year after the date on which the equipment is replaced to attain accreditation. However, a clinic may request a single, 6-month extension if it provides evidence to the agency establishing that, for good cause shown, such clinic cannot be accredited within 1 year after licensure, and that such accreditation will be completed within the 6-month extension. After obtaining accreditation as required by this subsection, each such clinic must maintain accreditation as a condition of renewal of its license. A clinic that files a change of ownership application must comply with the original accreditation timeframe requirements of the transferor. The agency shall deny a change of ownership application if the clinic is not in compliance with the accreditation requirements. When a clinic adds, replaces, or modifies magnetic resonance imaging equipment and the accreditation agency requires new accreditation, the clinic must be accredited within 1 year after the date of the addition, replacement, or modification but may request a single, 6-month extension if the clinic provides evidence of good cause to the agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency may deny the application or revoke the license of any entity formed for the purpose of avoiding compliance with the accreditation provisions of this subsection and whose principals were previously principals of an entity that was unable to meet the accreditation requirements within the specified timeframes. The agency may adopt rules as to the accreditation of magnetic resonance imaging clinics.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall give full faith and credit pertaining to any past variance and waiver granted to a magnetic resonance imaging clinic from rule 64-2002, Florida Administrative Code, by the Department of Health, until September 2004. After that date, such clinic must request a variance and waiver from the agency under s. 120.542.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of part II of chapter 408, the clinic shall display a sign in a conspicuous location within the clinic readily visible to all patients indicating that, pursuant to s. 626.9892, the Department of Financial Services may pay rewards of up to $25,000 to persons providing information leading to the arrest and conviction of persons committing crimes investigated by the Division of Insurance Fraud arising from violations of s. 440.105, s. 624.15, s. 626.9541, s. 626.989, or s. 817.234. An authorized employee of the Division of Insurance Fraud may make unannounced inspections of a clinic licensed under this part as necessary to determine whether the clinic is in compliance with this subsection. A licensed clinic shall allow full and complete access to the premises to such authorized employee of the division who makes an inspection to determine compliance with this subsection.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2003-411; s. 17, ch. 2004-298; s. 29, ch. 2004-350; s. 4, ch. 2006-305; s. 128, ch. 2007-230; s. 45, ch. 2009-223; s. 4, ch. 2011-122; s. 3, ch. 2012-160.</History>
</Section>