<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.487" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Home health service agreements; physician’s, physician assistant’s, and advanced registered nurse practitioner’s treatment orders; patient assessment; establishment and review of plan of care; provision of services; orders not to resuscitate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Services provided by a home health agency must be covered by an agreement between the home health agency and the patient or the patient’s legal representative specifying the home health services to be provided, the rates or charges for services paid with private funds, and the sources of payment, which may include Medicare, Medicaid, private insurance, personal funds, or a combination thereof. A home health agency providing skilled care must make an assessment of the patient’s needs within 48 hours after the start of services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When required by the provisions of chapter 464; part I, part III, or part V of chapter 468; or chapter 486, the attending physician, physician assistant, or advanced registered nurse practitioner, acting within his or her respective scope of practice, shall establish treatment orders for a patient who is to receive skilled care. The treatment orders must be signed by the physician, physician assistant, or advanced registered nurse practitioner before a claim for payment for the skilled services is submitted by the home health agency. If the claim is submitted to a managed care organization, the treatment orders must be signed within the time allowed under the provider agreement. The treatment orders shall be reviewed, as frequently as the patient’s illness requires, by the physician, physician assistant, or advanced registered nurse practitioner in consultation with the home health agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A home health agency shall arrange for supervisory visits by a registered nurse to the home of a patient receiving home health aide services in accordance with the patient’s direction, approval, and agreement to pay the charge for the visits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each patient has the right to be informed of and to participate in the planning of his or her care. Each patient must be provided, upon request, a copy of the plan of care established and maintained for that patient by the home health agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When nursing services are ordered, the home health agency to which a patient has been admitted for care must provide the initial admission visit, all service evaluation visits, and the discharge visit by a direct employee. Services provided by others under contractual arrangements to a home health agency must be monitored and managed by the admitting home health agency. The admitting home health agency is fully responsible for ensuring that all care provided through its employees or contract staff is delivered in accordance with this part and applicable rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The skilled care services provided by a home health agency, directly or under contract, must be supervised and coordinated in accordance with the plan of care.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Home health agency personnel may withhold or withdraw cardiopulmonary resuscitation if presented with an order not to resuscitate executed pursuant to s. 401.45. The agency shall adopt rules providing for the implementation of such orders. Home health personnel and agencies shall not be subject to criminal prosecution or civil liability, nor be considered to have engaged in negligent or unprofessional conduct, for withholding or withdrawing cardiopulmonary resuscitation pursuant to such an order and rules adopted by the agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 46, ch. 75-233; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 4, ch. 88-219; s. 1, ch. 90-61; ss. 9, 23, ch. 93-214; s. 783, ch. 95-148; s. 3, ch. 96-222; s. 5, ch. 99-331; s. 6, ch. 99-332; s. 159, ch. 2000-318; s. 5, ch. 2005-243.</History></Section>