<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.19" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Right of entry and inspection.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with part II of chapter 408, the agency and any duly designated officer or employee thereof or a member of the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman Council or the local long-term care ombudsman council shall have the right to enter upon and into the premises of any facility licensed pursuant to this part, or any distinct nursing home unit of a hospital licensed under chapter 395 or any freestanding facility licensed under chapter 395 that provides extended care or other long-term care services, at any reasonable time in order to determine the state of compliance with the provisions of this part, part II of chapter 408, and applicable rules in force pursuant thereto. The agency shall, within 60 days after receipt of a complaint made by a resident or resident’s representative, complete its investigation and provide to the complainant its findings and resolution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall coordinate nursing home facility licensing activities and responsibilities of any duly designated officer or employee involved in nursing home facility inspection to assure necessary, equitable, and consistent supervision of inspection personnel without unnecessary duplication of inspections, consultation services, or complaint investigations.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall every 15 months conduct at least one unannounced inspection to determine compliance by the licensee with statutes, and with rules promulgated under the provisions of those statutes, governing minimum standards of construction, quality and adequacy of care, and rights of residents. The survey shall be conducted every 6 months for the next 2-year period if the facility has been cited for a class I deficiency, has been cited for two or more class II deficiencies arising from separate surveys or investigations within a 60-day period, or has had three or more substantiated complaints within a 6-month period, each resulting in at least one class I or class II deficiency. In addition to any other fees or fines in this part, the agency shall assess a fine for each facility that is subject to the 6-month survey cycle. The fine for the 2-year period shall be $6,000, one-half to be paid at the completion of each survey. The agency may adjust this fine by the change in the Consumer Price Index, based on the 12 months immediately preceding the increase, to cover the cost of the additional surveys. The agency shall verify through subsequent inspection that any deficiency identified during inspection is corrected. However, the agency may verify the correction of a class III or class IV deficiency unrelated to resident rights or resident care without reinspecting the facility if adequate written documentation has been received from the facility, which provides assurance that the deficiency has been corrected. The giving or causing to be given of advance notice of such unannounced inspections by an employee of the agency to any unauthorized person shall constitute cause for suspension of not fewer than 5 working days according to the provisions of chapter 110.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall conduct unannounced onsite facility reviews following written verification of licensee noncompliance in instances in which a long-term care ombudsman council, pursuant to ss. 400.0071 and 400.0075, has received a complaint and has documented deficiencies in resident care or in the physical plant of the facility that threaten the health, safety, or security of residents, or when the agency documents through inspection that conditions in a facility present a direct or indirect threat to the health, safety, or security of residents. However, the agency shall conduct unannounced onsite reviews every 3 months of each facility while the facility has a conditional license. Deficiencies related to physical plant do not require followup reviews after the agency has determined that correction of the deficiency has been accomplished and that the correction is of the nature that continued compliance can be reasonably expected.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 69-309; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 17, ch. 70-361; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 5, ch. 76-201; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 35, 36, ch. 79-190; ss. 13, 18, ch. 80-186; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 12, 19, ch. 82-148; ss. 26, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; ss. 21, 30, ch. 93-177; ss. 25, 49, ch. 93-217; s. 14, ch. 99-394; s. 139, ch. 2000-349; s. 59, ch. 2000-367; s. 27, ch. 2001-45; s. 70, ch. 2007-230.</History></Section>