<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.0060" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When used in this part, unless the context clearly dictates otherwise, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Administrative assessment” means a review of conditions in a long-term care facility which impact the rights, health, safety, and welfare of residents with the purpose of noting needed improvement and making recommendations to enhance the quality of life for residents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means the Agency for Health Care Administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Elderly Affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Local council” means a local long-term care ombudsman council designated by the ombudsman pursuant to s. 400.0069. Local councils are also known as district long-term care ombudsman councils or district councils.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Long-term care facility” means a nursing home facility, assisted living facility, adult family-care home, board and care facility, or any other similar residential adult care facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Office” means the Office of State Long-Term Care Ombudsman created by s. 400.0063.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ombudsman” means the individual appointed by the Secretary of Elderly Affairs to head the Office of State Long-Term Care Ombudsman.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Resident” means an individual 60 years of age or older who resides in a long-term care facility.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Secretary” means the Secretary of Elderly Affairs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State council” means the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman Council created by s. 400.0067.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 30, ch. 93-177; s. 4, ch. 95-210; s. 1, ch. 2006-121.</History></Section>