<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0400.991" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">License requirements; background screenings; prohibitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements of part II of chapter 408 apply to the provision of services that require licensure pursuant to this part and part II of chapter 408 and to entities licensed by or applying for such licensure from the agency pursuant to this part. A license issued by the agency is required in order to operate a clinic in this state. Each clinic location shall be licensed separately regardless of whether the clinic is operated under the same business name or management as another clinic.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each mobile clinic must obtain a separate health care clinic license and must provide to the agency, at least quarterly, its projected street location to enable the agency to locate and inspect such clinic. A portable equipment provider must obtain a health care clinic license for a single administrative office and is not required to submit quarterly projected street locations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The initial clinic license application shall be filed with the agency by all clinics, as defined in s. 400.9905, on or before July 1, 2004.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall contain information that includes, but need not be limited to, information pertaining to the name, residence and business address, phone number, social security number, and license number of the medical or clinic director of the licensed medical providers employed or under contract with the clinic.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the requirements of part II of chapter 408, the applicant must file with the application satisfactory proof that the clinic is in compliance with this part and applicable rules, including:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A listing of services to be provided either directly by the applicant or through contractual arrangements with existing providers;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number and discipline of each professional staff member to be employed; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof of financial ability to operate as required under s. 408.810(8). As an alternative to submitting proof of financial ability to operate as required under s. 408.810(8), the applicant may file a surety bond of at least $500,000 which guarantees that the clinic will act in full conformity with all legal requirements for operating a clinic, payable to the agency. The agency may adopt rules to specify related requirements for such surety bond.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this subsection, the term “applicant” means individuals owning or controlling, directly or indirectly, 5 percent or more of an interest in a clinic; the medical or clinic director, or a similarly titled person who is responsible for the day-to-day operation of the licensed clinic; the financial officer or similarly titled individual who is responsible for the financial operation of the clinic; and licensed health care practitioners at the clinic.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall require level 2 background screening for applicants and personnel as required in s. 408.809(1)(e) pursuant to chapter 435 and s. 408.809.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant must submit to the agency, with the application, a description and explanation of any exclusions, permanent suspensions, or terminations of an applicant from the Medicare or Medicaid programs. Proof of compliance with the requirements for disclosure of ownership and control interest under the Medicaid or Medicare programs may be accepted in lieu of this submission. The description and explanation may indicate whether such exclusions, suspensions, or terminations were voluntary or not voluntary on the part of the applicant.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All agency forms for licensure application or exemption from licensure under this part must contain the following statement:</Text>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="BlockFlush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true">INSURANCE FRAUD NOTICE.<EmDash />A person who knowingly submits a false, misleading, or fraudulent application or other document when applying for licensure as a health care clinic, seeking an exemption from licensure as a health care clinic, or demonstrating compliance with part X of chapter 400, Florida Statutes, with the intent to use the license, exemption from licensure, or demonstration of compliance to provide services or seek reimbursement under the Florida Motor Vehicle No-Fault Law, commits a fraudulent insurance act, as defined in s. 626.989, Florida Statutes. A person who presents a claim for personal injury protection benefits knowing that the payee knowingly submitted such health care clinic application or document, commits insurance fraud, as defined in s. 817.234, Florida Statutes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2003-411; s. 56, ch. 2004-267; s. 16, ch. 2004-298; s. 28, ch. 2004-350; s. 123, ch. 2007-230; s. 18, ch. 2010-114; s. 3, ch. 2012-197.</History>
</Section>