<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.611" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Interdisciplinary records of care; confidentiality.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An up-to-date, interdisciplinary record of care being given and patient and family status shall be kept. Records shall contain pertinent past and current medical, nursing, social, and other therapeutic information and such other information that is necessary for the safe and adequate care of the patient. Notations regarding all aspects of care for the patient and family shall be made in the record. When services are terminated, the record shall show the date and reason for termination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Patient records shall be retained for a period of 5 years after termination of hospice services, unless otherwise provided by law. In the case of a patient who is a minor, the 5-year period shall begin on the date the patient reaches or would have reached the age of majority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Patient records of care are confidential. A hospice may not release a record or any portion thereof, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A patient or legal guardian has given express written informed consent;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A court of competent jurisdiction has so ordered; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state or federal agency, acting under its statutory authority, requires submission of aggregate statistical data. Any information obtained from patient records by a state agency pursuant to its statutory authority is confidential and exempt from the provisions of s. 119.07(1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 79-186; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 79, 83, ch. 83-181; ss. 12, 14, ch. 93-179; s. 232, ch. 96-406.</History></Section>