<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0400.0075" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Complaint notification and resolution procedures.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any complaint or problem verified by an ombudsman council as a result of an investigation or onsite administrative assessment, which complaint or problem is determined to require remedial action by the local council, shall be identified and brought to the attention of the long-term care facility administrator in writing. Upon receipt of such document, the administrator, with the concurrence of the local council chair, shall establish target dates for taking appropriate remedial action. If, by the target date, the remedial action is not completed or forthcoming, the local council chair may, after obtaining approval from the ombudsman and a majority of the members of the local council:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extend the target date if the chair has reason to believe such action would facilitate the resolution of the complaint.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 400.0077, publicize the complaint, the recommendations of the council, and the response of the long-term care facility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refer the complaint to the state council.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the local council chair believes that the health, safety, welfare, or rights of the resident are in imminent danger, the chair shall notify the ombudsman or legal advocate, who, after verifying that such imminent danger exists, shall seek immediate legal or administrative remedies to protect the resident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the ombudsman has reason to believe that the long-term care facility or an employee of the facility has committed a criminal act, the ombudsman shall provide the local law enforcement agency with the relevant information to initiate an investigation of the case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon referral from a local council, the state council shall assume the responsibility for the disposition of the complaint. If a long-term care facility fails to take action on a complaint by the state council, the state council may, after obtaining approval from the ombudsman and a majority of the state council members:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In accordance with s. 400.0077, publicize the complaint, the recommendations of the local or state council, and the response of the long-term care facility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the department and the agency a series of facility reviews pursuant to s. 400.19, s. 429.34, or s. 429.67 to ensure correction and nonrecurrence of conditions that give rise to complaints against a long-term care facility.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the department and the agency that the long-term care facility no longer receive payments under any state assistance program, including Medicaid.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommend to the department and the agency that procedures be initiated for revocation of the long-term care facility’s license in accordance with chapter 120.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the state council chair believes that the health, safety, welfare, or rights of the resident are in imminent danger, the chair shall notify the ombudsman or legal advocate, who, after verifying that such imminent danger exists, shall seek immediate legal or administrative remedies to protect the resident.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the ombudsman has reason to believe that the long-term care facility or an employee of the facility has committed a criminal act, the ombudsman shall provide local law enforcement with the relevant information to initiate an investigation of the case.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 75-233; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 244, ch. 77-147; s. 11, ch. 77-401; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 19, ch. 78-95; ss. 14, 18, ch. 80-186; ss. 9, 12, ch. 80-198; ss. 4, 6, ch. 81-184; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 4, ch. 82-46; ss. 17, 19, ch. 82-148; ss. 38, 79, 83, ch. 83-181; s. 17, ch. 90-347; ss. 8, 29, 30, ch. 93-177; s. 49, ch. 93-217; s. 762, ch. 95-148; s. 42, ch. 95-196; s. 115, ch. 99-8; s. 128, ch. 2000-349; s. 48, ch. 2000-367; s. 44, ch. 2004-5; s. 12, ch. 2006-121; s. 78, ch. 2007-5.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 400.317.</Text></Note></Section>