<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0392.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Adherence to treatment; treatment plan; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department, its authorized representatives, or a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459 shall prescribe an individualized treatment plan for each person who has active tuberculosis. The goal of the treatment plan is to achieve treatment to cure by the least restrictive means. The department shall develop, by rule, a standard treatment plan form that must include, but is not limited to, a statement of available services for treatment, which includes the use of directly observed therapy; all findings in the evaluation and diagnostic process; measurable objectives for treatment progress; and time periods for achieving each objective. Each treatment plan must be implemented through a case management approach designed to advance the individual needs of the person who has active tuberculosis. The person’s progress in achieving the objectives of the treatment plan must be periodically reviewed and revised as necessary, in consultation with the person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may petition a circuit court under s. 392.55, s. 392.56, or s. 392.57, as it deems appropriate, to require adherence to treatment plans prescribed under subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has active tuberculosis and who fails to comply with a treatment plan or any other requirement that is imposed by the court under s. 392.55, s. 392.56, or s. 392.57, or any minor’s parent, guardian, or custodian who fails to comply with a treatment plan or any other requirement of the court, or any person who aids or abets in the failure to comply with treatment plans and other requirements of the court may be punished by contempt proceedings in addition to other penalties that may be imposed under s. 392.67.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contempt proceedings may be initiated by the department or its authorized representatives.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-389; s. 1, ch. 88-398; s. 15, ch. 94-320.</History></Section>