<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0392.52" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Active tuberculosis” means tuberculosis disease that is demonstrated to be contagious by clinical or bacteriological evidence, or by other means as determined by rule of the department. Tuberculosis disease is considered active until cured.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“County health department” means an agency or entity designated as such in chapter 154.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Cure” or “treatment to cure” means the completion of a course of antituberculosis treatment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Directly observed therapy” means treatment in which a patient ingests medications under the observation of a health care provider or other responsible party.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Threat to the public health” means a rebuttable presumption that a person has active tuberculosis and:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not taking medications as prescribed;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not following the recommendations of the treating physician;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not seeking treatment for signs and symptoms compatible with tuberculosis; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evidences a disregard for the health of the public.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tuberculosis” means a disease caused by Mycobacterium tuberculosis, Mycobacterium bovis, or Mycobacterium africanum.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-389; s. 1, ch. 88-398; s. 3, ch. 94-320; s. 95, ch. 97-101; s. 34, ch. 97-237.</History></Section>