<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0392.69" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Appropriation, sinking, and maintenance trust funds; additional powers of the department.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature shall include in its annual appropriations act a sufficient sum for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys required to be paid by the several counties and patients for the care and maintenance of patients hospitalized by the department for tuberculosis shall be paid to the department, and the department shall immediately transmit these moneys to the Chief Financial Officer, who shall deposit the moneys in the Operations and Maintenance Trust Fund, which shall contain all moneys appropriated by the Legislature or received from patients or other third parties and shall be expended for the operation and maintenance of the state-operated tuberculosis hospital.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the execution of its public health program functions, notwithstanding s. 216.292(2)(b)2., the department is hereby authorized to use any sums of money which it may heretofore have saved or which it may hereafter save from its regular operating appropriation, or use any sums of money acquired by gift or grant, or any sums of money it may acquire by the issuance of revenue certificates of the hospital to match or supplement any state or federal funds, or any moneys received by said department by gift or otherwise, for the construction or maintenance of additional facilities or improvement to existing facilities, as the department deems necessary.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall appoint an advisory board, which shall meet quarterly to review and make recommendations relating to patient care at A. G. Holley State Hospital. Members shall be appointed for terms of 3 years, with such appointments being staggered so that terms of no more than two members expire in any one year. Members shall serve without compensation, but they are entitled to be reimbursed for per diem and travel expenses under s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-389; s. 1, ch. 88-398; s. 17, ch. 96-418; s. 28, ch. 99-397; s. 57, ch. 2000-371; s. 411, ch. 2003-261; s. 50, ch. 2005-152.</History></Section>