<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0392.56" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Hospitalization, placement, and residential isolation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of subsections (2) and (3), the department may petition the circuit court to order a person who has active tuberculosis to be hospitalized, placed in another health care facility or residential facility, or isolated from the general public in the home as a result of the probable spread of tuberculosis, until such time as the risk of infection to the general public can be eliminated or reduced in such a manner that a threat to the public health no longer exists.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not be ordered to be hospitalized, placed in another health care facility or residential facility, or isolated from the general public in the home, except upon the order of a circuit court and upon proof:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the department, by clear and convincing evidence, that a threat to the public health is posed by the person who has active tuberculosis;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the person who has active tuberculosis has been counseled about the disease, the threat to the public health posed by tuberculosis, and methods to minimize the risk to the public, and, despite such counseling, indicates an intent by words or action to expose the public to active tuberculosis; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That all other reasonable means of achieving compliance with treatment have been exhausted and no less restrictive alternative exists.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not be ordered by a circuit court to be hospitalized, placed in another health care facility or residential facility, or isolated from the general public in the home, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hearing has been held, with respect to which the person has received at least 72 hours’ prior written notification and has received a list of the proposed actions to be taken and the reasons for each such action. However, with the consent of the person or the person’s counsel, a hearing may be held within less than 72 hours;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The person has the right to attend the hearing, to cross-examine witnesses, and present evidence. After review and consultation by the court, counsel for the person may waive the client’s presence or allow the client to appear by television monitor where available; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court advises the person of the right to have counsel present. If the person is insolvent and unable to employ counsel, the court shall appoint legal counsel for the person pursuant to the indigence criteria in s. 27.52.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order requiring the hospitalization, placement in a health care facility or residential facility, or isolation from public in the home must expire no later than 180 days after the date of the order or when the physician charged with the care of the person determines that the person no longer poses a threat to the public health, if the determination is made before the end of the 180-day period. Orders for hospitalization of a person or placement in a facility or isolation in the home may not be renewed unless the person is afforded all rights conferred in subsections (2) and (3). A hearing must be held within 14 days before the expiration of the 180-day period to determine the necessity for the person’s continued hospitalization or necessary care and treatment to cure after release. The person’s records from the inception of the disease are admissible evidence in the hearing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department petitions the circuit court to order that a person who has active tuberculosis be hospitalized in a facility operated under s. 392.62, the department shall notify the facility of the potential court order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The circuit court, legal counsel, and local law enforcement officials, as appropriate, shall consult with the department concerning any necessary infection control procedures to be taken during any court hearing or detention.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-389; s. 1, ch. 88-398; s. 7, ch. 94-320; s. 106, ch. 2003-402; s. 120, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>