<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0392.61" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Community tuberculosis control programs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall operate, directly or by contract, community tuberculosis control programs in each county in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community tuberculosis control programs shall have the following functions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promotion of community and professional education about the causes and dangers of tuberculosis and methods of its control and treatment to cure;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Community and individual screening for the presence of tuberculosis;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Surveillance of all suspected and reported cases of active tuberculosis, including contact investigation as necessary and as directed by the department;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reporting of all known cases of tuberculosis to the department;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Development of an individualized treatment plan for each person who has active tuberculosis and who is under the care of the department, including provision of treatment to cure and followup, and the distribution of medication by means of directly observed therapy, if appropriate, to eligible persons under rules and guidelines developed by the department; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision of counseling, periodic retesting, and referral to appropriate social service, employment, medical, and housing agencies, as necessary for persons released from hospitalization or residential placement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prevent the department from operating regionally based tuberculosis control programs, if services are offered in each county.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 88-389; s. 1, ch. 88-398; s. 12, ch. 94-320; s. 82, ch. 2012-184.</History></Section>