<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0671.309" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Required refilings.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a security interest is perfected or has priority when this act takes effect as to all persons or as to certain persons without any filing or recording, and if the filing of a financing statement would be required for the perfection or priority of the security interest against those persons under this act, the perfection and priority rights of the security interest continue until 3 years after the effective date of this act. The perfection will then lapse unless a financing statement is filed as provided in subsection (4) or unless the security interest is perfected otherwise than by filing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a security interest is perfected when this act takes effect under a law other than the Uniform Commercial Code which requires no further filing, refiling, or recording to continue its perfection, perfection continues until and will lapse 3 years after this act takes effect, unless:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financing statement is filed as provided in subsection (4);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The security interest is perfected otherwise than by filing; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under <Reference Number="1" />s. 679.302(3) the other law continues to govern filing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a security interest is perfected by a filing, refiling, or recording under a law repealed by this act which required further filing, refiling, or recording to continue its perfection, perfection continues and will lapse on the date provided by the law so repealed for such further filing, refiling, or recording unless a financing statement is filed as provided in subsection (4) or unless the security interest is perfected otherwise than by filing.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A financing statement may be filed within 6 months before the perfection of a security interest would otherwise lapse. Any such financing statement may be signed by either the debtor or the secured party. It must identify the security agreement, statement, or notice (however denominated in any statute or other law repealed or modified by this act), state the office where and the date when the last filing, refiling, or recording, if any, was made with respect thereto and the filing number, if any, or book and page, if any, of recording and further state that the security agreement, statement, or notice, however denominated, in another filing office under the Uniform Commercial Code or under any statute or other law repealed or modified by this act is still effective. Sections <Reference Number="2" />679.103 and <Reference Number="3" />679.401 determine the proper place to file such a financing statement. Except as specified in this subsection, the provisions of <Reference Number="3" />s. 679.403(3) for continuation statements apply to such a financing statement.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 38, ch. 79-398; s. 6, ch. 90-278.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 3, ch. 2001-198.</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 1, ch. 2001-198.</Text></Note><Note Reference="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Repealed by s. 4, ch. 2001-198.</Text></Note><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 680.109.</Text></Note></Section>