<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0671.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purposes; rules of construction; variation by agreement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This code shall be liberally construed and applied to promote its underlying purposes and policies, which are:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To simplify, clarify, and modernize the law governing commercial transactions.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To permit the continued expansion of commercial practices through custom, usage, and agreement of the parties.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To make uniform the law among the various jurisdictions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided in this code, the effect of provisions of this code may be varied by agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligations of good faith, diligence, reasonableness, and care prescribed by this code may not be disclaimed by agreement, but the parties may by agreement determine the standards by which the performance of such obligations is to be measured if such standards are not manifestly unreasonable. Whenever this code requires an action to be taken within a reasonable time, a time that is not manifestly unreasonable may be fixed by agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The presence in certain provisions of this code of the words “unless otherwise agreed” or words of similar import does not imply that the effect of other provisions may not be varied by agreement under this subsection.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In this code, unless the context otherwise requires:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Words in the singular include the plural, and words in the plural include the singular.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Words of either gender also refer to the other gender.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 65-254; s. 551, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 2007-134.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">s. 1-102, U.C.C.; supersedes ss. 678.53, 614.31.</Text></Note></Section>