<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.07" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Persons engaged in criminal offense, having weapons.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever, while committing or attempting to commit any felony or while under indictment, displays, uses, threatens, or attempts to use any weapon or electric weapon or device or carries a concealed weapon is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever, while committing or attempting to commit any felony, displays, uses, threatens, or attempts to use any firearm or carries a concealed firearm is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, and s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following crimes are excluded from application of this section: Antitrust violations, unfair trade practices, restraints of trade, nonsupport of dependents, bigamy, or other similar offenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever, having previously been convicted of a violation of subsection (1) or subsection (2) and, subsequent to such conviction, displays, uses, threatens, or attempts to use any weapon, firearm, or electric weapon or device, carries a concealed weapon, or carries a concealed firearm while committing or attempting to commit any felony or while under indictment is guilty of a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. Sentence shall not be suspended or deferred under the provisions of this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 1637, 1868; RS 2423; s. 2, ch. 4124, 1893; GS 3269; RGS 5102; CGL 7204; s. 4, ch. 69-306; s. 741, ch. 71-136; s. 2, ch. 76-165; s. 2, ch. 91-223.</History></Section>