<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.29" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Paramilitary training; teaching or participation prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act shall be known and may be cited as the “State Antiparamilitary Training Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term “civil disorder” means a public disturbance involving acts of violence by an assemblage of three or more persons, which disturbance causes an immediate danger of, or results in, damage or injury to the property or person of any other individual within the United States.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever teaches or demonstrates to any other person the use, application, or making of any firearm, destructive device, or technique capable of causing injury or death to persons, knowing or having reason to know or intending that the same will be unlawfully employed for use in, or in furtherance of, a civil disorder within the United States, is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whoever assembles with one or more persons for the purpose of training with, practicing with, or being instructed in the use of any firearm, destructive device, or technique capable of causing injury or death to persons, intending to unlawfully employ the same for use in, or in furtherance of, a civil disorder within the United States, is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to prohibit any act of a law enforcement officer which is performed in connection with the lawful performance of his or her official duties or to prohibit the training or teaching of the use of weapons to be used for hunting, recreation, competition, self-defense or the protection of one’s person or property, or other lawful use.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 82-5; s. 164, ch. 83-216; s. 1220, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>