<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.001" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, except where the context otherwise requires:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Antique firearm” means any firearm manufactured in or before 1918 (including any matchlock, flintlock, percussion cap, or similar early type of ignition system) or replica thereof, whether actually manufactured before or after the year 1918, and also any firearm using fixed ammunition manufactured in or before 1918, for which ammunition is no longer manufactured in the United States and is not readily available in the ordinary channels of commercial trade.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Concealed firearm” means any firearm, as defined in subsection (6), which is carried on or about a person in such a manner as to conceal the firearm from the ordinary sight of another person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Concealed weapon” means any dirk, metallic knuckles, slungshot, billie, tear gas gun, chemical weapon or device, or other deadly weapon carried on or about a person in such a manner as to conceal the weapon from the ordinary sight of another person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tear gas gun” or “chemical weapon or device” means any weapon of such nature, except a device known as a “self-defense chemical spray.” “Self-defense chemical spray” means a device carried solely for purposes of lawful self-defense that is compact in size, designed to be carried on or about the person, and contains not more than two ounces of chemical.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Destructive device” means any bomb, grenade, mine, rocket, missile, pipebomb, or similar device containing an explosive, incendiary, or poison gas and includes any frangible container filled with an explosive, incendiary, explosive gas, or expanding gas, which is designed or so constructed as to explode by such filler and is capable of causing bodily harm or property damage; any combination of parts either designed or intended for use in converting any device into a destructive device and from which a destructive device may be readily assembled; any device declared a destructive device by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms; any type of weapon which will, is designed to, or may readily be converted to expel a projectile by the action of any explosive and which has a barrel with a bore of one-half inch or more in diameter; and ammunition for such destructive devices, but not including shotgun shells or any other ammunition designed for use in a firearm other than a destructive device. “Destructive device” does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A device which is not designed, redesigned, used, or intended for use as a weapon;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any device, although originally designed as a weapon, which is redesigned so that it may be used solely as a signaling, line-throwing, safety, or similar device;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any shotgun other than a short-barreled shotgun; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any nonautomatic rifle (other than a short-barreled rifle) generally recognized or particularly suitable for use for the hunting of big game.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Explosive” means any chemical compound or mixture that has the property of yielding readily to combustion or oxidation upon application of heat, flame, or shock, including but not limited to dynamite, nitroglycerin, trinitrotoluene, or ammonium nitrate when combined with other ingredients to form an explosive mixture, blasting caps, and detonators; but not including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Shotgun shells, cartridges, or ammunition for firearms;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fireworks as defined in s. 791.01;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Smokeless propellant powder or small arms ammunition primers, if possessed, purchased, sold, transported, or used in compliance with s. 552.241;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Black powder in quantities not to exceed that authorized by chapter 552, or by any rules adopted thereunder by the Department of Financial Services, when used for, or intended to be used for, the manufacture of target and sporting ammunition or for use in muzzle-loading flint or percussion weapons.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The exclusions contained in paragraphs (a)-(d) do not apply to the term “explosive” as used in the definition of “firearm” in subsection (6).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Firearm” means any weapon (including a starter gun) which will, is designed to, or may readily be converted to expel a projectile by the action of an explosive; the frame or receiver of any such weapon; any firearm muffler or firearm silencer; any destructive device; or any machine gun. The term “firearm” does not include an antique firearm unless the antique firearm is used in the commission of a crime.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Indictment” means an indictment or an information in any court under which a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year may be prosecuted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law enforcement officer” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All officers or employees of the United States or the State of Florida, or any agency, commission, department, board, division, municipality, or subdivision thereof, who have authority to make arrests;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Officers or employees of the United States or the State of Florida, or any agency, commission, department, board, division, municipality, or subdivision thereof, duly authorized to carry a concealed weapon;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the Armed Forces of the United States, the organized reserves, state militia, or Florida National Guard, when on duty, when preparing themselves for, or going to or from, military duty, or under orders;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An employee of the state prisons or correctional systems who has been so designated by the Department of Corrections or by a warden of an institution;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All peace officers;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All state attorneys and United States attorneys and their respective assistants and investigators.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Machine gun” means any firearm, as defined herein, which shoots, or is designed to shoot, automatically more than one shot, without manually reloading, by a single function of the trigger.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Short-barreled shotgun” means a shotgun having one or more barrels less than 18 inches in length and any weapon made from a shotgun (whether by alteration, modification, or otherwise) if such weapon as modified has an overall length of less than 26 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Short-barreled rifle” means a rifle having one or more barrels less than 16 inches in length and any weapon made from a rifle (whether by alteration, modification, or otherwise) if such weapon as modified has an overall length of less than 26 inches.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Slungshot” means a small mass of metal, stone, sand, or similar material fixed on a flexible handle, strap, or the like, used as a weapon.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Weapon” means any dirk, knife, metallic knuckles, slungshot, billie, tear gas gun, chemical weapon or device, or other deadly weapon except a firearm or a common pocketknife, plastic knife, or blunt-bladed table knife.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Electric weapon or device” means any device which, through the application or use of electrical current, is designed, redesigned, used, or intended to be used for offensive or defensive purposes, the destruction of life, or the infliction of injury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dart-firing stun gun” means any device having one or more darts that are capable of delivering an electrical current.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Readily accessible for immediate use” means that a firearm or other weapon is carried on the person or within such close proximity and in such a manner that it can be retrieved and used as easily and quickly as if carried on the person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Securely encased” means in a glove compartment, whether or not locked; snapped in a holster; in a gun case, whether or not locked; in a zippered gun case; or in a closed box or container which requires a lid or cover to be opened for access.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sterile area” means the area of an airport to which access is controlled by the inspection of persons and property in accordance with federally approved airport security programs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Ammunition” means an object consisting of all of the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A fixed metallic or nonmetallic hull or casing containing a primer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One or more projectiles, one or more bullets, or shot.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gunpowder.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">All of the specified components must be present for an object to be ammunition.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-306; ss. 13, 19, 35, ch. 69-106; ss. 1, 2, ch. 70-441; s. 32, ch. 73-334; s. 1, ch. 76-165; s. 12, ch. 77-120; s. 1, ch. 78-200; s. 19, ch. 79-3; s. 1, ch. 79-58; s. 1, ch. 80-112; s. 1, ch. 82-131; s. 162, ch. 83-216; s. 2, ch. 88-183; s. 43, ch. 88-381; s. 1, ch. 90-124; s. 1, ch. 90-176; s. 1, ch. 93-17; s. 1, ch. 97-72; s. 1202, ch. 97-102; s. 5, ch. 2000-161; s. 1904, ch. 2003-261; s. 1, ch. 2004-286; s. 1, ch. 2006-186; s. 1, ch. 2006-298.</History></Section>