<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.164" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">False reports concerning planting a bomb, explosive, or weapon of mass destruction in, or committing arson against, state-owned property; penalty; reward.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to make a false report, with intent to deceive, mislead, or otherwise misinform any person, concerning the placing or planting of any bomb, dynamite, other deadly explosive, or weapon of mass destruction as defined in s. 790.166, or concerning any act of arson or other violence to property owned by the state or any political subdivision. Any person violating this subsection commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law, adjudication of guilt or imposition of sentence for a violation of this section may not be suspended, deferred, or withheld. However, the state attorney may move the sentencing court to reduce or suspend the sentence of any person who is convicted of a violation of this section and who provides substantial assistance in the identification, arrest, or conviction of any of his or her accomplices, accessories, coconspirators, or principals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that a person accused of violating this section knowingly made a false report is prima facie evidence of the accused person’s intent to deceive, mislead, or otherwise misinform any person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a $5,000 reward for the giving of information to any law enforcement agency in the state, which information leads to the arrest and conviction of any person violating the provisions of this section. Any person claiming such reward shall apply to the law enforcement agency developing the case and be paid by the Department of Law Enforcement from the deficiency fund.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be only one reward given for each case, regardless of how many persons are arrested and convicted in connection with the case and regardless of how many persons submit claims for the reward.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Law Enforcement shall establish procedures to be used by all reward applicants, and the circuit judge in whose jurisdiction the action occurs shall review all such applications and make final determination as to those applicants entitled to receive an award.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalty provided by law with respect to any person who is convicted of a violation of this section that resulted in the mobilization or action of any law enforcement officer or any state or local agency, a person convicted of a violation of this section may be required by the court to pay restitution for all of the costs and damages arising from the criminal conduct.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 2, 2A, ch. 71-306; s. 1, ch. 76-146; s. 236, ch. 77-104; s. 25, ch. 79-8; s. 2, ch. 2002-28.</History></Section>