<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.331" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibition of civil actions against firearms or ammunition manufacturers, firearms trade associations, firearms or ammunition distributors, or firearms or ammunition dealers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds and declares that the manufacture, distribution, or sale of firearms and ammunition by manufacturers, distributors, or dealers duly licensed by the appropriate federal and state authorities is a lawful activity and is not unreasonably dangerous, and further finds that the unlawful use of firearms and ammunition, rather than their lawful manufacture, distribution, or sale, is the proximate cause of injuries arising from their unlawful use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as permitted by this section, a legal action against a firearms or ammunition manufacturer, firearms trade association, firearms or ammunition distributor, or firearms or ammunition dealer on behalf of the state or its agencies and instrumentalities, or on behalf of a county, municipality, special district, or any other political subdivision or agency of the state, for damages, abatement, or injunctive relief resulting from or arising out of the lawful design, marketing, distribution, or sale of firearms or ammunition to the public is prohibited. However, this subsection does not preclude a natural person from bringing an action against a firearms or ammunition manufacturer, firearms trade association, firearms or ammunition distributor, or firearms or ammunition dealer for breach of a written contract, breach of an express warranty, or injuries resulting from a defect in the materials or workmanship in the manufacture of a firearm or ammunition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A county, municipality, special district, or other political subdivision or agency of the state may not sue for or recover from a firearms or ammunition manufacturer, firearms trade association, firearms or ammunition distributor, or firearms or ammunition dealer damages, abatement, or injunctive relief in any case that arises out of or results from the lawful design, marketing, distribution, or sale of firearms or ammunition to the public.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit an action against a firearms or ammunition manufacturer, distributor, or dealer for:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Breach of contract or warranty in connection with a firearm or ammunition purchased by a county, municipality, special district, or other political subdivision or agency of the state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Injuries resulting from the malfunction of a firearm or ammunition due to a defect in design or manufacture.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the potential of a firearm or ammunition to cause serious injury, damage, or death as a result of normal function does not constitute a defective condition of the product.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A firearm or ammunition may not be deemed defective on the basis of its potential to cause serious injury, damage, or death when discharged legally or illegally.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a civil action is brought in violation of this section, the defendant may recover all expenses resulting from such action from the governmental entity bringing such action.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any civil action where the court finds that the defendant is immune as provided in this section, the court shall award the defendant all attorney’s fees, costs and compensation for loss of income, and expenses incurred as a result of such action.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to any action brought on or after the effective date of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2001-38.</History></Section>