<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.166" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Manufacture, possession, sale, delivery, display, use, or attempted or threatened use of a weapon of mass destruction or hoax weapon of mass destruction prohibited; definitions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Weapon of mass destruction” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any device or object that is designed or intended to cause death or serious bodily injury to any human or animal, or severe emotional or mental harm to any human, through the release, dissemination, or impact of toxic or poisonous chemicals, or their precursors;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any device or object involving a biological agent;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any device or object that is designed or intended to release radiation or radioactivity at a level dangerous to human or animal life; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any biological agent, toxin, vector, or delivery system.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Hoax weapon of mass destruction” means any device or object that by its design, construction, content, or characteristics appears to be or to contain, or is represented to be, constitute, or contain, a weapon of mass destruction as defined in this section, but which is, in fact, an inoperative facsimile, imitation, counterfeit, or representation of a weapon of mass destruction which does not meet the definition of a weapon of mass destruction or which does not actually contain or constitute a weapon, biological agent, toxin, vector, or delivery system prohibited by this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Biological agent” means any microorganism, virus, infectious substance, or biological product that may be engineered through biotechnology, or any naturally occurring or bioengineered component of any such microorganism, virus, infectious substance, or biological product, capable of causing:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Death, disease, or other biological malfunction in a human, an animal, a plant, or other living organism;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deterioration of food, water, equipment, supplies, or material of any kind; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deleterious alteration of the environment.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Toxin” means the toxic material of plants, animals, microorganisms, viruses, fungi, or infectious substances, or a recombinant molecule, whatever its origin or method of reproduction, including:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any poisonous substance or biological product that may be engineered through biotechnology produced by a living organism; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any poisonous isomer or biological product, homolog, or derivative of such substance.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Delivery system” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any apparatus, equipment, device, or means of delivery specifically designed to deliver or disseminate a biological agent, toxin, or vector; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any vector.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Vector” means a living organism or molecule, including a recombinant molecule or biological product that may be engineered through biotechnology, capable of carrying a biological agent or toxin to a host.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who, without lawful authority, manufactures, possesses, sells, delivers, sends, mails, displays, uses, threatens to use, attempts to use, or conspires to use, or who makes readily accessible to others a weapon of mass destruction commits a felony of the first degree, punishable by imprisonment for a term of years not exceeding life or as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, and if death results, commits a capital felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who, without lawful authority, manufactures, possesses, sells, delivers, mails, sends, displays, uses, threatens to use, attempts to use, or conspires to use, or who makes readily accessible to others, a hoax weapon of mass destruction commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who, while committing or attempting to commit any felony, possesses, displays, or threatens to use any hoax weapon of mass destruction commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other law, adjudication of guilt or imposition of sentence may not be suspended, deferred, or withheld for a violation of this section. However, the state attorney may move the sentencing court to reduce or suspend the sentence of any person who is convicted of a violation of this section and who provides substantial assistance in the identification, arrest, or conviction of any of his or her accomplices, accessories, coconspirators, or principals.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proof that a device or object described in subparagraph (1)(a)1. caused death or serious bodily injury to a human or animal through the release, dissemination, or impact of toxic or poisonous chemicals, or their precursors, is prima facie evidence that the device or object was designed or intended to cause such death or serious bodily injury. Proof that a device or object described in subparagraph (1)(a)3. released radiation or radioactivity at a level dangerous to human or animal life is prima facie evidence that the device or object was designed or intended for such release.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to any member or employee of the Armed Forces of the United States, a federal or state governmental agency, or a private entity who is otherwise engaged in lawful activity within the scope of his or her employment, if such person is otherwise duly authorized or licensed to manufacture, possess, sell, deliver, display, or otherwise engage in activity relative to this section and if such person is in compliance with applicable federal and state law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “weapon of mass destruction” does not include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A device or instrument that emits or discharges smoke or an offensive, noxious, or irritant liquid, powder, gas, or chemical for the purpose of immobilizing, incapacitating, or thwarting an attack by a person or animal and that is lawfully possessed or used by a person for the purpose of self-protection or, as provided in subsection (7), is lawfully possessed or used by any member or employee of the Armed Forces of the United States, a federal or state governmental agency, or a private entity. A member or employee of a federal or state governmental agency includes, but is not limited to, a law enforcement officer, as defined in s. 784.07; a federal law enforcement officer, as defined in s. 901.1505; and an emergency service employee, as defined in s. 496.404.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The liquid, powder, gas, chemical, or smoke that is emitted or discharged from a device or instrument as specified in paragraph (a).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to any other penalty provided by law with respect to any person who is convicted of a violation of this section that resulted in the mobilization or action of any law enforcement officer or any state or local agency, a person convicted of a violation of this section may be required by the court to pay restitution for all of the costs and damages arising from the criminal conduct.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2000-218; s. 4, ch. 2002-28.</History></Section>