<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.155" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Blood test for impairment or intoxication in cases of death or serious bodily injury; right to use reasonable force.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any recognized ability to refuse to submit to the tests provided in s. 790.153, if a law enforcement officer has probable cause to believe that a firearm used by a person under the influence of alcoholic beverages or controlled substances has caused the death or serious bodily injury of a human being, such person shall submit, upon the request of a law enforcement officer, to a test of his or her blood for the purpose of determining the alcoholic content thereof or the presence of controlled substances therein. The law enforcement officer may use reasonable force if necessary to require such person to submit to the administration of the blood test. The blood test shall be performed in a reasonable manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The term “serious bodily injury” means a physical condition which creates a substantial risk of death, serious personal disfigurement, or protracted loss or impairment of the function of any bodily member or organ.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of s. 316.1933(2), relating to blood tests for impairment or intoxication, are incorporated into this act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any criminal charge resulting from the incident giving rise to the officer’s demand for testing should be tried concurrently with a charge of any violation of s. 790.151. If such charges are tried separately, the fact that such person refused, resisted, obstructed, or opposed testing shall be admissible at the trial of the criminal offense which gave rise to the demand for testing.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The results of any test administered pursuant to this section for the purpose of detecting the presence of any controlled substance shall not be admissible as evidence in a criminal prosecution for the possession of a controlled substance.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision of law pertaining to the confidentiality of hospital records or other medical records, information obtained pursuant to this section shall be released to a court, prosecuting attorney, defense attorney, or law enforcement officer in connection with an alleged violation of s. 790.151 upon request for such information.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 91-84; s. 1212, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>