<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.08" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Taking possession of weapons and arms; reports; disposition; custody.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Every officer making an arrest under s. 790.07, or under any other law or municipal ordinance within the state, shall take possession of any weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms mentioned in s. 790.07 found upon the person arrested and deliver them to the sheriff of the county, or the chief of police of the municipality wherein the arrest is made, who shall retain the same until after the trial of the person arrested.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person arrested as aforesaid is convicted of violating s. 790.07, or of a similar offense under any municipal ordinance, or any other offense involving the use or attempted use of such weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms, such weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms shall become forfeited to the state, without any order of forfeiture being necessary, although the making of such an order shall be deemed proper, and such weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms shall be forthwith delivered to the sheriff by the chief of police or other person having custody thereof, and the sheriff is hereby made the custodian of such weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms for the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person arrested as aforesaid is acquitted of the offenses mentioned in subsection (2), the said weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms taken from the person as aforesaid shall be returned to him or her; however, if he or she fails to call for or receive the same within 60 days from and after his or her acquittal or the dismissal of the charges against him or her, the same shall be delivered to the sheriff as aforesaid to be held by the sheriff as hereinafter provided. This subsection shall likewise apply to persons and their weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms who have heretofore been acquitted or the charges against them dismissed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All such weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms now in, or hereafter coming into, the hands of any of the peace officers of this state or any of its political subdivisions, which have been found abandoned or otherwise discarded, or left in their hands and not reclaimed by the owners shall, within 60 days, be delivered by such peace officers to the sheriff of the county aforesaid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms coming into the hands of the sheriff pursuant to subsections (3) and (4) aforesaid shall, unless reclaimed by the owner thereof within 6 months from the date the same come into the hands of the said sheriff, become forfeited to the state, and no action or proceeding for their recovery shall thereafter be maintained in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms coming into the hands of the sheriff as aforesaid shall be listed, kept, and held by him or her as custodian for the state. Any or all such weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms suitable for use by the sheriff may be so used. All such weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms not needed by the said sheriff may be loaned to any other department of the state or to any county or municipality having use for such weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms. The sheriff shall take the receipt of such other department, county, or municipality for such weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms loaned to them. All weapons, electric weapons or devices, and arms which are not needed or which are useless or unfit for use shall be destroyed or otherwise disposed of by the sheriff as provided in chapter 705 or as provided in the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act. All sums received from the sale or other disposition of the said weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms disposed of by the sheriff under chapter 705 as aforesaid shall be paid into the State Treasury for the benefit of the State School Fund and shall become a part thereof. All sums received from the sale or other disposition of any such weapons, electric weapons or devices, or arms disposed of by the sheriff under the Florida Contraband Forfeiture Act shall be disbursed as provided therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to any municipality in any county having home rule under the State Constitution.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 3620, 1885; RS 2424; GS 3270; RGS 5103; CGL 7205; s. 1, ch. 22049, 1943; s. 1, ch. 65-189; ss. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, ch. 67-523; s. 3, ch. 67-2207; ss. 20, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 76-165; s. 24, ch. 79-8; s. 12, ch. 80-68; s. 1, ch. 83-21; s. 17, ch. 97-93; s. 1207, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>