<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Armor-piercing or exploding ammunition or dragon’s breath shotgun shells, bolo shells, or flechette shells prohibited.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Armor-piercing bullet” means any bullet which has a steel inner core or core of equivalent hardness and a truncated cone and which is designed for use in a handgun as an armor-piercing or metal-piercing bullet.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exploding bullet” means any bullet that can be fired from any firearm, if such bullet is designed or altered so as to detonate or forcibly break up through the use of an explosive or deflagrant contained wholly or partially within or attached to such bullet. The term does not include any bullet designed to expand or break up through the mechanical forces of impact alone or any signaling device or pest control device not designed to impact on any target.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Handgun” means a firearm capable of being carried and used by one hand, such as a pistol or revolver.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dragon’s breath shotgun shell” means any shotgun shell that contains exothermic pyrophoric misch metal as the projectile and that is designed for the sole purpose of throwing or spewing a flame or fireball to simulate a flamethrower.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bolo shell” means any shell that can be fired in a firearm and that expels as projectiles two or more metal balls connected by solid metal wire.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Flechette shell” means any shell that can be fired in a firearm and that expels two or more pieces of fin-stabilized solid metal wire or two or more solid dart-type projectiles.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who manufactures, sells, offers for sale, or delivers any armor-piercing bullet or exploding bullet, or dragon’s breath shotgun shell, bolo shell, or flechette shell is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who possesses an armor-piercing bullet or exploding bullet with knowledge of its armor-piercing or exploding capabilities loaded in a handgun, or who possesses a dragon’s breath shotgun shell, bolo shell, or flechette shell with knowledge of its capabilities loaded in a firearm, is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who possesses with intent to use an armor-piercing bullet or exploding bullet or dragon’s breath shotgun shell, bolo shell, or flechette shell to assist in the commission of a criminal act is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The possession of any item described in subsection (1) by any law enforcement officer, when possessed in connection with the performance of his or her duty as a law enforcement officer, or law enforcement agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacture of items described in subsection (1) exclusively for sale or delivery to law enforcement agencies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale or delivery of items described in subsection (1) to law enforcement agencies.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 83-253; s. 1, ch. 92-141; s. 1221, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>