<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.0655" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purchase and delivery of handguns; mandatory waiting period; exceptions; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be a mandatory 3-day waiting period, which shall be 3 days, excluding weekends and legal holidays, between the purchase and the delivery at retail of any handgun. “Purchase” means the transfer of money or other valuable consideration to the retailer. “Handgun” means a firearm capable of being carried and used by one hand, such as a pistol or revolver. “Retailer” means and includes every person engaged in the business of making sales at retail or for distribution, or use, or consumption, or storage to be used or consumed in this state, as defined in s. 212.02(13).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Records of handgun sales must be available for inspection by any law enforcement agency, as defined in s. 934.02, during normal business hours.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The 3-day waiting period shall not apply in the following circumstances:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a handgun is being purchased by a holder of a concealed weapons permit as defined in s. 790.06.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a trade-in of another handgun.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any retailer, or any employee or agent of a retailer, to deliver a handgun before the expiration of the 3-day waiting period, subject to the exceptions provided in subsection (2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a purchaser to obtain delivery of a handgun by fraud, false pretense, or false representation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 91-24; s. 3, ch. 92-183; s. 98, ch. 99-3.</History></Section>