<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0790.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonresidents who are United States citizens and hold a concealed weapons license in another state; reciprocity.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 790.01, a nonresident of Florida may carry a concealed weapon or concealed firearm while in this state if the nonresident:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is 21 years of age or older.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has in his or her immediate possession a valid license to carry a concealed weapon or concealed firearm issued to the nonresident in his or her state of residence.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a resident of the United States.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonresident is subject to the same laws and restrictions with respect to carrying a concealed weapon or concealed firearm as a resident of Florida who is so licensed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the resident of another state who is the holder of a valid license to carry a concealed weapon or concealed firearm issued in another state establishes legal residence in this state by:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Registering to vote; </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making a statement of domicile pursuant to s. 222.17; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filing for homestead tax exemption on property in this state,</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">the license shall remain in effect for 90 days following the date on which the holder of the license establishes legal state residence.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies only to nonresident concealed weapon or concealed firearm licenseholders from states that honor Florida concealed weapon or concealed firearm licenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirement of paragraph (1)(a) does not apply to a person who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a servicemember, as defined in s. 250.01; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a veteran of the United States Armed Forces who was discharged under honorable conditions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 99-132; s. 2, ch. 2012-108.</History>
</Section>