<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0790.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Making, possessing, throwing, projecting, placing, or discharging any destructive device or attempt so to do, felony; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who willfully and unlawfully makes, possesses, throws, projects, places, discharges, or attempts to make, possess, throw, project, place, or discharge any destructive device:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the act is perpetrated with the intent to do bodily harm to any person, or with the intent to do property damage, or if the act results in a disruption of governmental operations, commerce, or the private affairs of another person, commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the act results in bodily harm to another person or in property damage, commits a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the act results in the death of another person, commits a capital felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082. In the event the death penalty in a capital felony is held to be unconstitutional by the Florida Supreme Court or the United States Supreme Court, the court having jurisdiction over a person previously sentenced to death for a capital felony shall cause such person to be brought before the court, and the court shall sentence such person to life imprisonment if convicted of murder in the first degree or of a capital felony under this subsection, and such person shall be ineligible for parole. No sentence of death shall be reduced as a result of a determination that a method of execution is held to be unconstitutional under the State Constitution or the Constitution of the United States.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 59-29; s. 6, ch. 69-306; s. 1, ch. 70-85; s. 747, ch. 71-136; s. 6, ch. 72-724; s. 2, ch. 76-38; s. 44, ch. 88-381; s. 3, ch. 90-124; s. 3, ch. 90-176; s. 19, ch. 93-406; s. 2, ch. 94-228; s. 3, ch. 98-3.</History></Section>