<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0711.501" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In ss. 711.50-711.512, unless the context otherwise requires, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Beneficiary form” means a registration of a security which indicates the present owner of the security and the intention of the owner regarding the person who will become the owner of the security upon the death of the owner.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Devisee” means any person designated in a will to receive a disposition of real or personal property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Heirs” means those persons, including the surviving spouse, who are entitled under the statutes of intestate succession to the property of a decedent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means an individual, a corporation, an organization, or other legal entity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personal representative” includes an executor, administrator, successor personal representative, special administrator, and persons who perform substantially the same function under the law governing their status.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Property” includes both real and personal property or any interest therein and means anything that may be the subject of ownership.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Register,” including its derivatives, means to issue a certificate showing the ownership of a certificated security or, in the case of an uncertificated security, to initiate or transfer an account showing ownership of securities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Registering entity” means a person who originates or transfers a security title by registration, and includes a broker maintaining security accounts for customers and a transfer agent or other person acting for or as an issuer of securities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Security” means a share, participation, or other interest in property, in a business, or in an obligation of an enterprise or other issuer, and includes a certificated security, an uncertificated security, and a security account.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Security account” means:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A reinvestment account associated with a security, a securities account with a broker, a cash balance in a brokerage account, cash, interest, earnings, or dividends earned or declared on a security in an account, a reinvestment account, or a brokerage account, whether or not credited to the account before the owner’s death;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An investment management account, investment advisory account, investment agency account, custody account, or any other type of account with a bank or trust company, including the securities in the account, the cash balance in the account, and cash equivalents, and any interest, earnings, or dividends earned or declared on a security in the account, whether or not credited to the account before the owner’s death; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cash balance or other property held for or due to the owner of a security as a replacement for or product of an account security, whether or not credited to the account before the owner’s death.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State” includes any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession subject to the legislative authority of the United States.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 94-216; s. 1, ch. 2005-85.</History></Section>