<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0742.10" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Establishment of paternity for children born out of wedlock.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in chapters 39 and 63, this chapter provides the primary jurisdiction and procedures for the determination of paternity for children born out of wedlock. If the establishment of paternity has been raised and determined within an adjudicatory hearing brought under the statutes governing inheritance, or dependency under workers’ compensation or similar compensation programs; if an affidavit acknowledging paternity or a stipulation of paternity is executed by both parties and filed with the clerk of the court; if an affidavit, a notarized voluntary acknowledgment of paternity, or a voluntary acknowledgment of paternity that is witnessed by two individuals and signed under penalty of perjury as provided for in s. 382.013 or s. 382.016 is executed by both parties; or if paternity is adjudicated by the Department of Revenue as provided in s. 409.256, such adjudication, affidavit, or acknowledgment constitutes the establishment of paternity for purposes of this chapter. If an adjudicatory proceeding was not held, a notarized voluntary acknowledgment of paternity or voluntary acknowledgment of paternity, which is witnessed by two individuals and signed under penalty of perjury as specified by s. 92.525(2), creates a rebuttable presumption, as defined by s. 90.304, of paternity and is subject to the right of any signatory to rescind the acknowledgment within 60 days after the date the acknowledgment was signed or the date of an administrative or judicial proceeding relating to the child, including a proceeding to establish a support order, in which the signatory is a party, whichever is earlier. Both parents must provide their social security numbers on any acknowledgment of paternity, consent affidavit, or stipulation of paternity. Except for affidavits under seal pursuant to ss. 382.015 and 382.016, the Office of Vital Statistics shall provide certified copies of affidavits to the Title IV-D agency upon request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to the federal Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, each party is required to provide his or her social security number in accordance with this section. Disclosure of social security numbers obtained through this requirement shall be limited to the purpose of administration of the Title IV-D program for child support enforcement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt rules which establish the information which must be provided to an individual prior to execution of an affidavit or voluntary acknowledgment of paternity. The information shall explain the alternatives to, the legal consequences of, and the rights, including, if one parent is a minor, any rights afforded due to minority status, and responsibilities that arise from acknowledging paternity.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the 60-day period referred to in subsection (1), a signed voluntary acknowledgment of paternity shall constitute an establishment of paternity and may be challenged in court only on the basis of fraud, duress, or material mistake of fact, with the burden of proof upon the challenger, and under which the legal responsibilities, including child support obligations of any signatory arising from the acknowledgment may not be suspended during the challenge, except upon a finding of good cause by the court.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Judicial or administrative proceedings are not required or permitted to ratify an unchallenged acknowledgment of paternity.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 26949, 1951; s. 10, ch. 27991, 1953; s. 7, ch. 75-166; s. 153, ch. 86-220; s. 28, ch. 92-138; s. 21, ch. 93-208; s. 8, ch. 94-318; s. 70, ch. 97-170; s. 114, ch. 97-237; s. 41, ch. 99-397; s. 22, ch. 2001-53; s. 19, ch. 2004-334; s. 39, ch. 2005-39; s. 25, ch. 2008-151.</History></Section>