<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0742.15" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Gestational surrogacy contract.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to engaging in gestational surrogacy, a binding and enforceable gestational surrogacy contract shall be made between the commissioning couple and the gestational surrogate. A contract for gestational surrogacy shall not be binding and enforceable unless the gestational surrogate is 18 years of age or older and the commissioning couple are legally married and are both 18 years of age or older.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioning couple shall enter into a contract with a gestational surrogate only when, within reasonable medical certainty as determined by a physician licensed under chapter 458 or chapter 459:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioning mother cannot physically gestate a pregnancy to term;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The gestation will cause a risk to the physical health of the commissioning mother; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The gestation will cause a risk to the health of the fetus.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A gestational surrogacy contract must include the following provisions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commissioning couple agrees that the gestational surrogate shall be the sole source of consent with respect to clinical intervention and management of the pregnancy.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The gestational surrogate agrees to submit to reasonable medical evaluation and treatment and to adhere to reasonable medical instructions about her prenatal health.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (e), the gestational surrogate agrees to relinquish any parental rights upon the child’s birth and to proceed with the judicial proceedings prescribed under s. 742.16.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (e), the commissioning couple agrees to accept custody of and to assume full parental rights and responsibilities for the child immediately upon the child’s birth, regardless of any impairment of the child.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The gestational surrogate agrees to assume parental rights and responsibilities for the child born to her if it is determined that neither member of the commissioning couple is the genetic parent of the child.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As part of the contract, the commissioning couple may agree to pay only reasonable living, legal, medical, psychological, and psychiatric expenses of the gestational surrogate that are directly related to prenatal, intrapartal, and postpartal periods.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 93-237.</History></Section>