<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0742.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in ss. 742.11-742.17, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Assisted reproductive technology” means those procreative procedures which involve the laboratory handling of human eggs or preembryos, including, but not limited to, in vitro fertilization embryo transfer, gamete intrafallopian transfer, pronuclear stage transfer, tubal embryo transfer, and zygote intrafallopian transfer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Commissioning couple” means the intended mother and father of a child who will be conceived by means of assisted reproductive technology using the eggs or sperm of at least one of the intended parents.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Egg” means the unfertilized female reproductive cell.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fertilization” means the initial union of an egg and sperm.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gestational surrogate” means a woman who contracts to become pregnant by means of assisted reproductive technology without the use of an egg from her body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gestational surrogacy” means a state that results from a process in which a commissioning couple’s eggs or sperm, or both, are mixed in vitro and the resulting preembryo is implanted within another woman’s body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gestational surrogacy contract” means a written agreement between the gestational surrogate and the commissioning couple.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Gamete intrafallopian transfer” means the direct transfer of eggs and sperm into the fallopian tube prior to fertilization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Implantation” means the event that occurs when a fertilized egg adheres to the uterine wall for nourishment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“In vitro” refers to a laboratory procedure performed in an artificial environment outside a woman’s body.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“In vitro fertilization embryo transfer” means the transfer of an in vitro fertilized preembryo into a woman’s uterus.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Preembryo” means the product of fertilization of an egg by a sperm until the appearance of the embryonic axis.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Pronuclear stage transfer” or “zygote intrafallopian transfer” means the transfer of an in vitro fertilized preembryo into the fallopian tube before cell division takes place.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sperm” means the male reproductive cell.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Tubal embryo transfer” means the transfer of a dividing, in vitro fertilized preembryo into the fallopian tube.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 93-237.</History></Section>