<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0732.2045" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exclusions and overlapping application.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EXCLUSIONS.<EmDash />Section 732.2035 does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in s. 732.2155(4), any transfer of property by the decedent to the extent the transfer is irrevocable before the effective date of this subsection or after that date but before the date of the decedent’s marriage to the surviving spouse.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transfer of property by the decedent to the extent the decedent received adequate consideration in money or money’s worth for the transfer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any transfer of property by the decedent made with the written consent of the decedent’s spouse. For this purpose, spousal consent to split-gift treatment under the United States gift tax laws does not constitute written consent to the transfer by the decedent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proceeds of any policy of insurance on the decedent’s life in excess of the net cash surrender value of the policy whether payable to the decedent’s estate, a trust, or in any other manner.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any policy of insurance on the decedent’s life maintained pursuant to a court order.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The decedent’s one-half of the property to which ss. 732.216-732.228, or any similar provisions of law of another state, apply and real property that is community property under the laws of the jurisdiction where it is located.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property held in a qualifying special needs trust on the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property included in the gross estate of the decedent for federal estate tax purposes solely because the decedent possessed a general power of appointment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property which constitutes the protected homestead of the decedent whether held by the decedent or by a trust at the decedent’s death.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">OVERLAPPING APPLICATION.<EmDash />If s. 732.2035(1) and any other subsection of s. 732.2035 apply to the same property interest, the amount included in the elective estate under other subsections is reduced by the amount included under subsection (1). In all other cases, if more than one subsection of s. 732.2035 applies to a property interest, only the subsection resulting in the largest elective estate shall apply.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 99-343; s. 21, ch. 2001-226; s. 4, ch. 2009-115.</History></Section>