<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0732.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Adopted persons and persons born out of wedlock.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of intestate succession by or from an adopted person, the adopted person is a descendant of the adopting parent and is one of the natural kindred of all members of the adopting parent’s family, and is not a descendant of his or her natural parents, nor is he or she one of the kindred of any member of the natural parent’s family or any prior adoptive parent’s family, except that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adoption of a child by the spouse of a natural parent has no effect on the relationship between the child and the natural parent or the natural parent’s family.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adoption of a child by a natural parent’s spouse who married the natural parent after the death of the other natural parent has no effect on the relationship between the child and the family of the deceased natural parent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adoption of a child by a close relative, as defined in s. 63.172(2), has no effect on the relationship between the child and the families of the deceased natural parents.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of intestate succession in cases not covered by subsection (1), a person born out of wedlock is a descendant of his or her mother and is one of the natural kindred of all members of the mother’s family. The person is also a descendant of his or her father and is one of the natural kindred of all members of the father’s family, if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The natural parents participated in a marriage ceremony before or after the birth of the person born out of wedlock, even though the attempted marriage is void.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The paternity of the father is established by an adjudication before or after the death of the father. Chapter 95 shall not apply in determining heirs in a probate proceeding under this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The paternity of the father is acknowledged in writing by the father.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 11, ch. 75-220; s. 7, ch. 77-87; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 2, ch. 87-27; s. 954, ch. 97-102; s. 8, ch. 2007-74; s. 2, ch. 2009-115.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former ss. 731.29, 731.30.</Text></Note></Section>