<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0732.601" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Simultaneous Death Law.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless a contrary intention appears in the governing instrument:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When title to property or its devolution depends on priority of death and there is insufficient evidence that the persons have died otherwise than simultaneously, the property of each person shall be disposed of as if that person survived.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When two or more beneficiaries are designated to take successively by reason of survivorship under another person’s disposition of property and there is insufficient evidence that the beneficiaries died otherwise than simultaneously, the property thus disposed of shall be divided into as many equal parts as there are successive beneficiaries and the parts shall be distributed to those who would have taken if each designated beneficiary had survived.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When there is insufficient evidence that two joint tenants or tenants by the entirety died otherwise than simultaneously, the property so held shall be distributed one-half as if one had survived and one-half as if the other had survived. If there are more than two joint tenants and all of them so died, the property thus distributed shall be in the proportion that one bears to the number of joint tenants.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the insured and the beneficiary in a policy of life or accident insurance have died and there is insufficient evidence that they died otherwise than simultaneously, the proceeds of the policy shall be distributed as if the insured had survived the beneficiary.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 34, ch. 75-220; s. 966, ch. 97-102; s. 50, ch. 2001-226.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 736.05.</Text></Note></Section>