<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0732.401" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Descent of homestead.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If not devised as authorized by law and the constitution, the homestead shall descend in the same manner as other intestate property; but if the decedent is survived by a spouse and one or more descendants, the surviving spouse shall take a life estate in the homestead, with a vested remainder to the descendants in being at the time of the decedent’s death per stirpes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In lieu of a life estate under subsection (1), the surviving spouse may elect to take an undivided one-half interest in the homestead as a tenant in common, with the remaining undivided one-half interest vesting in the decedent’s descendants in being at the time of the decedent’s death, per stirpes.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The right of election may be exercised:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the surviving spouse; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the approval of a court having jurisdiction of the real property, by an attorney in fact or guardian of the property of the surviving spouse. Before approving the election, the court shall determine that the election is in the best interests of the surviving spouse during the spouse’s probable lifetime.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election must be made within 6 months after the decedent’s death and during the surviving spouse’s lifetime. The time for making the election may not be extended except as provided in paragraph (c).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition by an attorney in fact or by a guardian of the property of the surviving spouse for approval to make the election must be filed within 6 months after the decedent’s death and during the surviving spouse’s lifetime. If the petition is timely filed, the time for making the election shall be extended for at least 30 days after the rendition of the order allowing the election.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once made, the election is irrevocable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The election shall be made by filing a notice of election containing the legal description of the homestead property for recording in the official record books of the county or counties where the homestead property is located. The notice must be in substantially the following form:</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">ELECTION OF SURVIVING SPOUSE<NewLine />TO TAKE A ONE-HALF INTEREST OF<NewLine />DECEDENT’S INTEREST IN<NewLine/>HOMESTEAD PROPERTY</Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">STATE OF<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/></Text>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceBelow="true">COUNTY OF<HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro" SpaceAbove="true">The decedent, <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/>, died on <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/>. On the date of the decedent’s death, The decedent was married to <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/>, who survived the decedent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time of the decedent’s death, the decedent owned an interest in real property that the affiant believes to be homestead property described in s. 4, Article X of the State Constitution, which real property being in <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/> County, Florida, and described as: <Directions xml:space="preserve">(description of homestead property)</Directions>.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Affiant elects to take one-half of decedent’s interest in the homestead as a tenant in common in lieu of a life estate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If affiant is not the surviving spouse, affiant is the surviving spouse’s attorney in fact or guardian of the property, and an order has been rendered by a court having jurisdiction of the real property authorizing the undersigned to make this election.</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/></Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Affiant)</Directions></Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Sworn to (or affirmed) and subscribed before me this <HorizontalRule Type="Fixed"/> day of <Directions xml:space="preserve">(month)</Directions>, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>, by <Directions xml:space="preserve">(affiant)</Directions></Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Signature of Notary Public-State of Florida)</Directions></Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Print, Type, or Stamp Commissioned Name of Notary Public)</Directions></Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Personally Known OR Produced Identification</Text>
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Type of Identification Produced)</Directions></Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro" SpaceAbove="true">Unless and until an election is made under subsection (2), expenses relating to the ownership of the homestead shall be allocated between the surviving spouse, as life tenant, and the decedent’s descendants, as remaindermen, in accordance with chapter 738. If an election is made, expenses relating to the ownership of the homestead shall be allocated between the surviving spouse and the descendants as tenants in common in proportion to their respective shares, effective as of the date the election is filed for recording.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the surviving spouse’s life estate created in subsection (1) is disclaimed pursuant to chapter 739, the interests of the decedent’s descendants may not be divested.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not apply to property that the decedent owned in tenancy by the entireties or in joint tenancy with rights of survivorship.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 17, ch. 75-220; s. 37, ch. 2001-226; s. 12, ch. 2007-74; s. 7, ch. 2010-132; s. 3, ch. 2012-109.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Section 3, ch. 2012-109, provides that s. 732.401 is amended “[e]ffective July 1, 2012, and applicable only to estates of persons dying on or after July 1, 2012.”</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 731.27.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>