<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0732.107" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Escheat.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person dies leaving an estate without being survived by any person entitled to a part of it, that part shall escheat to the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Property that escheats shall be sold as provided in the Florida Probate Rules and the proceeds paid to the Chief Financial Officer of the state and deposited in the State School Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At any time within 10 years after the payment to the Chief Financial Officer, a person claiming to be entitled to the proceeds may reopen the administration to assert entitlement to the proceeds. If no claim is timely asserted, the state’s rights to the proceeds shall become absolute.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Legal Affairs shall represent the state in all proceedings concerning escheated estates.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a person entitled to the proceeds assigns the rights to receive payment to an attorney, Florida-certified public accountant, or private investigative agency which is duly licensed to do business in this state pursuant to a written agreement with that person, the Department of Financial Services is authorized to make distribution in accordance with the assignment.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payments made to an attorney, Florida-certified public accountant, or private investigative agency shall be promptly deposited into a trust or escrow account which is regularly maintained by the attorney, Florida-certified public accountant, or private investigative agency in a financial institution authorized to accept such deposits and located in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Distribution by the attorney, Florida-certified public accountant, or private investigative agency to the person entitled to the proceeds shall be made within 10 days following final credit of the deposit into the trust or escrow account at the financial institution, unless a party to the agreement protests the distribution in writing before it is made.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not be civilly or criminally liable for any proceeds distributed pursuant to this subsection, provided such distribution is made in good faith.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 10, ch. 75-220; s. 4, ch. 89-291; s. 9, ch. 89-299; s. 953, ch. 97-102; s. 32, ch. 2001-36; s. 17, ch. 2001-226; s. 1896, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 731.33.</Text></Note></Section>