<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0732.2135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Time of election; extensions; withdrawal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (2), the election must be filed on or before the earlier of the date that is 6 months after the date of service of a copy of the notice of administration on the surviving spouse, or an attorney in fact or guardian of the property of the surviving spouse, or the date that is 2 years after the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within the period provided in subsection (1), the surviving spouse or an attorney in fact or guardian of the property of the surviving spouse may petition the court for an extension of time for making an election. For good cause shown, the court may extend the time for election. If the court grants the petition for an extension, the election must be filed within the time allowed by the extension.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The surviving spouse or an attorney in fact, guardian of the property, or personal representative of the surviving spouse may withdraw an election at any time within 8 months after the decedent’s death and before the court’s order of contribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A petition for an extension of the time for making the election or for approval to make the election shall toll the time for making the election.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the court determines that an election is made or pursued in bad faith, the court may assess attorney’s fees and costs against the surviving spouse or the surviving spouse’s estate.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 75-220; s. 13, ch. 99-343; s. 28, ch. 2001-226; s. 4, ch. 2006-134; s. 7, ch. 2009-115.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 732.212.</Text></Note></Section>