<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0732.2095" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Valuation of property used to satisfy elective share.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Applicable valuation date” means:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of transfers in satisfaction of the elective share, the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of property held in a qualifying special needs trust on the date of the decedent’s death, the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of other property irrevocably transferred to or for the benefit of the surviving spouse during the decedent’s life, the date of the transfer.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of property distributed to the surviving spouse by the personal representative, the date of distribution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subparagraphs 1., 2., and 3., in the case of property passing in trust for the surviving spouse, the date or dates the trust is funded in satisfaction of the elective share.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of property described in s. 732.2035(2) or (3), the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of proceeds of any policy of insurance payable to the surviving spouse, the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of amounts payable to the surviving spouse under any plan or arrangement described in s. 732.2035(7), the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In all other cases, the date of the decedent’s death or the date the surviving spouse first comes into possession of the property, whichever occurs later.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualifying power of appointment” means a general power of appointment that is exercisable alone and in all events by the decedent’s spouse in favor of the spouse or the spouse’s estate. For this purpose, a general power to appoint by will is a qualifying power of appointment if the power may be exercised by the spouse in favor of the spouse’s estate without the consent of any other person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Qualifying invasion power” means a power held by the surviving spouse or the trustee of an elective share trust to invade trust principal for the health, support, and maintenance of the spouse. The power may, but need not, provide that the other resources of the spouse are to be taken into account in any exercise of the power.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in this subsection, the value of property for purposes of s. 732.2075 is the fair market value of the property on the applicable valuation date.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the surviving spouse has a life interest in property not in trust that entitles the spouse to the use of the property for life, the value of the spouse’s interest is one-half of the value of the property on the applicable valuation date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the surviving spouse has an interest in a trust, or portion of a trust, which meets the requirements of an elective share trust, the value of the spouse’s interest is a percentage of the value of the principal of the trust, or trust portion, on the applicable valuation date as follows:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred percent if the trust instrument includes both a qualifying invasion power and a qualifying power of appointment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Eighty percent if the trust instrument includes a qualifying invasion power but no qualifying power of appointment.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent in all other cases.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the surviving spouse is a beneficiary of a trust, or portion of a trust, which meets the requirements of a qualifying special needs trust, the value of the principal of the trust, or trust portion, on the applicable valuation date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the surviving spouse has an interest in a trust that does not meet the requirements of either an elective share trust or a qualifying special needs trust, the value of the spouse’s interest is the transfer tax value of the interest on the applicable valuation date; however, the aggregate value of all of the spouse’s interests in the trust shall not exceed one-half of the value of the trust principal on the applicable valuation date.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of any policy of insurance on the decedent’s life the proceeds of which are payable outright or to a trust described in paragraph (b), paragraph (c), or paragraph (d), the value of the policy for purposes of s. 732.2075 and paragraphs (b), (c), and (d) is the net proceeds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of a right to one or more payments from an annuity or under a similar contractual arrangement or under any plan or arrangement described in s. 732.2035(7), the value of the right to payments for purposes of s. 732.2075 and paragraphs (b), (c), and (d) is the transfer tax value of the right on the applicable valuation date.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 99-343; s. 25, ch. 2001-226.</History></Section>