<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0732.513" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Devises to trustee.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A valid devise may be made to the trustee of a trust that is evidenced by a written instrument in existence at the time of making the will, or by a written instrument subscribed concurrently with making of the will, if the written instrument is identified in the will.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The devise shall not be invalid for any or all of the following reasons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the trust is amendable or revocable, or both, by any person.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the trust has been amended or revoked in part after execution of the will or a codicil to it.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the only res of the trust is the possible expectancy of receiving, as a named beneficiary, a devise under a will or death benefits as described in s. 733.808, and even though the testator or other person has reserved any or all rights of ownership in the death benefit policy, contract, or plan, including the right to change the beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because of any of the provisions of s. 689.075.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The devise shall dispose of property under the terms of the instrument that created the trust as previously or subsequently amended.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An entire revocation of the trust by an instrument in writing before the testator’s death shall invalidate the devise or bequest.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless the will provides otherwise, the property devised shall not be held under a testamentary trust of the testator but shall become a part of the principal of the trust to which it is devised.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 3, ch. 75-74; s. 113, ch. 75-220; s. 2, ch. 88-340; s. 46, ch. 2001-226; s. 32, ch. 2006-217.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 736.17.</Text></Note></Section>