<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.612" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Transactions authorized for the personal representative; exceptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by the will or court order, and subject to the priorities stated in s. 733.805, without court order, a personal representative, acting reasonably for the benefit of the interested persons, may properly:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Retain assets owned by the decedent, pending distribution or liquidation, including those in which the personal representative is personally interested or that are otherwise improper for fiduciary investments.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Perform or compromise, or, when proper, refuse to perform, the decedent’s contracts. In performing the decedent’s enforceable contracts to convey or lease real property, among other possible courses of action, the personal representative may:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Convey the real property for cash payment of all sums remaining due or for the purchaser’s note for the sum remaining due, secured by a mortgage on the property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Deliver a deed in escrow, with directions that the proceeds, when paid in accordance with the escrow agreement, be paid as provided in the escrow agreement.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive assets from fiduciaries or other sources.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Invest funds as provided in ss. 518.10-518.14, considering the amount to be invested, liquidity needs of the estate, and the time until distribution will be made.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Acquire or dispose of an asset, excluding real property in this or another state, for cash or on credit and at public or private sale, and manage, develop, improve, exchange, partition, or change the character of an estate asset.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make ordinary or extraordinary repairs or alterations in buildings or other structures; demolish improvements; or erect new party walls or buildings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into a lease, as lessor or lessee, for a term within, or extending beyond, the period of administration, with or without an option to renew.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into a lease or arrangement for exploration and removal of minerals or other natural resources or enter into a pooling or unitization agreement.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Abandon property when it is valueless or so encumbered, or in a condition, that it is of no benefit to the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Vote, or refrain from voting, stocks or other securities in person or by general or limited proxy.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay calls, assessments, and other sums chargeable or accruing against, or on account of, securities, unless barred by the provisions relating to claims.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Hold property in the name of a nominee or in other form without disclosure of the interest of the estate, but the personal representative is liable for any act of the nominee in connection with the property so held.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insure the assets of the estate against damage or loss and insure against personal and fiduciary liability to third persons.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Borrow money, with or without security, to be repaid from the estate assets or otherwise, other than real property, and advance money for the protection of the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Extend, renew, or in any manner modify any obligation owing to the estate. If the personal representative holds a mortgage, security interest, or other lien upon property of another person, he or she may accept a conveyance or transfer of encumbered assets from the owner in satisfaction of the indebtedness secured by its lien instead of foreclosure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pay taxes, assessments, and other expenses incident to the administration of the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell or exercise stock subscription or conversion rights or consent, directly or through a committee or other agent, to the reorganization, consolidation, merger, dissolution, or liquidation of a corporation or other business enterprise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="18"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Allocate items of income or expense to either estate income or principal, as permitted or provided by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="19"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Employ persons, including, but not limited to, attorneys, accountants, auditors, appraisers, investment advisers, and others, even if they are one and the same as the personal representative or are associated with the personal representative, to advise or assist the personal representative in the performance of administrative duties; act upon the recommendations of those employed persons without independent investigation; and, instead of acting personally, employ one or more agents to perform any act of administration, whether or not discretionary. Any fees and compensation paid to a person who is the same as, associated with, or employed by, the personal representative shall be taken into consideration in determining the personal representative’s compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="20"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prosecute or defend claims or proceedings in any jurisdiction for the protection of the estate and of the personal representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="21"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sell, mortgage, or lease any personal property of the estate or any interest in it for cash, credit, or for part cash or part credit, and with or without security for the unpaid balance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="22"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Continue any unincorporated business or venture in which the decedent was engaged at the time of death:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the same business form for a period of not more than 4 months from the date of appointment, if continuation is a reasonable means of preserving the value of the business, including good will.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the same business form for any additional period of time that may be approved by court order.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="23"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for exoneration of the personal representative from personal liability in any contract entered into on behalf of the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="24"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfy and settle claims and distribute the estate as provided in this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="25"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into agreements with the proper officer or department head, commissioner, or agent of any department of the government of the United States, waiving the statute of limitations concerning the assessment and collection of any federal tax or any deficiency in a federal tax.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="26"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make partial distribution to the beneficiaries of any part of the estate not necessary to satisfy claims, expenses of administration, taxes, family allowance, exempt property, and an elective share, in accordance with the decedent’s will or as authorized by operation of law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="27"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Execute any instruments necessary in the exercise of the personal representative’s powers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 78, ch. 75-220; s. 3, ch. 76-172; s. 31, ch. 77-87; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 271, ch. 79-400; s. 1009, ch. 97-102; s. 135, ch. 2001-226.</History></Section>