<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.504" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Removal of personal representative; causes for removal.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A personal representative may be removed and the letters revoked for any of the following causes, and the removal shall be in addition to any penalties prescribed by law:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adjudication that the personal representative is incapacitated.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physical or mental incapacity rendering the personal representative incapable of the discharge of his or her duties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with any order of the court, unless the order has been superseded on appeal.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to account for the sale of property or to produce and exhibit the assets of the estate when so required.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Wasting or maladministration of the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to give bond or security for any purpose.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conviction of a felony.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Insolvency of, or the appointment of a receiver or liquidator for, any corporate personal representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holding or acquiring conflicting or adverse interests against the estate that will or may interfere with the administration of the estate as a whole. This cause of removal shall not apply to the surviving spouse because of the exercise of the right to the elective share, family allowance, or exemptions, as provided elsewhere in this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Revocation of the probate of the decedent’s will that authorized or designated the appointment of the personal representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Removal of domicile from Florida, if domicile was a requirement of initial appointment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal representative would not now be entitled to appointment.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 69, ch. 75-220; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 998, ch. 97-102; s. 117, ch. 2001-226; s. 10, ch. 2009-115.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 734.11.</Text></Note></Section>