<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.6121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Personal representative; powers as to environmental issues relating to property subject to administration; liability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as otherwise provided by the will or by court order, and subject to s. 733.805, the personal representative has, without court authorization, the powers specified in subsection (2).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A personal representative has the power, acting reasonably and for the benefit of the interested persons:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To inspect or investigate, or cause to be inspected or investigated, property subject to administration, including interests in sole proprietorships, partnerships, or corporations and any assets owned by such a business entity for the purpose of determining compliance with an environmental law affecting that property or to respond to an actual or threatened violation of an environmental law affecting that property;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To take, on behalf of the estate, any action necessary to prevent, abate, or otherwise remedy an actual or potential violation of an environmental law affecting property subject to administration, either before or after initiation of an enforcement action by a governmental body;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To settle or compromise at any time any claim against the estate or the personal representative that may be asserted by a governmental body or private party which involves the alleged violation of an environmental law affecting property subject to administration over which the personal representative has responsibility;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To disclaim any power granted by any document, statute, or rule of law which, in the sole judgment of the personal representative, could cause the personal representative to incur personal liability, or the estate to incur liability, under any environmental law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To decline to serve as a personal representative, or having undertaken to serve, to resign at any time, if the personal representative believes that there is or could be a conflict of interest because of potential claims or liabilities that could be asserted on behalf of the estate by reason of the type or condition of the assets held; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To charge against the assets of the estate the cost of any inspection, investigation, review, abatement, response, cleanup, or remedial action considered reasonable by the personal representative; and, in the event of the closing or termination of the estate or the transfer of the estate property to another personal representative, to hold moneys sufficient to cover the cost of cleaning up any known environmental problem.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A personal representative is not personally liable to any beneficiary or any other party for a decrease in value of assets in an estate by reason of the personal representative’s compliance or efforts to comply with an environmental law, specifically including any reporting requirement under that law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A personal representative who acquires ownership or control of a vessel or other property without having owned, operated, or materially participated in the management of that vessel or property before assuming ownership or control as personal representative is not considered an owner or operator for purposes of liability under chapter 376, chapter 403, or any other environmental law. A personal representative who willfully, knowingly, or recklessly causes or exacerbates a release or threatened release of a hazardous substance is personally liable for the cost of the response, to the extent that the release or threatened release is attributable to the personal representative’s activities. This subsection does not preclude the filing of claims against the assets that constitute the estate held by the personal representative or the filing of actions against the personal representative as representative of the estate. In such an action, an award or judgment against the personal representative must be satisfied only from the assets of the estate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Neither the acceptance by the personal representative of the property or a failure by the personal representative to inspect or investigate the property creates any inference of liability under an environmental law with respect to that property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of this section, the term “environmental law” means a federal, state, or local law, rule, regulation, or ordinance that relates to protection of the environment or human health, and the term “hazardous substance” means a substance, material, or waste defined as hazardous or toxic, or any contaminant, pollutant, or constituent thereof, or otherwise regulated by an environmental law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section applies to any estate admitted to probate on or after July 1, 1995.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 95-401; s. 1010, ch. 97-102; s. 136, ch. 2001-226.</History></Section>