<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0733.702" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitations on presentation of claims.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If not barred by s. 733.710, no claim or demand against the decedent’s estate that arose before the death of the decedent, including claims of the state and any of its political subdivisions, even if the claims are unmatured, contingent, or unliquidated; no claim for funeral or burial expenses; no claim for personal property in the possession of the personal representative; and no claim for damages, including, but not limited to, an action founded on fraud or another wrongful act or omission of the decedent, is binding on the estate, on the personal representative, or on any beneficiary unless filed in the probate proceeding on or before the later of the date that is 3 months after the time of the first publication of the notice to creditors or, as to any creditor required to be served with a copy of the notice to creditors, 30 days after the date of service on the creditor, even though the personal representative has recognized the claim or demand by paying a part of it or interest on it or otherwise. The personal representative may settle in full any claim without the necessity of the claim being filed when the settlement has been approved by the interested persons.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No cause of action, including, but not limited to, an action founded upon fraud or other wrongful act or omission, shall survive the death of the person against whom the claim may be made, whether or not an action is pending at the death of the person, unless a claim is filed within the time periods set forth in this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any claim not timely filed as provided in this section is barred even though no objection to the claim is filed unless the court extends the time in which the claim may be filed. An extension may be granted only upon grounds of fraud, estoppel, or insufficient notice of the claims period. No independent action or declaratory action may be brought upon a claim which was not timely filed unless an extension has been granted by the court. If the personal representative or any other interested person serves on the creditor a notice to file a petition for an extension, the creditor shall be limited to a period of 30 days from the date of service of the notice in which to file a petition for extension.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section affects or prevents:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A proceeding to enforce any mortgage, security interest, or other lien on property of the decedent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the limits of casualty insurance protection only, any proceeding to establish liability that is protected by the casualty insurance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The filing of a cross-claim or counterclaim against the estate in an action instituted by the estate; however, no recovery on a cross-claim or counterclaim shall exceed the estate’s recovery in that action.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall extend the limitations period set forth in s. 733.710.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 84, ch. 75-220; s. 2, ch. 80-127; s. 4, ch. 81-27; s. 160, ch. 83-216; s. 5, ch. 84-106; s. 4, ch. 85-79; s. 6, ch. 88-340; s. 5, ch. 89-340; s. 4, ch. 90-23; s. 1016, ch. 97-102; s. 146, ch. 2001-226; s. 6, ch. 2002-82; s. 26, ch. 2006-312; s. 21, ch. 2010-4.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 733.16.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>