<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.617" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Compensation of personal representative.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A personal representative shall be entitled to a commission payable from the estate assets without court order as compensation for ordinary services. The commission shall be based on the compensable value of the estate, which is the inventory value of the probate estate assets and the income earned by the estate during administration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A commission computed on the compensable value of the estate is presumed to be reasonable compensation for a personal representative in formal administration as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the rate of 3 percent for the first $1 million.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the rate of 2.5 percent for all above $1 million and not exceeding $5 million.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the rate of 2 percent for all above $5 million and not exceeding $10 million.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the rate of 1.5 percent for all above $10 million.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the previously described commission, a personal representative shall be allowed further compensation as is reasonable for any extraordinary services including, but not limited to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sale of real or personal property.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct of litigation on behalf of or against the estate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Involvement in proceedings for the adjustment or payment of any taxes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The carrying on of the decedent’s business.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dealing with protected homestead.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other special services which may be necessary for the personal representative to perform.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the will provides that a personal representative’s compensation shall be based upon specific criteria, other than a general reference to commissions allowed by law or words of similar import, including, but not limited to, rates, amounts, commissions, or reference to the personal representative’s regularly published schedule of fees in effect at the decedent’s date of death, or words of similar import, then a personal representative shall be entitled to compensation in accordance with that provision. However, except for references in the will to the personal representative’s regularly published schedule of fees in effect at the decedent’s date of death, or words of similar import, if there is no written contract with the decedent regarding compensation, a personal representative may renounce the provisions contained in the will and be entitled to compensation under this section. A personal representative may also renounce the right to all or any part of the compensation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the probate estate’s compensable value is $100,000 or more, and there are two representatives, each personal representative is entitled to the full commission allowed to a sole personal representative. If there are more than two personal representatives and the probate estate’s compensable value is $100,000 or more, the compensation to which two would be entitled must be apportioned among the personal representatives. The basis for apportionment shall be one full commission allowed to the personal representative who has possession of and primary responsibility for administration of the assets and one full commission among the remaining personal representatives according to the services rendered by each of them respectively. If the probate estate’s compensable value is less than $100,000 and there is more than one personal representative, then one full commission must be apportioned among the personal representatives according to the services rendered by each of them respectively.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the personal representative is a member of The Florida Bar and has rendered legal services in connection with the administration of the estate, then in addition to a fee as personal representative, there also shall be allowed a fee for the legal services rendered.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon petition of any interested person, the court may increase or decrease the compensation for ordinary services of the personal representative or award compensation for extraordinary services if the facts and circumstances of the particular administration warrant. In determining reasonable compensation, the court shall consider all of the following factors, giving weight to each as it determines to be appropriate:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The promptness, efficiency, and skill with which the administration was handled by the personal representative;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The responsibilities assumed by and the potential liabilities of the personal representative;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature and value of the assets that are affected by the decedent’s death;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The benefits or detriments resulting to the estate or interested persons from the personal representative’s services;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The complexity or simplicity of the administration and the novelty of the issues presented;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal representative’s participation in tax planning for the estate and the estate’s beneficiaries and in tax return preparation, review, or approval;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The nature of the probate, nonprobate, and exempt assets, the expenses of administration, the liabilities of the decedent, and the compensation paid to other professionals and fiduciaries;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any delay in payment of the compensation after the services were furnished; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other relevant factors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 80, ch. 75-220; s. 1, ch. 76-172; s. 5, ch. 88-340; s. 1, ch. 90-129; s. 10, ch. 93-257; s. 1, ch. 95-401; s. 141, ch. 2001-226; s. 109, ch. 2002-1.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 734.01.</Text></Note></Section>