<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.705" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of and objection to claims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal representative shall pay all claims within 1 year from the date of first publication of notice to creditors, provided that the time shall be extended with respect to claims in litigation, unmatured claims, and contingent claims for the period necessary to dispose of those claims pursuant to subsections (5), (6), (7), and (8). The court may extend the time for payment of any claim upon a showing of good cause. No personal representative shall be compelled to pay the debts of the decedent until after the expiration of 5 months from the first publication of notice to creditors. If any person brings an action against a personal representative within the 5 months on any claim to which the personal representative has not filed an objection, the plaintiff shall not receive any costs or attorneys’ fees, nor shall the judgment change the class of the claim for payment under this code.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before the expiration of 4 months from the first publication of notice to creditors or within 30 days from the timely filing or amendment of a claim, whichever occurs later, a personal representative or other interested person may file a written objection to a claim. If an objection is filed, the person filing it shall serve a copy of the objection as provided by the Florida Probate Rules. The failure to serve a copy of the objection constitutes an abandonment of the objection. For good cause, the court may extend the time for filing or serving an objection to any claim. Objection to a claim constitutes an objection to an amendment of that claim unless the objection is withdrawn.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the objection is filed by a person other than the personal representative, the personal representative may apply to the court for an order relieving him or her from the obligation to defend the estate in an independent action or for the appointment of the objector as administrator ad litem to defend the action. Fees for the attorney for the administrator ad litem may be awarded as provided in s. 733.106(3). If costs or attorney’s fees are awarded from or against the estate, the probate court may charge or apportion that award as provided in s. 733.106(4).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An objection by an interested person to a personal representative’s proof of claim shall state the particular item or items to which the interested person objects and shall be filed and served as provided in subsection (2). Issues of liability as between the estate and the personal representative individually for items listed in a personal representative’s proof of claim shall be determined in the estate administration, in a proceeding for accounting or surcharge, or in another appropriate proceeding, whether or not an objection has been filed. If an objection to an item listed as to be paid in a personal representative’s proof of claim is filed and served, and the personal representative has not paid the item, the other subsections of this section shall apply as if a claim for the item had been filed by the claimant; but if the personal representative has paid the claim after listing it as to be paid, issues of liability as between the estate and the personal representative individually shall be determined in the manner provided for an item listed as paid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The claimant is limited to a period of 30 days from the date of service of an objection within which to bring an independent action upon the claim, or a declaratory action to establish the validity and amount of an unmatured claim which is not yet due but which is certain to become due in the future, or a declaratory action to establish the validity of a contingent claim upon which no cause of action has accrued on the date of service of an objection and that may or may not become due in the future, unless an extension of this time is agreed to by the personal representative in writing before it expires. For good cause, the court may extend the time for filing an action or proceeding after objection is filed. No action or proceeding on the claim may be brought against the personal representative after the time limited above, and the claim is barred without court order. If an objection is filed to the claim of any creditor and the creditor brings an action to establish the claim, a judgment establishing the claim shall give it no priority over claims of the same class to which it belongs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A claimant may bring an independent action or declaratory action upon a claim which was not timely filed pursuant to s. 733.702(1) only if the claimant has been granted an extension of time to file the claim pursuant to s. 733.702(3).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an unmatured claim has not become due before the time for distribution of an estate, the personal representative may prepay the full amount of principal plus accrued interest due on the claim, without discount and without penalty, regardless of any prohibition against prepayment or provision for penalty in any instrument on which the claim is founded. If the claim is not prepaid, no order of discharge may be entered until the creditor and personal representative have filed an agreement disposing of the claim, or in the absence of an agreement until the court provides for payment by one of the following methods:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring the personal representative to reserve such assets as the court determines to be adequate to pay the claim when it becomes due; in fixing the amount to be reserved, the court may determine the value of any security or collateral to which the creditor may resort for payment of the claim and may direct the reservation, if necessary, of sufficient assets to pay the claim or to pay the difference between the value of any security or collateral and the amount necessary to pay the claim. If the estate is insolvent, the court may direct a proportionate amount to be reserved. The court shall direct that the amount reserved be retained by the personal representative until the time that the claim becomes due, and that so much of the reserved amount as is not used for payment be distributed according to law;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Requiring that the claim be adequately secured by a mortgage, pledge, bond, trust, guaranty, or other security, as may be determined by the court, the security to remain in effect until the time the claim becomes due, and so much of the security or collateral as is not needed for payment be distributed according to law; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making provisions for the disposition or satisfaction of the claim as are equitable, and in a manner so as not to delay unreasonably the closing of the estate.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no cause of action has accrued on a contingent claim before the time for distribution of an estate, no order of discharge may be entered until the creditor and the personal representative have filed an agreement disposing of the claim or, in the absence of an agreement, until:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court determines that the claim is adequately secured or that it has no value,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Three months from the date on which a cause of action accrues upon the claim, provided that no action on the claim is then pending,</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five years from the date of first publication of notice to creditors, or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court provides for payment of the claim upon the happening of the contingency by one of the methods described in paragraph (a), paragraph (b), or paragraph (c) of subsection (7),</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">whichever occurs first. No action or proceeding on the claim may be brought against the personal representative after the time limited above, and the claim is barred without court order. If an objection is filed to the claim of any creditor and the creditor brings an action to establish the claim, a judgment establishing the claim shall give it no priority over claims of the same class to which it belongs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Interest shall be paid by the personal representative on written obligations of the decedent providing for the payment of interest. On all other claims, interest shall be allowed and paid beginning 5 months from the first publication of the notice to creditors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may determine all issues concerning claims or matters not requiring trial by jury.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An order for extension of time authorized under this section may be entered only in the estate administration proceeding.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 86, ch. 75-220; s. 34, ch. 77-87; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 1, ch. 84-25; s. 1, ch. 86-249; s. 7, ch. 88-340; s. 7, ch. 89-340; s. 2, ch. 91-61; s. 1017, ch. 97-102; s. 149, ch. 2001-226.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 733.18.</Text></Note></Section>