<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.604" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Inventories and accountings; public records exemptions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless an inventory has been previously filed, a personal representative shall file a verified inventory of property of the estate, listing it with reasonable detail and including for each listed item its estimated fair market value at the date of the decedent’s death.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any inventory of an estate, whether initial, amended, or supplementary, filed with the clerk of the court in conjunction with the administration of an estate is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any inventory of an elective estate, whether initial, amended, or supplementary, filed with the clerk of the court in conjunction with an election made in accordance with part II of chapter 732 is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any accounting, whether interim, final, amended, or supplementary, filed in an estate proceeding is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any inventory or accounting made confidential and exempt by subparagraph 1., subparagraph 2., or subparagraph 3. shall be disclosed by the custodian for inspection or copying:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the personal representative;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To the personal representative’s attorney;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To an interested person as defined in s. 731.201; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By court order upon a showing of good cause.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">These exemptions apply to any inventory or accounting filed before, on, or after July 1, 2009.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This paragraph is subject to the Open Government Sunset Review Act in accordance with s. 119.15 and shall stand repealed on October 2, 2014, unless reviewed and saved from repeal through reenactment by the Legislature.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the personal representative learns of any property not included in the original inventory, or learns that the estimated value or description indicated in the original inventory for any item is erroneous or misleading, the personal representative shall file a verified amended or supplementary inventory showing any new items and their estimated value at the date of the decedent’s death, or the revised estimated value or description.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon written request to the personal representative, a beneficiary shall be furnished a written explanation of how the inventory value for an asset was determined, or, if an appraisal was obtained, a copy of the appraisal, as follows:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To a residuary beneficiary or heir in an intestate estate, regarding all inventoried assets.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To any other beneficiary, regarding all assets distributed or proposed to be distributed to that beneficiary.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The personal representative must notify each beneficiary of that beneficiary’s rights under this subsection. Neither a request nor the failure to request information under this subsection affects any rights of a beneficiary in subsequent proceedings concerning any accounting of the personal representative or the propriety of any action of the personal representative.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 76, ch. 75-220; s. 1, ch. 80-127; s. 4, ch. 84-106; s. 1, ch. 85-72; s. 29, ch. 85-342; s. 68, ch. 87-226; s. 28, ch. 95-401; s. 1003, ch. 97-102; s. 13, ch. 97-240; s. 127, ch. 2001-226; s. 1, ch. 2009-230.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 733.03.</Text></Note></Section>