<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.6175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Proceedings for review of employment of agents and compensation of personal representatives and employees of estate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may review the propriety of the employment of any person employed by the personal representative and the reasonableness of any compensation paid to that person or to the personal representative.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Court proceedings to determine reasonable compensation of the personal representative or any person employed by the personal representative, if required, are a part of the estate administration process, and the costs, including attorneys’ fees, of the person assuming the burden of proof of propriety of the employment and reasonableness of the compensation shall be determined by the court and paid from the assets of the estate unless the court finds the requested compensation to be substantially unreasonable. The court shall direct from which part of the estate the compensation shall be paid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The burden of proof of propriety of the employment and the reasonableness of the compensation shall be upon the personal representative and the person employed. Any person who is determined to have received excessive compensation from an estate for services rendered may be ordered to make appropriate refunds.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The court may determine reasonable compensation for the personal representative or any person employed by the personal representative without receiving expert testimony. Any party may offer expert testimony after notice to interested persons. If expert testimony is offered, a reasonable expert witness fee shall be awarded by the court and paid from the assets of the estate. The court shall direct from what part of the estate the fee shall be paid.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 76-172; s. 1014, ch. 97-102; s. 143, ch. 2001-226.</History></Section>