<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.808" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Death benefits; disposition of proceeds.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Death benefits of any kind, including, but not limited to, proceeds of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual life insurance policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A group life insurance policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A benefit plan as defined by s. 710.102;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annuity or endowment contract; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health or accident policy,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">may be made payable to the trustee under a trust agreement or declaration of trust in existence at the time of the death of the insured, employee, or annuitant or the owner of or participant in the benefit plan. The death benefits shall be held and disposed of by the trustee in accordance with the terms of the trust as they appear in writing on the date of the death of the insured, employee, annuitant, owner, or participant. It shall not be necessary to the validity of the trust agreement or declaration of trust, whether revocable or irrevocable, that it have a trust corpus other than the right of the trustee to receive death benefits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Death benefits of any kind, including, but not limited to, proceeds of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An individual life insurance policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A group life insurance policy;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A benefit plan as defined in s. 710.102;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annuity or endowment contract; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A health or accident policy,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">may be made payable to the trustee named, or to be named, in a written instrument that is admitted to probate as the last will of the insured, the owner of the policy, the employee, owner, or participant covered by the plan or contract, or any other person, whether or not the will is in existence at the time of designation. Upon the admission of the will to probate, the death benefits shall be paid to the trustee, to be held, administered, and disposed of in accordance with the terms of the trust or trusts created by the will.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the event no trustee makes proper claim to the proceeds from the insurance company or other obligor within a period of 6 months after the date of the death of the insured, employee, annuitant, owner, or participant, or if satisfactory evidence is furnished to the insurance company or obligor within that period that there is, or will be, no trustee to receive the proceeds, payment shall be made by the insurance company or obligor to the personal representative of the person making the designation, unless otherwise provided by agreement with the insurer or obligor during the lifetime of the insured, employee, annuitant, owner, or participant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Death benefits payable as provided in subsection (1), subsection (2), or subsection (3), unless paid to a personal representative under the provisions of subsection (3), shall not be deemed to be part of the decedent’s estate, and shall not be subject to any obligation to pay the expenses of the administration and obligations of the decedent’s estate or for contribution required from a trust under s. 733.607(2) to any greater extent than if the proceeds were payable directly to the beneficiaries named in the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The death benefits held in trust may be commingled with any other assets that may properly come into the trust.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect the validity of any designation of a beneficiary of proceeds previously made that designates as beneficiary the trustee of any trust established under a trust agreement or declaration of trust or by will.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 38, ch. 77-87; s. 158, ch. 2001-226; s. 7, ch. 2005-101.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 736.172.</Text></Note></Section>