<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.2121" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notice to creditors; filing of claims.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless creditors’ claims are otherwise barred by s. 733.710, the personal representative shall promptly publish a notice to creditors. The notice shall contain the name of the decedent, the file number of the estate, the designation and address of the court in which the proceedings are pending, the name and address of the personal representative, the name and address of the personal representative’s attorney, and the date of first publication. The notice shall state that creditors must file claims against the estate with the court during the time periods set forth in s. 733.702, or be forever barred.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Publication shall be once a week for 2 consecutive weeks, in a newspaper published in the county where the estate is administered or, if there is no newspaper published in the county, in a newspaper of general circulation in that county.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal representative shall promptly make a diligent search to determine the names and addresses of creditors of the decedent who are reasonably ascertainable, even if the claims are unmatured, contingent, or unliquidated, and shall promptly serve a copy of the notice on those creditors. Impracticable and extended searches are not required. Service is not required on any creditor who has filed a claim as provided in this part, whose claim has been paid in full, or whose claim is listed in a personal representative’s timely filed proof of claim.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal representative is not individually liable to any person for giving notice under this section, even if it is later determined that notice was not required. The service of notice to creditors in accordance with this section shall not be construed as admitting the validity or enforceability of a claim.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the personal representative in good faith fails to give notice required by this section, the personal representative is not liable to any person for the failure. Liability, if any, for the failure is on the estate.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a decedent at the time of death was 55 years of age or older, the personal representative shall promptly serve a copy of the notice to creditors and provide a copy of the death certificate on the Agency for Health Care Administration within 3 months after the first publication of the notice to creditors, unless the agency has already filed a statement of claim in the estate proceedings.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the Department of Revenue has not previously been served with a copy of the notice to creditors, then service of the inventory on the Department of Revenue shall be the equivalent of service of a copy of the notice to creditors.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Claims are barred as provided in ss. 733.702 and 733.710.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 95, ch. 2001-226; s. 9, ch. 2003-154; s. 4, ch. 2005-140.</History></Section>