<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.613" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Personal representative’s right to sell real property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a personal representative of an intestate estate, or whose testator has not conferred a power of sale or whose testator has granted a power of sale but the power is so limited by the will or by operation of law that it cannot be conveniently exercised, shall consider that it is for the best interest of the estate and of those interested in it that real property be sold, the personal representative may sell it at public or private sale. No title shall pass until the court authorizes or confirms the sale. No bona fide purchaser shall be required to examine any proceedings before the order of sale.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a decedent’s will confers specific power to sell or mortgage real property or a general power to sell any asset of the estate, the personal representative may sell, mortgage, or lease, without authorization or confirmation of court, any real property of the estate or any interest therein for cash or credit, or for part cash and part credit, and with or without security for unpaid balances. The sale, mortgage, or lease need not be justified by a showing of necessity, and the sale pursuant to power of sale shall be valid.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a sale or mortgage which occurs under a specific power to sell or mortgage real property, or under a court order authorizing or confirming that act, the purchaser or lender takes title free of claims of creditors of the estate and entitlements of estate beneficiaries, except existing mortgages or other liens against real property are not affected.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 78, ch. 75-220; s. 1011, ch. 97-102; s. 137, ch. 2001-226.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 733.23.</Text></Note></Section>