<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0733.615" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Joint personal representatives; when joint action required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If two or more persons are appointed joint personal representatives, and unless the will provides otherwise, the concurrence of all joint personal representatives appointed pursuant to a will or codicil executed prior to October 1, 1987, or appointed to administer an intestate estate of a decedent who died prior to October 1, 1987, or of a majority of joint personal representatives appointed pursuant to a will or codicil executed on or after October 1, 1987, or appointed to administer an intestate estate of a decedent dying on or after October 1, 1987, is required on all acts connected with the administration and distribution of the estate. This restriction does not apply when any joint personal representative receives and receipts for property due the estate, when the concurrence required under this subsection cannot readily be obtained in the time reasonably available for emergency action necessary to preserve the estate, or when a joint personal representative has been delegated to act for the others.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where action by a majority of the joint personal representatives appointed is authorized, a joint personal representative who has not joined in exercising a power is not liable to the beneficiaries or to others for the consequences of the exercise, and a dissenting joint personal representative is not liable for the consequences of an action in which the dissenting personal representative joins at the direction of the majority of the joint personal representatives, if the dissent is expressed in writing to the other joint personal representatives at or before the time of the action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person dealing with a joint personal representative without actual knowledge that joint personal representatives have been appointed, or if advised by a joint personal representative that the joint personal representative has authority to act alone for any of the reasons mentioned in subsection (1), is as fully protected in dealing with that joint personal representative as if that joint personal representative possessed and properly exercised the power.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-106; s. 1, ch. 87-317; s. 4, ch. 88-340; s. 1013, ch. 97-102; s. 139, ch. 2001-226.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Created from former s. 732.50.</Text></Note></Section>