<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0192.102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Payment of property appraisers’ and collectors’ commissions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board of county commissioners and school board of each county shall advance and pay to the county tax collector of each such county, at the first meeting of such board each month from October through July of each year, on demand of the county tax collector, an amount equal to one-twelfth of the commissions on the county taxes levied on the county tax roll for the preceding year and one-twelfth of the commissions on county occupational and beverage licenses paid to the tax collector in the preceding fiscal year. To demand the first advance under this section, each tax collector shall submit to the board of county commissioners a statement showing the calculation of the commissions on which the amount of each advance is to be based.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">On or before November 1 of each year, each tax collector who has received advances under the provisions of this section shall make an accounting to the board of county commissioners and the school board, and any adjustments necessary shall be made so that the total advances and commissions paid by the board of county commissioners and the school board shall be the amount of commissions earned. At no time within the year shall there be paid by the board of county commissioners and the school board more than the total advances due to that date or the commissions earned to that date, whichever is the greater. Nothing contained herein shall be construed to abrogate any law providing a salary for the tax collector or require the tax collector to accept the benefits of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Chief Financial Officer shall issue to each of the county property appraisers and collectors of taxes, on the first Monday of January, April, July, and October, on demand of such county property appraisers and collectors of taxes after approval by the Department of Revenue, and shall pay, his or her warrant for an amount equal to one-fourth of four-fifths of the total amount of commissions received by such county property appraisers and collectors of taxes or their predecessors in office from the state during and for the preceding year, and the balance of the commissions earned by such county property appraiser and collector of taxes, respectively, during each year, over and above the amount of such installment payments herein provided for, shall be payable when a report of errors and double assessments is approved by the county commissioners and a copy thereof filed with the Department of Revenue.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 70-243; s. 22, ch. 73-172; s. 1, ch. 74-234; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 968, ch. 95-147; s. 3, ch. 96-397; s. 173, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Consolidation of provisions of former ss. 192.101, 192.114, 192.122.</Text></Note></Section>