<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0597.0041" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prohibited acts; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for an aquaculture registrant to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commingle in the same container any shellfish aquaculture product with any wild product;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transport by vessel over water both wild and aquaculture products of the same species at the same time; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violate any provision of this chapter or chapter 500.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of this chapter or any rule promulgated hereunder is subject to a suspension or revocation of his or her certificate of registration or license under this chapter. The department may, in lieu of, or in addition to the suspension or revocation, impose on the violator an administrative fine in an amount not to exceed $1,000 per violation per day.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in subsection (4), any person who violates any provision of this chapter, or rule hereunder, commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person certified under this chapter who has been convicted of taking aquaculture species raised at a certified facility shall have his or her certificate revoked for 5 years by the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services pursuant to the provisions and procedures of s. 120.60.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any provision of s. 597.010 or s. 597.020, or any rule adopted under those sections, commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083 for the first offense; and for the second or any subsequent offense within a 12-month period, commits a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 28, ch. 96-247; s. 12, ch. 99-390; s. 28, ch. 2000-364; s. 39, ch. 2001-63.</History></Section>