<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0947.13" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of commission.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall have the powers and perform the duties of:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining what persons shall be placed on parole, subject to the provisions of ss. 947.172 and 947.174.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fixing the time and conditions of parole, as provided in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining whether a person has violated parole and taking action with respect to such a violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Making such investigations as may be necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reporting to the Board of Executive Clemency the circumstances, the criminal records, and the social, physical, mental, and psychiatric conditions and histories of persons under consideration by the board for pardon, commutation of sentence, or remission of fine, penalty, or forfeiture.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establishing the terms and conditions of persons released on conditional release under s. 947.1405, and determining subsequent ineligibility for conditional release due to a violation of the terms or conditions of conditional release and taking action with respect to such a violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As the Control Release Authority, determining what persons will be released on control release under s. 947.146, establishing the time and conditions of control release, if any, and determining whether a person has violated the conditions of control release and taking action with respect to such a violation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determining what persons will be released on conditional medical release under s. 947.149, establishing the conditions of conditional medical release, and determining whether a person has violated the conditions of conditional medical release and taking action with respect to such a violation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall immediately examine records of the department under s. 945.25, and any other records which it obtains, and may make such other investigations as may be necessary.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services and all other state, county, and city agencies, sheriffs and their deputies, and all peace officers shall cooperate with the commission and the department and shall aid and assist them in the performance of their duties.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 20519, 1941; s. 1, ch. 72-256; ss. 86, 87, ch. 77-120; s. 476, ch. 77-147; s. 9, ch. 78-417; s. 104, ch. 79-3; s. 7, ch. 82-171; s. 34, ch. 83-131; s. 2, ch. 85-295; ss. 31, 37, ch. 86-183; ss. 18, 67, ch. 88-122; s. 46, ch. 89-526; s. 17, ch. 89-531; s. 20, ch. 90-337; s. 1, ch. 93-2; s. 4, ch. 93-61; s. 320, ch. 99-8; s. 52, ch. 2004-335.</History></Section>