<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0947.24" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Discharge from parole supervision or release supervision.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When a person is placed on parole, control release, or conditional release, the commission shall determine the period of time the person will be under parole supervision or release supervision in the following manner:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person is being paroled or released under supervision from a single or concurrent sentence, the period of time the person will be under parole supervision or release supervision may not exceed 2 years unless the commission designates a longer period of time, in which case it must advise the parolee or releasee in writing of the reasons for the extended period. In any event, the period of parole supervision or release supervision may not exceed the maximum period for which the person has been sentenced.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person is being paroled or released under supervision from a consecutive sentence or sentences, the period of time the person will be under parole supervision or release supervision will be for the maximum period for which the person was sentenced.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall review the progress of each person who has been placed on parole, control release, or conditional release after 2 years of supervision in the community and biennially thereafter. The department shall provide to the commission the information necessary to conduct such a review. Such review must include consideration of whether to modify the reporting schedule, thereby authorizing the person under parole supervision or release supervision to submit reports quarterly, semiannually, or annually. The commission, after having retained jurisdiction of a person for a sufficient length of time to evidence satisfactory rehabilitation and cooperation, may further modify the terms and conditions of the person’s parole, control release, or conditional release, may discharge the person from parole supervision or release supervision, may relieve the person from making further reports, or may permit the person to leave the state or country, upon finding that such action is in the best interests of the person and society.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not affect the rights of a parolee to request modification of the terms and conditions of parole under s. 947.19.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 20519, 1941; s. 1, ch. 63-83; s. 9, ch. 74-112; s. 256, ch. 77-104; s. 34, ch. 83-131; s. 4, ch. 85-107; s. 37, ch. 86-183; ss. 27, 67, ch. 88-122; s. 17, ch. 89-531; s. 20, ch. 90-337; s. 1, ch. 93-2; s. 10, ch. 93-61; s. 6, ch. 2001-124.</History></Section>