<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0947.18" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conditions of parole.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No person shall be placed on parole merely as a reward for good conduct or efficient performance of duties assigned in prison. No person shall be placed on parole until and unless the commission finds that there is reasonable probability that, if the person is placed on parole, he or she will live and conduct himself or herself as a respectable and law-abiding person and that the person’s release will be compatible with his or her own welfare and the welfare of society. No person shall be placed on parole unless and until the commission is satisfied that he or she will be suitably employed in self-sustaining employment or that he or she will not become a public charge. The commission shall determine the terms upon which such person shall be granted parole. If the person’s conviction was for a controlled substance violation, one of the conditions must be that the person submit to random substance abuse testing intermittently throughout the term of supervision, upon the direction of the correctional probation officer as defined in s. 943.10(3). In addition to any other lawful condition of parole, the commission may make the payment of the debt due and owing to the state under s. 960.17 or the payment of the attorney’s fees and costs due and owing to the state under s. 938.29 a condition of parole subject to modification based on change of circumstances. If the person’s conviction was for a crime that was found to have been committed for the purpose of benefiting, promoting, or furthering the interests of a criminal gang, one of the conditions must be that the person be prohibited from knowingly associating with other criminal gang members or associates, except as authorized by law enforcement officials, prosecutorial authorities, or the court, for the purpose of aiding in the investigation of criminal activity.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 20519, 1941; s. 4, ch. 77-452; s. 34, ch. 83-131; s. 2, ch. 83-256; s. 37, ch. 86-183; ss. 67, 72, ch. 88-122; s. 17, ch. 89-531; ss. 15, 20, ch. 90-337; s. 1, ch. 93-2; s. 4, ch. 96-232; s. 1875, ch. 97-102; s. 43, ch. 97-271; s. 135, ch. 2003-402; s. 22, ch. 2008-238.</History></Section>