<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0947.149" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Conditional medical release.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission shall, in conjunction with the department, establish the conditional medical release program. An inmate is eligible for consideration for release under the conditional medical release program when the inmate, because of an existing medical or physical condition, is determined by the department to be within one of the following designations:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Permanently incapacitated inmate,” which means an inmate who has a condition caused by injury, disease, or illness which, to a reasonable degree of medical certainty, renders the inmate permanently and irreversibly physically incapacitated to the extent that the inmate does not constitute a danger to herself or himself or others.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Terminally ill inmate,” which means an inmate who has a condition caused by injury, disease, or illness which, to a reasonable degree of medical certainty, renders the inmate terminally ill to the extent that there can be no recovery and death is imminent, so that the inmate does not constitute a danger to herself or himself or others.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any provision to the contrary, any person determined eligible under this section and sentenced to the custody of the department may, upon referral by the department, be considered for conditional medical release by the commission, in addition to any parole consideration for which the inmate may be considered, except that conditional medical release is not authorized for an inmate who is under sentence of death. No inmate has a right to conditional medical release or to a medical evaluation to determine eligibility for such release.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The authority and whether or not to grant conditional medical release and establish additional conditions of conditional medical release rests solely within the discretion of the commission, in accordance with the provisions of this section, together with the authority to approve the release plan to include necessary medical care and attention. The department shall identify inmates who may be eligible for conditional medical release based upon available medical information and shall refer them to the commission for consideration. In considering an inmate for conditional medical release, the commission may require that additional medical evidence be produced or that additional medical examinations be conducted, and may require such other investigations to be made as may be warranted.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conditional medical release term of an inmate released on conditional medical release is for the remainder of the inmate’s sentence, without diminution of sentence for good behavior. Supervision of the medical releasee must include periodic medical evaluations at intervals determined by the commission at the time of release.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is discovered during the conditional medical release that the medical or physical condition of the medical releasee has improved to the extent that she or he would no longer be eligible for conditional medical release under this section, the commission may order that the releasee be returned to the custody of the department for a conditional medical release revocation hearing, in accordance with s. 947.141. If conditional medical release is revoked due to improvement in the medical or physical condition of the releasee, she or he shall serve the balance of her or his sentence with credit for the time served on conditional medical release and without forfeiture of any gain-time accrued prior to conditional medical release. If the person whose conditional medical release is revoked due to an improvement in medical or physical condition would otherwise be eligible for parole or any other release program, the person may be considered for such release program pursuant to law.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to revocation of conditional medical release pursuant to paragraph (a), conditional medical release may also be revoked for violation of any condition of the release established by the commission, in accordance with s. 947.141, and the releasee’s gain-time may be forfeited pursuant to s. 944.28(1).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the commission shall adopt rules as necessary to implement the conditional medical release program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 92-310; s. 2, ch. 94-121; s. 1672, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>