<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0658.35" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Share options; warrants.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After obtaining the approval of the majority of the board of directors, the majority of the holders of common stock of the bank, and the office and after complying with the provisions of s. 607.0624, any bank or trust company may, for the purpose of providing share options for or issuing warrants to one or more of its directors, officers, or employees, hold authorized but unissued, or purchase or otherwise acquire and hold, shares of its own capital stock in an amount not to exceed 20 percent of the total number of shares outstanding.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any such bank or trust company may thereafter from time to time, without first offering such shares of stock to its stockholders, grant options or issue warrants to such of its directors, officers, and employees as may be authorized by the board of directors. A share option or warrant expires within 10 years after issuance and has an exercise price of not less than the greater of the fair market value as of the date the option is granted on such shares or the par value thereof as determined by the board of directors; however, if such shares are not publicly traded, the book value of such shares may be substituted for the fair market value.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any bank or trust company may, from time to time, issue warrants to stockholders as authorized by the board of directors. A share option or warrant expires within 5 years after issuance and has an exercise price of not less than the greater of the fair market value as of the date the option is granted on such shares or the par value thereof as determined by the board of directors.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the exercise of the option or warrant, the bank or trust company may sell and issue such shares to the optionee or warrant holder.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-582; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 39, ch. 69-353; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 25, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 87-216; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 119, ch. 92-303; s. 1781, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 659.085.</Text></Note></Section>