<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0658.235" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Subscriptions for stock; approval of major shareholders.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 6 months after commencement of corporate existence, and at least 30 days prior to opening, the directors shall have completed the stock offering and shall file with the office a final list of subscribers to all of the capital stock of the proposed bank or trust company showing the name and residence of each subscriber and the amount of stock of every class subscribed for by each.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The directors shall also provide such detailed financial, business, and biographical information as the commission or office may reasonably require for each person who, together with related interests, subscribes to 10 percent or more of the voting stock or nonvoting stock which is convertible into voting stock of the proposed bank or trust company. The office shall make an investigation of the character, financial responsibility, and financial standing of each such person in order to determine whether he or she is likely to control the bank or trust company in a manner which would jeopardize the interests of the depositors and creditors of the bank or trust company, the other stockholders, or the general public. This investigation shall include a determination of whether any such person has been convicted of, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to, a violation of s. 655.50, relating to the Florida Control of Money Laundering in Financial Institutions Act; chapter 896, relating to offenses related to financial transactions; or any similar state or federal law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the time the shares are issued, the corporation shall furnish to the office a final list of shareholders and an affidavit from the corporation that the entire capital accounts have been fully and unconditionally paid in cash and that valid assets representing such total capital accounts are held by the bank, trust company, or escrow agent.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 31, 58, ch. 85-82; s. 12, ch. 89-229; s. 5, ch. 90-51; s. 1, ch. 91-307; s. 1, ch. 92-303; s. 540, ch. 97-102; s. 12, ch. 2001-243; s. 1768, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>