<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0658.43" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Approval by office; valuation of assets; emergency action.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After approval by the board of directors of each constituent bank or trust company, the plan of merger and merger agreement shall be submitted to the office for approval, together with a certified copy of the authorizing resolutions of the board of directors of each constituent state bank or state trust company showing approval by a majority of the entire board of directors of each such state bank or state trust company, and evidence of proper action by the board of directors of any constituent national bank.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Without approval by the office, no asset shall be carried on the books of the resulting state bank or state trust company at a valuation higher than that on the books of the constituent bank or trust company at the time of the last examination by a state or national bank or trust company examiner before the effective date of the merger.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall approve the plan of merger and merger agreement if it appears that:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resulting state bank or state trust company meets all the requirements of state law as to the formation of a new state bank or state trust company, except that this provision shall not apply to the establishment of branches by merger as provided in s. 658.26.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agreement provides an adequate capital structure, including surplus, of the resulting state bank or state trust company in relation to its activities which are to continue or are to be undertaken, and also in relation to its deposit liabilities in the case of a resulting state bank.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The valuation is fair.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The merger is not contrary to the public interest.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If the office disapproves a plan of merger or merger agreement, it shall state its objections and, the provisions of chapter 120 notwithstanding, give an opportunity to the constituent banks, trust companies, or banks and trust companies to amend the plan of merger and merger agreement to obviate such objections.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the resulting state bank is not to have trust powers, the office shall not approve a merger until adequate provision has been made for successors to fiduciary positions held by any constituent trust company or any constituent bank.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approval by the office, by final order or otherwise, of a plan of merger or merger agreement shall be deemed subject to approval of the plan of merger and merger agreement by the stockholders of each constituent bank or trust company as provided in s. 658.44(1) and shall also be deemed subject to approval of the merger and the plan of merger and merger agreement by each appropriate federal regulatory agency. Unless all such approvals have been obtained and proper evidence thereof submitted to the office within 6 months after the approval by the office, the approval by the office of the plan of merger and merger agreement shall be deemed to be revoked and terminated; however, the office on its own motion, or at the request of the constituent banks or trust companies for good cause shown, may extend the time for a period not exceeding 6 months.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No merger with a resulting state bank or trust company shall take place or be effective without the issuance by the office of a certificate of merger.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 28016, 1953; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 33, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 146, ch. 83-216; s. 19, ch. 89-229; s. 7, ch. 90-51; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 126, ch. 92-303; s. 1788, ch. 2003-261; s. 29, ch. 2005-181.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 661.04.</Text></Note></Section>