<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0658.165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Banker’s banks; formation; applicability of financial institutions codes; exceptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If authorized by the office, a corporation may be formed under the laws of this state for the purpose of becoming a banker’s bank. An application for authority to organize a banker’s bank is subject to ss. 658.19, 658.20, and 658.21, except that s. 658.20(1)(b) and (c) and the minimum stock ownership requirements for the organizing directors provided in s. 658.21(2) do not apply.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A banker’s bank chartered pursuant to subsection (1) is subject to the financial institutions codes and rules adopted thereunder; and, except as otherwise specifically provided herein or by rule or order of the commission or office, a banker’s bank is vested with or subject to the same rights, privileges, duties, restrictions, penalties, liabilities, conditions, and limitations that would apply to a state bank. A banker’s bank is organized solely to do business with other financial institutions and is not deemed to be doing business with the general public even if, as an incidental part of its activities, it does business to a limited extent with entities and persons other than financial institutions as follows:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The range of customers with which the banker’s bank does business is limited to financial institutions, including subsidiaries or organizations owned by financial institutions; directors, officers, or employees of the same or other financial institutions; individuals whose accounts are acquired at the request of a financial institution’s supervisory authority due to the actual or impending failure of a financial institution; and financial institution trade associations; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The banker’s bank does not make loans to, or investments in, entities and persons other than financial institutions which exceed 10 percent of the banker’s bank’s total assets, and the banker’s bank does not receive deposits from, or issue other liabilities to, entities and persons other than financial institutions which exceed 10 percent of the banker’s bank total liabilities.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a banker’s bank may repurchase, for its own account, shares of its own capital stock; however, the outstanding capital stock may not be reduced below the minimum required by this chapter without the prior approval of the office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A banker’s bank may provide services at the request of financial institutions in organization that have:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Received conditional regulatory approval from the office in the case of a state bank or trust company, or from the appropriate state regulatory agency in the case of an out-of-state bank or trust company, or received preliminary approval from the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency in the case of a national bank.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Filed articles of incorporation or organization pursuant to s. 658.23 in the case of a state bank or trust company, or pursuant to applicable state law in the case of an out-of-state bank or trust company, or filed acceptable articles of incorporation and an organization certificate in the case of a national bank.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Received capital funds in an amount not less than the minimum capitalization required in any notice of or order granting conditional regulatory approval.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A banker’s bank may provide services to the organizers of a financial institution in organization which has not received conditional regulatory approval if such services are limited to the financing of the expenses of organizing such proposed financial institution and expenses relating to the acquisition or construction of the institution’s proposed operating facilities and associated fixtures and equipment.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the commission or office finds that any provision of this chapter is inconsistent with the purpose for which a banker’s bank is organized and that the welfare of the public or any financial institution would not be jeopardized thereby, the commission, by rule, or the office, by order, may exempt a banker’s bank from such provision or limit the application thereof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 83-48; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 104, ch. 92-303; s. 8, ch. 2001-243; s. 1762, ch. 2003-261; s. 20, ch. 2011-194.</History>
</Section>