<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0658.19" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Application for authority to organize a bank or trust company.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A written application for authority to organize a banking corporation or a trust company shall be filed with the office by the proposed directors and shall include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, residence, and occupation of each proposed director.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed corporate name.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total initial capital, the number of shares of each class of the capital stock to be authorized, and the par value of the shares of each class.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The community, including the street and number, if available, or, if not available, the area within the community, where the principal office of the proposed bank or proposed trust company is to be located.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If known, the name and residence of the proposed president, the proposed chief executive officer if other than the proposed president and, if the application is for organization of a trust company or a bank with trust powers, the name and address of the proposed trust officer.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such detailed financial, business, and biographical information as the commission or office may reasonably require for each proposed director, president, chief executive officer (if other than the president), and trust officer (if applicable).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A request for trust powers if desired in connection with an application to organize a bank.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application shall be in such form as the commission prescribes and contain such additional information as the commission or office reasonably requires and shall be accompanied by the required fee, which shall not be refundable.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding chapter 120, an application may be returned to the applicant, on a one-time basis, for correction of substantial deficiencies and may be resubmitted without payment of an additional fee if such resubmission takes place within 60 days after the date the office returns the application.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 28016, 1953; s. 1, ch. 63-181; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 2, ch. 70-263; s. 2, ch. 73-119; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 1, ch. 79-144; ss. 9, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; s. 448, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 15, 46, ch. 82-214; ss. 26, 58, ch. 85-82; s. 38, ch. 87-99; s. 8, ch. 89-229; s. 1, ch. 91-307; s. 1, ch. 92-303; s. 9, ch. 2001-243; s. 1763, ch. 2003-261.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 659.02.</Text></Note></Section>