<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0658.12" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to other definitions contained in the financial institutions codes and unless the context otherwise requires:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Association” means an association as defined in s. 665.012.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Bank” means any person having a subsisting charter or other lawful authorization, under the laws of this or any other jurisdiction, authorizing such person to conduct a general commercial banking business. The term “bank” does not include a credit union or an association.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Banker’s bank” means a bank insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or a holding company which owns or controls such an insured bank, if a minimum of 75 percent of the stock of such bank or holding company is owned exclusively by other banks, the bank is organized solely to do business with other financial institutions, and the bank does not do business with the general public.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Branch” or “branch office” of a bank means any office or place of business of a bank, other than its main office and the facilities and operations authorized by ss. 658.26(4) and 660.33, at which deposits are received, checks are paid, or money is lent. With respect to a bank that has a trust department, the terms have the meanings herein ascribed to a branch or a branch office of a trust company and mean any office or place of business of a trust company, other than its main office and its trust service offices established pursuant to s. 660.33, where trust business is transacted with its customers.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Charter” of a bank or trust company means the lawful authority under the laws of this or any other jurisdiction to exist and conduct business as, and the franchise of, a bank or a trust company, as the case may be, and includes the written instrument however denominated or entitled which evidences such authority. When used as a verb, “charter” means the granting of such authority and franchise.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Community” means an incorporated city, town, or village or, where not within any of the foregoing or if the office determines that the area within the corporate limits of any of the foregoing is inappropriate under specific circumstances, such trade area or other area, determined by the office to be appropriate under the circumstances, in which are located persons having generally similar interests, including residential, social, or business interests or combinations thereof.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Court” means a court of competent jurisdiction.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Fiduciary” means a trustee; committee, guardian, custodian, conservator, or other personal representative of a person, property, or an estate; registrar or transfer agent of, or in connection with, evidences of indebtedness of every kind and of stocks and bonds and other securities; fiscal or financial agent; investment adviser; receiver; trustee in bankruptcy; assignee for creditors; or holder of any similar representative position or any other position of trust, including a person acting in any or all the capacities and performing any or all the functions enumerated in s. 660.34.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“General commercial banking business” includes:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The business of receiving demand and time deposits;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The payment of checks; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct of a trust business when duly authorized.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Item” means any instrument, or any electronically or otherwise recorded, stored, or transmitted message, for the payment of money, whether or not it is negotiable, but does not include money.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Law” means each valid and applicable statute, ordinance, rule, or regulation of any state and each of its political subdivisions or of the United States and each of its departments, agencies, or other entities authorized by the laws of the United States to issue rules or regulations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“National bank” means a bank organized and existing as a national banking association under the provisions of 12 U.S.C. s. 21 and other sections of the National Bank Act relating thereto.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Political subdivision” of this state means and includes counties, municipalities, and departments, commissions, districts, boards, and other bodies, whether corporate or otherwise, created by or pursuant to the provisions of the constitution or any other law and also includes any officer of any of the foregoing.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Primary service area” means the smallest geographical area from which a bank draws, or a proposed bank expects to draw, approximately 75 percent of its deposits; the term also means the smallest geographic area from which a trust company or the trust department of a bank or association draws, or a proposed trust company or a proposed trust department of a bank or association expects to draw, approximately 75 percent of the assets value of its fiduciary accounts.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Principal place of business” or “principal place of doing business” of a bank, the trust department of a bank, or a trust company means its main office.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State,” when used in the context of a state other than this state, means any or every other state of the United States, the District of Columbia, any and every territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="17">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State bank” means any bank which has a subsisting bank charter issued pursuant to the provisions of the financial institutions codes or the general banking laws of this state in effect prior to the enactment of the financial institutions codes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="18">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State member bank” means a state bank which is a member of the Federal Reserve System; and “state nonmember bank” means a state bank which is not a member of the Federal Reserve System.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="19">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“State trust company” means a corporation, other than a bank, which has a subsisting trust company charter issued pursuant to the provisions of the financial institutions codes or the applicable laws of the state in effect prior to the enactment of the financial institutions codes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="20">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trust business” means the business of acting as a fiduciary when such business is conducted by a bank, state or federal association, or a trust company, and also when conducted by any other business organization as its sole or principal business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="21">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trust company” means any business organization, other than a bank or state or federal association, which is authorized by lawful authority to engage in trust business. A bank or state or federal association conducting business pursuant to lawful authority, which also by lawful authority has authority to engage in trust business, is the functional equivalent of a trust company with respect to performance of fiduciary services, and may assume fiduciary duties under appointive instruments that establish fiduciary relationships.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="22">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trust department” means the functional division or department of a bank or state or federal association which conducts the trust business of a bank or state or federal association which has been granted trust powers, pursuant to the laws of this or any other jurisdiction, authorizing the bank or state or federal association to engage in trust business in addition to the general commercial banking business or general business of an association in which it engages.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="23">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Trust powers” means the rights and powers necessary to act as a fiduciary and, when the context so requires or admits, the term also means the authority granted to a bank, state or federal association, or trust company by, or pursuant to, the laws of this or any other jurisdiction to engage in trust business.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="24">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terms which are defined in other sections of the financial institutions codes shall, unless the context otherwise requires or unless by the provisions of the section in which such term is defined its meaning as so defined is limited, have the meanings ascribed to them in such other sections of the financial institutions codes.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 28016, 1953; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 276, ch. 71-377; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 2, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; s. 446, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 83-48; s. 13, ch. 91-110; s. 1, ch. 91-307; s. 60, ch. 92-82; ss. 1, 102, 103, ch. 92-303; s. 7, ch. 2001-243; s. 1760, ch. 2003-261; s. 99, ch. 2006-1; s. 19, ch. 2011-194.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 658.02.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>