<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0658.21" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Approval of application; findings required.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall approve the application if it finds that:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Local conditions indicate reasonable promise of successful operation for the proposed state bank or trust company. In determining whether an applicant meets the requirements of this subsection, the office shall consider all materially relevant factors, including:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose, objectives, and business philosophy of the proposed state bank or trust company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The projected financial performance of the proposed bank or trust company.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The feasibility of the proposed bank or trust company, as stated in the business plan, particularly with respect to asset and liability growth and management.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed capitalization is in such amount as the office deems adequate, but in no case may the total capital accounts at opening for a bank be less than $8 million. The total capital accounts at opening for a trust company may not be less than $3 million. The organizing directors of the proposed bank shall directly own or control at least the lesser of $3 million or 25 percent of the bank’s total capital accounts proposed at opening as approved by the office. When the proposed bank will be owned by a single-bank holding company, the organizing directors of the proposed bank collectively shall directly own or control at least an amount of the single-bank holding company’s capital accounts equal to the lesser of $3 million or 25 percent of the proposed bank’s total capital accounts proposed at opening as approved by the office. When the proposed bank will be owned by an existing multibank holding company, the proposed directors shall have a substantial capital investment in the holding company, as determined by the office; however, such investment shall not be required to exceed the amount otherwise required for a single-bank holding company application. The office may disallow illegally obtained currency, monetary instruments, funds, or other financial resources from the capitalization requirements of this section. The proposed stock offering must comply with the requirements of ss. 658.23-658.25 and 658.34-658.37.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed capital structure is in such form as the office may require, but, at a minimum, every state bank or trust company hereafter organized shall establish paid-in capital equal in amount to not less than 50 percent of its total capital accounts and a paid-in surplus equal in amount to not less than 20 percent of its paid-in capital.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The proposed officers have sufficient financial institution experience, ability, standing, and reputation and the proposed directors have sufficient business experience, ability, standing, and reputation to indicate reasonable promise of successful operation, and none of the proposed officers or directors has been convicted of, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to, any violation of s. 655.50, relating to the Florida Control of Money Laundering in Financial Institutions Act; chapter 896, relating to offenses related to financial institutions; or any similar state or federal law. At least two of the proposed directors who are not also proposed officers shall have had at least 1 year direct experience as an executive officer, regulator, or director of a financial institution within 3 years of the date of the application. However, if the applicant demonstrates that at least one of the proposed directors has very substantial experience as an executive officer, director, or regulator of a financial institution more than 3 years before the date of the application, the office may modify the requirement and allow only one director to have direct financial institution experience within the last 3 years. The proposed president or chief executive officer shall have had at least 1 year of direct experience as an executive officer, director, or regulator of a financial institution within the last 3 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporate name of the proposed state bank or trust company is approved by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provision has been made for suitable quarters at the location in the application.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 22, 51, ch. 84-216; ss. 28, 58, ch. 85-82; s. 9, ch. 89-229; s. 4, ch. 90-51; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 106, ch. 92-303; s. 7, ch. 97-30; s. 10, ch. 2001-243; s. 1765, ch. 2003-261; s. 12, ch. 2008-75.</History></Section>