<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0658.34" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Shares of capital stock.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank or trust company shall issue its capital stock with par value of not less than $1 per share.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No bank or trust company shall issue any shares of capital stock at a price less than par value, and prior to issuance, any such shares must be fully paid in cash.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the approval of the office, a bank or trust company may issue preferred stock of one or more classes in an amount and with a par value as approved by the office.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">With the approval of the office, a bank or trust company may issue less than all the number of shares of any of its capital stock authorized by its articles of incorporation. Such authorized but unissued shares may be issued only for the following purposes:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To provide for stock options and warrants as provided in s. 658.35.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To declare or pay a stock dividend; however, any such stock dividend must comply with the provisions of this section and s. 658.37.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To increase the capital of the bank or trust company.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Stock of the same class may not be issued or sold by the financial institution that creates different rights, options, warrants, or benefits among the purchasers or stockholders of that class of stock. Such prohibition does not restrict the financial institution from creating uniform restrictions on the transfer of stock as permitted in s. 607.0627.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 28016, 1953; ss. 12, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-409; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 1, ch. 77-457; ss. 24, 151, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 118, ch. 92-303; s. 12, ch. 93-111; s. 16, ch. 2001-243; s. 1780, ch. 2003-261; s. 13, ch. 2008-75.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 659.08.</Text></Note></Section>