<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0658.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Opening for business.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A bank or trust company corporation shall open and conduct a general commercial bank or trust business no later than 12 months after the commencement of its corporate existence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 30 days prior to its intended opening date, the corporation shall notify the office of its proposed opening date and confirm its compliance with all conditions imposed in the order or orders issued by the office relating to its organization.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The office shall perform a preopening examination to verify good faith compliance with all the requirements of law and that the bank or trust company corporation is ready to engage in a general commercial bank or trust business. If the office finds that such requirements have been met, it shall issue a certificate of authorization to transact a general commercial bank or trust business. Upon the issuance of the certificate of authorization, the bank or trust company corporation shall become a state bank or a state trust company and the certificate shall constitute its charter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon opening for business, a bank or trust company shall have power to engage in a general commercial bank or trust business and to exercise, subject to law, all such incidental powers as may reasonably promote its general commercial bank or trust business.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 15, 152, ch. 80-260; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 24, 51, ch. 84-216; ss. 33, 58, ch. 85-82; s. 14, ch. 89-229; s. 1, ch. 91-307; ss. 1, 110, ch. 92-303; s. 13, ch. 2001-243; s. 1770, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>