<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0715.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Nonliability of landlord after disposition of property.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 715.101, after the landlord releases to the former tenant property which remains on the premises after a tenancy is terminated, the landlord is not liable with respect to that property to any person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After the landlord releases property pursuant to s. 715.108 to a person who is not the former tenant and who is reasonably believed by the landlord to be the owner of the property, the landlord is not liable with respect to that property to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person to whom notice was given pursuant to s. 715.104; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person to whom notice was not given pursuant to s. 715.104 unless such person proves that, prior to releasing the property, the landlord believed or reasonably should have believed that such person had an interest in the property and also that the landlord knew or should have known upon reasonable investigation the address of such person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where property is disposed of pursuant to s. 715.109, the landlord is not liable with respect to that property to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person to whom notice was given pursuant to s. 715.104; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person to whom notice was not given pursuant to s. 715.104 unless such person proves that, prior to disposing of the property pursuant to s. 715.109, the landlord believed or reasonably should have believed that such person had an interest in the property and also that the landlord knew or should have known upon reasonable investigation the address of such person.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-151.</History></Section>