<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0715.104" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Notification of former tenant of personal property remaining on premises after tenancy has terminated.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When personal property remains on the premises after a tenancy has terminated or expired and the premises have been vacated by the tenant, through eviction or otherwise, the landlord shall give written notice to such tenant and to any other person the landlord reasonably believes to be the owner of the property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall describe the property in a manner reasonably adequate to permit the owner of the property to identify it. The notice may describe all or a portion of the property, but the limitation of liability provided by s. 715.11 does not protect the landlord from any liability arising from the disposition of property not described in the notice, except that a trunk, valise, box, or other container which is locked, fastened, or tied in a manner which deters immediate access to its contents may be described as such without describing its contents. The notice shall advise the person to be notified that reasonable costs of storage may be charged before the property is returned, and the notice shall state where the property may be claimed and the date before which the claim must be made. The date specified in the notice shall be a date not fewer than 10 days after the notice is personally delivered or, if mailed, not fewer than 15 days after the notice is deposited in the mail.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall be personally delivered or sent by first-class mail, postage prepaid, to the person to be notified at her or his last known address and, if there is reason to believe that the notice sent to that address will not be received by that person, also delivered or sent to such other address, if any, known to the landlord where such person may reasonably be expected to receive the notice.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 11, ch. 83-151; s. 842, ch. 97-102.</History></Section>