<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0515.25" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter, the term:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Approved safety pool cover” means a manually or power-operated safety pool cover that meets all of the performance standards of the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) in compliance with standard F1346-91.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Barrier” means a fence, dwelling wall, or nondwelling wall, or any combination thereof, which completely surrounds the swimming pool and obstructs access to the swimming pool, especially access from the residence or from the yard outside the barrier.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Exit alarm” means a device that makes audible, continuous alarm sounds when any door or window which permits access from the residence to any pool area that is without an intervening enclosure is opened or left ajar.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Indoor swimming pool” means a swimming pool that is totally contained within a building and surrounded on all four sides by walls of or within the building.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Medically frail elderly person” means any person who is at least 65 years of age and has a medical problem that affects balance, vision, or judgment, including, but not limited to, a heart condition, diabetes, or Alzheimer’s disease or any related disorder.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Outdoor swimming pool” means any swimming pool that is not an indoor swimming pool.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Portable spa” means a nonpermanent structure intended for recreational bathing, in which all controls and water-heating and water-circulating equipment are an integral part of the product and which is cord-connected and not permanently electrically wired.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Public swimming pool” means a swimming pool, as defined in s. 514.011(2), which is operated, with or without charge, for the use of the general public; however, the term does not include a swimming pool located on the grounds of a private residence.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residential” means situated on the premises of a detached one-family or two-family dwelling or a one-family townhouse not more than three stories high.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Swimming pool” means any structure, located in a residential area, that is intended for swimming or recreational bathing and contains water over 24 inches deep, including, but not limited to, in-ground, aboveground, and on-ground swimming pools; hot tubs; and nonportable spas.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Young child” means any person under the age of 6 years.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2000-143.</History></Section>