<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0515.29" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Residential swimming pool barrier requirements.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A residential swimming pool barrier must have all of the following characteristics:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The barrier must be at least 4 feet high on the outside.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The barrier may not have any gaps, openings, indentations, protrusions, or structural components that could allow a young child to crawl under, squeeze through, or climb over the barrier.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The barrier must be placed around the perimeter of the pool and must be separate from any fence, wall, or other enclosure surrounding the yard unless the fence, wall, or other enclosure or portion thereof is situated on the perimeter of the pool, is being used as part of the barrier, and meets the barrier requirements of this section.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The barrier must be placed sufficiently away from the water’s edge to prevent a young child or medically frail elderly person who may have managed to penetrate the barrier from immediately falling into the water.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The structure of an aboveground swimming pool may be used as its barrier or the barrier for such a pool may be mounted on top of its structure; however, such structure or separately mounted barrier must meet all barrier requirements of this section. In addition, any ladder or steps that are the means of access to an aboveground pool must be capable of being secured, locked, or removed to prevent access or must be surrounded by a barrier that meets the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Gates that provide access to swimming pools must open outward away from the pool and be self-closing and equipped with a self-latching locking device, the release mechanism of which must be located on the pool side of the gate and so placed that it cannot be reached by a young child over the top or through any opening or gap.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A wall of a dwelling may serve as part of the barrier if it does not contain any door or window that opens to provide access to the swimming pool.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A barrier may not be located in a way that allows any permanent structure, equipment, or similar object to be used for climbing the barrier.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2000-143.</History></Section>