<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0515.27" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Residential swimming pool safety feature options; penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to pass final inspection and receive a certificate of completion, a residential swimming pool must meet at least one of the following requirements relating to pool safety features:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pool must be isolated from access to a home by an enclosure that meets the pool barrier requirements of s. 515.29;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pool must be equipped with an approved safety pool cover;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All doors and windows providing direct access from the home to the pool must be equipped with an exit alarm that has a minimum sound pressure rating of 85 dB A at 10 feet; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All doors providing direct access from the home to the pool must be equipped with a self-closing, self-latching device with a release mechanism placed no lower than 54 inches above the floor.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who fails to equip a new residential swimming pool with at least one pool safety feature as required in subsection (1) commits a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, except that no penalty shall be imposed if the person, within 45 days after arrest or issuance of a summons or a notice to appear, has equipped the pool with at least one safety feature as required in subsection (1) and has attended a drowning prevention education program established by s. 515.31. However, the requirement of attending a drowning prevention education program is waived if such program is not offered within 45 days after issuance of the citation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2000-143.</History></Section>