<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0189.419" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Effect of failure to file certain reports or information.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an independent special district fails to file the reports or information required under s. 189.415, s. 189.416, s. 189.417, or s. 189.418(9) with the local general-purpose government or governments in which it is located, the person authorized to receive and read the reports or information or the local general-purpose government shall notify the district’s registered agent. If requested by the district, the local general-purpose government shall grant an extension of up to 30 days for filing the required reports or information. If the governing body of the local general-purpose government or governments determines that there has been an unjustified failure to file these reports or information, it may notify the department, and the department may proceed pursuant to s. 189.421(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a dependent special district fails to file the reports or information required under s. 189.416, s. 189.417, or s. 189.418(9) with the local governing authority to which it is dependent, the local governing authority shall take whatever steps it deems necessary to enforce the special district’s accountability. Such steps may include, as authorized, withholding funds, removing governing board members at will, vetoing the special district’s budget, conducting the oversight review process set forth in s. 189.428, or amending, merging, or dissolving the special district in accordance with the provisions contained in the ordinance that created the dependent special district.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a special district fails to file the reports or information required under s. 218.38 with the appropriate state agency, the agency shall notify the department, and the department shall send a certified technical assistance letter to the special district which summarizes the requirements and encourages the special district to take steps to prevent the noncompliance from reoccurring.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a special district fails to file the reports or information required under s. 112.63 with the appropriate state agency, the agency shall notify the department and the department shall proceed pursuant to s. 189.421(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a special district fails to file the reports or information required under s. 218.32 or s. 218.39 with the appropriate state agency or office, the state agency or office shall, and the Legislative Auditing Committee may, notify the department and the department shall proceed pursuant to s. 189.421.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 79-183; s. 26, ch. 89-169; s. 14, ch. 96-324; s. 145, ch. 2001-266; s. 20, ch. 2004-305; s. 15, ch. 2011-144.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 189.007.</Text></Note></Section>