<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0189.434" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Board of supervisors.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A board of supervisors shall govern each authority.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall be composed of nine members. Not sooner than 60 days after the authority is established, the Governor shall appoint two members to the board; the county commission of the eligible county shall appoint three members to the board; the mayor of the eligible county shall appoint one member to the board; the city commission with the largest population shall appoint two members to the board; and the mayor of such city shall appoint one member to the board. In the event that within 30 days after the Governor has made two appointments to the board, all nine members shall not have been appointed, then the members of the board of such authority who shall have been appointed shall select by majority vote among them at the organizational meeting of the board, without regard to the presence of a quorum, the remaining members of the board. Each appointing authority shall appoint members of the board to succeed those whose terms are expiring not less than 60 days before the expiration of such term. All members of the board must have expertise in one or more of the following areas: public finance, private finance, public accounting, commercial law, commercial real estate, real estate development, general contracting, architecture, and administration of professional sports team operations. A member of the board may not, at the time of appointment, hold an elected public office in the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The organizational meeting of the board shall be held not less than 30 days and not more than 45 days after the Governor has made two appointments to the board. Appointed members of the board shall hold office for a term of 4 years or until their successors take office, except that the two initial members appointed by the Governor, one of the initial members appointed by the commission of the eligible county, and one of the initial members appointed by the mayor of the eligible county shall be appointed to terms of 3 years. In the event that initial members are appointed by the board, the board shall designate which, if any, of the initial members appointed by the board shall hold office for a term of 3 years, such that four of the nine initial members of the board shall be designated to hold office for terms of 3 years. If during a member’s term of office a vacancy occurs, the Governor shall fill the vacancy by appointment for the remainder of the term.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the board must be residents of the eligible county in which the authority is located.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Five members of the board shall constitute a quorum, and the affirmative vote of a majority of the members present and voting is necessary to take any official action.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The members of the board shall serve without compensation but are entitled to reimbursement for travel and per diem expenses in accordance with s. 112.061.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall at the time of organizing, and annually thereafter, elect a chair for a term of 1 year or until a successor is elected or the chair is removed, with or without cause, by the board. The chair shall preside at all meetings of the board. If the chair is absent or disqualified at any meeting, any member of the board may be designated chair pro tempore for that meeting.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2000-348.</History></Section>