<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0189.421" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Failure of district to disclose financial reports.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If notified pursuant to s. 189.419(1), (4), or (5), the department shall attempt to assist a special district in complying with its financial reporting requirements by sending a certified letter to the special district, and, if the special district is dependent, sending a copy of that letter to the chair of the local governing authority. The letter must include a description of the required report, including statutory submission deadlines, a contact telephone number for technical assistance to help the special district comply, a 60-day deadline for filing the required report with the appropriate entity, the address where the report must be filed, and an explanation of the penalties for noncompliance.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A special district that is unable to meet the 60-day reporting deadline must provide written notice to the department before the expiration of the deadline stating the reason the special district is unable to comply with the deadline, the steps the special district is taking to prevent the noncompliance from reoccurring, and the estimated date that the special district will file the report with the appropriate agency. The district’s written response does not constitute an extension by the department; however, the department shall forward the written response to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the written response refers to the reports required under s. 218.32 or s. 218.39, the Legislative Auditing Committee for its consideration in determining whether the special district should be subject to further state action in accordance with s. 11.40(2)(b).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the written response refers to the reports or information requirements listed in s. 189.419(1), the local general-purpose government or governments for their consideration in determining whether the oversight review process set forth in s. 189.428 should be undertaken.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the written response refers to the reports or information required under s. 112.63, the Department of Management Services for its consideration in determining whether the special district should be subject to further state action in accordance with s. 112.63(4)(d)2.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of a special district to comply with the actuarial and financial reporting requirements under s. 112.63, s. 218.32, or s. 218.39 after the procedures of subsection (1) are exhausted shall be deemed final action of the special district. The actuarial and financial reporting requirements are declared to be essential requirements of law. Remedy for noncompliance shall be by writ of certiorari as set forth in subsection (4).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to s. 11.40(2)(b), the Legislative Auditing Committee shall notify the department of those districts that fail to file the required reports. If the procedures described in subsection (1) have not yet been initiated, the department shall initiate such procedures upon receiving the notice from the Legislative Auditing Committee. Otherwise, within 60 days after receiving such notice, or within 60 days after the expiration of the 60-day deadline provided in subsection (1), whichever occurs later, the department, notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 120, shall file a petition for writ of certiorari with the circuit court. Venue for all actions pursuant to this subsection is in Leon County. The court shall award the prevailing party attorney’s fees and costs unless affirmatively waived by all parties. A writ of certiorari shall be issued unless a respondent establishes that the notification of the Legislative Auditing Committee was issued as a result of material error. Proceedings under this subsection are otherwise governed by the Rules of Appellate Procedure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Pursuant to s. 112.63(4)(d)2., the Department of Management Services may notify the department of those special districts that have failed to file the required adjustments, additional information, or report or statement after the procedures of subsection (1) have been exhausted. Within 60 days after receiving such notice or within 60 days after the 60-day deadline provided in subsection (1), whichever occurs later, the department, notwithstanding chapter 120, shall file a petition for writ of certiorari with the circuit court. Venue for all actions pursuant to this subsection is in Leon County. The court shall award the prevailing party attorney’s fees and costs unless affirmatively waived by all parties. A writ of certiorari shall be issued unless a respondent establishes that the notification of the Department of Management Services was issued as a result of material error. Proceedings under this subsection are otherwise governed by the Rules of Appellate Procedure.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 79-183; s. 79, ch. 81-259; s. 27, ch. 89-169; s. 80, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 961, ch. 95-147; s. 32, ch. 96-410; s. 20, ch. 97-255; s. 21, ch. 2004-305; s. 23, ch. 2011-34; s. 16, ch. 2011-144; s. 19, ch. 2012-5.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 189.008.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>