<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0189.412" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Special District Information Program; duties and responsibilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Special District Information Program of the Department of Economic Opportunity is created and has the following special duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The collection and maintenance of special district noncompliance status reports from the Department of Management Services, the Department of Financial Services, the Division of Bond Finance of the State Board of Administration, the Auditor General, and the Legislative Auditing Committee, for the reporting required in ss. 112.63, 218.32, 218.38, and 218.39. The noncompliance reports must list those special districts that did not comply with the statutory reporting requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintenance of a master list of independent and dependent special districts which shall be available on the department’s website.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The publishing and updating of a “Florida Special District Handbook” that contains, at a minimum:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A section that specifies definitions of special districts and status distinctions in the statutes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A section or sections that specify current statutory provisions for special district creation, implementation, modification, dissolution, and operating procedures.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A section that summarizes the reporting requirements applicable to all types of special districts as provided in ss. 189.417 and 189.418.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When feasible, securing and maintaining access to special district information collected by all state agencies in existing or newly created state computer systems.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The facilitation of coordination and communication among state agencies regarding special district information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The conduct of studies relevant to special districts.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of assistance related to and appropriate in the performance of requirements specified in this chapter, including assisting with an annual conference sponsored by the Florida Association of Special Districts or its successor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Providing assistance to local general-purpose governments and certain state agencies in collecting delinquent reports or information, helping special districts comply with reporting requirements, declaring special districts inactive when appropriate, and, when directed by the Legislative Auditing Committee, initiating enforcement provisions as provided in ss. 189.4044, 189.419, and 189.421.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 89-169; s. 15, ch. 90-502; s. 79, ch. 92-279; s. 55, ch. 92-326; s. 15, ch. 95-154; ss. 3, 17, ch. 95-272; ss. 11, 12, ch. 96-324; s. 15, ch. 97-255; s. 3, ch. 97-287; s. 69, ch. 99-255; s. 32, ch. 99-378; s. 45, ch. 2001-266; s. 25, ch. 2002-1; s. 168, ch. 2003-261; s. 18, ch. 2004-305; s. 48, ch. 2010-102; s. 65, ch. 2011-142; s. 13, ch. 2011-144.</History></Section>