<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0189.431" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Legislative findings; intent.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature finds that certain counties in the state have the need for enhancement of areas surrounding major downtown areas through the improvement of existing facilities and the development of facilities and other attractions, including professional sports facilities, and other related amenities and infrastructure. The Legislature also finds that these projects serve a paramount public purpose and that there is a need to provide a comprehensive method and funding sources for providing for the development and operation of facilities and other attractions, including professional sports facilities, and other related amenities and infrastructure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is declared to be the intent of the Legislature to prescribe a uniform procedure for establishing independent authorities for the purpose of planning, financing, constructing, renovating, developing, operating, and maintaining facilities and other attractions, including professional sports facilities and other related amenities and infrastructure within highly populated counties of the state and within counties contiguous therewith.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that each authority shall take all steps reasonable, necessary, or advisable to generate local support for the development of projects, including professional sports facilities and related amenities and infrastructure, to serve as an intermediary and facilitate negotiations with and among private interests, community organizations, and governmental authorities in connection with the construction or development of such projects, to explore, research, and analyze financing and related alternatives for the construction or development of such projects, and to present findings and recommendations to the appropriate governmental entities with respect to the construction or development of such projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Because the independent authorities so created shall be empowered to exercise certain substantial powers and authority in more than one county, it is declared to be the intent of the Legislature that the Community Improvement Authority Act be construed for all purposes as a general law that relates to more than one county and that the independent authorities so created not be deemed to have jurisdiction lying wholly within any one county within the meaning of any constitutional, statutory, or charter provision.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2000-348.</History></Section>