<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0469.007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Responsibilities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualifying agent is a primary qualifying agent unless that agent is a secondary qualifying agent under this section.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All primary qualifying agents for a business organization are jointly and equally responsible for supervision of all operations of the business organization, for all field work at all sites, and for financial matters, both for the organization in general and for each specific job.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon approval by the department, a business entity may designate a financially responsible officer for purposes of licensure. A financially responsible officer shall assume personal responsibility for all financial aspects of the business organization and shall not be designated as the primary qualifying agent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Where a business organization has a licensed financially responsible officer, the primary qualifying agent shall be responsible for all construction or consulting activities of the business organization, both in general and for each specific job.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One of the qualifying agents for a business organization that has more than one qualifying agent may be designated as the sole primary qualifying agent for the business organization by a joint agreement that is executed, on a form provided by the department, by all qualifying agents for the business organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The joint agreement must be submitted to the department for approval. If the department determines that the joint agreement is in good order, it shall approve the designation and immediately notify the qualifying agents of such approval. The designation made by the joint agreement is effective upon receipt of the notice by the qualifying agents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The qualifying agent designated for a business organization by a joint agreement is the sole primary qualifying agent for the business organization, and all other qualifying agents for the business organization are secondary qualifying agents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A designated sole primary qualifying agent has all the responsibilities and duties of a primary qualifying agent, notwithstanding that there are secondary qualifying agents for specified jobs. The designated sole primary qualifying agent is jointly and equally responsible with secondary qualifying agents for field work supervision.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secondary qualifying agent is responsible only for:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The supervision of field work at sites where that agent’s license was used to obtain the building permit.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any other work for which that agent accepts responsibility. A secondary qualifying agent is not responsible for supervision of financial matters.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualifying agent who has been designated by a joint agreement as the sole primary qualifying agent for a business organization may terminate that status by giving actual notice to the business organization, to the department, and to all secondary qualifying agents of the agent’s intention to terminate that status. Notice to the department must include proof satisfactory to the department that the agent has given the notice required in this paragraph.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The status of the qualifying agent shall cease upon the designation of a new primary qualifying agent or 60 days after satisfactory notice of termination has been provided to the department, whichever first occurs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If no new primary qualifying agent has been designated within 60 days, all secondary qualifying agents for the business organization shall become primary qualifying agents unless the joint agreement specifies that one or more of them shall become sole qualifying agents under such circumstances, in which case only they shall become sole qualifying agents.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any change in the status of a qualifying agent is prospective only. A qualifying agent is not responsible for any predecessor’s actions but is responsible, even after a change in status, for all matters that were the agent’s own responsibility while in a particular status.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 94-119.</History></Section>