<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0469.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This chapter does not apply to:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authorized employee of the United States, this state, or any municipality, county, or other political subdivision, public or private school, or private entity who has completed all training required by NESHAP and OSHA or by ASHARA for the activities described in this paragraph and who is conducting abatement work solely for maintenance purposes within the scope of the person’s employment involving less than 160 square feet of asbestos-containing materials or less than 260 linear feet of asbestos-containing material on pipe, so long as the employee is not available for hire or does not otherwise engage in asbestos abatement, contracting, or consulting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Asbestos-related activities which disturb asbestos-containing materials within manufacturing, utility, or military facilities and which are undertaken by regular full-time employees of the owner or operator who have completed all training required by this chapter or NESHAP and OSHA for conducting such activities in areas where access is restricted to authorized personnel who are carrying out specific assignments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reinspections at public or private schools, whether K-12 or any other configuration, when conducted by an employee who has completed the AHERA-required training for such reinspections pursuant to this chapter and who is conducting work within the scope of the person’s employment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Moving, removal, or disposal of asbestos-containing materials on a residential building where the owner occupies the building, the building is not for sale or lease, and the work is performed according to the owner-builder limitations provided in this paragraph. To qualify for exemption under this paragraph, an owner must personally appear and sign the building permit application. The permitting agency shall provide the person with a disclosure statement as provided in chapter 1 of the Florida Building Code.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An authorized employee of the United States, this state, or any municipality, county, or other political subdivision who has completed all training required by NESHAP and OSHA or by ASHARA for the activities described in this paragraph, while engaged in asbestos-related activities involving the demolition of a building owned by that governmental unit, where such activities are within the scope of that employment and the employee does not hold out for hire or otherwise engage in asbestos abatement, contracting, or consulting.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure as an asbestos contractor is not required for the moving, removal, or disposal of asbestos-containing roofing material by a roofing contractor certified or registered under part I of chapter 489, if all such activities are performed under the direction of an onsite roofing supervisor trained as provided in s. 469.012.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure as an asbestos contractor or asbestos consultant is not required for the moving, removal, repair, maintenance, or disposal, or related inspections, of asbestos-containing resilient floor covering or its adhesive, if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The resilient floor covering is a Category I nonfriable material as defined in NESHAP and remains a Category I nonfriable material during removal activity.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All such activities are performed in accordance with all applicable asbestos standards of the United States Occupational Safety and Health Administration under 29 C.F.R. part 1926.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The removal is not subject to asbestos licensing or accreditation requirements under federal asbestos NESHAP regulations of the United States Environmental Protection Agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Written notice of the time, place, and company performing the removal and certification that all conditions required under this subsection are met are provided to the Department of Business and Professional Regulation at least 3 days prior to such removal. The contractor removing such flooring materials is responsible for maintaining proof that all the conditions required under this subsection are met.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The department may inspect removal sites to determine compliance with this subsection and shall adopt rules governing inspections.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensure as an asbestos consultant or contractor is not required for the repair, maintenance, removal, or disposal of asbestos-containing pipe or conduit, if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pipe or conduit is used for electrical, electronic, communications, gas, sewer, or water service;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pipe or conduit is not located in a building;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The pipe or conduit is made of Category I or Category II nonfriable material as defined in NESHAP; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All such activities are performed according to all applicable regulations, including work practices and training, of the United States Occupational Safety and Health Administration under 29 C.F.R. part 1926.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or affect otherwise applicable Florida Statutes and rules promulgated thereunder, or Environmental Protection Agency or OSHA regulations regarding asbestos activities.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 53, ch. 94-119; s. 13, ch. 98-419; s. 15, ch. 99-254; s. 36, ch. 2000-141; s. 34, ch. 2001-186; s. 3, ch. 2001-372; s. 36, ch. 2011-213; s. 9, ch. 2012-61.</History>
</Section>