<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0338.161" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Authority of department or toll agencies to advertise and promote electronic toll collection; expanded uses of electronic toll collection system; authority of department to collect tolls, fares, and fees for private and public entities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may incur expenses for paid advertising, marketing, and promotion of toll facilities and electronic toll collection products and services. Promotions may include discounts and free products.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may receive funds from advertising placed on electronic toll collection products and promotional materials to defray the costs of products and services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or any toll agency created by statute may incur expenses to advertise or promote its electronic toll collection system to consumers on or off the turnpike or toll system.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department or toll agency created by statute finds that it can increase nontoll revenues or add convenience or other value for its customers, the department or toll agency may enter into agreements with a private or public entity allowing the use of its electronic toll collection system to pay parking fees for vehicles equipped with a transponder or similar device. The department or toll agency may initiate feasibility studies of other future uses of its electronic toll collection system and make recommendations to the Legislature to authorize such uses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds that it can increase nontoll revenues or add convenience or other value for its customers, and if a public or private transportation facility owner agrees that its facility will become interoperable with the department’s electronic toll collection and video billing systems, the department <Reference Number="1" />is authorized to enter into an agreement with the <Reference Number="2" />private or public entities for the department’s use of its electronic toll collection and video billing systems to collect and enforce for the owner tolls, fares, administrative fees, and other applicable charges <Reference Number="3" />imposed in connection with use of transportation facilities of the <Reference Number="4" />private or public entities that become interoperable with the department’s electronic toll collection system. The department may modify its rules regarding toll collection procedures and the imposition of administrative charges to be applicable to toll facilities that are not part of the turnpike system or otherwise owned by the department. This subsection may not be construed to limit the authority of the department under any other provision of law or under any agreement entered into prior to July 1, 2012.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 16, ch. 97-280; s. 16, ch. 2000-266; s. 35, ch. 2007-196; s. 24, ch. 2012-128; s. 43, ch. 2012-174.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 43, ch. 2012-174. The amendment by s. 24, ch. 2012-128, used the word “may” instead of the words “is authorized to.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 43, ch. 2012-174. The amendment by s. 24, ch. 2012-128, used the words “owner of such facility under which the department uses” instead of the words “private or public entities for the department’s use of.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 43, ch. 2012-174. The amendment by s. 24, ch. 2012-128, used the word “due” instead of the word “imposed.”</Text></Note><Note Reference="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As amended by s. 43, ch. 2012-174. The amendment by s. 24, ch. 2012-128, used the words “owner’s facility” instead of the words “private or public entities.”</Text></Note></Section>