<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0338.2275" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Approved turnpike projects.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legislative approval of the department’s tentative work program that contains the turnpike project constitutes approval to issue bonds as required by s. 11(f), Art. VII of the State Constitution. No more than $10 billion of bonds may be outstanding to fund approved turnpike projects.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may use turnpike revenues, the State Transportation Trust Fund moneys allocated for turnpike projects pursuant to s. 339.65, federal funds, and bond proceeds, and shall use the most cost-efficient combination of such funds, in developing a financial plan for funding turnpike projects. The department must submit a report of the estimated cost for each ongoing turnpike project and for each planned project to the Legislature 14 days before the convening of the regular legislative session. Verification of economic feasibility and statements of environmental feasibility for individual turnpike projects must be based on the entire project as approved. Statements of environmental feasibility are not required for those projects listed in s. 12, chapter 90-136, Laws of Florida, for which the Project Development and Environmental Reports were completed by July 1, 1990. All required environmental permits must be obtained before the department may advertise for bids for contracts for the construction of any turnpike project.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Bonds may not be issued to fund a turnpike project until the department has made a final determination that the project is economically feasible in accordance with s. 338.221, based on the most current information available.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 12, ch. 90-136; s. 129, ch. 92-152; s. 68, ch. 93-164; ss. 5, 79, ch. 94-237; s. 46, ch. 95-257; s. 20, ch. 97-280; s. 56, ch. 2000-152; s. 3, ch. 2003-409; s. 6, ch. 2007-66; s. 36, ch. 2007-196; s. 48, ch. 2012-174.</History></Section>