<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0338.239" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Traffic control on the turnpike system.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to adopt rules with respect to the use of the turnpike system, which rules must relate to vehicular speeds, loads and dimensions, safety devices, rules of the road, and other matters necessary to carry out the purposes of ss. 338.22-338.241. Insofar as these rules may be inconsistent with the provisions of chapter 316, the rules control. A violation of these rules must be punished pursuant to chapters 316 and 318.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Members of the Florida Highway Patrol are vested with the power, and charged with the duty, to enforce the rules of the department. Approved expenditures incurred by the Florida Highway Patrol in carrying out its powers and duties under ss. 338.22-338.241 may be treated as a part of the cost of the operation of the turnpike system, and the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles shall be reimbursed by the turnpike enterprise for such expenses incurred on the turnpike system. Florida Highway Patrol Troop K shall be headquartered with the turnpike enterprise and shall be the official and preferred law enforcement troop for the turnpike system. The Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles may, upon request of the executive director of the turnpike enterprise and approval of the Legislature, increase the number of authorized positions for Troop K, or the executive director of the turnpike enterprise may contract with the Department of Highway Safety and Motor Vehicles for additional troops to patrol the turnpike system.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 23, ch. 28128, 1953; ss. 10, 23, 24, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 244, ch. 71-136; s. 8, ch. 74-377; s. 51, ch. 76-31; s. 56, ch. 78-95; s. 198, ch. 84-309; s. 14, ch. 88-286; s. 49, ch. 95-257; s. 57, ch. 96-350; s. 133, ch. 99-13; s. 98, ch. 99-385; s. 23, ch. 2002-20.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 340.23.</Text></Note></Section>