<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0338.2216" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Turnpike Enterprise; powers and authority.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the powers granted to the department, the Florida Turnpike Enterprise has full authority to exercise all powers granted to it under this chapter. Powers shall include, but are not limited to, the ability to plan, construct, maintain, repair, and operate the Florida Turnpike System.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the express intention of the Florida Turnpike Law that the Florida Turnpike Enterprise be authorized to plan, develop, own, purchase, lease, or otherwise acquire, demolish, construct, improve, relocate, equip, repair, maintain, operate, and manage the Florida Turnpike System; to expend funds to publicize, advertise, and promote the advantages of using the turnpike system and its facilities; and to cooperate, coordinate, partner, and contract with other entities, public and private, to accomplish these purposes.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The executive director of the turnpike enterprise shall appoint a staff, which shall be exempt from part II of chapter 110. Among the staff shall be a chief financial officer, who must be a proven, effective administrator with demonstrated experience in financial management of a large bonded capital program and must hold an active license to practice public accounting in Florida pursuant to chapter 473. The turnpike enterprise staff shall also include the Office of Toll Operations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Turnpike Enterprise shall pursue and implement new technologies and processes in its operations and collection of tolls and the collection of other amounts associated with road and infrastructure usage. Such technologies and processes must include, without limitation, video billing and variable pricing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall have the authority to employ procurement methods available to the Department of Management Services under chapters 255 and 287 and under any rule adopted under such chapters solely for the benefit of the turnpike enterprise.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The turnpike enterprise shall be a single budget entity and shall develop a budget pursuant to chapter 216. The turnpike enterprise’s budget shall be submitted to the Legislature along with the department’s budget.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 216.301 to the contrary and in accordance with s. 216.351, the Executive Office of the Governor shall, on July 1 of each year, certify forward all unexpended funds appropriated or provided pursuant to this section for the turnpike enterprise. Of the unexpended funds certified forward, any unencumbered amounts shall be carried forward. Such funds carried forward shall not exceed 5 percent of the original approved operating budget as defined in s. 216.181(1) of the turnpike enterprise. Funds carried forward pursuant to this section may be used for any lawful purpose, including, but not limited to, promotional and market activities, technology, and training. Any certified forward funds remaining undisbursed on September 30 of each year shall be carried forward.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The powers conferred upon the turnpike enterprise under ss. 338.22-338.241 shall be in addition and supplemental to the existing powers of the department and the turnpike enterprise, and these powers shall not be construed as repealing any provision of any other law, general or local, but shall supersede such other laws that are inconsistent with the exercise of the powers provided under ss. 338.22-338.241 and provide a complete method for the exercise of such powers granted.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2002-20; s. 57, ch. 2002-402; s. 4, ch. 2003-286; s. 6, ch. 2004-6; s. 42, ch. 2006-122; s. 15, ch. 2009-85.</History></Section>