<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.3135" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary certificate for visiting physicians to practice in approved cancer centers.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any physician who has been accepted for a course of training by a cancer center approved by the board and who meets all of the qualifications set forth in this section may be issued a temporary certificate to practice in a board-approved cancer center under the International Cancer Center Visiting Physician Program. A certificate may be issued to a physician who will be training under the direct supervision of a physician employed by or under contract with an approved cancer center for a period of no more than 1 year. The purpose of the International Cancer Center Visiting Physician Program is to provide to internationally respected and highly qualified physicians advanced education and training on cancer treatment techniques developed at an approved cancer center. The board may issue this temporary certificate in accordance with the restrictions set forth in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary certificate for practice in an approved cancer center may be issued without examination to an individual who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an accredited medical school or its equivalent, or is a graduate of a foreign medical school listed with the World Health Organization;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid and unencumbered license to practice medicine in another country;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form adopted by the board and remitted a nonrefundable application fee not to exceed $300;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not committed any act in this or any other jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining a physician under s. 456.072 or s. 458.331;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the financial responsibility requirements of s. 458.320; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been accepted for a course of training by a cancer center approved by the board.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall by rule establish qualifications for approval of cancer centers under this section, which at a minimum shall require the cancer center to be licensed under chapter 395 and have met the standards required to be a National Cancer Institute-designated cancer center. The board shall review the cancer centers approved under this section not less than annually to ascertain that the minimum requirements of this chapter and the rules adopted thereunder are being complied with. If it is determined that such minimum requirements are not being met by an approved cancer center, the board shall rescind its approval of that cancer center and no temporary certificate for that cancer center shall be valid until such time as the board reinstates its approval of that cancer center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recipient of a temporary certificate for practice in an approved cancer center may use the certificate to practice for the duration of the course of training at the approved cancer center so long as the duration of the course does not exceed 1 year. If at any time the cancer center is no longer approved by the board, the temporary certificate shall expire and the recipient shall no longer be authorized to practice in this state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A recipient of a temporary certificate for practice in an approved cancer center is limited to practicing in facilities owned or operated by that approved cancer center and is limited to only practicing under the direct supervision of a physician who holds a valid, active, and unencumbered license to practice medicine in this state issued under this chapter or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall not issue a temporary certificate for practice in an approved cancer center to any physician who is under investigation in another jurisdiction for an act that would constitute a violation of this chapter or chapter 456 until such time as the investigation is complete and the physician is found innocent of all charges.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician applying under this section is exempt from the requirements of ss. 456.039-456.046. All other provisions of chapters 456 and 458 apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any year, the maximum number of temporary certificates that may be issued by the board under this section may not exceed 10 at each approved cancer center.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 as necessary to implement this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize a physician who is not licensed to practice medicine in this state to qualify for or otherwise engage in the practice of medicine in this state, except as provided in this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 36, ch. 2000-318; s. 75, ch. 2001-62.</History></Section>