<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.335" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Prescription or administration of dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO).</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, “physician” means a doctor of medicine or osteopathic medicine licensed under this chapter or chapter 459.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No physician shall be subject to disciplinary action by the Board of Medicine or Board of Osteopathic Medicine for prescribing or administering dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) to a patient under his or her care who has requested the substance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The patient, after being fully informed as to alternative methods of treatment and their potential for cure and upon request for the administration of dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) by his or her physician, shall sign a written release, releasing the physician and, when applicable, the hospital or health facility from any liability therefor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician shall inform the patient in writing if dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) has not been approved as a treatment or cure by the Food and Drug Administration of the United States Department of Health and Human Services for the disorder for which it is being prescribed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This act shall not apply to conditions for which dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) has been approved as a treatment by the Food and Drug Administration of the United States Department of Health and Human Services.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 79-302; s. 5, ch. 80-340; s. 299, ch. 81-259; s. 2, ch. 81-318; ss. 25, 26, ch. 86-245; s. 14, ch. 91-220; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 82, ch. 92-149; s. 211, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>