<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.3124" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restricted license; certain experienced foreign-trained physicians.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who was trained in a medical school that is listed in the World Directory of Medical Schools published by the World Health Organization and is located in a country other than the United States, Canada, or Puerto Rico may apply to take Step III of the United States Medical Licensing Examination, if the person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Legally practiced medicine for at least 5 years in the country in which the school is located;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has passed Steps I and II of the United States Medical Licensing Examination;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is certified by the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates as qualified for a restricted license to practice medicine;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is not subject to discipline, investigation, or prosecution in any jurisdiction for acts that threaten the public health, safety, or welfare or violate chapter 456 or this chapter; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has been a resident of this state since July 1, 1996.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person applying for licensure under this section must submit to the Department of Health on or before December 31, 2000:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A completed application and documentation required by the Board of Medicine to prove compliance with subsection (1); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A nonrefundable application fee not to exceed $500 and a nonrefundable examination fee not to exceed $300 plus the actual cost to purchase and administer the examination.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person applying under this section may take the examination a maximum of 5 times within 5 years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A restricted licensee under this section must practice under the supervision of a licensee approved by the board, with the first year of licensure under direct supervision and the second year in community service under indirect supervision, including practicing with organizations that serve indigent populations, such as s. 501(c)(3) agencies, public health units, prisons, or other organizations approved by the board.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 458.311(1)(f), a person who successfully meets the requirements of this section and who successfully passes Step III of the United States Medical Licensing Examination is eligible for full licensure as a physician.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall adopt rules to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 110, ch. 97-261; s. 214, ch. 97-264; s. 44, ch. 98-166; s. 17, ch. 99-332; s. 185, ch. 99-397; s. 103, ch. 2000-160.</History></Section>