<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.3137" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Temporary certificate for visiting physicians to obtain medical privileges for instructional purposes in conjunction with certain plastic surgery training programs and plastic surgery educational symposiums.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any physician who has been invited by both:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plastic surgery training program that is affiliated with a medical school within this state that is accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An educational symposium cosponsored by the American Society of Plastic Surgeons, the Plastic Surgery Educational Foundation, or the American Society for Aesthetic Plastic Surgery,</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">may be issued a temporary certificate for limited privileges solely for purposes of providing educational training in plastic surgery in accordance with the restrictions set forth in this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary certificate to practice medicine for educational purposes to help teach plastic surgery residents of a medical school within this state in conjunction with a nationally sponsored educational symposium may be issued without examination, upon verification by the board that the individual meets all of the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an accredited medical school or its equivalent or is a graduate of a foreign medical school listed with the World Health Organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Holds a valid and unencumbered license to practice medicine in another state or country.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a recognized expert in a specific area of plastic surgery as demonstrated by peer-reviewed publications, invited lectureships, and academic affiliations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed an application form adopted by the board and remitted a nonrefundable application fee not to exceed $300.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not committed an act in this or any other jurisdiction that would constitute a basis for disciplining a physician under s. 456.072 or s. 458.331.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets the financial responsibility requirements of s. 458.320(1) or (2).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is applying only in connection with both a medical school within this state that is accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education and an educational symposium sponsored by the American Society of Plastic Surgeons, the Plastic Surgery Educational Foundation, or the American Society for Aesthetic Plastic Surgery.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A temporary certificate issued under this section is valid for no more than 3 days per year, and such certificate expires 1 year after issuance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue more than six temporary certificates under this section per calendar year.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order for a physician who is a graduate of a foreign medical school and holds a valid and unencumbered license to practice medicine in another country but does not hold a license to practice medicine in this or another state to obtain a temporary certificate under this section, the organization sponsoring the educational symposium must pay for any medical judgments incurred by that physician by obtaining a surety bond issued by a surety company authorized to do business in this state or establishing a certificate of deposit or a guaranteed letter of credit with a licensed and insured bank or savings institution located in the state. The amount of the bond, certificate of deposit, or guaranteed letter of credit shall be an amount not less than $250,000.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A physician applying under this section is exempt from the requirements of ss. 456.039-456.046. All other provisions of chapter 456 and this chapter apply.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall not issue a temporary certificate for practice to any physician who is under investigation in another jurisdiction for an act that would constitute a violation of this chapter or chapter 456 until such time as the investigation is complete and the physician is found innocent of all charges.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-75.</History></Section>