<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.311" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by examination; requirements; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person desiring to be licensed as a physician, who does not hold a valid license in any state, shall apply to the department on forms furnished by the department. The department shall license each applicant who the board certifies:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed the application form and remitted a nonrefundable application fee not to exceed $500.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is at least 21 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is of good moral character.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not committed any act or offense in this or any other jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining a physician pursuant to s. 458.331.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any applicant who has graduated from medical school after October 1, 1992, has completed the equivalent of 2 academic years of preprofessional, postsecondary education, as determined by rule of the board, which shall include, at a minimum, courses in such fields as anatomy, biology, and chemistry prior to entering medical school.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets one of the following medical education and postgraduate training requirements:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an allopathic medical school or allopathic college recognized and approved by an accrediting agency recognized by the United States Office of Education or is a graduate of an allopathic medical school or allopathic college within a territorial jurisdiction of the United States recognized by the accrediting agency of the governmental body of that jurisdiction;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the language of instruction of the medical school is other than English, has demonstrated competency in English through presentation of a satisfactory grade on the Test of Spoken English of the Educational Testing Service or a similar test approved by rule of the board; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed an approved residency of at least 1 year.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an allopathic foreign medical school registered with the World Health Organization and certified pursuant to s. 458.314 as having met the standards required to accredit medical schools in the United States or reasonably comparable standards;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the language of instruction of the foreign medical school is other than English, has demonstrated competency in English through presentation of the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates English proficiency certificate or by a satisfactory grade on the Test of Spoken English of the Educational Testing Service or a similar test approved by rule of the board; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed an approved residency of at least 1 year.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is a graduate of an allopathic foreign medical school which has not been certified pursuant to s. 458.314;</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has had his or her medical credentials evaluated by the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates, holds an active, valid certificate issued by that commission, and has passed the examination utilized by that commission; and</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed an approved residency of at least 1 year; however, after October 1, 1992, the applicant shall have completed an approved residency or fellowship of at least 2 years in one specialty area. However, to be acceptable, the fellowship experience and training must be counted toward regular or subspecialty certification by a board recognized and certified by the American Board of Medical Specialties.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has submitted to the department a set of fingerprints on a form and under procedures specified by the department, along with a payment in an amount equal to the costs incurred by the Department of Health for the criminal background check of the applicant.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has obtained a passing score, as established by rule of the board, on the licensure examination of the United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE); or a combination of the United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE), the examination of the Federation of State Medical Boards of the United States, Inc. (FLEX), or the examination of the National Board of Medical Examiners up to the year 2000; or for the purpose of examination of any applicant who was licensed on the basis of a state board examination and who is currently licensed in at least one other jurisdiction of the United States or Canada, and who has practiced pursuant to such licensure for a period of at least 10 years, use of the Special Purpose Examination of the Federation of State Medical Boards of the United States (SPEX) upon receipt of a passing score as established by rule of the board. However, for the purpose of examination of any applicant who was licensed on the basis of a state board examination prior to 1974, who is currently licensed in at least three other jurisdictions of the United States or Canada, and who has practiced pursuant to such licensure for a period of at least 20 years, this paragraph does not apply.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As prescribed by board rule, the board may require an applicant who does not pass the national licensing examination after five attempts to complete additional remedial education or training. The board shall prescribe the additional requirements in a manner that permits the applicant to complete the requirements and be reexamined within 2 years after the date the applicant petitions the board to retake the examination a sixth or subsequent time.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (1)(f)3., a graduate of a foreign medical school need not present the certificate issued by the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates or pass the examination utilized by that commission if the graduate:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has received a bachelor’s degree from an accredited United States college or university.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has studied at a medical school which is recognized by the World Health Organization.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed all of the formal requirements of the foreign medical school, except the internship or social service requirements, and has passed part I of the National Board of Medical Examiners examination or the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates examination equivalent.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has completed an academic year of supervised clinical training in a hospital affiliated with a medical school approved by the Council on Medical Education of the American Medical Association and upon completion has passed part II of the National Board of Medical Examiners examination or the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates examination equivalent.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the board shall assure that applicants for licensure meet the criteria in subsection (1) through an investigative process. When the investigative process is not completed within the time set out in s. 120.60(1) and the department or board has reason to believe that the applicant does not meet the criteria, the State Surgeon General or the State Surgeon General’s designee may issue a 90-day licensure delay which shall be in writing and sufficient to notify the applicant of the reason for the delay. The provisions of this subsection shall control over any conflicting provisions of s. 120.60(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may not certify to the department for licensure any applicant who is under investigation in another jurisdiction for an offense which would constitute a violation of this chapter until such investigation is completed. Upon completion of the investigation, the provisions of s. 458.331 shall apply. Furthermore, the department may not issue an unrestricted license to any individual who has committed any act or offense in any jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining a physician pursuant to s. 458.331. When the board finds that an individual has committed an act or offense in any jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining a physician pursuant to s. 458.331, then the board may enter an order imposing one or more of the terms set forth in subsection (8).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each applicant who meets the requirements of this chapter shall be licensed as a physician, with rights as defined by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon certification by the board, the department shall impose conditions, limitations, or restrictions on a license if the applicant is on probation in another jurisdiction for an act which would constitute a violation of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board determines that any applicant for licensure has failed to meet, to the board’s satisfaction, each of the appropriate requirements set forth in this section, it may enter an order requiring one or more of the following terms:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to certify to the department an application for licensure, certification, or registration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification to the department of an application for licensure, certification, or registration with restrictions on the scope of practice of the licensee; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification to the department of an application for licensure, certification, or registration with placement of the physician on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the board may specify, including, but not limited to, requiring the physician to submit to treatment, attend continuing education courses, submit to reexamination, or work under the supervision of another physician.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 8, ch. 79-302; s. 292, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 3, ch. 84-222; s. 4, ch. 84-543; s. 4, ch. 84-553; s. 29, ch. 85-175; s. 1, ch. 85-344; ss. 6, 25, 26, ch. 86-245; s. 17, ch. 88-1; s. 4, ch. 88-205; s. 18, ch. 89-162; s. 1, ch. 89-266; ss. 5, 42, ch. 89-374; s. 1, ch. 89-541; s. 3, ch. 90-60; s. 25, ch. 90-228; s. 2, ch. 90-249; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 92-53; s. 77, ch. 92-149; s. 20, ch. 95-145; s. 215, ch. 96-410; s. 1086, ch. 97-103; s. 133, ch. 97-237; s. 18, ch. 97-264; s. 9, ch. 97-273; s. 1, ch. 97-295; s. 42, ch. 98-166; s. 93, ch. 99-397; s. 115, ch. 2000-153; s. 69, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>