<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.324" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Breast cancer; information on treatment alternatives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITION.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term “medically viable,” as applied to treatment alternatives, means modes of treatment generally considered by the medical profession to be within the scope of current, acceptable standards, including treatment alternatives described in the written summary prepared by the Florida Cancer Control and Research Advisory Council in accordance with s. 1004.435(4)(m).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMMUNICATION OF TREATMENT ALTERNATIVES.<EmDash />Each physician treating a patient who is, or in the judgment of the physician is at high risk of being, diagnosed as having breast cancer shall inform such patient of the medically viable treatment alternatives available to such patient; shall describe such treatment alternatives; and shall explain the relative advantages, disadvantages, and risks associated with the treatment alternatives to the extent deemed necessary to allow the patient to make a prudent decision regarding such treatment options. In compliance with this subsection:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician may, in his or her discretion:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Orally communicate such information directly to the patient or the patient’s legal representative;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide the patient or the patient’s legal representative with a copy of the written summary prepared in accordance with s. 1004.435(4)(m) and express a willingness to discuss the summary with the patient or the patient’s legal representative; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Both communicate such information directly and provide a copy of the written summary to the patient or the patient’s legal representative for further consideration and possible later discussion.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In providing such information, the physician shall take into consideration the emotional state of the patient, the physical state of the patient, and the patient’s ability to understand the information.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The physician may, in his or her discretion and without restriction, recommend any mode of treatment which is in his or her judgment the best treatment for the patient.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">Nothing in this subsection shall reduce other provisions of law regarding informed consent.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RECORDS.<EmDash />Every physician treating a patient who is, or in the judgment of the physician is at high risk of being, diagnosed as having breast cancer shall indicate on such patient’s medical record compliance or noncompliance with the provisions of subsection (2).</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 84-222; s. 1, ch. 85-65; ss. 16, 25, 26, ch. 86-245; s. 2, ch. 90-314; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 93-267; s. 207, ch. 97-103; s. 1012, ch. 2002-387.</History></Section>