<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.310" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Restricted licenses.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to provide medical services to all the residents of this state at an affordable cost.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Board of Medicine may, by rule, develop criteria and, without examination, issue restricted licenses annually to up to 100 persons to practice medicine in this state who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meet the requirements of s. 458.311;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Show evidence of the active licensed practice of medicine in another jurisdiction for at least 2 years of the immediately preceding 4 years, or completion of board-approved postgraduate training within the year preceding the filing of an application; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enter into a contract to practice for a period of 24 months solely in the employ of the state or a federally funded community health center or migrant health center, at the current salary level for that position. The Board of Medicine shall designate areas of critical need in the state where these restricted licensees may practice.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Before the end of the 24-month practice period, the physician must take and successfully complete the licensure examination.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the restricted licensee breaches the terms of the employment contract, he or she may not be licensed as a physician in this state under any licensing provisions.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 50, ch. 92-149; s. 201, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>