<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.3191" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Reference Number="1" /><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Physician survey.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each person who applies for licensure renewal as a physician under this chapter or chapter 459 must, in conjunction with the renewal of such license under procedures adopted by the Department of Health and in addition to any other information that may be required from the applicant, furnish the following to the Department of Health in a physician survey:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licensee information, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Frequency and geographic location of practice within the state.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Practice setting.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Percentage of time spent in direct patient care.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Anticipated change to license or practice status.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Areas of specialty or certification.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Availability and trends relating to critically needed services, including, but not limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Obstetric care and services, including incidents of deliveries.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Radiological services, particularly performance of mammograms and breast-imaging services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Physician services for hospital emergency departments and trauma centers, including on-call hours.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other critically needed specialty areas, as determined by the department.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such information furnished must include a statement submitted by the physician that the information provided is true and accurate to the best of his or her knowledge and the submission does not contain any knowingly false information.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall issue a nondisciplinary citation to any physician licensed under this chapter or chapter 459 who fails to complete the survey within 90 days after the renewal of his or her license to practice as a physician.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The citation must notify a physician who fails to complete the survey required by this section that his or her license will not be renewed for any subsequent license renewal unless the physician completes the survey.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In conjunction with issuing the license renewal notice required by s. 456.038, the Department of Health shall notify each physician licensed under this chapter or chapter 459 who has failed to complete the survey at the licensee’s last known address of record with the Department of Health of the requirement that the physician survey be completed prior to the subsequent license renewal. At any subsequent license renewal, the Department of Health may not renew the license of any physician licensed under this chapter or chapter 459 until the survey required under this section is completed by the licensee.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 necessary to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2007-172.</History><Note Reference="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Also published at s. 459.0081.</Text></Note></Section>