<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.303" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Provisions not applicable to other practitioners; exceptions, etc.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of ss. 458.301, 458.303, 458.305, 458.307, 458.309, 458.311, 458.313, 458.315, 458.317, 458.319, 458.321, 458.327, 458.329, 458.331, 458.337, 458.339, 458.341, 458.343, 458.345, and 458.347 shall have no application to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other duly licensed health care practitioners acting within their scope of practice authorized by statute.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any physician lawfully licensed in another state or territory or foreign country, when meeting duly licensed physicians of this state in consultation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Commissioned medical officers of the Armed Forces of the United States and of the Public Health Service of the United States while on active duty and while acting within the scope of their military or public health responsibilities.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person while actually serving without salary or professional fees on the resident medical staff of a hospital in this state, subject to the provisions of s. 458.321.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person furnishing medical assistance in case of an emergency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The domestic administration of recognized family remedies.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The practice of the religious tenets of any church in this state.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or manufacturer who, without the use of drugs or medicine, mechanically fits or sells lenses, artificial eyes or limbs, or other apparatus or appliances or is engaged in the mechanical examination of eyes for the purpose of constructing or adjusting spectacles, eyeglasses, or lenses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in s. 458.301, s. 458.303, s. 458.305, s. 458.307, s. 458.309, s. 458.311, s. 458.313, s. 458.319, s. 458.321, s. 458.327, s. 458.329, s. 458.331, s. 458.337, s. 458.339, s. 458.341, s. 458.343, s. 458.345, or s. 458.347 shall be construed to prohibit any service rendered by a registered nurse or a licensed practical nurse, if such service is rendered under the direct supervision and control of a licensed physician who provides specific direction for any service to be performed and gives final approval to all services performed. Further, nothing in this or any other chapter shall be construed to prohibit any service rendered by a medical assistant in accordance with the provisions of s. 458.3485.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 8, ch. 79-302; s. 290, ch. 81-259; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 2, ch. 84-543; s. 1, ch. 84-552; s. 2, ch. 84-553; s. 9, ch. 85-196; s. 1, ch. 85-307; ss. 2, 25, 26, ch. 86-245; s. 15, ch. 88-1; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 14, ch. 97-264.</History></Section>