<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.3165" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Public psychiatry certificate.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board shall issue a public psychiatry certificate to an individual who remits an application fee not to exceed $300, as set by the board, who is a board-certified psychiatrist, who is licensed to practice medicine without restriction in another state, and who meets the requirements in s. 458.311(1)(a)-(g) and (5). A recipient of a public psychiatry certificate may use the certificate to work at any public mental health facility or program funded in part or entirely by state funds.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such certificate shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorize the holder to practice only in a public mental health facility or program funded in part or entirely by state funds.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be issued and renewable biennially if the State Surgeon General and the chair of the department of psychiatry at one of the public medical schools or the chair of the department of psychiatry at the accredited medical school at the University of Miami recommend in writing that the certificate be issued or renewed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Automatically expire if the holder’s relationship with a public mental health facility or program expires.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not be issued to a person who has been adjudged unqualified or guilty of any of the prohibited acts in this chapter.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may take disciplinary action against a certificateholder for noncompliance with any part of this section or for any reason for which a regular licensee may be subject to discipline.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 11, 26, ch. 86-245; s. 20, ch. 88-1; s. 22, ch. 89-162; s. 10, ch. 89-374; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 204, ch. 97-103; s. 150, ch. 97-237; s. 26, ch. 97-273; s. 221, ch. 99-8; s. 97, ch. 99-397; s. 72, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>