<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0458.313" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure by endorsement; requirements; fees.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who, upon applying to the department on forms furnished by the department and remitting a fee set by the board not to exceed $500, the board certifies:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has met the qualifications for licensure in s. 458.311(1)(b)-(g) or in s. 458.311(1)(b)-(e) and (g) and (3);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to January 1, 2000, has obtained a passing score, as established by rule of the board, on the licensure examination of the Federation of State Medical Boards of the United States, Inc. (FLEX), on the United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE), or on the examination of the National Board of Medical Examiners, or on a combination thereof, and on or after January 1, 2000, has obtained a passing score on the United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE); and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has submitted evidence of the active licensed practice of medicine in another jurisdiction, for at least 2 of the immediately preceding 4 years, or evidence of successful completion of either a board-approved postgraduate training program within 2 years preceding filing of an application or a board-approved clinical competency examination within the year preceding the filing of an application for licensure. For purposes of this paragraph, “active licensed practice of medicine” means that practice of medicine by physicians, including those employed by any governmental entity in community or public health, as defined by this chapter, medical directors under s. 641.495(11) who are practicing medicine, and those on the active teaching faculty of an accredited medical school.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may require an applicant for licensure by endorsement to take and pass the appropriate licensure examination prior to certifying the applicant as eligible for licensure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department and the board shall ensure that applicants for licensure by endorsement meet applicable criteria in this chapter through an investigative process. When the investigative process is not completed within the time set out in s. 120.60(1) and the department or board has reason to believe that the applicant does not meet the criteria, the State Surgeon General or the State Surgeon General’s designee may issue a 90-day licensure delay which shall be in writing and sufficient to notify the applicant of the reason for the delay. The provisions of this subsection shall control over any conflicting provisions of s. 120.60(1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The board may promulgate rules and regulations, to be applied on a uniform and consistent basis, which may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon certification by the board, the department shall impose conditions, limitations, or restrictions on a license by endorsement if the applicant is on probation in another jurisdiction for an act which would constitute a violation of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who is under investigation in any jurisdiction for an act or offense which would constitute a violation of this chapter until such time as the investigation is complete, at which time the provisions of s. 458.331 shall apply. Furthermore, the department may not issue an unrestricted license to any individual who has committed any act or offense in any jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining a physician pursuant to s. 458.331. When the board finds that an individual has committed an act or offense in any jurisdiction which would constitute the basis for disciplining a physician pursuant to s. 458.331, the board may enter an order imposing one or more of the terms set forth in subsection (7).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the board determines that any applicant for licensure by endorsement has failed to meet, to the board’s satisfaction, each of the appropriate requirements set forth in this section, it may enter an order requiring one or more of the following terms:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal to certify to the department an application for licensure, certification, or registration;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification to the department of an application for licensure, certification, or registration with restrictions on the scope of practice of the licensee; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Certification to the department of an application for licensure, certification, or registration with placement of the physician on probation for a period of time and subject to such conditions as the board may specify, including, but not limited to, requiring the physician to submit to treatment, attend continuing education courses, submit to reexamination, or work under the supervision of another physician.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 1, 8, ch. 79-302; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; s. 5, ch. 84-543; s. 5, ch. 84-553; ss. 1, 3, ch. 85-56; ss. 7, 25, 26, ch. 86-245; ss. 1, 4, ch. 87-296; s. 18, ch. 88-1; s. 7, ch. 88-277; s. 14, ch. 88-392; s. 19, ch. 89-162; s. 6, ch. 89-374; s. 1, ch. 90-52; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 78, ch. 92-149; s. 216, ch. 96-410; s. 1087, ch. 97-103; s. 134, ch. 97-237; s. 19, ch. 97-264; s. 10, ch. 97-273; s. 95, ch. 99-397; s. 70, ch. 2008-6.</History></Section>