<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0538.31" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions; applicability.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this part, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Department” means the Department of Revenue.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Jewelry” means a personal ornament that contains precious metals and may contain gemstones.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Mail-in secondhand precious metals dealer” means any person or entity that:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducts business within this state and that contracts with other persons or entities to buy precious metals or jewelry through an Internet website, the United States mail, or telemarketing; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Conducts business within this state and regularly engages in the business of purchasing jewelry or precious metals through the mail or Internet-based transactions.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Precious metals” means any item containing any gold, silver, or platinum, or any combination thereof.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Seller” means any person or entity offering precious metals or jewelry for purchase which belong solely to that person or entity and has absolute authority to sell such goods.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Transaction” includes any event relating to the purchase of secondhand precious metals or jewelry by a mail-in secondhand precious metals dealer.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not apply to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or entity that is available to the public for walk-in business and regulated under part I.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchase, consignment, or trade of secondhand precious metals or jewelry with another mail-in secondhand precious metals dealer or secondhand dealer regulated under part I.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2009-158; s. 3, ch. 2009-162.</History></Section>