<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0538.235" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Method of payment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secondary metals recycler may not enter into any cash transaction:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In excess of $1,000 for the purchase of regulated metals property; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In any amount for the purchase of restricted regulated metals property.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment in excess of $1,000 for the purchase of regulated metals property shall be made by check issued to the seller of the metal and payable to the seller.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment for the purchase of restricted regulated metals property shall be made by check issued to the seller of the metal and payable to the seller or by electronic payment to the seller’s bank account or the seller’s employer’s bank account.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each check shall be mailed by the secondary metals recycler directly to the street address of the seller that is on file with the secondary metals recycler unless otherwise provided in this part. A check may not be mailed to a post office box. Electronic payments shall be transmitted to an account for which the seller is listed as an account holder or an employee or agent of the seller.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each check or electronic payment shall be mailed or transmitted by the secondary metals recycler to the seller within 3 days after the purchase transaction unless otherwise provided in this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The secondary metals recycler may provide a check at the time of the purchase transaction, rather than mailing the check as required in paragraph (a), if the seller is:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An organization, corporation, or association registered with the state as a charitable, philanthropic, religious, fraternal, civic, patriotic, social, or school-sponsored organization or association, or any nonprofit corporation or association;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A law enforcement officer acting in an official capacity;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A trustee in bankruptcy, executor, administrator, or receiver who has presented proof of such status to the secondary metals recycler;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A public official acting under judicial process or authority who has presented proof of such status to the secondary metals recycler;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A sheriff acting under the authority of a court’s writ of execution, or by virtue of any process issued by a court, if proof thereof has been presented to the secondary metals recycler; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manufacturing, industrial, or other commercial vendor that generates regulated materials in the ordinary course of business.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2008-69; s. 6, ch. 2012-179.</History>
</Section>