<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0538.26" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Certain acts and practices prohibited.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for a secondary metals recycler to do or allow any of the following acts:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase regulated metals property, restricted regulated metals property, or ferrous metals before 7 a.m. or after 7 p.m.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase regulated metals property, restricted regulated metals property, or ferrous metals from any seller who presents such property for sale at the registered location of the secondary metals recycler when such property was not transported in a motor vehicle.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase regulated metals property, restricted regulated metals property, or ferrous metals from any location other than a fixed location.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase regulated metals property from a seller who:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Uses a name other than his or her own name or the registered name of the seller’s business;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is younger than 18 years of age; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is visibly or apparently under the influence of drugs or alcohol.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Purchase any restricted regulated metals property listed in paragraph (b) unless the secondary metals recycler obtains reasonable proof that the seller:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Owns such property. Reasonable proof of ownership may include, but is not limited to, a receipt or bill of sale; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is an employee, agent, or contractor of the property’s owner who is authorized to sell the property on behalf of the owner. Reasonable proof of authorization to sell the property includes, but is not limited to, a signed letter on the owner’s letterhead, dated no later than 90 days before the sale, authorizing the seller to sell the property.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purchase of any of the following regulated metals property is subject to the restrictions provided in paragraph (a):</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A manhole cover.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An electric light pole or other utility structure and its fixtures, wires, and hardware that are readily identifiable as connected to the utility structure.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A guard rail.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A street sign, traffic sign, or traffic signal and its fixtures and hardware.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Communication, transmission, distribution, and service wire from a utility, including copper or aluminum bus bars, connectors, grounding plates, or grounding wire.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A funeral marker or funeral vase.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A historical marker.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Railroad equipment, including, but not limited to, a tie plate, signal house, control box, switch plate, E clip, or rail tie junction.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any metal item that is observably marked upon reasonable inspection with any form of the name, initials, or logo of a governmental entity, utility company, cemetery, or railroad.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A copper, aluminum, or aluminum-copper condensing or evaporator coil, including its tubing or rods, from an air-conditioning or heating unit, excluding coils from window air-conditioning or heating units and motor vehicle air-conditioning or heating units.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An aluminum or stainless steel container or bottle designed to hold propane for fueling forklifts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A stainless steel beer keg.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A catalytic converter or any nonferrous part of a catalytic converter unless purchased as part of a motor vehicle.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="14">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Metallic wire that has been burned in whole or in part to remove insulation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="15">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brass or bronze commercial valve or fitting, referred to as a “fire department connection and control valve” or an “FDC valve,” that is commonly used on structures for access to water for the purpose of extinguishing fires.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="16">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brass or bronze commercial potable water backflow preventer valve that is commonly used to prevent backflow of potable water from commercial structures into municipal domestic water service systems.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="17">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A shopping cart.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="18">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brass water meter.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="19">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A storm grate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="20">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A brass sprinkler head used in commercial agriculture.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 89-533; s. 1, ch. 90-192; s. 8, ch. 90-318; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 1, ch. 92-157; s. 6, ch. 2008-69; s. 8, ch. 2012-179.</History>
</Section>