<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0538.23" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Violations and penalties.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraph (b), a secondary metals recycler who knowingly and intentionally:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violates s. 538.20 or s. 538.21;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Engages in a pattern of failing to keep records required by s. 538.19;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violates <Reference Number="1"/>s. 538.26(4); or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violates s. 538.235,</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secondary metals recycler who commits a third or subsequent violation of paragraph (a) commits a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A secondary metals recycler is presumed to know upon receipt of stolen regulated metals property in a purchase transaction that the regulated metals property has been stolen from another if the secondary metals recycler knowingly and intentionally fails to maintain the information required in s. 538.19 and shall, upon conviction of a violation of s. 812.015, be punished as provided in s. 812.014(2) or (3).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly gives false verification of ownership or who gives a false or altered identification and who receives money or other consideration from a secondary metals recycler in return for regulated metals property commits:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the value of the money or other consideration received is less than $300.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084, if the value of the money or other consideration received is $300 or more.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a lawful owner recovers stolen regulated metals property from a secondary metals recycler who has complied with this part, and the person who sold the regulated metals property to the secondary metals recycler is convicted of theft, a violation of this section, or dealing in stolen property, the court shall order the defendant to make full restitution, including, without limitation, attorneys’ fees, court costs, and other expenses to the secondary metals recycler pursuant to s. 775.089.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person acting as a secondary metals recycler who is not registered with the department under s. 538.25 commits a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 89-533; s. 1, ch. 90-192; s. 4, ch. 91-429; ss. 3, 4, ch. 92-79; s. 2, ch. 92-157; s. 4, ch. 93-37; s. 10, ch. 95-184; s. 3, ch. 2008-69; s. 10, ch. 2012-179; s. 1, ch. 2012-185.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Redesignated as s. 538.26(2) by s. 8, ch. 2012-179.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>