<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0538.11" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Powers and duties of department; rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The same duties and privileges imposed by chapter 212 upon dealers of tangible personal property respecting the keeping of books and records and accounts and compliance with rules of the department shall apply to and be binding upon all persons who are subject to the provisions of this chapter. The department shall administer, collect, and enforce the registration authorized under this chapter pursuant to the same procedures used in the administration, collection, and enforcement of the general state sales tax imposed under chapter 212, except as provided in this section. The provisions of chapter 212 regarding the keeping of records and books shall apply. The department is authorized to employ persons and incur other expenses for which funds are appropriated by the Legislature. The department is empowered to adopt such rules, and shall prescribe and publish such forms, as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this chapter. The Legislature hereby finds that the failure to promptly implement the provisions of this chapter would present an immediate threat to the welfare of the state. Therefore, the executive director of the department is hereby authorized to adopt emergency rules pursuant to s. 120.54(4), for purposes of implementing this chapter. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, such emergency rules shall remain effective for 6 months from the date of adoption. Other rules of the department related to and in furtherance of the orderly implementation of the chapter shall not be subject to a rule challenge under s. 120.56(2) or a drawout proceeding under s. 120.54(3)(c)2. but, once adopted, shall be subject to an invalidity challenge under s. 120.56(3). Such rules shall be adopted by the Governor and Cabinet and shall become effective upon filing with the Department of State, notwithstanding the provisions of s. 120.54(3)(e)6.</Text></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 89-533; s. 1, ch. 90-192; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 247, ch. 96-410; s. 35, ch. 97-99; s. 25, ch. 2001-63.</History></Section>