<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.977" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Enrollment.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall automatically enroll into a managed care plan those Medicaid recipients who do not voluntarily choose a plan pursuant to s. 409.969. The agency shall automatically enroll recipients in plans that meet or exceed the performance or quality standards established pursuant to s. 409.967 and may not automatically enroll recipients in a plan that is deficient in those performance or quality standards. When a specialty plan is available to accommodate a specific condition or diagnosis of a recipient, the agency shall assign the recipient to that plan. In the first year of the first contract term only, if a recipient was previously enrolled in a plan that is still available in the region, the agency shall automatically enroll the recipient in that plan unless an applicable specialty plan is available. Except as otherwise provided in this part, the agency may not engage in practices that are designed to favor one managed care plan over another.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When automatically enrolling recipients in managed care plans, the agency shall automatically enroll based on the following criteria:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the plan has sufficient network capacity to meet the needs of the recipients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether the recipient has previously received services from one of the plan’s primary care providers.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whether primary care providers in one plan are more geographically accessible to the recipient’s residence than those in other plans.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A newborn of a mother enrolled in a plan at the time of the child’s birth shall be enrolled in the mother’s plan. Upon birth, such a newborn is deemed enrolled in the managed care plan, regardless of the administrative enrollment procedures, and the managed care plan is responsible for providing Medicaid services to the newborn. The mother may choose another plan for the newborn within 90 days after the child’s birth.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall develop a process to enable a recipient with access to employer-sponsored health care coverage to opt out of all managed care plans and to use Medicaid financial assistance to pay for the recipient’s share of the cost in such employer-sponsored coverage. Contingent upon federal approval, the agency shall also enable recipients with access to other insurance or related products providing access to health care services created pursuant to state law, including any product available under the Florida Health Choices Program, or any health exchange, to opt out. The amount of financial assistance provided for each recipient may not exceed the amount of the Medicaid premium that would have been paid to a managed care plan for that recipient. The agency shall seek federal approval to require Medicaid recipients with access to employer-sponsored health care coverage to enroll in that coverage and use Medicaid financial assistance to pay for the recipient’s share of the cost for such coverage. The amount of financial assistance provided for each recipient may not exceed the amount of the Medicaid premium that would have been paid to a managed care plan for that recipient.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2011-134.</History>
</Section>