<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.9102" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">A qualified state Long-Term Care Insurance Partnership Program in Florida.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration, in consultation with the Office of Insurance Regulation and the Department of Children and Family Services, is directed to establish a qualified state Long-Term Care Insurance Partnership Program in Florida, in compliance with the requirements of s. 1917(b) of the Social Security Act, as amended.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide incentives for an individual to obtain or maintain insurance to cover the cost of long-term care.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide a mechanism to qualify for coverage of the costs of long-term care needs under Medicaid without first being required to substantially exhaust his or her assets, including a provision for the disregard of any assets in an amount equal to the insurance benefit payments that are made to or on behalf of an individual who is a beneficiary under the program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Alleviate the financial burden on the state’s medical assistance program by encouraging the pursuit of private initiatives.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration, in consultation with the Office of Insurance Regulation and the Department of Children and Family Services, and in accordance with federal guidelines, shall create standards for long-term care partnership program information distributed to individuals through insurance companies offering approved long-term care partnership program policies.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration is authorized to amend the Medicaid state plan and adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services, when determining eligibility for Medicaid long-term care services for an individual who is the beneficiary of an approved long-term care partnership program policy, shall reduce the total countable assets of the individual by an amount equal to the insurance benefit payments that are made to or on behalf of the individual. The department is authorized to adopt rules pursuant to ss. 120.536(1) and 120.54 to implement this subsection.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 2005-252; ss. 1, 3, ch. 2006-254.</History></Section>