<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.91213" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Quarterly progress reports and annual reports.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall submit to the Governor, the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the Senate, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the Office of Program Policy Analysis and Government Accountability the following reports:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The quarterly progress report submitted to the United States Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services no later than 60 days following the end of each quarter. The intent of this report is to present the agency’s analysis and the status of various operational areas. The quarterly progress report must include, but need not be limited to:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Events occurring during the quarter or anticipated to occur in the near future which affect health care delivery, including, but not limited to, the approval of and contracts for new plans, which report must specify the coverage area, phase-in period, populations served, and benefits; the enrollment; grievances; and other operational issues.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Action plans for addressing any policy and administrative issues.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agency efforts related to collecting and verifying encounter data and utilization data.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollment data disaggregated by plan and by eligibility category, such as Temporary Assistance for Needy Families or Supplemental Security Income; the total number of enrollees; market share; and the percentage change in enrollment by plan. In addition, the agency shall provide a summary of voluntary and mandatory selection rates and disenrollment data.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of monitoring budget neutrality, enrollment data, member-month data, and expenditures in the format for monitoring budget neutrality which is provided by the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Activities and associated expenditures of the low-income pool.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Activities related to the implementation of choice counseling, including efforts to improve health literacy and the methods used to obtain public input, such as recipient focus groups.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Participation rates in the enhanced benefit accounts program, including participation levels; a summary of activities and associated expenditures; the number of accounts established, including active participants and individuals who continue to retain access to funds in an account but who no longer actively participate; an estimate of quarterly deposits in the accounts; and expenditures from the accounts.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollment data concerning employer-sponsored insurance which document the number of individuals selecting to opt out when employer-sponsored insurance is available. The agency shall include data that identify enrollee characteristics, including the eligibility category, type of employer-sponsored insurance, and type of coverage, such as individual or family coverage. The agency shall develop and maintain disenrollment reports specifying the reason for disenrollment in an employer-sponsored insurance program. The agency shall also track and report on those enrollees who elect the option to reenroll in the Medicaid reform demonstration.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Progress toward meeting the demonstration goals.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Evaluation activities.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An annual report documenting accomplishments, project status, quantitative and case-study findings, utilization data, and policy and administrative difficulties in the operation of the Medicaid waiver demonstration program. The agency shall submit the draft annual report no later than October 1 after the end of each fiscal year.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with the annual report for demonstration year two, the agency shall include a section concerning the administration of enhanced benefit accounts, the participation rates, an assessment of expenditures, and an assessment of potential cost savings.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning with the annual report for demonstration year four, the agency shall include a section that provides qualitative and quantitative data describing the impact the low-income pool has had on the rate of uninsured people in this state, beginning with the implementation of the demonstration program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 2005-358.</History></Section>