<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.8177" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Program evaluation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, in consultation with the Department of Health, the Department of Children and Family Services, and the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation, shall contract for an evaluation of the Florida Kidcare program and shall by January 1 of each year submit to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a report of the program. In addition to the items specified under s. 2108 of Title XXI of the Social Security Act, the report shall include an assessment of crowd-out and access to health care, as well as the following:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the operation of the program, including the progress made in reducing the number of uncovered low-income children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the effectiveness in increasing the number of children with creditable health coverage, including an assessment of the impact of outreach.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The characteristics of the children and families assisted under the program, including ages of the children, family income, and access to or coverage by other health insurance prior to the program and after disenrollment from the program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The quality of health coverage provided, including the types of benefits provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount and level, including payment of part or all of any premium, of assistance provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average length of coverage of a child under the program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program’s choice of health benefits coverage and other methods used for providing child health assistance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The sources of nonfederal funding used in the program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An assessment of the effectiveness of the Florida Kidcare program, including Medicaid, the Florida Healthy Kids program, Medikids, and the Children’s Medical Services network, and other public and private programs in the state in increasing the availability of affordable quality health insurance and health care for children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A review and assessment of state activities to coordinate the program with other public and private programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An analysis of changes and trends in the state that affect the provision of health insurance and health care to children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A description of any plans the state has for improving the availability of health insurance and health care for children.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="m"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Recommendations for improving the program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="n"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Other studies as necessary.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall submit each month to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a report of enrollment for each program component of the Florida Kidcare program.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 44, 57, ch. 98-288; s. 6, ch. 2000-253; s. 14, ch. 2002-400; s. 22, ch. 2003-405; s. 11, ch. 2009-113.</History></Section>