<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.967" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Managed care plan accountability.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall establish a 5-year contract with each managed care plan selected through the procurement process described in s. 409.966. A plan contract may not be renewed; however, the agency may extend the term of a plan contract to cover any delays during the transition to a new plan.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall establish such contract requirements as are necessary for the operation of the statewide managed care program. In addition to any other provisions the agency may deem necessary, the contract must require:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Physician compensation.</Font><EmDash />Managed care plans are expected to coordinate care, manage chronic disease, and prevent the need for more costly services. Effective care management should enable plans to redirect available resources and increase compensation for physicians. Plans achieve this performance standard when physician payment rates equal or exceed Medicare rates for similar services. The agency may impose fines or other sanctions on a plan that fails to meet this performance standard after 2 years of continuous operation.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Emergency services.</Font><EmDash />Managed care plans shall pay for services required by ss. 395.1041 and 401.45 and rendered by a noncontracted provider. The plans must comply with s. 641.3155. Reimbursement for services under this paragraph is the lesser of:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provider’s charges;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The usual and customary provider charges for similar services in the community where the services were provided;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The charge mutually agreed to by the entity and the provider within 60 days after submittal of the claim; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rate the agency would have paid on the most recent October 1st.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Access.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall establish specific standards for the number, type, and regional distribution of providers in managed care plan networks to ensure access to care for both adults and children. Each plan must maintain a regionwide network of providers in sufficient numbers to meet the access standards for specific medical services for all recipients enrolled in the plan. The exclusive use of mail-order pharmacies may not be sufficient to meet network access standards. Consistent with the standards established by the agency, provider networks may include providers located outside the region. A plan may contract with a new hospital facility before the date the hospital becomes operational if the hospital has commenced construction, will be licensed and operational by January 1, 2013, and a final order has issued in any civil or administrative challenge. Each plan shall establish and maintain an accurate and complete electronic database of contracted providers, including information about licensure or registration, locations and hours of operation, specialty credentials and other certifications, specific performance indicators, and such other information as the agency deems necessary. The database must be available online to both the agency and the public and have the capability to compare the availability of providers to network adequacy standards and to accept and display feedback from each provider’s patients. Each plan shall submit quarterly reports to the agency identifying the number of enrollees assigned to each primary care provider.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each managed care plan must publish any prescribed drug formulary or preferred drug list on the plan’s website in a manner that is accessible to and searchable by enrollees and providers. The plan must update the list within 24 hours after making a change. Each plan must ensure that the prior authorization process for prescribed drugs is readily accessible to health care providers, including posting appropriate contact information on its website and providing timely responses to providers. For Medicaid recipients diagnosed with hemophilia who have been prescribed anti-hemophilic-factor replacement products, the agency shall provide for those products and hemophilia overlay services through the agency’s hemophilia disease management program.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Managed care plans, and their fiscal agents or intermediaries, must accept prior authorization requests for any service electronically.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Encounter data.</Font><EmDash />The agency shall maintain and operate a Medicaid Encounter Data System to collect, process, store, and report on covered services provided to all Medicaid recipients enrolled in prepaid plans.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each prepaid plan must comply with the agency’s reporting requirements for the Medicaid Encounter Data System. Prepaid plans must submit encounter data electronically in a format that complies with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act provisions for electronic claims and in accordance with deadlines established by the agency. Prepaid plans must certify that the data reported is accurate and complete.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency is responsible for validating the data submitted by the plans. The agency shall develop methods and protocols for ongoing analysis of the encounter data that adjusts for differences in characteristics of prepaid plan enrollees to allow comparison of service utilization among plans and against expected levels of use. The analysis shall be used to identify possible cases of systemic underutilization or denials of claims and inappropriate service utilization such as higher-than-expected emergency department encounters. The analysis shall provide periodic feedback to the plans and enable the agency to establish corrective action plans when necessary. One of the focus areas for the analysis shall be the use of prescription drugs.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall make encounter data available to those plans accepting enrollees who are assigned to them from other plans leaving a region.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Continuous improvement.</Font><EmDash />The agency shall establish specific performance standards and expected milestones or timelines for improving performance over the term of the contract.</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each managed care plan shall establish an internal health care quality improvement system, including enrollee satisfaction and disenrollment surveys. The quality improvement system must include incentives and disincentives for network providers.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each plan must collect and report the Health Plan Employer Data and Information Set (HEDIS) measures, as specified by the agency. These measures must be published on the plan’s website in a manner that allows recipients to reliably compare the performance of plans. The agency shall use the HEDIS measures as a tool to monitor plan performance.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each managed care plan must be accredited by the National Committee for Quality Assurance, the Joint Commission, or another nationally recognized accrediting body, or have initiated the accreditation process, within 1 year after the contract is executed. For any plan not accredited within 18 months after executing the contract, the agency shall suspend automatic assignment under s. 409.977 and 409.984.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By the end of the fourth year of the first contract term, the agency shall issue a request for information to determine whether cost savings could be achieved by contracting for plan oversight and monitoring, including analysis of encounter data, assessment of performance measures, and compliance with other contractual requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Program integrity.</Font><EmDash />Each managed care plan shall establish program integrity functions and activities to reduce the incidence of fraud and abuse, including, at a minimum:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provider credentialing system and ongoing provider monitoring, including maintenance of written provider credentialing policies and procedures which comply with federal and agency guidelines;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An effective prepayment and postpayment review process including, but not limited to, data analysis, system editing, and auditing of network providers;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures for reporting instances of fraud and abuse pursuant to chapter 641;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrative and management arrangements or procedures, including a mandatory compliance plan, designed to prevent fraud and abuse; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designation of a program integrity compliance officer.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Grievance resolution.</Font><EmDash />Consistent with federal law, each managed care plan shall establish and the agency shall approve an internal process for reviewing and responding to grievances from enrollees. Each plan shall submit quarterly reports on the number, description, and outcome of grievances filed by enrollees.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Penalties.</Font><EmDash /></Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Withdrawal and enrollment reduction.<EmDash />Managed care plans that reduce enrollment levels or leave a region before the end of the contract term must reimburse the agency for the cost of enrollment changes and other transition activities. If more than one plan leaves a region at the same time, costs must be shared by the departing plans proportionate to their enrollments. In addition to the payment of costs, departing provider services networks must pay a per-enrollee penalty of up to 3 months’ payment and continue to provide services to the enrollee for 90 days or until the enrollee is enrolled in another plan, whichever occurs first. In addition to payment of costs, all other departing plans must pay a penalty of 25 percent of that portion of the minimum surplus maintained pursuant to s. 641.225(1) which is attributable to the provision of coverage to Medicaid enrollees. Plans shall provide at least 180 days’ notice to the agency before withdrawing from a region. If a managed care plan leaves a region before the end of the contract term, the agency shall terminate all contracts with that plan in other regions pursuant to the termination procedures in subparagraph 3.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Encounter data.<EmDash />If a plan fails to comply with the encounter data reporting requirements of this section for 30 days, the agency must assess a fine of $5,000 per day for each day of noncompliance beginning on the 31st day. On the 31st day, the agency must notify the plan that the agency will initiate contract termination procedures on the 90th day unless the plan comes into compliance before that date.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Termination.<EmDash />If the agency terminates more than one regional contract with the same managed care plan due to noncompliance with the requirements of this section, the agency shall terminate all the regional contracts held by that plan. When terminating multiple contracts, the agency must develop a plan to provide for the transition of enrollees to other plans, and phase in the terminations over a time period sufficient to ensure a smooth transition.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Prompt payment.</Font><EmDash />Managed care plans shall comply with ss. 641.315, 641.3155, and 641.513.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Electronic claims.</Font><EmDash />Managed care plans, and their fiscal agents or intermediaries, shall accept electronic claims in compliance with federal standards.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Fair payment.</Font><EmDash />Provider service networks must ensure that no entity licensed under chapter 395 with a controlling interest in the network charges a Medicaid managed care plan more than the amount paid to that provider by the provider service network for the same service.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Itemized payment.</Font><EmDash />Any claims payment to a provider by a managed care plan, or by a fiscal agent or intermediary of the plan, must be accompanied by an itemized accounting of the individual claims included in the payment including, but not limited to, the enrollee’s name, the date of service, the procedure code, the amount of reimbursement, and the identification of the plan on whose behalf the payment is made.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Italic">Provider dispute resolution.</Font><EmDash />Disputes between a plan and a provider may be resolved as described in s. 408.7057.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ACHIEVED SAVINGS REBATE.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency is responsible for verifying the achieved savings rebate for all Medicaid prepaid plans. To assist the agency, a prepaid plan shall:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit an annual financial audit conducted by an independent certified public accountant in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards to the agency on or before June 1 for the preceding year; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Submit an annual statement prepared in accordance with statutory accounting principles on or before March 1 pursuant to s. 624.424 if the plan is regulated by the Office of Insurance Regulation.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall contract with independent certified public accountants to conduct compliance audits for the purpose of auditing financial information, including but not limited to: annual premium revenue, medical and administrative costs, and income or losses reported by each prepaid plan, in order to determine and validate the achieved savings rebate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any audit required under this subsection must be conducted by an independent certified public accountant who meets criteria specified by rule. The rules must also provide that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The entity selected by the agency to conduct the audit may not have a conflict of interest that might affect its ability to perform its responsibilities with respect to an examination.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rates charged to the prepaid plan being audited are consistent with rates charged by other certified public accountants and are comparable with the rates charged for comparable examinations.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each prepaid plan audited shall pay to the agency the expenses of the audit at the rates established by the agency by rule. Such expenses include actual travel expenses, reasonable living expense allowances, compensation of the certified public accountant, and necessary attendant administrative costs of the agency directly related to the examination. Travel expense and living expense allowances are limited to those expenses incurred on account of the audit and must be paid by the examined prepaid plan together with compensation upon presentation by the agency to the prepaid plan of a detailed account of the charges and expenses after a detailed statement has been filed by the auditor and approved by the agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All moneys collected from prepaid plans for such audits shall be deposited into the Grants and Donations Trust Fund, and the agency may make deposits into such fund from moneys appropriated for the operation of the agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At a location in this state, the prepaid plan shall make available to the agency and the agency’s contracted certified public accountant all books, accounts, documents, files, and information that relate to the prepaid plan’s Medicaid transactions. Records not in the prepaid plan’s immediate possession must be made available to the agency or the certified public accountant in this state within 3 days after a request is made by the agency or certified public accountant engaged by the agency. A prepaid plan has an obligation to cooperate in good faith with the agency and the certified public accountant. Failure to comply to such record requests shall be deemed a breach of contract. </Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Once the certified public accountant completes the audit, the certified public accountant shall submit an audit report to the agency attesting to the achieved savings of the plan. The results of the audit report are dispositive.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Achieved savings rebates validated by the certified public accountant are due within 30 days after the report is submitted. Except as provided in paragraph (h), the achieved savings rebate is established by determining pretax income as a percentage of revenues and applying the following income sharing ratios:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred percent of income up to and including 5 percent of revenue shall be retained by the plan.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Fifty percent of income above 5 percent and up to 10 percent shall be retained by the plan, and the other 50 percent refunded to the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">One hundred percent of income above 10 percent of revenue shall be refunded to the state.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A plan that exceeds agency-defined quality measures in the reporting period may retain an additional 1 percent of revenue. For the purpose of this paragraph, the quality measures must include plan performance for preventing or managing complex, chronic conditions that are associated with an elevated likelihood of requiring high-cost medical treatments.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following may not be included as allowable expenses in calculating income for determining the achieved savings rebate:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payment of achieved savings rebates.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any financial incentive payments made to the plan outside of the capitation rate.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any financial disincentive payments levied by the state or federal government.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Expenses associated with any lobbying or political activities.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The cash value or equivalent cash value of bonuses of any type paid or awarded to the plan’s executive staff, other than base salary.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Reserves and reserve accounts.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Administrative costs, including, but not limited to, reinsurance expenses, interest payments, depreciation expenses, bad debt expenses, and outstanding claims expenses in excess of actuarially sound maximum amounts set by the agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The agency shall consider these and other factors in developing contracts that establish shared savings arrangements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepaid plans that incur a loss in the first contract year may apply the full amount of the loss as an offset to income in the second contract year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If, after an audit, the agency determines that a prepaid plan owes an additional rebate, the plan has 30 days after notification to make the payment. Upon failure to timely pay the rebate, the agency shall withhold future payments to the plan until the entire amount is recouped. If the agency determines that a prepaid plan has made an overpayment, the agency shall return the overpayment within 30 days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEDICAL LOSS RATIO.<EmDash />If required as a condition of a waiver, the agency may calculate a medical loss ratio for managed care plans. The calculation shall use uniform financial data collected from all plans and shall be computed for each plan on a statewide basis. The method for calculating the medical loss ratio shall meet the following criteria:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except as provided in paragraphs (b) and (c), expenditures shall be classified in a manner consistent with 45 C.F.R. part 158.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds provided by plans to graduate medical education institutions to underwrite the costs of residency positions shall be classified as medical expenditures, provided the funding is sufficient to sustain the positions for the number of years necessary to complete the residency requirements and the residency positions funded by the plans are active providers of care to Medicaid and uninsured patients.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to final determination of the medical loss ratio for any period, a plan may contribute to a designated state trust fund for the purpose of supporting Medicaid and indigent care and have the contribution counted as a medical expenditure for the period.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 2011-134; s. 7, ch. 2012-44.</History>
</Section>