<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.821" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Florida Kidcare program public records exemption.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Personal identifying information of a Florida Kidcare program applicant or enrollee, as defined in s. 409.811, held by the Agency for Health Care Administration, the Department of Children and Family Services, the Department of Health, or the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation is confidential and exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon request, such information shall be disclosed to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Another governmental entity in the performance of its official duties and responsibilities;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue for purposes of administering the state Title IV-D program;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Health Choices, Inc., for the purpose of administering the program authorized pursuant to s. 408.910; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who has the written consent of the program applicant.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This section does not prohibit an enrollee’s legal guardian from obtaining confirmation of coverage, dates of coverage, the name of the enrollee’s health plan, and the amount of premium being paid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption applies to any information identifying a Florida Kidcare program applicant or enrollee held by the Agency for Health Care Administration, the Department of Children and Family Services, the Department of Health, or the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation before, on, or after the effective date of this exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A knowing and willful violation of this section is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 98-119; s. 56, ch. 2000-153; ss. 1, 2, ch. 2003-104; s. 35, ch. 2005-39; s. 11, ch. 2005-82; ss. 1, 2, ch. 2008-146; s. 5, ch. 2011-195.</History>
</Section>