<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.175" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Licensure of family foster homes, residential child-caring agencies, and child-placing agencies; public records exemption.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The purpose of this section is to protect the health, safety, and well-being of all children in the state who are cared for by family foster homes, residential child-caring agencies, and child-placing agencies by providing for the establishment of licensing requirements for such homes and agencies and providing procedures to determine adherence to these requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nothing in this section gives any governmental agency jurisdiction or authority to regulate, control, or supervise the form, manner, or content of any religious curriculum or teachings of a family foster home or of a child-caring or child-placing agency, provided the health, safety, or well-being of the child is not adversely affected.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Agency” means a residential child-caring agency or a child-placing agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Boarding school” means a school which is accredited by the Florida Council of Independent Schools or the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools; which is accredited by the Council on Accreditation, the Commission on Accreditation of Rehabilitation Facilities, or the Coalition for Residential Education; and which is registered with the Department of Education as a school. Its program must follow established school schedules, with holiday breaks and summer recesses in accordance with other public and private school programs. The children in residence must customarily return to their family homes or legal guardians during school breaks and must not be in residence year-round, except that this provision does not apply to foreign students. The parents of these children retain custody and planning and financial responsibility. A boarding school currently in existence and a boarding school opening and seeking accreditation have 3 years to comply with the requirements of this paragraph. A boarding school must provide proof of accreditation or documentation of the accreditation process upon request. A boarding school that cannot produce the required documentation or that has not registered with the Department of Education shall be considered to be providing residential group care without a license. The department may impose administrative sanctions or seek civil remedies as provided under paragraph (11)(a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child” means any unmarried person under the age of 18 years.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Child-placing agency” means any person, corporation, or agency, public or private, other than the parent or legal guardian of the child or an intermediary acting pursuant to chapter 63, that receives a child for placement and places or arranges for the placement of a child in a family foster home, residential child-caring agency, or adoptive home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Family foster home” means a private residence in which children who are unattended by a parent or legal guardian are provided 24-hour care. Such homes include emergency shelter family homes and specialized foster homes for children with special needs. A person who cares for a child of a friend for a period not to exceed 90 days, a relative who cares for a child and does not receive reimbursement for such care from the state or federal government, or an adoptive home which has been approved by the department or by a licensed child-placing agency for children placed for adoption is not considered a family foster home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means “license” as defined in s. 120.52(10). A license under this section is issued to a family foster home or other facility and is not a professional license of any individual. Receipt of a license under this section shall not create a property right in the recipient. A license under this act is a public trust and a privilege, and is not an entitlement. This privilege must guide the finder of fact or trier of law at any administrative proceeding or court action initiated by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Operator” means any onsite person ultimately responsible for the overall operation of a child-placing agency, family foster home, or residential child-caring agency, whether or not she or he is the owner or administrator of such an agency or home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Owner” means the person who is licensed to operate the child-placing agency, family foster home, or residential child-caring agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Personnel” means all owners, operators, employees, and volunteers working in a child-placing agency, family foster home, or residential child-caring agency who may be employed by or do volunteer work for a person, corporation, or agency that holds a license as a child-placing agency or a residential child-caring agency, but the term does not include those who do not work on the premises where child care is furnished and have no direct contact with a child or have no contact with a child outside of the presence of the child’s parent or guardian. For purposes of screening, the term includes any member, over the age of 12 years, of the family of the owner or operator or any person other than a client, over the age of 12 years, residing with the owner or operator if the agency or family foster home is located in or adjacent to the home of the owner or operator or if the family member of, or person residing with, the owner or operator has any direct contact with the children. Members of the family of the owner or operator, or persons residing with the owner or operator, who are between the ages of 12 years and 18 years are not required to be fingerprinted, but must be screened for delinquency records. For purposes of screening, the term also includes owners, operators, employees, and volunteers working in summer day camps, or summer 24-hour camps providing care for children. A volunteer who assists on an intermittent basis for less than 10 hours per month shall not be included in the term “personnel” for the purposes of screening if a person who meets the screening requirement of this section is always present and has the volunteer in his or her line of sight.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Residential child-caring agency” means any person, corporation, or agency, public or private, other than the child’s parent or legal guardian, that provides staffed 24-hour care for children in facilities maintained for that purpose, regardless of whether operated for profit or whether a fee is charged. Such residential child-caring agencies include, but are not limited to, maternity homes, runaway shelters, group homes that are administered by an agency, emergency shelters that are not in private residences, and wilderness camps. Residential child-caring agencies do not include hospitals, boarding schools, summer or recreation camps, nursing homes, or facilities operated by a governmental agency for the training, treatment, or secure care of delinquent youth, or facilities licensed under s. 393.067 or s. 394.875 or chapter 397.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Screening” means the act of assessing the background of personnel and includes, but is not limited to, employment history checks as provided in chapter 435, using the level 2 standards for screening set forth in that chapter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="l">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Summer day camp” means recreational, educational, and other enrichment programs operated during summer vacations for children who are 5 years of age on or before September 1 and older.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="m">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Summer 24-hour camp” means recreational, educational, and other enrichment programs operated on a 24-hour basis during summer vacation for children who are 5 years of age on or before September 1 and older, that are not exclusively educational.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The total number of children placed in each family foster home shall be based on the recommendation of the department, or the community-based care lead agency where one is providing foster care and related services, based on the needs of each child in care, the ability of the foster family to meet the individual needs of each child, including any adoptive or biological children living in the home, the amount of safe physical plant space, the ratio of active and appropriate adult supervision, and the background, experience, and skill of the family foster parents.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the total number of children in a family foster home will exceed five, including the family’s own children, an assessment of each child to be placed in the home must be completed by a family services counselor and approved in writing by the counselor’s supervisor prior to placement of any additional children in the home, except that, if the placement involves a child whose sibling is already in the home or a child who has been in placement in the home previously, the assessment must be completed within 72 hours after placement. The assessment must assess and document the mental, physical, and psychosocial needs of the child and recommend the maximum number of children in a family foster home that will allow the child’s needs to be met.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For any licensed family foster home, the appropriateness of the number of children in the home must be reassessed annually as part of the relicensure process. For a home with more than five children, if it is determined by the licensure study at the time of relicensure that the total number of children in the home is appropriate and that there have been no substantive licensure violations and no indications of child maltreatment or child-on-child sexual abuse within the past 12 months, the relicensure of the home shall not be denied based on the total number of children in the home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person, family foster home, or residential child-caring agency may not provide continuing full-time child care or custody unless such person, home, or agency has first procured a license from the department to provide such care. This requirement does not apply to a person who is a relative of the child by blood, marriage, or adoption, a permanent guardian established under s. 39.6221, a licensed child-placing agency, or an intermediary for the purposes of adoption pursuant to chapter 63.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person or agency, other than a parent or legal guardian of the child or an intermediary as defined in s. 63.032, shall not place or arrange for the placement of a child in a family foster home, residential child-caring agency, or adoptive home unless such person or agency has first procured a license from the department to do so.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A state, county, city, or political subdivision shall not operate a residential group care agency, or receive children for placement in residential group care facilities, family foster homes, or adoptive homes without a license issued pursuant to this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This license requirement does not apply to boarding schools, recreation and summer camps, nursing homes, hospitals, or to persons who care for children of friends or neighbors in their homes for periods not to exceed 90 days or to persons who have received a child for adoption from a licensed child-placing agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department or licensed child-placing agency may place a 16-year-old child or 17-year-old child in her or his own unlicensed residence, or in the unlicensed residence of an adult who has no supervisory responsibility for the child, provided the department or licensed child-placing agency retains supervisory responsibility for the child.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall adopt and amend licensing rules for family foster homes, residential child-caring agencies, and child-placing agencies. The department may also adopt rules relating to the screening requirements for summer day camps and summer 24-hour camps. The requirements for licensure and operation of family foster homes, residential child-caring agencies, and child-placing agencies shall include:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The operation, conduct, and maintenance of these homes and agencies and the responsibility which they assume for children served and the evidence of need for that service.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of food, clothing, educational opportunities, services, equipment, and individual supplies to assure the healthy physical, emotional, and mental development of the children served.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The appropriateness, safety, cleanliness, and general adequacy of the premises, including fire prevention and health standards, to provide for the physical comfort, care, and well-being of the children served.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The ratio of staff to children required to provide adequate care and supervision of the children served and, in the case of foster homes, the maximum number of children in the home.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The good moral character based upon screening, education, training, and experience requirements for personnel.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may grant exemptions from disqualification from working with children or the developmentally disabled as provided in s. 435.07.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision of preservice and inservice training for all foster parents and agency staff.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Satisfactory evidence of financial ability to provide care for the children in compliance with licensing requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="9">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The maintenance by the agency of records pertaining to admission, progress, health, and discharge of children served, including written case plans and reports to the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="10">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provision for parental involvement to encourage preservation and strengthening of a child’s relationship with the family.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="11">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The transportation safety of children served.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="12">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions for safeguarding the cultural, religious, and ethnic values of a child.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="13">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provisions to safeguard the legal rights of children served.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The requirements for the licensure and operation of a child-placing agency shall also include compliance with the requirements of ss. 63.0422 and 790.335.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall randomly drug test a licensed foster parent if there is a reasonable suspicion that he or she is using illegal drugs. The cost of testing shall be paid by the foster parent but shall be reimbursed by the department if the test is negative. The department may adopt rules necessary to administer this paragraph.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In promulgating licensing rules pursuant to this section, the department may make distinctions among types of care; numbers of children served; and the physical, mental, emotional, and educational needs of the children to be served by a home or agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall not adopt rules which interfere with the free exercise of religion or which regulate religious instruction or teachings in any child-caring or child-placing home or agency; however, nothing herein shall be construed to allow religious instruction or teachings that are inconsistent with the health, safety, or well-being of any child; with public morality; or with the religious freedom of children, parents, or legal guardians who place their children in such homes or agencies.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department’s rules shall include adoption of a form to be used by child-placing agencies during an adoption home study that requires all prospective adoptive applicants to acknowledge in writing the receipt of a document containing solely and exclusively the language provided for in s. 790.174 verbatim.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An application for a license shall be made on forms provided, and in the manner prescribed, by the department. The department shall make a determination as to the good moral character of the applicant based upon screening.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application, the department shall conduct a licensing study based on its licensing rules; shall inspect the home or the agency and the records, including financial records, of the agency; and shall interview the applicant. The department may authorize a licensed child-placing agency to conduct the licensing study of a family foster home to be used exclusively by that agency and to verify to the department that the home meets the licensing requirements established by the department. Upon certification by a licensed child-placing agency that a family foster home meets the licensing requirements, the department shall issue the license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed family foster home, child-placing agency, or residential child-caring agency which applies for renewal of its license shall submit to the department a list of personnel who have worked on a continuous basis at the applicant family foster home or agency since submitting fingerprints to the department, identifying those for whom a written assurance of compliance was provided by the department and identifying those personnel who have recently begun working at the family foster home or agency and are awaiting the results of the required fingerprint check, along with the date of the submission of those fingerprints for processing. The department shall by rule determine the frequency of requests to the Department of Law Enforcement to run state criminal records checks for such personnel except for those personnel awaiting the results of initial fingerprint checks for employment at the applicant family foster home or agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may pursue other remedies provided in this section in addition to denial or revocation of a license for failure to comply with the screening requirements. The disciplinary actions determination to be made by the department and the procedure for hearing for applicants and licensees shall be in accordance with chapter 120.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the department has reasonable cause to believe that grounds for denial or termination of employment exist, it shall notify, in writing, the applicant, licensee, or summer or recreation camp, and the personnel affected, stating the specific record which indicates noncompliance with the screening requirements.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Procedures established for hearing under chapter 120 shall be available to the applicant, licensee, summer day camp, or summer 24-hour camp, and affected personnel, in order to present evidence relating either to the accuracy of the basis for exclusion or to the denial of an exemption from disqualification.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Refusal on the part of an applicant to dismiss personnel who have been found not to be in compliance with the requirements for good moral character of personnel shall result in automatic denial or revocation of license in addition to any other remedies provided in this section which may be pursued by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At the request of the department, the local county health department shall inspect a home or agency according to the licensing rules promulgated by the department. Inspection reports shall be furnished to the department within 30 days of the request. Such an inspection shall only be required when called for by the licensing agency.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All residential child-caring agencies must meet firesafety standards for such agencies adopted by the Division of State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services and must be inspected annually. At the request of the department, firesafety inspections shall be conducted by the Division of State Fire Marshal or a local fire department official who has been certified by the division as having completed the training requirements for persons inspecting such agencies. Inspection reports shall be furnished to the department within 30 days of a request.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the licensing process, the licensing staff of the department shall provide consultation on request.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determination that the applicant meets the state minimum licensing requirements, the department shall issue a license without charge to a specific person or agency at a specific location. A license may be issued if all the screening materials have been timely submitted; however, a license may not be issued or renewed if any person at the home or agency has failed the required screening. The license is nontransferable. A copy of the license shall be displayed in a conspicuous place. Except as provided in paragraph (j), the license is valid for 1 year from the date of issuance, unless the license is suspended or revoked by the department or is voluntarily surrendered by the licensee. The license is the property of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A license issued for the operation of a family foster home or agency, unless sooner suspended, revoked, or voluntarily returned, will expire automatically 1 year from the date of issuance except as provided in paragraph (j). Ninety days prior to the expiration date, an application for renewal shall be submitted to the department by a licensee who wishes to have the license renewed. A license shall be renewed upon the filing of an application on forms furnished by the department if the applicant has first met the requirements established under this section and the rules promulgated hereunder.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for a family foster group home having a licensed capacity for more than five children, the department may issue a license that is valid for longer than 1 year but no longer than 3 years to a family foster home that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has maintained a license with the department as a family foster home for at least the 3 previous consecutive years;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Remains in good standing with the department; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Has not been the subject of a report of child abuse or neglect with any findings of maltreatment.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">A family foster home that has been issued a license valid for longer than 1 year must be monitored and visited as frequently as one that has been issued a 1-year license. The department reserves the right to reduce a licensure period to 1 year at any time.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not license summer day camps or summer 24-hour camps. However, the department shall have access to the personnel records of such facilities to ensure compliance with the screening requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a provisional license to an applicant who is unable to conform to the licensing requirements at the time of the study, but who is believed able to meet the licensing requirements within the time allowed by the provisional license. The issuance of a provisional license shall be contingent upon the submission to the department of an acceptable written plan to overcome the deficiency by the expiration date of the provisional license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provisional license may be issued when the applicant fails to meet licensing requirements in matters that are not of immediate danger to the children and the agency has submitted a corrective action plan which is approved by the department. A provisional license may be issued if the screening material has been timely submitted; however, a provisional license may not be issued unless the applicant is in compliance with the requirements in this section for screening of personnel.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A provisional license shall not be issued for a period in excess of 1 year and shall not be subject to renewal; and it may be suspended if periodic inspection by the department indicates that insufficient progress has been made toward compliance with the requirements.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Authorized licensing staff of the department who are qualified by training may make scheduled or unannounced inspections of a licensed home or agency at any reasonable time to investigate and evaluate the compliance of the home or agency with the licensing requirements. All licensed homes and agencies shall be inspected at least annually.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall investigate complaints to determine whether a home or agency is meeting the licensure requirements. The department shall advise the home or agency of the complaint and shall provide a written report of the results of the investigation to the licensee.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke a license.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any of the following actions by a home or agency or its personnel is a ground for denial, suspension, or revocation of a license:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An intentional or negligent act materially affecting the health or safety of children in the home or agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of the provisions of this section or of licensing rules promulgated pursuant to this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Noncompliance with the requirements for good moral character as specified in paragraph (5)(a).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to dismiss personnel found in noncompliance with requirements for good moral character.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure to comply with the requirements of ss. 63.0422 and 790.335.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="10">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may institute injunctive proceedings in a court of competent jurisdiction to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enforce the provisions of this section or any license requirement, rule, or order issued or entered into pursuant thereto; or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminate the operation of an agency in which any of the following conditions exist:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The licensee has failed to take preventive or corrective measures in accordance with any order of the department to maintain conformity with licensing requirements.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is a violation of any of the provisions of this section, or of any licensing requirement promulgated pursuant to this section, which violation threatens harm to any child or which constitutes an emergency requiring immediate action.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Terminate the operation of a summer day camp or summer 24-hour camp providing care for children when such camp has willfully and knowingly refused to comply with the screening requirements for personnel or has refused to terminate the employment of personnel found to be in noncompliance with the requirements for good moral character as determined in paragraph (5)(a).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds, within 30 days after written notification by registered mail of the requirement for licensure, that a person or agency continues to care for or to place children without a license or, within 30 days after written notification by registered mail of the requirement for screening of personnel and compliance with paragraph (5)(a) for the hiring and continued employment of personnel, that a summer day camp or summer 24-hour camp continues to provide care for children without complying, the department shall notify the appropriate state attorney of the violation of law and, if necessary, shall institute a civil suit to enjoin the person or agency from continuing the placement or care of children or to enjoin the summer day camp or summer 24-hour camp from continuing the care of children.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Such injunctive relief may be temporary or permanent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="11">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is authorized to seek compliance with the licensing requirements of this section to the fullest extent possible by reliance on administrative sanctions and civil actions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department determines that a person or agency is caring for a child or is placing a child without a valid license issued by the department or has made a willful or intentional misstatement on any license application or other document required to be filed in connection with an application for a license, the department, as an alternative to or in conjunction with an administrative action against such person or agency, shall make a reasonable attempt to discuss each violation with, and recommend corrective action to, the person or the administrator of the agency, prior to written notification thereof. The department, instead of fixing a period within which the person or agency must enter into compliance with the licensing requirements, may request a plan of corrective action from the person or agency that demonstrates a good faith effort to remedy each violation by a specific date, subject to the approval of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any action taken to correct a violation shall be documented in writing by the person or administrator of the agency and verified through followup visits by licensing personnel of the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person or agency has failed to remedy each violation by the specific date agreed upon with the department, the department shall within 30 days notify the person or agency by certified mail of its intention to refer the violation or violations to the office of the state attorney.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the person or agency fails to come into compliance with the licensing requirements within 30 days of written notification, it is the intent of the Legislature that the department within 30 days refer the violation or violations to the office of the state attorney.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="12">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person or agency to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide continuing full-time care for or to receive or place a child apart from her or his parents in a residential group care facility, family foster home, or adoptive home without a valid license issued by the department if such license is required by subsection (5); or</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make a willful or intentional misstatement on any license application or other document required to be filed in connection with an application for a license.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, agency, summer day camp, or summer 24-hour camp providing care for children to:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Willfully or intentionally fail to comply with the requirements for the screening of personnel or the dismissal of personnel found not to be in compliance with the requirements for good moral character as specified in paragraph (5)(a).</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Use information from the criminal records obtained under this section for any purpose other than screening a person for employment as specified in this section or to release such information to any other person for any purpose other than screening for employment as specified in this section.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person, agency, summer day camp, or summer 24-hour camp providing care for children to use information from the juvenile records of any person obtained under this section for any purpose other than screening for employment as specified in this section or to release information from such records to any other person for any purpose other than screening for employment as specified in this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A first violation of paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) is a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A second or subsequent violation of paragraph (a) or paragraph (b) is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A violation of paragraph (c) is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="13">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds that any violation of this section or the rules promulgated pursuant to this section places the children served by the person or agency in immediate danger, the department may take the resident children into custody and place them in the care of another family foster home or residential child-caring agency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="14">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to provide improved services to children, the department shall provide or cause to be provided preservice training for prospective foster parents and emergency shelter parents and inservice training for foster parents and emergency shelter parents who are licensed and supervised by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a condition of licensure, foster parents and emergency shelter parents shall successfully complete a minimum of 21 hours of preservice training. The preservice training shall be uniform statewide and shall include, but not be limited to, such areas as:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Orientation regarding agency purpose, objectives, resources, policies, and services;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Role of the foster parent and the emergency shelter parent as a treatment team member;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Transition of a child into and out of foster care and emergency shelter care, including issues of separation, loss, and attachment;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Management of difficult child behavior that can be intensified by placement, by prior abuse or neglect, and by prior placement disruptions;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prevention of placement disruptions;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Care of children at various developmental levels, including appropriate discipline; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Effects of foster parenting on the family of the foster parent and the emergency shelter parent.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In consultation with foster parents, each district or lead agency shall develop a plan for making the completion of the required training as convenient as possible for potential foster parents and emergency-shelter parents. The plan should include, without limitation, such strategies as providing training in nontraditional locations and at nontraditional times. The plan must be revised at least annually and must be included in the information provided to each person applying to become a foster parent or emergency-shelter parent.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to licensure renewal, each foster parent and emergency shelter parent shall successfully complete 8 hours of inservice training. Periodic time-limited training courses shall be made available for selective use by foster parents and emergency shelter parents. Such inservice training shall include subjects affecting the daily living experiences of foster parenting as a foster parent or as an emergency shelter parent, whichever is appropriate. For a foster parent or emergency shelter parent participating in the required inservice training, the department shall reimburse such parent for travel expenditures and, if both parents in a home are attending training or if the absence of the parent would leave the children without departmentally approved adult supervision, either the department shall make provision for child care or shall reimburse the foster or emergency shelter parents for child care purchased by the parents for children in their care.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="15">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Division of Risk Management of the Department of Financial Services shall provide coverage through the Department of Children and Family Services to any person who owns or operates a family foster home solely for the Department of Children and Family Services and who is licensed to provide family foster home care in her or his place of residence. The coverage shall be provided from the general liability account of the State Risk Management Trust Fund, and the coverage shall be primary. The coverage is limited to general liability claims arising from the provision of family foster home care pursuant to an agreement with the department and pursuant to guidelines established through policy, rule, or statute. Coverage shall be limited as provided in ss. 284.38 and 284.385, and the exclusions set forth therein, together with other exclusions as may be set forth in the certificate of coverage issued by the trust fund, shall apply. A person covered under the general liability account pursuant to this subsection shall immediately notify the Division of Risk Management of the Department of Financial Services of any potential or actual claim.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This subsection may not be construed as designating or not designating that a person who owns or operates a family foster home as described in this subsection or any other person is an employee or agent of the state. Nothing in this subsection amends, expands, or supersedes the provisions of s. 768.28.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="16">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following information held by the Department of Children and Family Services regarding a foster parent applicant and such applicant’s spouse, minor child, and other adult household member is exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home, business, work, child care, or school addresses and telephone numbers;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Birth dates;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical records;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The floor plan of the home; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Photographs of such persons.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foster parent applicant does not receive a foster parent license, the information made exempt pursuant to this paragraph shall become public 5 years after the date of application, except that medical records shall remain exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption applies to information made exempt by this paragraph before, on, or after the effective date of the exemption.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following information held by the Department of Children and Family Services regarding a licensed foster parent and the foster parent’s spouse, minor child, and other adult household member is exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The home, business, work, child care, or school addresses and telephone numbers;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Birth dates;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="c">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical records;</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="d">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The floor plan of the home; and</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="e">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Photographs of such persons.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If a foster parent’s license is no longer active, the information made exempt pursuant to this paragraph shall become public 5 years after the expiration date of such foster parent’s foster care license except that:</Text>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="a">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medical records shall remain exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
					<SubSubParagraph Id="b">
						<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Exempt information regarding a licensed foster parent who has become an adoptive parent and exempt information regarding such foster parent’s spouse, minor child, or other adult household member shall remain exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
					</SubSubParagraph>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This exemption applies to information made exempt by this paragraph before, on, or after the effective date of the exemption.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name, address, and telephone number of persons providing character or neighbor references regarding foster parent applicants or licensed foster parents held by the Department of Children and Family Services are exempt from s. 119.07(1) and s. 24(a), Art. I of the State Constitution.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 69-268; ss. 19, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 1, ch. 70-255; s. 3, ch. 76-168; s. 276, ch. 77-147; s. 1, ch. 77-457; s. 7, ch. 78-433; s. 5, ch. 80-102; ss. 2, 3, ch. 81-318; ss. 3, 5, ch. 83-250; ss. 1, 20, 21, ch. 84-311; s. 35, ch. 85-54; s. 28, ch. 87-238; s. 1, ch. 87-535; s. 41, ch. 88-337; s. 2, ch. 90-225; s. 42, ch. 90-306; s. 11, ch. 91-33; s. 29, ch. 91-57; s. 2, ch. 91-71; s. 56, ch. 91-220; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 29, ch. 93-39; s. 15, ch. 93-156; s. 23, ch. 94-134; s. 23, ch. 94-135; s. 19, ch. 95-152; s. 16, ch. 95-158; s. 42, ch. 95-228; s. 132, ch. 95-418; s. 13, ch. 96-268; s. 6, ch. 96-402; ss. 251, 252, ch. 96-406; s. 194, ch. 97-101; s. 1018, ch. 97-103; s. 1, ch. 98-29; s. 23, ch. 2000-122; s. 11, ch. 2000-217; s. 5, ch. 2000-265; ss. 97, 155, ch. 2000-349; s. 8, ch. 2001-68; s. 6, ch. 2002-219; ss. 1, 2, ch. 2003-83; s. 9, ch. 2003-146; s. 442, ch. 2003-261; s. 19, ch. 2004-267; s. 12, ch. 2006-194; s. 18, ch. 2008-104; ss. 1, 2, ch. 2008-169; s. 20, ch. 2008-245; s. 2, ch. 2010-6; s. 23, ch. 2010-114.</History>
</Section>