<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.903" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Mandatory payments for eligible persons.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall make payments for medical assistance and related services on behalf of the following persons who the department, or the Social Security Administration by contract with the Department of Children and Family Services, determines to be eligible, subject to the income, assets, and categorical eligibility tests set forth in federal and state law. Payment on behalf of these Medicaid eligible persons is subject to the availability of moneys and any limitations established by the General Appropriations Act or chapter 216.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Low-income families with children are eligible for Medicaid provided they meet the following requirements:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The family includes a dependent child who is living with a caretaker relative.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The family’s income does not exceed the gross income test limit.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The family’s countable income and resources do not exceed the applicable Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) income and resource standards under the AFDC state plan in effect in July 1996, except as amended in the Medicaid state plan to conform as closely as possible to the requirements of the welfare transition program, to the extent permitted by federal law.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who receives payments from, who is determined eligible for, or who was eligible for but lost cash benefits from the federal program known as the Supplemental Security Income program (SSI). This category includes a low-income person age 65 or over and a low-income person under age 65 considered to be permanently and totally disabled.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child under age 21 living in a low-income, two-parent family, and a child under age 7 living with a nonrelative, if the income and assets of the family or child, as applicable, do not exceed the resource limits under the Temporary Cash Assistance Program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child who is eligible under Title IV-E of the Social Security Act for subsidized board payments, foster care, or adoption subsidies, and a child for whom the state has assumed temporary or permanent responsibility and who does not qualify for Title IV-E assistance but is in foster care, shelter or emergency shelter care, or subsidized adoption. This category includes a young adult who is eligible to receive services under s. 409.1451(5), until the young adult reaches 21 years of age, without regard to any income, resource, or categorical eligibility test that is otherwise required. This category also includes a person who as a child was eligible under Title IV-E of the Social Security Act for foster care or the state-provided foster care and who is a participant in the Road-to-Independence Program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A pregnant woman for the duration of her pregnancy and for the postpartum period as defined in federal law and rule, or a child under age 1, if either is living in a family that has an income which is at or below 150 percent of the most current federal poverty level, or, effective January 1, 1992, that has an income which is at or below 185 percent of the most current federal poverty level. Such a person is not subject to an assets test. Further, a pregnant woman who applies for eligibility for the Medicaid program through a qualified Medicaid provider must be offered the opportunity, subject to federal rules, to be made presumptively eligible for the Medicaid program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child born after September 30, 1983, living in a family that has an income which is at or below 100 percent of the current federal poverty level, who has attained the age of 6, but has not attained the age of 19. In determining the eligibility of such a child, an assets test is not required. A child who is eligible for Medicaid under this subsection must be offered the opportunity, subject to federal rules, to be made presumptively eligible. A child who has been deemed presumptively eligible for Medicaid shall not be enrolled in a managed care plan until the child’s full eligibility determination for Medicaid has been completed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A child living in a family that has an income which is at or below 133 percent of the current federal poverty level, who has attained the age of 1, but has not attained the age of 6. In determining the eligibility of such a child, an assets test is not required. A child who is eligible for Medicaid under this subsection must be offered the opportunity, subject to federal rules, to be made presumptively eligible. A child who has been deemed presumptively eligible for Medicaid shall not be enrolled in a managed care plan until the child’s full eligibility determination for Medicaid has been completed.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person who is age 65 or over or is determined by the agency to be disabled, whose income is at or below 100 percent of the most current federal poverty level and whose assets do not exceed limitations established by the agency. However, the agency may only pay for premiums, coinsurance, and deductibles, as required by federal law, unless additional coverage is provided for any or all members of this group by s. 409.904(1).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 32, ch. 91-282; s. 97, ch. 96-175; s. 27, ch. 98-191; s. 13, ch. 2000-163; s. 95, ch. 2000-165; s. 8, ch. 2000-253; s. 50, ch. 2000-256; s. 8, ch. 2002-19; s. 6, ch. 2004-270; s. 4, ch. 2005-60; s. 13, ch. 2006-194; s. 3, ch. 2007-147; s. 11, ch. 2010-209.</History>
</Section>