<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.16713" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Allocation of funds for community-based care lead agencies.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Core services funding” means all funds allocated to community-based care lead agencies operating under contract with the department pursuant to s. 409.1671, with the following exceptions:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds appropriated for independent living;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds appropriated for maintenance adoption subsidies;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds allocated by the department for protective investigations training;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Nonrecurring funds;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Designated mental health wrap-around services funds; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Funds for special projects for a designated community-based care lead agency.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Equity allocation model” means an allocation model that uses the following factors:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of children in poverty;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of child abuse hotline workload;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of children in care; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of contribution in the reduction of out-of-home care.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proportion of children in poverty” means the average of the proportion of children in the geographic area served by the community-based care lead agency based on the following subcomponents:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children up to 18 years of age who are below the poverty level as determined by the latest available Small Area Income and Poverty Estimates (SAIPE) from the United States Census Bureau;</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Children eligible for free or reduced-price meals as determined by the latest available survey published by the Department of Education; and</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The number of children in families receiving benefits from the federal Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) in the most recent month as determined by the department.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proportion of child abuse hotline workload” means the weighted average of the following subcomponents:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average number of initial and additional child abuse reports received during the month for the most recent 12 months based on child protective investigations trend reports as determined by the department. This subcomponent shall be weighted as 20 percent of the factor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average count of children in investigations in the most recent 12 months based on child protective investigations trend reports as determined by the department. This subcomponent shall be weighted as 40 percent of the factor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The average count of children in investigations with a most serious finding of verified abuse in the most recent 12 months based on child protective investigations trend reports as determined by the department. This subcomponent shall be weighted as 40 percent of the factor.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proportion of children in care” means the proportion of the sum of the number of children in care receiving in-home services and the number of children in out-of-home care at the end of the most recent month as reported in the child welfare services trend reports as determined by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Proportion of contribution in the reduction of out-of-home care” means the proportion of the number of children in out-of-home care on December 31, 2006, minus the number of children in out-of-home care as of the end of the most recent month as reported in the child welfare services trend reports as determined by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The equity allocation of core services funds shall be calculated based on the following weights:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of children in poverty shall be weighted as 30 percent of the total;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of child abuse hotline workload shall be weighted as 30 percent of the total;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of children in care shall be weighted as 30 percent of the total; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Proportion of contribution to the reduction in out-of-home care shall be weighted as 10 percent of the total.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Beginning in the 2011-2012 state fiscal year, 75 percent of the recurring core services funding for each community-based care lead agency shall be based on the prior year recurring base of core services funds and 25 percent shall be based on the equity allocation model.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the 2011-2012 state fiscal year, any new core services funds shall be allocated based on the equity allocation model. Such allocations shall be proportional to the proportion of funding based on the equity model and allocated only to the community-based care lead agency contracts where the current funding proportion is less than the proportion of funding based on the equity model.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2011-62.</History>
</Section>