<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.9201" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Medicaid fraud.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this section, the term:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Prescription drug” means any drug, including, but not limited to, finished dosage forms or active ingredients that are subject to, defined by, or described by s. 503(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or by s. 465.003(8), s. 499.003(46) or (53) or s. 499.007(13).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Value” means the amount billed to the Medicaid program for the property dispensed or the market value of a legend drug or goods or services at the time and place of the offense. If the market value cannot be determined, the term means the replacement cost of the legend drug or goods or services within a reasonable time after the offense.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly sells, who knowingly attempts or conspires to sell, or who knowingly causes any other person to sell or attempt or conspire to sell a legend drug that was paid for by the Medicaid program commits a felony.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the legend drug involved is less than $20,000, the crime is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the legend drug involved is $20,000 or more but less than $100,000, the crime is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the legend drug involved is $100,000 or more, the crime is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly purchases, or who knowingly attempts or conspires to purchase, a legend drug that was paid for by the Medicaid program and intended for use by another person commits a felony.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the legend drug is less than $20,000, the crime is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the legend drug is $20,000 or more but less than $100,000, the crime is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the legend drug is $100,000 or more, the crime is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly makes or knowingly causes to be made, or who attempts or conspires to make, any false statement or representation to any person for the purpose of obtaining goods or services from the Medicaid program commits a felony.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the goods or services is less than $20,000, the crime is a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the goods or services is $20,000 or more but less than $100,000, the crime is a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the value of the goods or services involved is $100,000 or more, the crime is a felony of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The value of individual items of the legend drugs or goods or services involved in distinct transactions committed during a single scheme or course of conduct, whether involving a single person or several persons, may be aggregated when determining the punishment for the offense.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 2004-344; s. 38, ch. 2008-207; s. 37, ch. 2010-161.</History>
</Section>