<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.9118" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disproportionate share program for specialty hospitals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall design and implement a system of making disproportionate share payments to those hospitals licensed in accordance with part I of chapter 395 as a specialty hospital which meet all requirements listed in subsection (2). Notwithstanding s. 409.915, counties are exempt from contributing toward the cost of this special reimbursement for patients.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following formula shall be used by the agency to calculate the total amount earned for hospitals that participate under this section:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">TAE=(MD/TMD) x TA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Where:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TAE=total amount earned by a specialty hospital.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TA=total appropriation for payments to hospitals that qualify under this program.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">MD=total Medicaid days for each qualifying hospital.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">TMD=total Medicaid days for all hospitals that qualify under this program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to receive payments under this section, a hospital must be licensed in accordance with part I of chapter 395, to participate in the Florida Title XIX program, and meet the following requirements:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be certified or certifiable to be a provider of Title XVIII services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive all of its inpatient clients through referrals or admissions from county public health departments, as defined in chapter 154.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Require a diagnosis for the control of a communicable disease for all admissions for inpatient treatment.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 13, ch. 97-260.</History></Section>