<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.1679" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Additional requirements; reimbursement methodology.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each program established under ss. 409.1676 and 409.1677 must meet the following expectations, which must be included in its contracts with the department or lead agency:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No more than 10 percent of the children served may move from one living environment to another, unless the child is returned to family members or is moved, in accordance with the treatment plan, to a less-restrictive setting. Each child must have a comprehensive transitional plan that identifies the child’s living arrangement upon leaving the program and specific steps and services that are being provided to prepare for that arrangement. Specific expectations as to the time period necessary for the achievement of these permanency goals must be included in the contract.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each child must receive a full academic year of appropriate educational instruction. No more than 10 percent of the children may be in more than one academic setting in an academic year, unless the child is being moved, in accordance with an educational plan, to a less-restrictive setting. Each child must demonstrate academic progress and must be performing at grade level or at a level commensurate with a valid academic assessment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Siblings must be kept together in the same living environment 100 percent of the time, unless that is determined by the provider not to be in the children’s best interest. When siblings are separated in placement, the decision must be reviewed and approved by the court within 30 days.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The program must experience a caregiver turnover rate and an incidence of child runaway episodes which are at least 50 percent below the rates experienced in the rest of the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to providing a comprehensive assessment, the program must provide, 100 percent of the time, any or all of the following services that are indicated through the assessment: residential care; transportation; behavioral health services; recreational activities; clothing, supplies, and miscellaneous expenses associated with caring for these children; necessary arrangements for or provision of educational services; and necessary and appropriate health and dental care.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The children who are served in this program must be satisfied with the services and living environment.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The caregivers must be satisfied with the program.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 409.141, the Department of Children and Family Services shall fairly and reasonably reimburse the programs established under ss. 409.1676 and 409.1677 based on a prospective per diem rate, which must be specified annually in the General Appropriations Act. Funding for these programs shall be made available from resources appropriated and identified in the General Appropriations Act.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 2001-68; s. 120, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>