<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.818" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Administration.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to implement ss. 409.810-409.821, the following agencies shall have the following duties:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop a simplified eligibility application mail-in form to be used for determining the eligibility of children for coverage under the Florida Kidcare program, in consultation with the agency, the Department of Health, and the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation. The simplified eligibility application form must include an item that provides an opportunity for the applicant to indicate whether coverage is being sought for a child with special health care needs. Families applying for children’s Medicaid coverage must also be able to use the simplified application form without having to pay a premium.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish and maintain the eligibility determination process under the program except as specified in subsection (5). The department shall directly, or through the services of a contracted third-party administrator, establish and maintain a process for determining eligibility of children for coverage under the program. The eligibility determination process must be used solely for determining eligibility of applicants for health benefits coverage under the program. The eligibility determination process must include an initial determination of eligibility for any coverage offered under the program, as well as a redetermination or reverification of eligibility each subsequent 6 months. Effective January 1, 1999, a child who has not attained the age of 5 and who has been determined eligible for the Medicaid program is eligible for coverage for 12 months without a redetermination or reverification of eligibility. In conducting an eligibility determination, the department shall determine if the child has special health care needs. The department, in consultation with the Agency for Health Care Administration and the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation, shall develop procedures for redetermining eligibility which enable a family to easily update any change in circumstances which could affect eligibility. The department may accept changes in a family’s status as reported to the department by the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation without requiring a new application from the family. Redetermination of a child’s eligibility for Medicaid may not be linked to a child’s eligibility determination for other programs.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Inform program applicants about eligibility determinations and provide information about eligibility of applicants to the Florida Kidcare program and to insurers and their agents, through a centralized coordinating office.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules necessary for conducting program eligibility functions.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Health shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Design an eligibility intake process for the program, in coordination with the Department of Children and Family Services, the agency, and the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation. The eligibility intake process may include local intake points that are determined by the Department of Health in coordination with the Department of Children and Family Services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Chair a state-level Florida Kidcare coordinating council to review and make recommendations concerning the implementation and operation of the program. The coordinating council shall include representatives from the department, the Department of Children and Family Services, the agency, the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation, the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission, local government, health insurers, health maintenance organizations, health care providers, families participating in the program, and organizations representing low-income families.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In consultation with the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation and the Department of Children and Family Services, establish a toll-free telephone line to assist families with questions about the program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules necessary to implement outreach activities.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration, under the authority granted in s. 409.914(1), shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Calculate the premium assistance payment necessary to comply with the premium and cost-sharing limitations specified in s. 409.816. The premium assistance payment for each enrollee in a health insurance plan participating in the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation shall equal the premium approved by the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation and the Office of Insurance Regulation of the Financial Services Commission pursuant to ss. 627.410 and 641.31, less any enrollee’s share of the premium established within the limitations specified in s. 409.816. The premium assistance payment for each enrollee in an employer-sponsored health insurance plan approved under ss. 409.810-409.821 shall equal the premium for the plan adjusted for any benchmark benefit plan actuarial equivalent benefit rider approved by the Office of Insurance Regulation pursuant to ss. 627.410 and 641.31, less any enrollee’s share of the premium established within the limitations specified in s. 409.816. In calculating the premium assistance payment levels for children with family coverage, the agency shall set the premium assistance payment levels for each child proportionately to the total cost of family coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Make premium assistance payments to health insurance plans on a periodic basis. The agency may use its Medicaid fiscal agent or a contracted third-party administrator in making these payments. The agency may require health insurance plans that participate in the Medikids program or employer-sponsored group health insurance to collect premium payments from an enrollee’s family. Participating health insurance plans shall report premium payments collected on behalf of enrollees in the program to the agency in accordance with a schedule established by the agency.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Monitor compliance with quality assurance and access standards developed under s. 409.820 and in accordance with s. 2103(f) of the Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. s. 1397cc(f).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Establish a mechanism for investigating and resolving complaints and grievances from program applicants, enrollees, and health benefits coverage providers, and maintain a record of complaints and confirmed problems. In the case of a child who is enrolled in a health maintenance organization, the agency must use the provisions of s. 641.511 to address grievance reporting and resolution requirements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Approve health benefits coverage for participation in the program, following certification by the Office of Insurance Regulation under subsection (4).</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adopt rules necessary for calculating premium assistance payment levels, making premium assistance payments, monitoring access and quality assurance standards, investigating and resolving complaints and grievances, administering the Medikids program, and approving health benefits coverage.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The agency is designated the lead state agency for Title XXI of the Social Security Act for purposes of receipt of federal funds, for reporting purposes, and for ensuring compliance with federal and state regulations and rules.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Office of Insurance Regulation shall certify that health benefits coverage plans that seek to provide services under the Florida Kidcare program, except those offered through the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation or the Children’s Medical Services Network, meet, exceed, or are actuarially equivalent to the benchmark benefit plan and that health insurance plans will be offered at an approved rate. In determining actuarial equivalence of benefits coverage, the Office of Insurance Regulation and health insurance plans must comply with the requirements of s. 2103 of Title XXI of the Social Security Act. The department shall adopt rules necessary for certifying health benefits coverage plans.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Healthy Kids Corporation shall retain its functions as authorized in s. 624.91, including eligibility determination for participation in the Healthy Kids program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency, the Department of Health, the Department of Children and Family Services, the Florida Healthy Kids Corporation, and the Office of Insurance Regulation, after consultation with and approval of the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate, are authorized to make program modifications that are necessary to overcome any objections of the United States Department of Health and Human Services to obtain approval of the state’s child health insurance plan under Title XXI of the Social Security Act.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 45, 57, ch. 98-288; s. 7, ch. 2000-253; s. 448, ch. 2003-261; s. 22, ch. 2003-405; s. 11, ch. 2004-1; s. 8, ch. 2006-28; s. 3, ch. 2009-55; s. 12, ch. 2009-113.</History></Section>