<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.212" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Optional supplementation.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There may be monthly optional supplementation payments, made in such amount as determined by the department, to any person who:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Meets all the program eligibility criteria for an assisted living facility or for adult foster care, family placement, or other specialized living arrangement; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Is receiving a Supplemental Security Income check or is determined to be eligible for optional supplementation by the department.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The base rate of payment for optional state supplementation shall be established by the department within funds appropriated. Additional amounts may be provided for mental health residents in facilities designed to provide limited mental health services as provided for in s. 429.075. The base rate of payment does not include the personal needs allowance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Assisted living facilities, adult family-care homes, family placement, or any other specialized living arrangement accepting residents who receive optional supplementation payments must comply with the requirements of 42 U.S.C. s. 1382e(e).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the amount of optional supplementation provided by the state, a person may receive additional supplementation from third parties to contribute to his or her cost of care. Additional supplementation may be provided under the following conditions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Payments shall be made to the assisted living facility, or to the operator of an adult family-care home, family placement, or other special living arrangement, on behalf of the person and not directly to the optional state supplementation recipient.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Contributions made by third parties shall be entirely voluntary and shall not be a condition of providing proper care to the client.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The additional supplementation shall not exceed two times the provider rate recognized under the optional state supplementation program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Rent vouchers issued pursuant to a federal, state, or local housing program may be issued directly to a recipient of optional state supplementation.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When contributions are made in accordance with the provisions of subsection (4), the department shall not count such supplements as income to the client for purposes of determining eligibility for, or computing the amount of, optional state supplementation benefits, nor shall the department increase an optional state supplementation payment to offset the reduction in Supplemental Security Income benefits that will occur because of the third-party contribution.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The optional state supplementation rate shall be increased by the cost-of-living adjustment to the federal benefits rate provided the average state optional supplementation contribution does not increase as a result.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules to administer this section relating to eligibility requirements for optional state supplementation.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 10, ch. 78-433; s. 9, ch. 89-294; s. 16, ch. 90-295; s. 32, ch. 91-263; s. 31, ch. 95-210; s. 16, ch. 95-418; s. 10, ch. 97-82; s. 5, ch. 97-98; s. 44, ch. 97-103; s. 12, ch. 98-148; s. 8, ch. 98-152; s. 10, ch. 2000-163; s. 47, ch. 2000-256; s. 79, ch. 2006-197.</History></Section>