<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.2578" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Access to employment information; administrative fine.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of establishing paternity, establishing a child support obligation, or enforcing a support obligation, all persons in this state, including for-profit, not-for-profit, and governmental employers or contractors, shall, upon written request from the IV-D agency for information concerning an individual employee of such person, provide to the IV-D agency of this state or its designee or to the Title IV-D agency of any other state or its designee information on the employment, compensation, and benefits of any employee who has a liability to pay support and is delinquent or who has a potential liability. The IV-D agency may also make such a request for the purpose of modifying a child support obligation after an unsuccessful attempt to obtain the information from either party. The information requested shall be provided within 30 days of receipt of the written request. The Title IV-D agency of this state is authorized to impose a fine for failure to respond to its request.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to imposition of a fine, the department shall issue a written notification of noncompliance. Failure to comply with the request within 15 days of receipt of the written notification without good cause may result in the agency taking the following actions:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Imposition of an administrative fine of not more than $500;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The application by the Title IV-D agency or its designee, to the circuit court for an order compelling compliance. The person who is determined to be in noncompliance with the request shall be liable for reasonable attorney’s fees and costs associated with the department bringing this action upon showing by the department that the person failed to comply with the request without good cause.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All fines collected pursuant to this section shall be made payable to the Child Support Enforcement Application and Program Revenue Trust Fund.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Title IV-D agency has the authority to adopt rules and procedures to implement this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 57, ch. 97-170; s. 31, ch. 98-397; s. 40, ch. 2001-158.</History></Section>