<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.914" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Assistance for the uninsured.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall use the claims payment systems, utilization control systems, cost control systems, case management systems, and other systems and controls that it has developed for the management and control of the Medicaid program to assist other agencies and entities, if appropriate, in paying claims and performing other activities necessary for the conduct of programs of state government, or for working with other public and private agencies to solve problems of lack of insurance, underinsurance, or uninsurability. When conducting these services, the agency shall ensure:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That full payment is received for services provided.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That costs of providing these services are clearly segregated from costs necessary for the conduct of the Medicaid program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the program conducted serves the interests of the state in ensuring that effective and quality health care at a reasonable cost is provided to the citizens of the state.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall seek federal statutory or regulatory reforms to establish a Medicaid buy-in program to provide medical assistance to persons ineligible for Medicaid because of current income and categorical restrictions. The agency shall use funds provided by the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation to assist in developing the buy-in program, including, but not limited to, the determination of eligibility and service coverages; cost sharing requirements; managed care provisions; changes needed to the Medicaid program’s claims processing, utilization control, cost control, case management, and provider enrollment systems to operate a buy-in program.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall seek federal authorization and financial support for a buy-in program that provides federally supported medical assistance coverage for persons with incomes up to 250 percent of the federal poverty level. The agency shall not implement the Medicaid buy-in program until it has received necessary federal authorization and financial participation and state appropriations.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 45, ch. 91-282; s. 52, ch. 93-129; s. 189, ch. 99-8.</History></Section>