<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.25635" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Determination and collection of noncovered medical expenses.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITION.<EmDash />As used in this section, “noncovered medical expenses” means uninsured medical, dental, or prescription medication expenses that are ordered to be paid on behalf of a child as provided in s. 61.13(1)(b) or a similar law of another state.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">PROCEEDING TO DETERMINE AMOUNT OWED FOR NONCOVERED MEDICAL EXPENSES.<EmDash />In a Title IV-D case, the Department of Revenue may proceed under this section to determine the amount owed by an obligor for noncovered medical expenses if:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligor is subject to a support order that requires the obligor to pay all or part of a child’s noncovered medical expenses.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligee provides the department with a written declaration under penalty of perjury that states:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Noncovered medical expenses have been incurred on behalf of the dependent child whom the obligor has been ordered to support.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligee has paid for noncovered medical expenses that have been incurred on behalf of the child.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligor has not paid all or part of the child’s noncovered medical expenses as ordered.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount paid by the obligee for noncovered medical expenses and the amount the obligor allegedly owes to the obligee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligee provides documentation in support of the written declaration.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTICE OF PROCEEDING.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To proceed under this section, the Department of Revenue shall serve a notice on the obligor that states:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the department has commenced a proceeding to determine the amount the obligor owes for noncovered medical expenses.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name of the court or other tribunal that issued the support order that requires the obligor to pay noncovered medical expenses and the date of the order.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the proceeding is based on the requirements of the support order, the obligee’s written sworn statement, and the supporting documentation provided to the department by the obligee.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The amount of noncovered medical expenses that the obligee alleges the obligor owes.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the support order was entered by a court of this state or a tribunal of another state, that the obligor may file a motion in the circuit court to contest the amount of noncovered medical expenses owed within 25 days after the date of mailing of the notice or, if the support order was entered by the department, that the obligor may file with the department a petition to contest within 25 days after the date of mailing of the notice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="6">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the support order was entered by a court of this state or a tribunal of another state, that the court shall determine the amount owed by the obligor and enter judgment as appropriate if the obligor timely files a motion in the circuit court to contest the amount of noncovered medical expenses owed or, if the support order was entered by the department, the department shall determine the amount owed by the obligor and render a final order as appropriate if the obligor timely files with the department a petition to contest the amount of noncovered medical expenses owed.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="7">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor does not timely file a motion or petition to contest the amount alleged to be owed, that the obligor shall owe the amount alleged in the notice.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="8">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If an amount owed is determined after a hearing or becomes final because the obligor does not file a timely motion or petition to contest, the department shall begin collection action.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice shall be served on the obligor by regular mail that is sent to the obligor’s address of record according to the clerk of the court or according to the Department of Revenue if the support order was entered by the department or to a more recent address if known. A copy of the obligee’s written declaration and supporting documentation must be served on the obligor with the notice. The department shall provide the obligee with a copy of the notice and with any subsequent notice of hearing.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RIGHT TO HEARING; DETERMINATION AFTER HEARING; WAIVER OF HEARING.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 25 days after the date the notice required by subsection (3) is mailed, if the support order was entered by a court of this state or a tribunal of another state, the obligor may file a motion in the circuit court to contest the amount of noncovered medical expenses owed. If a timely motion is filed, the court shall determine after a hearing whether the obligor owes the obligee the amount alleged for noncovered medical expenses and enter a judgment, as appropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 25 days after the date the notice required by subsection (3) is mailed, if the support order was entered by the Department of Revenue, the obligor may file with the department a petition to contest the amount of noncovered medical expenses owed. If a timely petition is filed, the department shall determine after a hearing pursuant to chapter 120 whether the obligor owes the obligee for the amount alleged for noncovered medical expenses and render a final order, as appropriate.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor does not timely file a motion or petition to contest, the amount owed as alleged in the notice becomes final and is legally enforceable.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">EFFECT OF DETERMINATION BY THE DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE AND UNCONTESTED PROCEEDINGS.<EmDash />The amount owed for noncovered medical expenses that is determined by the Department of Revenue as provided in paragraph (4)(b) or that becomes final as provided in paragraph (4)(c) has the same effect as a judgment entered by a court.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">FILING WITH THE DEPOSITORY; RECORDING; MAINTENANCE OF ACCOUNTS.<EmDash />When an amount owed for noncovered medical expenses is determined, the department shall file a certified copy of the final order or uncontested notice with the depository. Upon receipt of a final order or uncontested notice, the depository shall record the final order or uncontested notice in the same manner as a final judgment. The depository shall maintain necessary accounts to reflect obligations and payments for noncovered medical expenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COLLECTION ACTION; ADMINISTRATIVE REMEDIES.<EmDash />Any administrative remedy available for collection of support may be used to collect noncovered medical expenses that are determined or established under this section. The department may collect noncovered medical expenses in installments by adding a periodic payment to an income deduction notice issued by the department.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SUPPLEMENTAL REMEDY.<EmDash />This section provides a supplemental remedy for determining and enforcing noncovered medical expenses. As an alternative, the department or any other party may petition the circuit court for enforcement of noncovered medical expenses.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULEMAKING AUTHORITY.<EmDash />The department may adopt rules to implement this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 27, ch. 2005-39; s. 9, ch. 2010-187.</History>
</Section>