<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.9119" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disproportionate share program for specialty hospitals for children.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to the payments made under s. 409.911, the Agency for Health Care Administration shall develop and implement a system under which disproportionate share payments are made to those hospitals that are licensed by the state as specialty hospitals for children and were licensed on January 1, 2000, as specialty hospitals for children. This system of payments must conform to federal requirements and must distribute funds in each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made by making quarterly Medicaid payments. Notwithstanding s. 409.915, counties are exempt from contributing toward the cost of this special reimbursement for hospitals that serve a disproportionate share of low-income patients. The agency may make disproportionate share payments to specialty hospitals for children as provided for in the General Appropriations Act.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless specified in the General Appropriations Act, the agency shall use the following formula to calculate the total amount earned for hospitals that participate in the specialty hospital for children disproportionate share program:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">TAE = DSR x BMPD x MD</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Where:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TAE = total amount earned by a specialty hospital for children.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">DSR = disproportionate share rate.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">BMPD = base Medicaid per diem.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">MD = Medicaid days.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall calculate the total additional payment for hospitals that participate in the specialty hospital for children disproportionate share program as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">TAP = (TAE x TA) ÷ STAE</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Where:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TAP = total additional payment for a specialty hospital for children.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TAE = total amount earned by a specialty hospital for children.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TA = total appropriation for the specialty hospital for children disproportionate share program.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">STAE = sum of total amount earned by each hospital that participates in the specialty hospital for children disproportionate share program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A hospital may not receive any payments under this section until it achieves full compliance with the applicable rules of the agency. A hospital that is not in compliance for two or more consecutive quarters may not receive its share of the funds. Any forfeited funds must be distributed to the remaining participating specialty hospitals for children that are in compliance.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 18, ch. 2000-163; ss. 16, 66, ch. 2000-171; s. 55, ch. 2000-256; s. 17, ch. 2003-405; s. 13, ch. 2009-55.</History></Section>