<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.1755" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">One Church, One Child of Florida Corporation Act; creation; duties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “One Church, One Child of Florida Corporation Act.”</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash />The Legislature finds and declares that there is an increasing number of black children in foster care waiting to be adopted. Black children are disproportionately overrepresented in the foster care system and remain in foster care longer. A black child is more likely to be referred for neglect or abuse and remain in permanent custody of the state because he or she is less likely to be adopted. It is the intent of the Legislature that a nonprofit corporation, to be known as the “One Church, One Child of Florida Corporation,” be organized for the purpose of providing services to adoptable black children and increasing the child’s potential for placement in a permanent family home; participating in charitable work; involving persons with religious and clerical expertise; providing literacy and educational guidance; and promoting child welfare services to black children available for adoption.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CORPORATION AUTHORIZATION; DUTIES; POWERS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There is hereby authorized the “One Church, One Child of Florida Corporation,” which shall operate as a not-for-profit corporation and shall be located within the Department of Children and Family Services for administrative purposes. The department shall provide administrative support and services to the corporation to the extent requested by the executive director and to the extent that resources are available.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide for community awareness and involvement by utilizing the resources of black churches to help find permanent homes for black children available for adoption.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop, monitor, and evaluate projects designed to address problems associated with the child welfare system, especially those issues affecting black children.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Develop beneficial programs that shall include, but not be limited to, community education, cultural relations training, family support, transition support groups, counseling, parenting skills and education, legal and other adoption-related costs, and any other activities that will enhance and support the adopted child’s transition into permanency.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide training and technical assistance to community organizations such as black churches, social service agencies, and other organizations that assist in identifying prospective parents willing to adopt.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide, in conjunction with the Department of Children and Family Services, a summary to the Legislature by September 1 of each year on the status of the corporation.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Secure staff necessary to properly administer the corporation. Staff costs shall be funded from general revenue, grant funds, and state and private donations. The board of directors is authorized to determine the number of staff necessary to administer the corporation, but the staff shall include, at a minimum, an executive director and a staff assistant.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The corporation shall have all powers necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes and provisions of this section, including, but not limited to, the power to receive and accept grants, loans, and advances of funds from any public or private agency for, or in aid of, the purposes of this section, and to receive and accept contributions from any source of money, property, labor, or any other thing of value, to be held, used, and applied for such purposes.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">BOARD OF DIRECTORS.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The One Church, One Child of Florida Corporation shall operate subject to the supervision and approval of a board of directors consisting of 23 members, with two directors representing each service district of the Department of Children and Family Services and one director who shall be an at-large member.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each member of the board of directors shall be appointed by the Governor for a 3-year term. The board shall appoint the executive director, who shall be responsible for other staff as authorized by the board.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any member of the board is in violation of the provisions of this section or bylaws adopted thereto, the board may recommend to the Governor that such member be removed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Board members shall receive no compensation, but shall be entitled to receive per diem and travel expenses as provided in s. 112.061.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">There shall be no liability on the part of, and no cause of action of any nature shall arise against, any member of the board, or its employees or agents, for any action taken by them in performance of their powers and duties under this section.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 74, ch. 90-306; s. 27, ch. 91-201; s. 5, ch. 91-429; s. 47, ch. 95-196; s. 116, ch. 97-101.</History></Section>