<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.974" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Eligible plans.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ELIGIBLE PLAN SELECTION.<EmDash />The agency shall select eligible plans through the procurement process described in s. 409.966. The agency shall notice invitations to negotiate no later than January 1, 2013.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure two plans for Region 1. At least one plan shall be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure two plans for Region 2. At least one plan shall be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least three plans and up to five plans for Region 3. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least three plans and up to five plans for Region 4. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least two plans and up to four plans for Region 5. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least four plans and up to seven plans for Region 6. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least three plans and up to six plans for Region 7. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least two plans and up to four plans for Region 8. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="i">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least two plans and up to four plans for Region 9. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="j">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least two plans and up to four plans for Region 10. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="k">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agency shall procure at least five plans and up to 10 plans for Region 11. At least one plan must be a provider service network if any provider service networks submit a responsive bid.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">If no provider service network submits a responsive bid, the agency shall procure no more than one less than the maximum number of eligible plans permitted in that region. Within 12 months after the initial invitation to negotiate, the agency shall attempt to procure a provider service network. The agency shall notice another invitation to negotiate only with provider service networks in those regions where no provider service network has been selected.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">QUALITY SELECTION CRITERIA.<EmDash />In addition to the criteria established in s. 409.966, the agency shall consider evidence that an eligible plan has written agreements or signed contracts or has made substantial progress in establishing relationships with providers before the plan submitting a response. The agency shall evaluate and give special weight to evidence of signed contracts with essential providers as defined by the agency pursuant to s. 409.975(1). The agency shall exercise a preference for plans with a provider network in which over 10 percent of the providers use electronic health records, as defined in s. 408.051. When all other factors are equal, the agency shall consider whether the organization has a contract to provide managed long-term care services in the same region and shall exercise a preference for such plans.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SPECIALTY PLANS.<EmDash />Participation by specialty plans shall be subject to the procurement requirements of this section. The aggregate enrollment of all specialty plans in a region may not exceed 10 percent of the total enrollees of that region.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">CHILDREN’S MEDICAL SERVICES NETWORK.<EmDash />Participation by the Children’s Medical Services Network shall be pursuant to a single, statewide contract with the agency that is not subject to the procurement requirements or regional plan number limits of this section. The Children’s Medical Services Network must meet all other plan requirements for the managed medical assistance program.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MEDICARE PLANS.<EmDash />Participation by a Medicare Advantage Preferred Provider Organization, Medicare Advantage Provider-sponsored Organization, Medicare Advantage Health Maintenance Organization, Medicare Advantage Coordinated Care Plan, or Medicare Advantage Special Needs Plan shall be pursuant to a contract with the agency that is consistent with the Medicare Improvement for Patients and Providers Act of 2008, Pub. L. No. 110-275. Such plans are not subject to the procurement requirements if the plan’s Medicaid enrollees consist exclusively of dually eligible recipients who are enrolled in the plan in order to receive Medicare benefits as of the date that the invitation to negotiate is issued. Otherwise, such plans are subject to all procurement requirements.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 15, ch. 2011-134; s. 53, ch. 2012-5; s. 9, ch. 2012-44.</History>
</Section>