<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.25575" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Support enforcement; privatization.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to encourage the Department of Revenue to contract with private entities for the provision of support enforcement services whenever such contracting is cost-effective.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall contract for the delivery, administration, or management of support enforcement activities and other related services or programs, when appropriate. The department shall retain responsibility for the quality of contracted services and programs and shall ensure that services are delivered in accordance with applicable federal and state statutes and regulations.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish a quality assurance program for the privatization of services. The program must include standards for each specific component of these services. The department shall establish minimum thresholds for each component. Each program operated pursuant to contract must be evaluated annually by the department or by an objective competent entity designated by the department under the provisions of the quality assurance program. The evaluation must be financed from cost savings associated with the privatization of services. The quality assurance program must be financed through administrative savings generated by this act.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall establish and operate a comprehensive system to measure and report annually the outcomes and effectiveness of the services that have been privatized. The department shall use these findings in making recommendations to the Governor and the Legislature for future program and funding priorities in the support enforcement system.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity contracting to provide support enforcement services under this section must comply with all statutory requirements and agency regulations in the provision of contractual services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any entity contracting to provide support enforcement services under this section must also participate in and cooperate with any federal program that will assist in the maximization of federal supports for these services, as directed by the department.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 46, ch. 97-170; s. 27, ch. 2001-158; s. 123, ch. 2010-102.</History>
</Section>