<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.2598" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License suspension proceeding to enforce support order.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">DEFINITIONS.<EmDash />As used in this section, the term:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“License” means a license, permit, certificate, registration, franchise, or other form of written permission issued by a licensing agency to an individual which authorizes the individual to engage in an occupation, business, trade, or profession or to engage in a recreational activity, including hunting or fishing. Where the context permits, the term also includes an application for a new or renewal license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensee” means an individual who has a license.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Licensing agency” means a department, commission, agency, district, county, municipality, or other subdivision of state or local government which issues licenses.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTICE OF NONCOMPLIANCE AND INTENT TO SUSPEND LICENSE.<EmDash />If a support order has not been complied with for at least 30 days, the Department of Revenue may commence a license suspension proceeding to enforce compliance with the support order by providing written notice to the obligor that states:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the obligor is not in compliance with the support order and whether the noncompliance is due to the obligor’s nonpayment of current support, delinquencies or arrears, or the failure to provide health care coverage or medical support.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The kind of license that is subject to suspension.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the obligor may avoid license suspension by complying with the support order or entering into a written agreement with the department within 30 days after the mailing of the notice.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor timely complies with the support order or a written agreement entered into with the department, the proceeding ends and the obligor’s license is not suspended.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That the obligor may contest license suspension by filing a petition in circuit court within 30 days after the mailing of the notice of noncompliance.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor timely files a petition in circuit court, that the license suspension proceeding is stayed pending a ruling by the court.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">The notice shall be served on the obligor by regular mail sent to the obligor’s last address of record with the local depository or a more recent address if known, which may include the obligor’s mailing address as reflected by the records of the licensing agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">HEARING; STAY OF PROCEEDING.<EmDash />The obligor may contest license suspension by filing a petition in circuit court within 30 days after the mailing of the notice of noncompliance and serving a copy of the petition on the Department of Revenue. If the obligor timely files a petition in circuit court, the license suspension proceeding is stayed pending a ruling by the court. The obligor may contest on the basis of a mistake of fact concerning the obligor’s compliance with the support order, the reasonableness of a payment agreement offered by the department, or the identity of the obligor. A timely petition to contest must be heard by the court within 15 days after the petition is filed. The court must enter an order ruling on the matter within 10 days after the hearing, and a copy of the order must be served on the parties.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">COMPLIANCE; REINSTATEMENT.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor complies with the support order or a written agreement entered into with the department after a proceeding is commenced but before the obligor’s license is suspended, the proceeding shall cease and the obligor’s license may not be suspended. If the obligor subsequently does not comply with the support order, the department may commence a new proceeding or proceed as provided in paragraph (c) if the obligor enters into a written agreement and does not comply with the agreement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor complies with the support order or a written agreement entered into with the department after the obligor’s license is suspended, the department shall provide the obligor with a reinstatement notice and the licensing agency shall reinstate the obligor’s license at no additional charge to the obligor.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the obligor enters into a written agreement with the department and does not comply with the agreement, the department shall notify the licensing agency to suspend the obligor’s license unless the obligor notifies the department that the obligor can no longer comply with the written agreement. If the obligor notifies the department of the inability to comply with the written agreement, the obligor shall provide full disclosure to the department of the obligor’s income, assets, and employment. If after full disclosure the written agreement cannot be renegotiated, the department or the obligor may file a petition in circuit court to determine the matter.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensing agency shall promptly reinstate the obligor’s license upon receipt of a court order for reinstatement.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any other statutory provision, a notice from the court or the department shall reinstate to the obligor all licenses established in chapter 379 that were valid at the time of suspension.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">NOTICE TO LICENSING AGENCY; SUSPENSION.<EmDash /></Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Revenue shall notify the licensing agency to suspend the obligor’s license when:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Thirty or more days have elapsed after a proceeding has been commenced and the obligor has not complied with the support order or a written agreement entered into with the department or filed a timely petition to contest license suspension in circuit court;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The obligor enters into a written agreement with the department and does not comply with the agreement, unless the obligor notifies the department that the obligor can no longer comply with the agreement; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department is ordered to do so by the circuit court.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon notice by the department or the circuit court, the licensing agency shall suspend the obligor’s license and may only reinstate the license upon further notice by the department or the court.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">ENFORCEMENT OF SUBPOENAS.<EmDash />A license may be suspended under this section to enforce compliance with a subpoena, order to appear, order to show cause, or similar order in a child support or paternity proceeding by using the same procedures as those used for enforcing compliance with a support order.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">MULTIPLE LICENSES.<EmDash />The Department of Revenue may combine a proceeding under this section with a proceeding to suspend a driver’s license under s. 61.13016. A proceeding to suspend a license under this section may apply to one or more of the obligor’s licenses.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">RULEMAKING AUTHORITY.<EmDash />The Department of Revenue may adopt rules to implement and enforce the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 9, ch. 93-208; s. 4, ch. 95-222; s. 95, ch. 96-175; s. 1021, ch. 97-103; s. 59, ch. 97-170; s. 29, ch. 98-166; s. 36, ch. 99-289; s. 21, ch. 2000-160; s. 19, ch. 2000-364; s. 44, ch. 2001-158; s. 993, ch. 2002-387; s. 18, ch. 2004-334; s. 33, ch. 2005-39; s. 57, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>