<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.8134" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Program expenditure ceiling; enrollment.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for the Medicaid program, a ceiling shall be placed on annual federal and state expenditures for the Florida Kidcare program as provided each year in the General Appropriations Act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Florida Kidcare program may conduct enrollment continuously throughout the year. Children eligible for coverage under the Title XXI-funded Florida Kidcare program shall be enrolled on a first-come, first-served basis using the date the enrollment application is received. Enrollment shall immediately cease when the expenditure ceiling is reached. Year-round enrollment shall only be held if the Social Services Estimating Conference determines that sufficient federal and state funds will be available to finance the increased enrollment. The application for the Florida Kidcare program is valid for a period of 120 days after the date it was received. At the end of the 120-day period, if the applicant has not been enrolled in the program, the application is invalid and the applicant shall be notified of the action. The applicant may reactivate the application after notification of the action taken by the program. Except for the Medicaid program, whenever the Social Services Estimating Conference determines that there are presently, or will be by the end of the current fiscal year, insufficient funds to finance the current or projected enrollment in the Florida Kidcare program, all additional enrollment must cease and additional enrollment may not resume until sufficient funds are available to finance such enrollment.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon determination by the Social Services Estimating Conference that there are insufficient funds to finance the current enrollment in the Florida Kidcare program within current appropriations, the program shall initiate disenrollment procedures to remove enrollees, except those children enrolled in the Children’s Medical Services Network, on a last-in, first-out basis until the expenditure and appropriation levels are balanced.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The agencies that administer the Florida Kidcare program components shall collect and analyze the data needed to project program enrollment costs, including price level adjustments, participation and attrition rates, current and projected caseloads, utilization, and current and projected expenditures for the next 3 years. The agencies shall report caseload and expenditure trends to the Social Services Estimating Conference in accordance with chapter 216.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 37, 57, ch. 98-288; s. 3, ch. 2000-253; s. 22, ch. 2003-405; s. 3, ch. 2004-1; s. 3, ch. 2004-270; s. 2, ch. 2005-123; s. 6, ch. 2006-28; s. 6, ch. 2009-113.</History></Section>