<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.9115" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Disproportionate share program for mental health hospitals.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration shall design and implement a system of making mental health disproportionate share payments to hospitals that qualify for disproportionate share payments under s. 409.911. This system of payments shall conform with federal requirements and shall distribute funds in each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made by making quarterly Medicaid payments. Notwithstanding s. 409.915, counties are exempt from contributing toward the cost of this special reimbursement for patients.</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following formula shall be used by the agency to calculate the total amount earned for hospitals that participate in the mental health disproportionate share program:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">TAP = (DSH/TDSH) x TA</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">Where:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TAP = total additional payment for a mental health hospital.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">DSH = total amount earned by a mental health hospital under s. 409.911.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">TDSH = sum of total amount earned by each hospital that participates in the mental health hospital disproportionate share program.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceBelow="true">TA = total appropriation for the mental health hospital disproportionate share program.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to receive payments under this section, a hospital must participate in the Florida Title XIX program and must:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Agree to serve all individuals referred by the agency who require inpatient psychiatric services, regardless of ability to pay.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be certified or certifiable to be a provider of Title XVIII services.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Receive all of its inpatient clients from admissions governed by the Baker Act as specified in chapter 394.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 92-322; s. 5, ch. 95-430; s. 4, ch. 96-420; s. 3, ch. 97-153; ss. 4, 38, ch. 98-46; ss. 3, 53, ch. 99-228; s. 13, ch. 2000-171; s. 9, ch. 2002-2.</History></Section>