<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.017" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Revenue Maximization Act; legislative intent; revenue maximization program.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">SHORT TITLE.<EmDash />This section may be cited as the “Revenue Maximization Act.”</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">LEGISLATIVE INTENT.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Legislature recognizes that state funds do not fully utilize federal funding matching opportunities for health and human services needs. It is the intent of the Legislature to authorize the use of certified local funding for federal matching programs to the fullest extent possible to maximize federal funding of local preventive services and local child development programs in this state. To that end, the Legislature expects that state agencies will take a proactive approach in implementing this legislative priority. It is the further intent of the Legislature that this act shall be revenue neutral with respect to state funds.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that revenue maximization opportunities using certified local funding shall occur only after available state funds have been utilized to generate matching federal funding for the state.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that participation in revenue maximization is to be voluntary for local political subdivisions.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for funds expended pursuant to Title XIX of the Social Security Act, it is the intent of the Legislature that certified local funding for federal matching programs not supplant or replace state funds. Beginning July 1, 2004, any state funds supplanted or replaced with local tax revenues for Title XIX funds shall be expressly approved in the General Appropriations Act or by the Legislative Budget Commission pursuant to chapter 216.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature that revenue maximization shall not divert existing funds from state agencies that are currently using local funds to maximize matching federal and state funds to the greatest extent possible.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is the intent of the Legislature to encourage and allow any agency to engage, through a competitive procurement process, an entity with expertise in claiming justifiable and appropriate federal funds through revenue maximization efforts both retrospectively and prospectively. This claiming may include, but not be limited to, administrative and services activities that are eligible under federal matching programs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">REVENUE MAXIMIZATION PROGRAM.<EmDash /></Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For purposes of this section, the term “agency” means any state agency or department that is involved in providing health, social, or human services, including, but not limited to, the Agency for Health Care Administration, the Department of Children and Family Services, the Department of Elderly Affairs, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the Department of Education, and the State Board of Education.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Agency for Health Care Administration may develop a procurement document and procedure to claim administrative federal matching funds for state-provided educational services. The agency shall then competitively procure an entity with appropriate expertise and experience to retrospectively and prospectively maximize federal revenues through administrative claims for federal matching funds for state-provided educational services.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency shall establish programs and mechanisms designed to maximize the use of local funding for federal programs in accordance with this section.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The use of local matching funds under this section must be limited to public revenue funds of local political subdivisions, including, but not limited to, counties, municipalities, and special districts. To the extent permitted by federal law, funds donated to such local political subdivisions by private entities, such as, but not limited to, the United Way, community foundations or other foundations, and businesses, or by individuals are considered to be public revenue funds available for matching federal funding.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to paragraph (g), any federal reimbursement received as a result of the certification of local matching funds must, unless specifically prohibited by federal law or state law, including the General Appropriations Act, and subject to the availability of specific appropriation and release authority, be returned within 30 days after receipt by the agency by the most expedient means possible to the local political subdivision providing such funding, and the local political subdivision must be provided an annual accounting of federal reimbursements received by the state or its agencies as a result of the certification of the local political subdivision’s matching funds. The receipt by a local political subdivision of such matching funds must not in any way influence or be used as a factor in developing any agency’s annual operating budget allocation methodology or formula or any subsequent budget amendment allocations or formulas. If necessary, agreements must be made between an agency and the local political subdivision to accomplish that purpose. Such an agreement may provide that the local political subdivision must: verify the eligibility of the local program or programs and the individuals served thereby to qualify for federal matching funds; shall develop and maintain the financial records necessary for documenting the appropriate use of federal funds; shall comply with all applicable state and federal laws, regulations, and rules that regulate such federal services; and shall reimburse the cost of any disallowance of federal funding previously provided to a local political subdivision resulting from the failure of that local political subdivision to comply with applicable state or federal laws, rules, or regulations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency, as applicable, shall work with local political subdivisions to modify any state plans and to seek and implement any federal waivers necessary to implement this section. If such modifications or waivers require the approval of the Legislature, the agency, as applicable, shall draft such legislation and present it to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives and to the respective committee chairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives by January 1, 2004, and, as applicable, annually thereafter.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="g">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency, as applicable, before funds generated under this section are distributed to any local political subdivision, may deduct the actual administrative cost for implementing and monitoring the local match program; however, such administrative costs may not exceed 5 percent of the total federal reimbursement funding to be provided to the local political subdivision under paragraph (e). To the extent that any other provision of state law applies to the certification of local matching funds for a specific program, the provisions of that statute which relate to administrative costs apply in lieu of the provisions of this paragraph. The failure to remit reimbursement to the local political subdivision will result in the payment of interest, in addition to the amount to be reimbursed at a rate pursuant to s. 55.03(1) on the unpaid amount from the expiration of the 30-day period until payment is received.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="h">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each agency, respectively, shall annually submit to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, no later than January 1, a report that documents the specific activities undertaken during the previous fiscal year under this section. The report must include, but is not limited to, a statement of the total amount of federal matching funds generated by local matching funds under this section, reported by federal funding source; the total amount of block grant funds expended during the previous fiscal year, reported by federal funding source; the total amount for federal matching fund programs, including, but not limited to, Temporary Assistance for Needy Families and Child Care and Development Fund, of unobligated funds and unliquidated funds, both as of the close of the previous federal fiscal year; the amount of unliquidated funds that is in danger of being returned to the Federal Government at the end of the current federal fiscal year; and a detailed plan and timeline for spending any unobligated and unliquidated funds by the end of the current federal fiscal year.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 2003-146; s. 48, ch. 2004-5; s. 2, ch. 2008-143; s. 299, ch. 2011-142.</History>
</Section>