<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.816" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Limitations on premiums and cost-sharing.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The following limitations on premiums and cost-sharing are established for the program.</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollees who receive coverage under the Medicaid program may not be required to pay:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollment fees, premiums, or similar charges; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copayments, deductibles, coinsurance, or similar charges.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollees in families with a family income equal to or below 150 percent of the federal poverty level, who are not receiving coverage under the Medicaid program, may not be required to pay:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollment fees, premiums, or similar charges that exceed the maximum monthly charge permitted under s. 1916(b)(1) of the Social Security Act; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Copayments, deductibles, coinsurance, or similar charges that exceed a nominal amount, as determined consistent with regulations referred to in s. 1916(a)(3) of the Social Security Act. However, such charges may not be imposed for preventive services, including well-baby and well-child care, age-appropriate immunizations, and routine hearing and vision screenings.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Enrollees in families with a family income above 150 percent of the federal poverty level who are not receiving coverage under the Medicaid program or who are not eligible under s. 409.814(6) may be required to pay enrollment fees, premiums, copayments, deductibles, coinsurance, or similar charges on a sliding scale related to income, except that the total annual aggregate cost-sharing with respect to all children in a family may not exceed 5 percent of the family’s income. However, copayments, deductibles, coinsurance, or similar charges may not be imposed for preventive services, including well-baby and well-child care, age-appropriate immunizations, and routine hearing and vision screenings.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">ss. 41, 57, ch. 98-288; s. 22, ch. 2003-405; s. 9, ch. 2009-113; s. 91, ch. 2010-5.</History>
</Section>