<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.141" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Equitable reimbursement methodology.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To assure high standards of care and essential residential services as a component of the services continuum for at-risk youth and families, the Department of Children and Family Services shall adopt an equitable reimbursement methodology. This methodology, which addresses only those children placed in nonprofit residential group care by the department and funded through public appropriations, shall consist of a standardized base of allowable costs of a provider’s actual per diem rate costs. The actual percentage of base costs met through this methodology shall be determined by the availability of state funding. The full utilization of the department’s Children, Youth and Families Purchase of Residential Group Care Appropriation Category shall be used to fund this methodology. Definitions of care and allowable costs shall be based upon those mandated services standards as set out in chapter 10M-9, Florida Administrative Code (Licensing Standards Residential Child Care Agencies), plus any special enhancements required by the specific treatment component. Actual costs shall be verified through the agency’s annual fiscal audit for the 2 prior calendar years.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This adopted rate control method shall include a consumer price index factor to acknowledge both the postaudit time lapse of the allowable costs methodology and the universal cost variables beyond the control of the group care providers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This methodology shall assure that the existing disparities between actual costs of care and the current state reimbursement levels are addressed in a fair and systematic manner, while recognizing that nonprofit residential group care providers shall provide the remaining percentage of their program costs. Cost containment measures shall be included through the allowable costs definition and verification process.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Children and Family Services shall develop administrative rules in full cooperation with the Florida Group Child Care Association to carry out the intent and provisions of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 90-204; s. 111, ch. 97-101.</History></Section>