<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0409.25658" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Use of unclaimed property for past due support.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In a joint effort to facilitate the collection and payment of past due support, the Department of Revenue, in cooperation with the Department of Financial Services, shall identify persons owing support collected through a court who are presumed to have unclaimed property held by the Department of Financial Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall periodically provide the Department of Financial Services with an electronic file of support obligors who owe past due support. The Department of Financial Services shall conduct a data match of the file against all apparent owners of unclaimed property under chapter 717 and provide the resulting match list to the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon receipt of the data match list, the department shall provide to the Department of Financial Services the obligor’s last known address. The Department of Financial Services shall follow the notification procedures under s. 717.118.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to paying an obligor’s approved claim, the Department of Financial Services shall notify the department that such claim has been approved. Upon confirmation that the Department of Financial Services has approved the claim, the department shall immediately send a notice by certified mail to the obligor, with a copy to the Department of Financial Services, advising the obligor of the department’s intent to intercept the approved claim up to the amount of the past due support, and informing the obligor of the obligor’s right to request a hearing under chapter 120. The Department of Financial Services shall retain custody of the property until a final order has been entered and any appeals thereon have been concluded. If the obligor fails to request a hearing, the department shall enter a final order instructing the Department of Financial Services to transfer to the department the property in the amount stated in the final order. Upon such transfer, the Department of Financial Services shall be released from further liability related to the transferred property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section provide a supplemental remedy, and the department may use this remedy in conjunction with any other method of collecting support.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 26, ch. 98-397; s. 37, ch. 2001-158; s. 12, ch. 2002-173; s. 444, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>