<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0409.979" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Eligibility.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicaid recipients who meet all of the following criteria are eligible to receive long-term care services and must receive long-term care services by participating in the long-term care managed care program. The recipient must be:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Sixty-five years of age or older, or age 18 or older and eligible for Medicaid by reason of a disability.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Determined by the Comprehensive Assessment Review and Evaluation for Long-Term Care Services (CARES) Program to require nursing facility care as defined in s. 409.985(3).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Medicaid recipients who, on the date long-term care managed care plans become available in their region, reside in a nursing home facility or are enrolled in one of the following long-term care Medicaid waiver programs are eligible to participate in the long-term care managed care program for up to 12 months without being reevaluated for their need for nursing facility care as defined in s. 409.985(3):</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Assisted Living for the Frail Elderly Waiver.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Aged and Disabled Adult Waiver.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Consumer-Directed Care Plus Program as described in s. 409.221.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The long-term care community-based diversion pilot project as described in s. 430.705.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Channeling Services Waiver for Frail Elders.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The Department of Elderly Affairs shall make offers for enrollment to eligible individuals based on a wait-list prioritization and subject to availability of funds. Before enrollment offers, the department shall determine that sufficient funds exist to support additional enrollment into plans.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 20, ch. 2011-134; s. 14, ch. 2012-33.</History>
</Section>