<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0196.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Reference Number="1"/>
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemption for certain permanently and totally disabled veterans and for surviving spouses of veterans.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any real estate that is owned and used as a homestead by a veteran who was honorably discharged with a service-connected total and permanent disability and for whom a letter from the United States Government or United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor has been issued certifying that the veteran is totally and permanently disabled is exempt from taxation, if the veteran is a permanent resident of this state on January 1 of the tax year for which exemption is being claimed or was a permanent resident of this state on January 1 of the year the veteran died.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The production by a veteran or the spouse or surviving spouse of a letter of total and permanent disability from the United States Government or United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor before the property appraiser of the county in which property of the veteran lies is prima facie evidence of the fact that the veteran or the surviving spouse is entitled to the exemption.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the totally and permanently disabled veteran predeceases his or her spouse and if, upon the death of the veteran, the spouse holds the legal or beneficial title to the homestead and permanently resides thereon as specified in s. 196.031, the exemption from taxation carries over to the benefit of the veteran’s spouse until such time as he or she remarries or sells or otherwise disposes of the property. If the spouse sells the property, an exemption not to exceed the amount granted from the most recent ad valorem tax roll may be transferred to his or her new residence, as long as it is used as his or her primary residence and he or she does not remarry.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any real estate that is owned and used as a homestead by the surviving spouse of a veteran who died from service-connected causes while on active duty as a member of the United States Armed Forces and for whom a letter from the United States Government or United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor has been issued certifying that the veteran who died from service-connected causes while on active duty is exempt from taxation if the veteran was a permanent resident of this state on January 1 of the year in which the veteran died.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The production by the surviving spouse of a letter that was issued as required under paragraph (a) and that attests the veteran’s death while on active duty is prima facie evidence of the fact that the surviving spouse is entitled to an exemption under paragraph (a).</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The tax exemption that applies under paragraph (a) to the surviving spouse carries over to the benefit of the veteran’s surviving spouse as long as the spouse holds the legal or beneficial title to the homestead, permanently resides thereon as specified in s. 196.031, and does not remarry. If the surviving spouse sells the property, an exemption not to exceed the amount granted from the most recent ad valorem tax roll may be transferred to his or her new residence as long as it is used as his or her primary residence and he or she does not remarry.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An applicant for the exemption under this section may apply for the exemption before receiving the necessary documentation from the United States Government or the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor. Upon receipt of the documentation, the exemption shall be granted as of the date of the original application, and the excess taxes paid shall be refunded. Any refund of excess taxes paid shall be limited to those paid during the 4-year period of limitation set forth in s. 197.182(1)(e).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 57-778; s. 1, ch. 65-193; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-55; s. 2, ch. 71-133; s. 1, ch. 76-163; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 1, ch. 83-71; s. 10, ch. 86-177; s. 1, ch. 92-167; s. 62, ch. 93-268; s. 1, ch. 93-400; s. 1, ch. 97-157; s. 2, ch. 2012-54; s. 19, ch. 2012-193.</History>
	<Note Reference="1">
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">A. Section 3, ch. 2012-54, provides that:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“Construction.<EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(1) The revisions to s. 196.081, Florida Statutes, made by this act operate prospectively to the 2013 tax roll and do not provide a basis for relief from an assessment of taxes not paid or create a right to a refund of taxes paid before January 1, 2013.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">“(2) The provisions of s. 196.081(5), Florida Statutes, as created by this act apply to the homestead exemption of the surviving spouse of a first responder whose death occurs before, on, or after the effective date of this act.” Subsection (5), as created by s. 2, ch. 2012-54, was redesignated as subsection (6) by the editors to conform to the fact that s. 19, ch. 2012-193, also created a subsection (5).</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">B. Section 5, ch. 2012-54, provides that “[e]xcept as otherwise expressly provided in this act and except for this section, which shall take effect July 1, 2012, this act shall take effect on the same date that CS for SJR 1056, or a similar joint resolution having substantially the same specific intent and purpose, takes effect if approved by the electors at the general election held in November 2012 or at an earlier special election specifically authorized by law for that purpose.” Senate Joint Resolution 1056 did not pass; House Joint Resolution 93, which was substantially similar to Senate Joint Resolution 1056, did pass. If House Joint Resolution 93 is approved by a vote of the electors, s. 196.081, as amended by s. 19, ch. 2012-193, and s. 2, ch. 2012-54, will read:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent"><Font xml:space="preserve" Style="Bold">196.081 Exemption for certain permanently and totally disabled veterans and for surviving spouses of veterans; exemption for surviving spouses of first responders who die in the line of duty.</Font><EmDash/></Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(1) Any real estate that is owned and used as a homestead by a veteran who was honorably discharged with a service-connected total and permanent disability and for whom a letter from the United States Government or United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor has been issued certifying that the veteran is totally and permanently disabled is exempt from taxation, if the veteran is a permanent resident of this state on January 1 of the tax year for which exemption is being claimed or was a permanent resident of this state on January 1 of the year the veteran died.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(2) The production by a veteran or the spouse or surviving spouse of a letter of total and permanent disability from the United States Government or United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor before the property appraiser of the county in which property of the veteran lies is prima facie evidence of the fact that the veteran or the surviving spouse is entitled to the exemption.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(3) If the totally and permanently disabled veteran predeceases his or her spouse and if, upon the death of the veteran, the spouse holds the legal or beneficial title to the homestead and permanently resides thereon as specified in s. 196.031, the exemption from taxation carries over to the benefit of the veteran’s spouse until such time as he or she remarries or sells or otherwise disposes of the property. If the spouse sells the property, an exemption not to exceed the amount granted from the most recent ad valorem tax roll may be transferred to his or her new residence, as long as it is used as his or her primary residence and he or she does not remarry.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(4) Any real estate that is owned and used as a homestead by the surviving spouse of a veteran who died from service-connected causes while on active duty as a member of the United States Armed Forces and for whom a letter from the United States Government or United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor has been issued certifying that the veteran who died from service-connected causes while on active duty is exempt from taxation if the veteran was a permanent resident of this state on January 1 of the year in which the veteran died.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The production of the letter by the surviving spouse which attests to the veteran’s death while on active duty is prima facie evidence that the surviving spouse is entitled to the exemption.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The tax exemption carries over to the benefit of the veteran’s surviving spouse as long as the spouse holds the legal or beneficial title to the homestead, permanently resides thereon as specified in s. 196.031, and does not remarry. If the surviving spouse sells the property, an exemption not to exceed the amount granted under the most recent ad valorem tax roll may be transferred to his or her new residence as long as it is used as his or her primary residence and he or she does not remarry.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(5)  An applicant for the exemption under this section may apply for the exemption before receiving the necessary documentation from the United States Government or the United States Department of Veterans Affairs or its predecessor. Upon receipt of the documentation, the exemption shall be granted as of the date of the original application, and the excess taxes paid shall be refunded. Any refund of excess taxes paid shall be limited to those paid during the 4-year period of limitation set forth in s. 197.182(1)(e).</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(6) Any real estate that is owned and used as a homestead by the surviving spouse of a first responder who died in the line of duty while employed by the state or any political subdivision of the state, including authorities and special districts, and for whom a letter from the state or appropriate political subdivision of the state, or other authority or special district, has been issued which legally recognizes and certifies that the first responder died in the line of duty while employed as a first responder is exempt from taxation if the first responder and his or her surviving spouse were permanent residents of this state on January 1 of the year in which the first responder died.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(a) The production of the letter by the surviving spouse which attests to the first responder’s death in the line of duty is prima facie evidence that the surviving spouse is entitled to the exemption.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(b) The tax exemption applies as long as the surviving spouse holds the legal or beneficial title to the homestead, permanently resides thereon as specified in s. 196.031, and does not remarry. If the surviving spouse sells the property, an exemption not to exceed the amount granted under the most recent ad valorem tax roll may be transferred to his or her new residence if it is used as his or her primary residence and he or she does not remarry.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">(c) As used in this subsection only, and not applicable to the payment of benefits under s. 112.19 or s. 112.191, the term:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">1. “First responder” means a law enforcement officer or correctional officer as defined in s. 943.10, a firefighter as defined in s. 633.30, or an emergency medical technician or paramedic as defined in s. 401.23 who is a full-time paid employee, part-time paid employee, or unpaid volunteer.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">2. “In the line of duty” means:</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">a. While engaging in law enforcement;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">b. While performing an activity relating to fire suppression and prevention;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">c. While responding to a hazardous material emergency;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">d. While performing rescue activity;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">e. While providing emergency medical services;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">f. While performing disaster relief activity;</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">g. While otherwise engaging in emergency response activity; or</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">h. While engaging in a training exercise related to any of the events or activities enumerated in this subparagraph if the training has been authorized by the employing entity.</Text>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Flush" SpaceAbove="true">A heart attack or stroke that causes death or causes an injury resulting in death must occur within 24 hours after an event or activity enumerated in this subparagraph and must be directly and proximately caused by the event or activity in order to be considered as having occurred in the line of duty.</Text>
	</Note>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 192.111.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>