<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0196.192" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemptions from ad valorem taxation.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subject to the provisions of this chapter:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All property owned by an exempt entity, including educational institutions, and used exclusively for exempt purposes shall be totally exempt from ad valorem taxation.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All property owned by an exempt entity, including educational institutions, and used predominantly for exempt purposes shall be exempted from ad valorem taxation to the extent of the ratio that such predominant use bears to the nonexempt use.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">All tangible personal property loaned or leased by a natural person, by a trust holding property for a natural person, or by an exempt entity to an exempt entity for public display or exhibition on a recurrent schedule is exempt from ad valorem taxation if the property is loaned or leased for no consideration or for nominal consideration.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">For purposes of this section, each use to which the property is being put must be considered in granting an exemption from ad valorem taxation, including any economic use in addition to any physical use. For purposes of this section, property owned by a limited liability company, the sole member of which is an exempt entity, shall be treated as if the property were owned directly by the exempt entity. This section does not apply in determining the exemption for property owned by governmental units pursuant to s. 196.199.</Text>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 3, ch. 71-133; s. 2, ch. 88-102; s. 2, ch. 89-122; s. 3, ch. 2007-106; s. 2, ch. 2008-193.</History>
</Section>