<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0196.194" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Value adjustment board; notice; hearings; appearance before the board.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The value adjustment board shall hear disputed or appealed applications for exemption and shall grant such exemptions in whole or in part in accordance with criteria set forth in this chapter. It may review exemptions on its own motion or upon motion of the property appraiser. Review of an exemption application upon motion of the board shall not be held until the applicant has had at least 5 calendar days’ notice of the intent of the board to review the application.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">At least 2 weeks prior to the meeting of the value adjustment board, but no sooner than May 15, notice of the meeting shall be published in a newspaper of general circulation within the county or, if no such newspaper is published within the county, notice shall be placed on the courthouse door and two other prominent places within the county. Such notice shall indicate:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a list maintained by the property appraiser of all applicants for exemption who have had their applications for exemption wholly or partially approved is available to the public, at a location specified in the notice, and the hours during which the list may be seen. The notice shall further indicate, by name, the types of exemptions which are included in the list.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">That a list maintained by the property appraiser of all applicants for exemption who have had their applications for exemption denied is available to the public, at a location specified in the notice, and the hours during which the list may be seen. The notice shall further indicate, by name, the types of exemptions which are included in the list.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The exemption procedures of the value adjustment board shall be as provided in chapter 194, except as otherwise provided in this chapter. Records of the value adjustment board showing the names of persons and organizations granted exemptions, the street address or other designation of location of the exempted property, and the extent of the exemptions granted shall be part of the public record.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 71-133; s. 1, ch. 76-122; s. 16, ch. 76-133; s. 62, ch. 80-274; s. 158, ch. 91-112.</History></Section>