<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0196.111" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Property appraisers may notify persons entitled to homestead exemption; publication of notice; costs.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As soon as practicable after February 5 of each current year, the property appraisers of the several counties may mail to each person to whom homestead exemption was granted for the year immediately preceding and whose application for exemption for the current year has not been filed as of February 1 thereof, a form for application for homestead exemption, together with a notice reading substantially as follows:</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignCenter" SpaceAbove="true">NOTICE TO TAXPAYERS ENTITLED<NewLine />TO HOMESTEAD EXEMPTION</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent" SpaceAbove="true">Records in this office indicate that you have not filed an application for homestead exemption for the current year.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">If you wish to claim such exemption, please fill out the enclosed form and file it with your property appraiser on or before March 1, <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Indent">Failure to do so may constitute a waiver of said exemption for the year <Directions xml:space="preserve">(year)</Directions>.</Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true"><Directions xml:space="preserve">(Property Appraiser)</Directions></Text><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="AlignRight" SpaceAbove="true" SpaceBelow="true"><HorizontalRule Type="Fixed" /> County, Florida</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The expenditure of funds for any of the requirements of this section is hereby declared to be for a county purpose; and the board of county commissioners of each county shall, if notices are mailed under subsection (1), appropriate and provide the necessary funds for such purposes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 67-534; ss. 1, 2, ch. 69-55; s. 14, ch. 74-234; s. 1, ch. 77-102; s. 17, ch. 83-204; s. 2, ch. 85-315; s. 17, ch. 99-6.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 192.142.</Text></Note></Section>