<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0552.38" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Security requirement.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a prerequisite to obtaining or renewing a valid user license as required by s. 552.091(5)(a), or obtaining or renewing a valid license or permit under s. 552.30, a person who uses explosives in connection with construction materials mining activities must post and maintain a bond or letter of credit as security as required under subsection (2). Evidence that the bond has been posted and maintained in compliance with this section must be maintained by any licensee or permitholder for the use of explosives in connection with construction materials mining activities as part of the mandatory record maintenance requirements of s. 552.112. The person must maintain, in a format approved by the Division of State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services, a completed form that shows the amount and location of the bond or identifies the bond surety and the current bond value.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The bond or letter of credit required under subsection (1) must be in an amount not less than $100,000, notwithstanding an award made by an administrative law judge under s. 552.40(7). In the case of a multiple licenseholder or multiple permitholder, a single bond in the aggregate amount of not less than $100,000 may be provided as security for the individual permits or licenses. If the user of explosives has not been identified as a respondent in any pending claim for damages under this chapter, and if renewal of the license or permit is not sought, the bond required under this section may be released upon the expiration of the license or permit or 181 days after the final use of explosives under the license, whichever occurs later, if the bond to be released is not security for other permits.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal may adopt rules for the administration of this section.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 5, ch. 2003-62.</History></Section>