<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0552.094" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of licenses, permits; prohibitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each license issued by the division shall set forth, as a minimum, the full name, date of birth, and physical description of the licensee; the purpose for which the license is to be used in relation to explosives; the type of explosives to be manufactured, distributed, or used; a license number; and any restrictions placed upon the licensee by the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each permit issued by the division shall set forth, as a minimum, the full name, date of birth, and physical description of the permittee; the purpose for which the permit is to be used in relation to explosives; a permit number; the name and license number of the user employing such blaster; and any restrictions placed upon the permittee by the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A blaster’s permit shall be valid solely for use by the holder thereof in the course of her or his employment by the licensed user named therein.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may, in its discretion, include other information and data in the license or permit.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No license or permit shall be issued, renewed, or be allowed to remain in effect for any natural person:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under 21 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been convicted of a felony and has not been pardoned or had her or his civil rights restored.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been adjudicated mentally incompetent and has not had her or his civil rights restored.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No license or permit shall be issued to any person by the division pursuant to an application unless the division shall determine from the information set forth in the application that the purpose for which the applicant seeks the permit or license falls within the purview of this chapter and that such purpose is not violative of any other laws of the state.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person knowingly to withhold information or present to the division any false, fictitious, or misrepresented application, identification, document, information, or data intended or likely to deceive the division for the purpose of obtaining a license or permit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 6, ch. 77-84; s. 6, ch. 89-233; s. 793, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>