<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0552.30" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Construction materials mining activities.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding the provisions of s. 552.25, the State Fire Marshal shall have the sole and exclusive authority to promulgate standards, limits, and regulations regarding the use of explosives in conjunction with construction materials mining activities. Such authority to regulate use shall include, directly or indirectly, the operation, handling, licensure, or permitting of explosives and setting standards or limits, including, but not limited to, ground vibration, frequency, intensity, blast pattern, air blast and time, date, occurrence, and notice restrictions. As used in this section, “construction materials mining activities” means the extraction of limestone and sand suitable for production of construction aggregates, sand, cement, and road base materials for shipment offsite by any person or company primarily engaged in the commercial mining of any such natural resources.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The State Fire Marshal shall establish statewide ground vibration limits for construction materials mining activities which conform to those limits established in the United States Bureau of Mines, Report of Investigations 8507, Appendix B - Alternative Blasting Level Criteria (Figure B-1). The State Fire Marshal may, at his or her sole discretion, by rule or formal agreement, delegate to the applicable municipality or county, the monitoring and enforcement components of regulations governing the use of explosives, as recognized in this section, by construction materials mining activities. Such delegation may include the assessment and collection of reasonable fees by the municipality or county for the purpose of carrying out the delegated activities.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 30, ch. 2000-266; s. 1, ch. 2003-62.</History></Section>