<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0552.081" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Definitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As used in this chapter:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Explosive materials” means explosives, blasting agents, or detonators.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Explosives” means any chemical compound, mixture, or device, the primary purpose of which is to function by explosion. The term “explosives” includes, but is not limited to, dynamite, nitroglycerin, trinitrotoluene, other high explosives, black powder, pellet powder, initiating explosives, detonators, safety fuses, squibs, detonating cord, igniter cord, and igniters. “Explosives” does not include cartridges for firearms and does not include fireworks as defined in chapter 791.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Blasting agent” means any material or mixture, consisting of fuel and oxidizer, intended for blasting and not otherwise defined as an explosive, provided the finished product, ready for use or shipment, cannot be detonated by means of a number 8 test blasting cap when unconfined.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Detonator” means any device containing a detonating charge that is used for initiating detonation of an explosive and includes, but is not limited to, blasting caps and electric blasting caps of instantaneous and delay types.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Person” means any natural person, partnership, association, or corporation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer-distributor” means a person engaged in the manufacture, compounding, combining, production, or distribution of explosives.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Dealer” means a person engaged in the wholesale or retail business of buying and selling explosives.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“User” means a dealer or manufacturer-distributor who uses an explosive as an ultimate consumer or a person who, as an ultimate consumer of an explosive, purchases such explosive from a dealer or manufacturer-distributor.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Blaster” means a person employed by a user who detonates or otherwise effects the explosion of an explosive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Sale” and its various forms includes delivery of an explosive with or without consideration.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Highway” means any public highway in this state, including public streets, alleys, and other thoroughfares, by whatever name, in any municipality.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Manufacturer’s mark” means the mark placed on each carton of and each individual piece of explosive by the manufacturer to identify the manufacturer and the location, date, and shift of manufacture.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Two-component explosives” means any two inert components which, when mixed, become capable of detonation by a No. 6 blasting cap, and shall be classified as a Class “A” explosive when so mixed.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Division” means the Division of State Fire Marshal of the Department of Financial Services.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Purchase” and its various forms means acquisition of any explosive by a person with or without consideration.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 29944, 1955; ss. 1, 2, ch. 59-83; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 205, ch. 71-377; s. 2, ch. 77-84; s. 658, ch. 2003-261.</History></Section>