<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0552.091" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">License or permit required of manufacturer-distributor, dealer, user, or blaster of explosives.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It shall be unlawful for any person to engage in the business of a manufacturer-distributor or to acquire, sell, possess, store, or engage in the use of explosives in this state, except in conformity with the provisions of this chapter.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each manufacturer-distributor, dealer, user, or blaster must be possessed of a valid and subsisting license or permit issued by the division, except that if a manufacturer-distributor makes sales to users, such manufacturer shall not be required to obtain an additional license as a dealer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In the case of multiple locations for storage of explosives, each manufacturer-distributor, dealer, or user maintaining more than one permanent storage magazine location shall possess an additional license, as herein set forth, for each such location.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer-distributor of two-component explosives is required to purchase a manufacturer-distributor explosive license. Dealers of two-component explosives are required to purchase a dealer’s explosive license. A user’s explosive license is required of any person to purchase, mix, or use two-component explosives from a dealer or manufacturer-distributor. A blaster’s explosive permit is required of any person employed by a user to mix, detonate, or otherwise effect the explosion of two-component explosives, provided that a user who is a natural person is not required to obtain a blaster’s permit in addition to the user’s license in order to mix, detonate, or otherwise effect the explosion of any explosive.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Licenses, permits, and fees therefor are required for each license year for the following:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Manufacturer-distributor license<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />$650</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Dealer license<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />450</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">User license<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />125</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Blaster permit<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />50</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Duplicate licenses or permits or address changes<FlushRight Fill="Dot" />5</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, no fee shall be required for a dealer license if the only explosive sold by the dealer is black powder for recreational use.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Said licenses and permits shall be issued by the division for each license year beginning October 1 and expiring the following September 30.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 2, ch. 29944, 1955; s. 1, ch. 57-184; s. 3, ch. 59-83; s. 1, ch. 65-59; ss. 13, 35, ch. 69-106; s. 3, ch. 77-84; s. 1, ch. 80-169; s. 3, ch. 89-233.</History></Section>