<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0552.092" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Forms for applications for licenses and permits.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The forms for applications for explosives licenses and permits shall be prescribed by the division.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application for a license required under this chapter shall be filed in writing with the division. Each application for a license shall require, as a minimum, the full name, date of birth, place of birth, social security number, physical description, residence address, and business address of the applicant; the types of explosives to be manufactured, distributed, or used by the applicant; and the purpose for which the license is sought in relation to explosives. Each application shall be accompanied by an accurate and current photograph of the applicant and a complete set of fingerprints of the applicant taken by an authorized law enforcement officer, unless the applicant has possessed a valid license during the prior license year and such license has not lapsed or been suspended or revoked. If fingerprints are required, the set of fingerprints shall be accompanied by a processing fee to be established by rule, which fee shall defray the costs of processing to the division, and such fingerprints shall be submitted by the division to the Department of Law Enforcement for state processing and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for federal processing. If the application does not require a set of fingerprints, the division shall submit the name of the applicant to the Department of Law Enforcement for processing. Each application shall be in such form as to provide that the data and other information set forth therein shall be sworn to by the applicant or, if the applicant is a corporation, the application shall be sworn to by an officer thereof. The officer applying on behalf of a corporation shall provide all the information and data, and meet all other requirements, which are required for a natural person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each application for a permit required under this chapter shall be filed in writing with the division. Each application for a permit shall require, as a minimum, the full name, date of birth, place of birth, social security number, physical description, and residence address of the applicant and the name and the license number of the user employing such blaster. Each application shall be accompanied by an accurate and current photograph of the applicant and a complete set of fingerprints of the applicant taken by an authorized law enforcement officer, unless the applicant has possessed a valid permit during the prior permit year and such permit has not lapsed or been suspended or revoked. If fingerprints are required, the set of fingerprints shall be accompanied by a processing fee to be established by rule, which fee shall defray the costs of processing to the division, and such fingerprints shall be submitted by the division to the Department of Law Enforcement for state processing and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for federal processing. If the application does not require a set of fingerprints, the division shall submit the name of the applicant to the Department of Law Enforcement for processing. Each application shall be in such form as to provide that the data and other information set forth therein shall be sworn to by the applicant.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The division may require any applicant to furnish such other information or data not required by this section if such information or data is deemed necessary.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 77-84; s. 20, ch. 79-8; s. 1, ch. 79-174; s. 4, ch. 89-233.</History></Section>