<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0552.22" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who manufactures, purchases, transports, keeps, stores, possesses, distributes, sells, or uses any explosive with the intent to harm life, limb, or property is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084. Manufacturing, purchasing, possessing, distributing, or selling an explosive under circumstances contrary to the provisions of this chapter or such regulations as are adopted pursuant thereto shall be prima facie evidence of an intent to use the explosive for destruction of life, limb, or property.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who possesses any explosive material, knowing or having reasonable cause to believe that such explosive material was stolen, is guilty of a felony of the third degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly withholds information or presents to the division any false, fictitious, or misrepresented application, identification, document, information, statement, or data, intended or likely to deceive, for the purpose of obtaining an explosives license or permit is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly withholds information or makes any false or fictitious entry or misrepresentation upon any records required by s. 552.111 or s. 552.112 is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is the holder of an explosives license or permit and who fails to report the loss, theft, or unexplained shortage of any explosive material as required by s. 552.113 is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who violates any order, rule, or regulation of the division, an order to cease and desist, or an order to correct conditions issued pursuant to this chapter is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who is the holder of an explosives license or permit and who abandons any explosive material is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license or permit of any person convicted of violating subsection (1) or subsection (2) is automatically and permanently revoked upon such conviction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The license or permit of any person convicted of violating subsection (3), subsection (4), subsection (5), subsection (6), or subsection (7) is automatically revoked upon such conviction, and the division shall not issue a license or permit to such person for 2 years from the date of such conviction.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person who knowingly possesses an explosive in violation of the provisions of s. 552.101 is guilty of a misdemeanor of the first degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 7, ch. 29944, 1955; s. 9, ch. 59-83; s. 2, ch. 65-59; s. 548, ch. 71-136; s. 21, ch. 77-84; s. 224, ch. 79-400; s. 1, ch. 84-17; s. 145, ch. 91-224.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Former s. 552.14.</Text></Note></Section>