<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0573.108" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Findings required to issue marketing order.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">After notice and hearing, the department shall issue a marketing order if it finds and sets forth that the order will tend to accomplish the objectives and purposes of ss. 573.101-573.124, and:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions are necessary in order to effect a reasonable correlation of the supply of agricultural commodities affected with market demands therefor and the marketing order or amendments thereto will tend to reestablish or maintain a level of prices for agricultural commodities which will provide a purchasing power for the commodities adequate to maintain sufficient producers as are required to provide such supply of the quantities and qualities of agricultural commodities necessary to fulfill the normal requirements of consumers.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The marketing order or amendments thereto will tend to approach equality of purchasing power at as rapid a rate as is feasible in view of the market demand for agricultural commodities.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The marketing order or amendments thereto are in conformity with the provisions of ss. 573.101-573.124 and will tend to effectuate the declared purposes and policies of ss. 573.101-573.124.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The marketing order or amendments thereto will protect the interests of consumers of agricultural commodities by exercising the powers of ss. 573.101-573.124 only to the extent necessary to establish the equality of purchasing power described in subsection (1).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provided that no marketing order would be issued wherein the commodity addressed is subject to regulation by any other state agency unless a memorandum of agreement is executed between the department and the regulating agency.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 8, 26, ch. 87-171; s. 4, ch. 91-429.</History></Section>