<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0296.14" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Personal property; deceased residents; residents leaving.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any resident of the home may deposit personal property other than money with the administrator for safekeeping. The property must be returned to the depositor upon demand, and a written statement of acceptance must be executed by the depositor under oath.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator or the administrator’s designee must maintain an itemized record of the deposit of personal property which contains, but need not be limited to, the name of the depositor, the date of deposit, a description of the article or articles deposited, the disposition of the article or articles, and the date of disposition.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The personal property of a deceased resident which is not otherwise provided for may be held for the heirs, devisees, or legatees for a period of 1 year after the date of the resident’s death. The personal property of a resident who is discharged or voluntarily leaves may be held for the resident or for his or her heirs, devisees, or legatees for a period of 1 year after the date of discharge or departure.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator may make a monthly charge for the safekeeping of unclaimed personal property. If the charge is not paid, a lien upon the property to secure its payment accrues to the home.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The administrator shall cause a public sale to be held when in the judgment of the administrator the probable value of the property exceeds the probable cost of the sale. All cost incurred in the sale of the unclaimed personal property must be reimbursed to the home along with any lien on the property. All unclaimed funds must be disposed of in accordance with chapter 717.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 8, ch. 89-168; s. 258, ch. 95-148; s. 12, ch. 98-16.</History></Section>