<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0296.36" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Eligibility and priority of admittance.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">To be eligible for admittance to the home, the person must be a veteran as provided in s. 1.01(14) or have eligible peacetime service as defined in s. 296.02 and must:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Be in need of nursing home care.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have been a resident of the state for 1 year immediately preceding, and at the time of application for, admission to the home.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Not owe money to the department for services rendered during any previous stay at a department facility.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have applied for all financial assistance reasonably available through governmental sources.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Have been approved as eligible for care and treatment by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The director may waive the residency requirement for a veteran who is otherwise eligible under Florida law for admittance to a home. The waiver must be limited to a veteran who is a disaster evacuee of a state that is under a declared state of emergency.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Admittance priority must be given to eligible veterans in the following order of priority:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An eligible veteran who is a resident of the State of Florida.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An eligible veteran who has a service-connected disability as determined by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, or was discharged or released from military service for disability incurred or aggravated in the line of duty and the disability is the condition for which nursing home care is needed.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An eligible veteran who has a non-service-connected disability and is unable to defray the expense of nursing home care and so states under oath before a notary public or other officer authorized to administer an oath.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 14, ch. 92-80; s. 16, ch. 98-16; s. 2, ch. 2000-282; s. 1, ch. 2006-239; s. 4, ch. 2010-177.</History>
</Section>