<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0499.73" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Suspension or revocation of license or permit.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The violation of any provision of this part, any rule adopted pursuant thereto, or any cease and desist order issued by the department by a licensee or permittee as provided in this part shall be cause for revocation or suspension of all licenses or permits held by such licensee or permittee after the department has determined the licensee or permittee to be guilty of such violation.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds the licensee or permittee to be guilty of such violation, it shall enter its order suspending or revoking the license or permit of the person charged. An order of suspension shall state the period of time of such suspension, which period shall not be in excess of 1 year from the date of such order. An order of revocation may be entered for a period not exceeding 5 years; such order shall effect the revocation of all licenses or permits then held by the person charged, and during such period no license or permit shall be issued to said person. If, during the period between the beginning of proceedings and the entry of an order of suspension or revocation by the department, a new license or permit has been issued to the person charged, any order of suspension or revocation shall operate effectively with respect to the new license or permit held by such person.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any person or office of a corporation whose permit or license has been suspended or revoked shall not be issued a new permit or license under any other name or company name until the expiration of the suspension or revocation in which she or he has been involved.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The provisions of this section are cumulative and shall not affect the administrative fine and injunction provisions of ss. 499.72 and 499.76.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 11, ch. 86-133; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 600, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>