<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0499.062" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Seizure and condemnation of drugs, devices, or cosmetics.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any article of any drug, device, or cosmetic that is adulterated or misbranded under this part is subject to seizure and condemnation by the department or by its duly authorized agents designated for that purpose in regard to drugs, devices, or cosmetics.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Whenever a duly authorized officer or employee of the department finds cause, or has probable cause to believe that cause exists, for the seizure of any drug, device, or cosmetic, as set out in this part, he or she shall affix to the article a tag, stamp, or other appropriate marking, giving notice that the article is, or is suspected of being, subject to seizure under this part and that the article has been detained and seized by the department. Such officer or employee shall also warn all persons not to remove or dispose of the article, by sale or otherwise, until permission is given by the department or the court. Any person who violates this subsection is guilty of a felony of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When any article detained or seized under this subsection has been found by the department to be subject to seizure and condemnation, the department shall petition the court for an order of condemnation or sale, as the court directs. The proceeds of the sale of drugs, devices, and cosmetics, less the legal costs and charges, shall be deposited into the Professional Regulation Trust Fund.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the department finds that any article seized under this subsection was not subject to seizure, the department or the designated officer or employee shall remove the tag or marking.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 1, ch. 83-265; ss. 42, 43, 44, 52, ch. 92-69; s. 593, ch. 97-103; s. 33, ch. 2008-207; s. 15, ch. 2012-143.</History>
	<Note>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (2) intro. former s. 499.063; paragraphs (2)(a), (b) former s. 499.064.</Text>
	</Note>
</Section>