<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0499.015" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Registration of drugs, devices, and cosmetics; issuance of certificates of free sale.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for those persons exempted from the definition of manufacturer in s. 499.003(31), any person who manufactures, packages, repackages, labels, or relabels a drug, device, or cosmetic in this state must register such drug, device, or cosmetic biennially with the department; pay a fee in accordance with the fee schedule provided by s. 499.041; and comply with this section. The registrant must list each separate and distinct drug, device, or cosmetic at the time of registration.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may not register any product that does not comply with the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as amended, or Title 21 C.F.R. Registration of a product by the department does not mean that the product does in fact comply with all provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as amended.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may require the submission of a catalog and specimens of labels at the time of application for registration of drugs, devices, and cosmetics packaged and prepared in compliance with the federal act, which submission constitutes a satisfactory compliance for registration of the products. With respect to all other drugs, devices, and cosmetics, the department may require the submission of a catalog and specimens of labels at the time of application for registration, but the registration will not become effective until the department has examined and approved the label of the drug, device, or cosmetic product. This approval or denial must include written notification to the manufacturer.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Except for those persons exempted from the definition of manufacturer in s. 499.003(31), a person may not sell any product that he or she has failed to register in conformity with this section. Such failure to register subjects such drug, device, or cosmetic product to seizure and condemnation as provided in s. 499.062, and subjects such person to the penalties and remedies provided in this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Unless a registration is renewed, it expires 2 years after the last day of the month in which it was issued. The department may issue a stop-sale notice or order against a person that is subject to the requirements of this section and that fails to comply with this section within 31 days after the date the registration expires. The notice or order shall prohibit such person from selling or causing to be sold any drugs, devices, or cosmetics covered by this part until he or she complies with the requirements of this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A product regulated under this section which is not included in the biennial registration may not be sold until it is registered and complies with this section.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue a certificate of free sale for any product that is required to be registered under this part.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A product registration is valid only for the company named on the registration and located at the address on the registration. A person whose product is registered by the department under this section must notify the department before any change in the name or address of the establishment to which the product is registered. If a person whose product is registered ceases conducting business, the person must notify the department before closing the business.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding any requirements set forth in this part, a manufacturer of medical devices that is registered with the federal Food and Drug Administration is exempt from this section and s. 499.041(6) if:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer’s medical devices are approved for marketing by, or listed with the federal Food and Drug Administration in accordance with federal law for commercial distribution; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The manufacturer subcontracts with a manufacturer of medical devices to manufacture components of such devices.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">However, the manufacturer must submit evidence of such registration, listing, or approval with its initial application for a permit to do business in this state, as required in s. 499.01 and any changes to such information previously submitted at the time of renewal of the permit. Evidence of approval, listing, and registration by the federal Food and Drug Administration must include:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For Class II devices, a copy of the premarket notification letter (510K);</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For Class III devices, a Federal Drug Administration premarket approval number;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a manufacturer who subcontracts with a manufacturer of medical devices to manufacture components of such devices, a Federal Drug Administration registration number; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For a manufacturer of medical devices whose devices are exempt from premarket approval by the Federal Drug Administration, a Federal Drug Administration registration number.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 110, ch. 83-218; s. 1, ch. 83-265; s. 3, ch. 84-115; ss. 20, 52, ch. 92-69; s. 587, ch. 97-103; s. 36, ch. 98-151; s. 1, ch. 99-165; s. 41, ch. 2000-242; s. 12, ch. 2000-326; s. 18, ch. 2001-63; s. 33, ch. 2001-89; s. 88, ch. 2004-5; s. 18, ch. 2008-207; s. 63, ch. 2009-21.</History></Section>