<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0499.002" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Purpose, administration, and enforcement of and exemption from this part.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part is intended to:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Safeguard the public health and promote the public welfare by protecting the public from injury by product use and by merchandising deceit involving drugs, devices, and cosmetics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Provide uniform legislation to be administered so far as practicable in conformity with the provisions of, and regulations issued under the authority of, the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and that portion of the Federal Trade Commission Act which expressly prohibits the false advertisement of drugs, devices, and cosmetics.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Promote thereby uniformity of such state and federal laws, and their administration and enforcement, throughout the United States.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall administer and enforce this part to prevent fraud, adulteration, misbranding, or false advertising in the preparation, manufacture, repackaging, or distribution of drugs, devices, and cosmetics.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purpose of any investigation or proceeding conducted by the department under this part, the department may administer oaths, take depositions, issue and serve subpoenas, and compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, documents, or other evidence. The department shall exercise this power on its own initiative. Challenges to, and enforcement of, the subpoenas and orders shall be handled as provided in s. 120.569.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each state attorney, county attorney, or municipal attorney to whom the department or its designated agent reports any violation of this part shall cause appropriate proceedings to be instituted in the proper courts without delay and to be prosecuted in the manner required by law.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">This part does not require the department to report, for the institution of proceedings under this part, minor violations of this part when it believes that the public interest will be adequately served in the circumstances by a suitable written notice or warning.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Common carriers engaged in interstate commerce are not subject to this part if they are engaged in the usual course of business as common carriers.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 1, ch. 83-265; ss. 2, 3, ch. 86-133; s. 2, ch. 87-50; ss. 2, 4, 6, 48, 49, 50, 52, ch. 92-69; s. 240, ch. 96-410; s. 236, ch. 99-8; s. 1, ch. 2008-207.</History><Note><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Subsection (2) former s. 499.004; subsection (3) former s. 499.0053; subsection (4) former s. 499.07; subsection (5) former s. 499.071; subsection (6) former s. 499.081.</Text></Note></Section>