<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0499.066" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Penalties; remedies.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In addition to other penalties and other enforcement provisions:</Text>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may institute such suits or other legal proceedings as are required to enforce any provision of this part. If it appears that a person has violated any provision of this part for which criminal prosecution is provided, the department may provide the appropriate state attorney or other prosecuting agency having jurisdiction with respect to such prosecution with the relevant information in the department’s possession.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any person engaged in any activity covered by this part violates any provision of this part, any rule adopted under this part, or a cease and desist order as provided by this part, the department may obtain an injunction in the circuit court of the county in which the violation occurred or in which the person resides or has its principal place of business, and may apply in that court for such temporary and permanent orders as the department considers necessary to restrain the person from engaging in any such activities until the person complies with this part, the rules adopted under this part, and the orders of the department authorized by this part or to mandate compliance with this part, the rules adopted under this part, and any order or permit issued by the department under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may impose an administrative fine, not to exceed $5,000 per violation per day, for the violation of any provision of this part or rules adopted under this part. Each day a violation continues constitutes a separate violation, and each separate violation is subject to a separate fine. All amounts collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the Professional Regulation Trust Fund and are appropriated for the use of the department in administering this part. In determining the amount of the fine to be levied for a violation, the department shall consider:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The severity of the violation;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any actions taken by the person to correct the violation or to remedy complaints; and</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Any previous violations.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deposit any rewards, fines, or collections that are due the department and which derive from joint enforcement activities with other state and federal agencies which relate to this part, chapter 893, or the federal act, into the Professional Regulation Trust Fund. The proceeds of those rewards, fines, and collections are appropriated for the use of the department in administering this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue an emergency order immediately suspending or revoking a permit if it determines that any condition in the establishment presents a danger to the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may issue an emergency order to immediately remove from commerce and public access any drug, device, or cosmetic, if the department determines that the drug, device, or cosmetic presents a clear and present danger to the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Resignation or termination of an affiliated party does not affect the department’s jurisdiction or discretion to proceed with action to suspend or revoke a permit or to impose other penalties or enforcement actions authorized by law.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 26, ch. 82-402; s. 117, ch. 83-218; s. 1, ch. 83-265; s. 7, ch. 86-133; s. 3, ch. 86-271; ss. 45, 52, ch. 92-69; ss. 4, 5, 8, ch. 94-309; s. 24, ch. 2003-155; s. 35, ch. 2008-207; s. 16, ch. 2012-143.</History>
</Section>