<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0499.008" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Adulterated cosmetics.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A cosmetic is adulterated:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it bears or contains any poisonous or deleterious substance that is injurious to users under the conditions of use prescribed in the labeling or advertisement thereof or under such conditions of use as are customary or usual; however, this subsection does not apply to coal-tar hair dye:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The label of which bears the following legend conspicuously displayed thereon: “Caution: This product contains ingredients which may cause skin irritation on certain individuals, and a preliminary test according to accompanying directions should first be made. This product must not be used for dyeing the eyelashes or eyebrows; to do so may cause blindness”; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The labeling of which bears adequate directions for such preliminary testing.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it consists in whole or in part of any filthy, putrid, or decomposed substance.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it has been produced, prepared, packed, or held under conditions whereby it could have become contaminated with filth or whereby it could have been rendered injurious to health.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is not a hair dye and it is, or it bears or contains, a color additive that is unsafe within the meaning of the federal act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">For the purposes of subsections (1) and (4), the term “hair dye” does not include eyelash dyes or eyebrow dyes.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 1, ch. 83-265; ss. 12, 52, ch. 92-69; s. 8, ch. 2008-207.</History></Section>