<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0499.067" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Denial, suspension, or revocation of permit, certification, or registration.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke a permit if it finds that there has been a substantial failure to comply with this part or chapter 465, chapter 501, or chapter 893, the rules adopted under this part or those chapters, any final order of the department, or applicable federal laws or regulations or other state laws or rules governing drugs, devices, or cosmetics.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny an application for a permit or certification, or suspend or revoke a permit or certification, if the department finds that:</Text>
				<SubParagraph Id="1">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is not of good moral character or that it would be a danger or not in the best interest of the public health, safety, and welfare if the applicant were issued a permit or certification.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="2">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant has not met the requirements for the permit or certification.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="3">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant is not eligible for a permit or certification for any of the reasons enumerated in s. 499.012.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="4">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant, permittee, or person certified under s. 499.012(16) demonstrates any of the conditions enumerated in s. 499.012.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
				<SubParagraph Id="5">
					<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The applicant, permittee, or person certified under s. 499.012(16) has committed any violation of ss. 499.005-499.0054.</Text>
				</SubParagraph>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke any registration required by the provisions of this part for the violation of any provision of this part or of any rules adopted under this part.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may revoke or suspend a permit:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the permit was obtained by misrepresentation or fraud or through a mistake of the department;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the permit was procured, or attempted to be procured, for any other person by making or causing to be made any false representation; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the permittee has violated any provision of this part or rules adopted under this part.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any permit issued under this part is revoked or suspended, the owner, manager, operator, or proprietor of the establishment shall cease to operate as the permit authorized, from the effective date of the suspension or revocation until the person is again registered with the department and possesses the required permit. If a permit is revoked or suspended, the owner, manager, or proprietor shall remove all signs and symbols that identify the operation as premises permitted as a drug wholesaling establishment; drug, device, or cosmetic manufacturing establishment; or retail establishment. The department shall determine the length of time for which the permit is to be suspended. If a permit is revoked, the person that owns or operates the establishment may not apply for any permit under this part for a period of 1 year after the date of the revocation. A revocation of a permit may be permanent if the department considers that to be in the best interest of the public health.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="5">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke a permit issued under this part which authorizes the permittee to purchase prescription drugs if any owner, officer, employee, or other person who participates in administering or operating the establishment has been found guilty of any violation of this part or chapter 465, chapter 501, or chapter 893, any rules adopted under this part or those chapters, or any federal or state drug law, regardless of whether the person has been pardoned, had her or his civil rights restored, or had adjudication withheld.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="6">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department shall deny, suspend, or revoke the permit of any person or establishment if the assignment, sale, transfer, or lease of an establishment permitted under this part will avoid an administrative penalty, civil action, or criminal prosecution.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="7">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notwithstanding s. 120.60(5), if a permittee fails to comply with s. 499.012(6), the department may revoke the permit of the permittee and shall provide notice of the intended agency action by posting a notice at the department’s headquarters and by mailing a copy of the notice of intended agency action by certified mail to the most recent mailing address on record with the department and, if the permittee is not a natural person, to the permittee’s registered agent on file with the Department of State.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="8">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke a permit if it finds the permittee has not complied with the credentialing requirements of s. 499.0121(15).</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="9">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may deny, suspend, or revoke a permit if it finds the permittee has not complied with the reporting requirements of, or knowingly made a false statement in a report required by, s. 499.0121(14).</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 1, ch. 83-265; s. 8, ch. 86-133; ss. 12, 14, ch. 88-159; s. 4, ch. 89-296; ss. 46, 52, ch. 92-69; s. 44, ch. 95-144; s. 594, ch. 97-103; s. 17, ch. 2000-326; s. 26, ch. 2003-155; s. 37, ch. 2008-207; s. 20, ch. 2011-141.</History>
</Section>