<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Section Number="0499.03" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd">
	<Catchline xml:space="preserve">Possession of certain drugs without prescriptions unlawful; exemptions and exceptions.</Catchline>
	<SectionBody>
		<Subsection Id="1">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person may not possess, or possess with intent to sell, dispense, or deliver, any habit-forming, toxic, harmful, or new drug subject to s. 499.003(33), or prescription drug as defined in s. 499.003(43), unless the possession of the drug has been obtained by a valid prescription of a practitioner licensed by law to prescribe the drug. However, this section does not apply to the delivery of such drugs to persons included in any of the classes named in this subsection, or to the agents or employees of such persons, for use in the usual course of their businesses or practices or in the performance of their official duties, as the case may be; nor does this section apply to the possession of such drugs by those persons or their agents or employees for such use:</Text>
			<Paragraph Id="a">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed pharmacist or any person under the licensed pharmacist’s supervision while acting within the scope of the licensed pharmacist’s practice;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="b">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed practitioner authorized by law to prescribe prescription drugs or any person under the licensed practitioner’s supervision while acting within the scope of the licensed practitioner’s practice;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="c">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A qualified person who uses prescription drugs for lawful research, teaching, or testing, and not for resale;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="d">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A licensed hospital or other institution that procures such drugs for lawful administration or dispensing by practitioners;</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="e">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An officer or employee of a federal, state, or local government; or</Text>
			</Paragraph>
			<Paragraph Id="f">
				<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A person that holds a valid permit issued by the department pursuant to this part which authorizes that person to possess prescription drugs.</Text>
			</Paragraph>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="2">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The possession of a drug under subsection (1) by any person not exempted under this section, which drug is not properly labeled to indicate that possession is by a valid prescription of a practitioner licensed by law to prescribe such drug, is prima facie evidence that such possession is unlawful.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="3">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Violation of subsection (1) is a misdemeanor of the second degree, punishable as provided in s. 775.082 or s. 775.083, except that possession with the intent to sell, dispense, or deliver is a third degree felony, punishable as provided in s. 775.082, s. 775.083, or s. 775.084.</Text>
		</Subsection>
		<Subsection Id="4">
			<Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may adopt rules regarding persons engaged in lawful teaching, research, or testing who possess prescription drugs and may issue letters of exemption to facilitate the lawful possession of prescription drugs under this section.</Text>
		</Subsection>
	</SectionBody>
	<History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 1, ch. 83-265; s. 5, ch. 84-115; s. 75, ch. 87-243; ss. 30, 52, ch. 92-69; s. 37, ch. 98-151; s. 43, ch. 2000-242; s. 14, ch. 2000-326; s. 19, ch. 2001-63; s. 89, ch. 2004-5; s. 22, ch. 2008-207; s. 42, ch. 2010-161.</History>
</Section>