<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0499.64" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Issuance of licenses and permits; prohibitions.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Each license and permit issued by the department shall set forth, as a minimum, the full name, date of birth, and physical description of the licensee or permittee and shall have permanently affixed an accurate and current photograph of the licensee or permittee. A license or permit issued to a corporation shall set forth the full name, date of birth, and physical description of the chief executive officer and/or resident agent residing in this state and shall have permanently affixed an accurate and current photograph of the chief executive officer and/or resident agent residing in this state. Each license and permit shall also contain a license or permit number.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The department may, in its discretion, include other data or information in the license or permit when deemed appropriate.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">No license or permit shall be issued, renewed, or allowed to remain in effect for any natural person, or for any corporation which has any corporate officer:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Under 18 years of age.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been convicted of a felony under the prescription drug or controlled substance laws of this state or any other state or federal jurisdiction, regardless of whether he or she has been pardoned or had his or her civil rights restored.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been convicted of any felony other than a felony under the prescription drug or controlled substance laws of this state or any other state or federal jurisdiction and has not been pardoned or had his or her civil rights restored.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Who has been adjudicated mentally incompetent and has not had his or her civil rights restored.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">It is unlawful for any person to knowingly withhold information or present to the department any false, fictitious, or misrepresented application, identification, document, information, or data intended or likely to deceive the department for the purpose of obtaining a license or permit.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">ss. 10, 11, ch. 86-133; s. 4, ch. 91-429; s. 597, ch. 97-103.</History></Section>