<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0499.007" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Misbranded drug or device.</Catchline><SectionBody><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A drug or device is misbranded:</Text><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its labeling is in any way false or misleading.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If in package form, it does not bear a label containing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and place of business of the manufacturer, repackager, or distributor of the finished dosage form of the drug. For the purpose of this paragraph, the finished dosage form of a prescription drug is that form of the drug which is, or is intended to be, dispensed or administered to the patient and requires no further manufacturing or processing other than packaging, reconstitution, and labeling; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or numerical count. However, under this section, reasonable variations are permitted, and the department shall establish by rule exemptions for small packages.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is an active pharmaceutical ingredient in bulk form and does not bear a label containing:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The name and place of business of the manufacturer, repackager, or distributor; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or numerical count.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If any word, statement, or other information required by or under this part to appear on the label or labeling is not prominently placed thereon with such conspicuousness as compared with other words, statements, designs, or devices in the labeling, and in such terms, as to render the word, statement, or other information likely to be read and understood under customary conditions of purchase and use.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a drug and is not designated solely by a name recognized in an official compendium and its label does not bear:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The common or usual name of the drug, if any; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In case it is fabricated from two or more ingredients, the common or usual name and quantity of each active ingredient.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If its labeling does not bear:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adequate directions for use; and</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Adequate warnings against use in those pathological conditions in which its use may be dangerous to health or against use by children if its use may be dangerous to health, or against unsafe dosage or methods or duration of administration or application, in such manner and form as are necessary for the protection of users.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it purports to be a drug the name of which is recognized in the official compendium and it is not packaged and labeled as prescribed therein. However, the method of packaging may be modified with the consent of the department.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it has been found by the department to be a drug liable to deterioration and it is not packaged in such form and manner, and its label bears a statement of such precautions, as the department by rule requires as necessary to protect the public health. Such rule may not be established for any drug recognized in an official compendium until the department has informed the appropriate body charged with the revision of such compendium of the need for such packaging or labeling requirements and that body has failed within a reasonable time to prescribe such requirements.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="9"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A drug and its container or finished dosage form is so made, formed, or filled as to be misleading;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An imitation of another drug; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Offered for sale under the name of another drug.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="10"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is dangerous to health when used in the dosage or with the frequency or duration prescribed, recommended, or suggested in the labeling of the drug.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="11"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is, purports to be, or is represented as a drug composed wholly or partly of insulin and it is not from a batch with respect to which a certificate has been issued pursuant to s. 506 of the federal act, which certificate is in effect with respect to the drug.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="12"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is, purports to be, or is represented as a drug composed wholly or partly of any kind of antibiotic requiring certification under the federal act and it is not from a batch with respect to which a certificate has been issued pursuant to s. 507 of the federal act, which certificate is in effect with respect to the drug. However, this subsection does not apply to any drug or class of drugs exempted by regulations adopted under s. 507(c) or (d) of the federal act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="13"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a drug intended for use by humans which is a habit-forming drug or which, because of its toxicity or other potentiality for harmful effect, or the method of its use, or the collateral measures necessary to its use, is not safe for use except under the supervision of a practitioner licensed by law to administer such drugs, or which is limited by an effective application under s. 505 of the federal act to use under the professional supervision of a practitioner licensed by law to prescribe such drug, if it is not dispensed only:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon the written prescription of a practitioner licensed by law to prescribe such drug;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon an oral prescription of such practitioner, which is reduced promptly to writing and filled by the pharmacist; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">By refilling any such written or oral prescription, if such refilling is authorized by the prescriber in the original prescription or by oral order which is reduced promptly to writing and filled by the pharmacist.</Text></Paragraph><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Reversion">This subsection does not relieve any person from any requirement prescribed by law with respect to controlled substances as defined in the applicable federal and state laws.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="14"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a drug that is subject to paragraph (13)(a), and if, at any time before it is dispensed, its label does not bear the statement:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Caution: Federal Law Prohibits Dispensing Without Prescription”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Rx Only”;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The prescription symbol followed by the word “Only”; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">“Caution: State Law Prohibits Dispensing Without Prescription.”</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="15"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a drug that is not subject to paragraph (13)(a), if at any time before it is dispensed its label bears the statement of caution required in subsection (14).</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="16"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If it is a color additive, the intended use of which in or on drugs is for the purpose of coloring only and its packaging and labeling are not in conformity with the packaging and labeling requirements that apply to such color additive and are prescribed under the federal act.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="17"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">A drug dispensed by filling or refilling a written or oral prescription of a practitioner licensed by law to prescribe such drug is exempt from the requirements of this section, except subsections (1), (9), (11), and (12) and the packaging requirements of subsections (7) and (8), if the drug bears a label that contains the name and address of the dispenser or seller, the prescription number and the date the prescription was written or filled, the name of the prescriber and the name of the patient, and the directions for use and cautionary statements. This exemption does not apply to any drug dispensed in the course of the conduct of a business of dispensing drugs pursuant to diagnosis by mail or to any drug dispensed in violation of subsection (13). The department may, by rule, exempt drugs subject to s. 499.062 from subsection (13) if compliance with that subsection is not necessary to protect the public health, safety, and welfare.</Text></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 34, ch. 82-225; s. 107, ch. 83-218; s. 1, ch. 83-265; s. 2, ch. 84-115; ss. 11, 52, ch. 92-69; s. 586, ch. 97-103; s. 38, ch. 99-397; s. 10, ch. 2003-155; s. 84, ch. 2004-5; s. 7, ch. 2008-207.</History></Section>