<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0120.63" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Exemption from act.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Upon application of any agency, the Administration Commission may exempt any process or proceeding governed by this act from one or more requirements of this act:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the agency head has certified that the requirement would conflict with any provision of federal law or rules with which the agency must comply;</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">In order to permit persons in the state to receive tax benefits or federal funds under any federal law; or</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">When the commission has found that conformity with the requirements of the part or parts of this act for which exemption is sought would be so inconvenient or impractical as to defeat the purpose of the agency proceeding involved or the purpose of this act and would not be in the public interest in light of the nature of the intended action and the enabling act or other laws affecting the agency.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The commission may not exempt an agency from any requirement of this act pursuant to this section until it establishes alternative procedures to achieve the agency’s purpose which shall be consistent, insofar as possible, with the intent and purpose of the act.</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prior to the granting of any exemption authorized by this section, the commission shall hold a public hearing after notice given as provided in s. 120.525. Upon the conclusion of the hearing, the commission, through the Executive Office of the Governor, shall issue an order specifically granting or denying the exemption and specifying any processes or proceedings exempted and the extent of the exemption; transmit to the committee and to the Department of State a copy of the petition, a certified copy of the order granting or denying the petition, and a copy of any alternative procedures prescribed; and give notice of the petition and the commission’s response in the Florida Administrative Weekly.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">An exemption and any alternative procedure prescribed shall terminate 90 days following adjournment sine die of the then-current or next regular legislative session after issuance of the exemption order, or upon the effective date of any subsequent legislation incorporating the exemption or any partial exemption related thereto, whichever is earlier. The exemption granted by the commission shall be renewable upon the same or similar facts not more than once. Such renewal shall terminate as would an original exemption.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 1, ch. 74-310; s. 11, ch. 76-131; s. 1, ch. 77-53; s. 8, ch. 77-453; s. 87, ch. 79-190; s. 7, ch. 79-299; s. 70, ch. 79-400; s. 58, ch. 81-259; s. 29, ch. 96-159.</History></Section>