<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Section Number="0120.545" xmlns="http://StatRev.xsd"><Catchline xml:space="preserve">Committee review of agency rules.</Catchline><SectionBody><Subsection Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">As a legislative check on legislatively created authority, the committee shall examine each proposed rule, except for those proposed rules exempted by s. 120.81(1)(e) and (2), and its accompanying material, and each emergency rule, and may examine any existing rule, for the purpose of determining whether:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule is an invalid exercise of delegated legislative authority.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The statutory authority for the rule has been repealed.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule reiterates or paraphrases statutory material.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule is in proper form.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="e"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The notice given prior to its adoption was sufficient to give adequate notice of the purpose and effect of the rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="f"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule is consistent with expressed legislative intent pertaining to the specific provisions of law which the rule implements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="g"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule is necessary to accomplish the apparent or expressed objectives of the specific provision of law which the rule implements.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="h"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule is a reasonable implementation of the law as it affects the convenience of the general public or persons particularly affected by the rule.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="i"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule could be made less complex or more easily comprehensible to the general public.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="j"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule’s statement of estimated regulatory costs complies with the requirements of s. 120.541 and whether the rule does not impose regulatory costs on the regulated person, county, or city which could be reduced by the adoption of less costly alternatives that substantially accomplish the statutory objectives.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="k"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The rule will require additional appropriations.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="l"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the rule is an emergency rule, there exists an emergency justifying the adoption of such rule, the agency is within its statutory authority, and the rule was adopted in compliance with the requirements and limitations of s. 120.54(4).</Text></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The committee may request from an agency such information as is reasonably necessary for examination of a rule as required by subsection (1). The committee shall consult with legislative standing committees having jurisdiction over the subject areas. If the committee objects to a rule, the committee shall, within 5 days after the objection, certify that fact to the agency whose rule has been examined and include with the certification a statement detailing its objections with particularity. The committee shall notify the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate of any objection to an agency rule concurrent with certification of that fact to the agency. Such notice shall include a copy of the rule and the statement detailing the committee’s objections to the rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after receipt of the objection, if the agency is headed by an individual, or within 45 days after receipt of the objection, if the agency is headed by a collegial body, the agency shall:</Text><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the rule is not yet in effect:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File notice pursuant to s. 120.54(3)(d) of only such modifications as are necessary to address the committee’s objection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File notice pursuant to s. 120.54(3)(d) of withdrawal of the rule; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the committee in writing that it refuses to modify or withdraw the rule.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the rule is in effect:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File notice pursuant to s. 120.54(3)(a), without prior notice of rule development, to amend the rule to address the committee’s objection;</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">File notice pursuant to s. 120.54(3)(a) to repeal the rule; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the committee in writing that the agency refuses to amend or repeal the rule.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the objection is to the statement of estimated regulatory costs:</Text><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Prepare a corrected statement of estimated regulatory costs, give notice of the availability of the corrected statement in the first available issue of the Florida Administrative Weekly, and file a copy of the corrected statement with the committee; or</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the committee that it refuses to prepare a corrected statement of estimated regulatory costs.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph></Subsection><Subsection Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the agency to respond to a committee objection to a rule that is not yet in effect within the time prescribed in subsection (3) constitutes withdrawal of the rule in its entirety. In this event, the committee shall notify the Department of State that the agency, by its failure to respond to a committee objection, has elected to withdraw the rule. Upon receipt of the committee’s notice, the Department of State shall publish a notice to that effect in the next available issue of the Florida Administrative Weekly. Upon publication of the notice, the rule shall be stricken from the files of the Department of State and the files of the agency.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="5"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the agency to respond to a committee objection to a rule that is in effect within the time prescribed in subsection (3) constitutes a refusal to amend or repeal the rule.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="6"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of the agency to respond to a committee objection to a statement of estimated regulatory costs within the time prescribed in subsection (3) constitutes a refusal to prepare a corrected statement of estimated regulatory costs.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="7"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the committee objects to a rule and the agency refuses to modify, amend, withdraw, or repeal the rule, the committee shall file with the Department of State a notice of the objection, detailing with particularity the committee’s objection to the rule. The Department of State shall publish this notice in the Florida Administrative Weekly. If the rule is published in the Florida Administrative Code, a reference to the committee’s objection and to the issue of the Florida Administrative Weekly in which the full text thereof appears shall be recorded in a history note.</Text></Subsection><Subsection Id="8"><Paragraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the committee objects to a rule, or portion of a rule, and the agency fails to initiate administrative action to modify, amend, withdraw, or repeal the rule consistent with the objection within 60 days after the objection, or thereafter fails to proceed in good faith to complete such action, the committee may submit to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a recommendation that legislation be introduced to address the committee’s objection.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="b"><SubParagraph Id="1"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the committee votes to recommend the introduction of legislation to address the committee’s objection, the committee shall, within 5 days after this determination, certify that fact to the agency whose rule or proposed rule has been examined. The committee may request that the agency temporarily suspend the rule or suspend the adoption of the proposed rule, pending consideration of proposed legislation during the next regular session of the Legislature.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="2"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Within 30 days after receipt of the certification, if the agency is headed by an individual, or within 45 days after receipt of the certification, if the agency is headed by a collegial body, the agency shall:</Text><SubSubParagraph Id="a"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Temporarily suspend the rule or suspend the adoption of the proposed rule; or</Text></SubSubParagraph><SubSubParagraph Id="b"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Notify the committee in writing that the agency refuses to temporarily suspend the rule or suspend the adoption of the proposed rule.</Text></SubSubParagraph></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="3"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If the agency elects to temporarily suspend the rule or suspend the adoption of the proposed rule, the agency shall give notice of the suspension in the Florida Administrative Weekly. The rule or the rule adoption process shall be suspended upon publication of the notice. An agency may not base any agency action on a suspended rule or suspended proposed rule, or portion of such rule, prior to expiration of the suspension. A suspended rule or suspended proposed rule, or portion of such rule, continues to be subject to administrative determination and judicial review as provided by law.</Text></SubParagraph><SubParagraph Id="4"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">Failure of an agency to respond to committee certification within the time prescribed by subparagraph 2. constitutes a refusal to suspend the rule or to suspend the adoption of the proposed rule.</Text></SubParagraph></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="c"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">The committee shall prepare proposed legislation to address the committee’s objection in accordance with the rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives for prefiling and introduction in the next regular session of the Legislature. The proposed legislation shall be presented to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives with the committee recommendation.</Text></Paragraph><Paragraph Id="d"><Text xml:space="preserve" Style="Intro">If proposed legislation addressing the committee’s objection fails to become law, any temporary agency suspension shall expire.</Text></Paragraph></Subsection></SectionBody><History xml:space="preserve">s. 4, ch. 76-131; s. 1, ch. 77-174; s. 6, ch. 80-391; s. 3, ch. 81-309; s. 4, ch. 87-385; s. 8, ch. 92-166; s. 20, ch. 95-280; s. 14, ch. 96-159; s. 16, ch. 2000-151; s. 18, ch. 2008-4; s. 7, ch. 2008-104.</History></Section>